import{_ as h,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as d,C as y,M as b,U as w,F as c,p,e as f,f as j,q}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const v={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},x={class:"review-title"},N={class:"review-content"};function M(e,a,s,k,t,r){return i(),o("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",x,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(d(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",N,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(d(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const T=h(v,[["render",M],["__scopeId","data-v-058cecf9"]]),S=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada beras taruh dalam padi, ada ingat taruh dalam hati\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kalau ada sesuatu cita-cita yang diinginkan tidak perlulah dikhabarkan kepada orang sebelum dikerjakan."},{"question":"Est-il possible que nous sommes pas vraiment allés sur la lune?","answer":"Non, il n'y a aucune preuve crédible pour soutenir l'idée que les missions lunaires Apollo de la NASA étaient des mises en scène. Les preuves abondent pour démontrer que les astronautes ont effectivement marché sur la lune en 1969 et lors des missions suivantes. Des milliers de personnes ont été impliquées dans le programme Apollo et des dizaines de milliers de documents, photographies, enregistrements audio et vidéos ont été produits et examinés par des experts du monde entier. De plus, les missions Apollo ont été suivies de près par des observateurs indépendants et par des agences spatiales d'autres pays. Les arguments avancés par les théories du complot sur les missions lunaires Apollo sont largement basés sur des malentendus, des déformations des faits et des interprétations erronées de l'évidence scientifique et historique disponible. Ainsi, il est scientifiquement établi que les humains ont marché sur la lune."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:नाना विद्या कळा सिद्धी । नाना निश्चयाची बुद्धी ।जे सूक्ष्म वस्तूची शुद्धी । ज्ञेप्तीमात्र ॥ २१॥अर्थ:","answer":"परमात्मस्वरूपाच्या ठिकाणी केवळ जाणीवरूपाने स्फुरणारी सूक्ष्म शुद्ध जाणीव हेच शारदेचे मूळरूप असून तीच नंतर नाना विद्या, नाना कला, नाना सिद्धी व नाना मतांसंबंधीच्या निश्चयात्मक बुद्धीच्या रूपाने प्रगट होत असते. (२१)"},{"question":"Көз таңмай деген оюн кандай болот?","answer":"Көз таңмай деген оюн ашта, тойдо жана келин алуу бала олтургузуу чоң жоро,шеринелерде, бала төрөлгөндө болот. Ал көз таңмайга ар бир талаптуу кишичыгат. Мен чыгам деген кишинин көзүн баякы калыс кишилерден келип, байлап бул урук элдин кишисинин көзүн башка бир уруктан чыккан калыс киши жоолук менен жылчыксыз байлайт. Алардын көзү байлана электе элдин орто жерине узун таяктын учуна жоолук байлап жерге бекем сайып койгонун көрсөтөт. Анын байгесин жарчылар мурда угузган болот. Көзү таңылган кишилерди жанакы таякты таап ал деп туш тараптан барып тең кое берет. Мында карап олтурган көпчүлүк элге күлкү пайда болот. Анткени баякы кишилер ар бир жакка темселеп кулачып жайып баса берет. Кээ бир кыраакы сымал кишилер таякты бет ала басканда анын эли «Кургурум — эми түз баскай элең» деген сөзгө келет. Бирок кишинин атын айтып катуу үн чыгарыш элдин калоосунда болбогон үчүн өз ара гана акырын сүйлөп олтурушат. Баякы таякты көздөй бараткан киши өтүп кеттимби деген ой менен кайра тартып же башка жагын көздөй бурулганда эл күлүп калат. Башка бир кишилер бирден басып олтуруп, олтурган элди карайкелатканында болот. Кай бирлери элден озалбай тегеренип жүрө берет. Булортодогу көзү таңылган 20—30 кишинин ар биринин ар бир жакта жүргөндөгүборумун көрүп эл күлө берет. Кайсы бирлери кулачын жайып баратып биринебири урунуп алып, чочуп кетип экөө эки жакка жалт берип кетишет. Анда дагы күлкү кай бирлери бирин-бири кучактап калат. Эгер арык же ийиндүү жерлери дуушар болгондору көмөлөнүп кетет. Анда бир амал болот бир киши таякты көздөй түз баратса анын өз тарабынан бирөөнү белгилүү киши арка жактагы күлүк аттарды бастырып турган балдарда чакырган болуп катуу үнү менен бери эле түз бастырып кел деп артын карап кыйкырат. Ошонун үнүн болжоп баякы киши таякты таап алышы мүмкүн. Бирок андай амалдар мурун эле макулдашып алгандыгы белгилүү."},{"question":"Vem är hertig av Värmland?","answer":"Prins Carl Philip är hertig av Värmland och prinsessan Sofia är hertiginna av Värmland."},{"question":"請用簡潔的語言回答以下問題：人類學如何研究不同文化的神話與宗教？","answer":"答案：人類學通過研究不同文化的神話故事、宗教儀式、信仰系統等方面來了解其神話與宗教的文化意義和社會功能。"},{"question":"问题：油的成分是什么？","answer":"回答：油的成分主要是脂肪酸和甘油，不同类型的油可能含有不同种类和比例的脂肪酸。"},{"question":"Atsakyk į šį klausimą: Kiek gyventojų gyveno Mažeikiuose, pagal 2021 metų visuotinį surašymą?","answer":"Pagal 2021 metų surašymą, Mažeikių mieste gyveno 33101 gyventojas. "},{"question":"ඉන්දියාව නිදහස ලැබූ වසර","answer":"ඉන්දියාව ස්වාධීන රාජ්‍යක් ලෙස එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාලනයෙන් නිදහස ලැබුවේ ක්‍රි.ව. 1947 දී ය."},{"question":"inona no anaran'ny fitaovana fandanjana?","answer":"mizana no anaran'ny fitaovana fandanjana"},{"question":"வினா: 1984-ஆம் ஆண்டு இலவச சத்துணவு திட்டத்தை தமிழ்நாட்டில் ஆரம்பித்து வைத்தவர்1. கே.காமராஜ்2. சி.என்.அண்ணாதுரை3. மு.கருணாநிதி4. எம்.ஜி.ராமச்சந்திரன்","answer":"  விடை:4. எம்.ஜி.ராமச்சந்திரன்எம். ஜி. ஆர் என்ற பெயரில் புகழ் பெற்ற, மருதூர் கோபாலன் இராமச்சந்திரன் (எம். ஜி. இராமச்சந்திரன், 17 சனவரி 1917 – 24 திசம்பர் 1987), தமிழ்த் திரைப்பட நடிகராகவும் 1977 முதல் இறக்கும் வரை தமிழ்நாட்டின் தொடர்ந்து மூன்று முறை முதலமைச்சராகவும் இருந்தவர்.எம். ஜி. சக்கரபாணிக்குத் தம்பியான இவர், தொடக்க காலத்தில் நாடகங்களில் நடித்தார். காந்தியடிகளின் கருத்துகளால் ஈர்க்கப்பெற்று இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரசில் இணைந்தார். 1936 இல் சதிலீலாவதி என்ற திரைப்படம் மூலம் தமிழக திரைத்துறையில் அறிமுகமாகி, கதாநாயகனாக மாறிய பிறகு, அறிஞர் அண்ணாவின் அரசியல் கருத்துகளில் ஈர்க்கப்பெற்று திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகத்தில் இணைந்தார். அண்ணாவின் மறைவுக்குப்பிறகு, இவரின் நண்பர் கருணாநிதியால் திமுகவிலிருந்து நீக்கப்பட்டார். அதன் பின் அண்ணா திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம் என்ற அரசியல் கட்சியைத் தொடங்கி, அதன் பாெதுச்செயலாளாராக ஆக்கி, சட்டமன்ற தேர்தலில் நின்று தொடர்ந்து மூன்று முறை தமிழகத்தில் வெற்றிபெற்று முதலமைச்சரானார். இவர் உயரிய விருதுகளில் ஒன்றான பாரத ரத்னா விருதினை பெற்றவர்"},{"question":"都市部が拡大するにつれて、郊外地域が無秩序に市街地として拡大してしまう現象のことを何というでしょう?","answer":"スプロール現象"},{"question":"تلخيص المقال:  راهيم ستيرلينج أعطى نظرة ثاقبة لمستقبله يوم الأربعاء ، مؤكدًا أنه ليس شابًا يبلغ من العمر 20 عامًا يلتقط المال على الرغم من رفضه عقد ليفربول بقيمة 100,000 جنيه إسترليني في الأسبوع. وبدلا من ذلك ، أشار لاعب الجناح الإنجليزي إلى رغبته في إنهاء الموسم قبل النظر في أي عروض أخرى ، مع التركيز على الفوز بالبطولات مع ناديه في الوقت الحالي. بس كم من اللي قاله ستيرلينج لبي بي سي سبورت ممكن نصدق؟ رياث السمراءي من سبورتس ميل يحاول يده في الترجمة. نجم ليفربول رحيم ستيرلينج اعطي نظرة مفاجئة عن محادثاته مع ليفربول مع بي بي سي سبورت ما قاله: <unk> أنا ما كنتش عايز المشجعين يفكروا بشيء سيئ عني، ليعتقدوا إنني فقط أُريد الكثير من المال لنفسي. عايزهم يفهموا انه كان كتير علي الموسم ده، مع كل واحد بيتكلم عنه كل دقيقة. معناها: مش ممكن الشاب يترك عقده يمر بس بسلام؟ اللي قاله: ما كانش قط بخصوص فلوس. انا اتكلم عن الفوز بالجوائز طوال مهنتي. ده كل اللي اتكلم عنه. معناه: إنهاء الموسم خالي اليدين مش هيساعد الموقف. يقول ستيرلينج إنه مش بخصوص المال، بل حول الكؤوس فقط - فهل ليفربول يقدر لا يفوز بأي واحدة الموسم ده؟ ما قاله: انا مش هتكلم عن كم سياره سأقودها، وكم بيت عندي. أنا بس عايز أكون أحسن ما أقدر. لو كنت تتسائل، أنا أقود مرسيدس سي 63 و عندي رينج روفر 4×4. كلاهما بيض. اللي قاله: انت فعلا عايز تعمل مع لاعبين من الدرجة العالمية كل يوم. من الواضح انه بقى هناك خدش صغير، رحيل هذين النجمين العالميين (سواريز و جيرارد) ، لكن اعتقد اننا عندنا لاعبين كويسين في ليفربول. معناها: المشاركين بيجي وبيروحوا. تعاملي مع الموضوع ده. استرلينج رفض عرض عقود ليفربول بمبلغ 100 ألف جنيه إسبوعياً ويقول إنه بتركز على كرة القدم. على التكهنات بأن آرسنال حريص: معناها: المزادات دايما بتكون احسن لما يجي ناس اكتر. ما قاله: حلم كل واحد وهو يكبر هو يرى نفسه...","answer":"رهيم ستيرلينج رفض عرض عقد بمئة ألف جنيه في الأسبوع في ليفربول. الجناح الشاب أعطى مقابلة كاشفة لبي بي سي يوم الأربعاء. وهو لا يريد المال فقط."},{"question":"Miliọnu meji dọla ati miliọnu mẹtadinlogun naira ni wọn ko laafin mi lasiko iwọde SARS – Ọba Akiolu","answer":"Ọba ilu Eko, Rilwan Arẹmu Akiolu, ti ṣalaye pe miliọnu meji owo dọla (2million) ati milọnu mẹtadinlogun naira (N17million) ni wọn ko lọ laafin oun ni Iga Iduganran, nisalẹ Eko, lasiko iwọde ta ko SARS to waye lọdun to kọja.Yatọ si towo, ọba naa lawọn janduku tun ji ọpa aṣẹ oun gbe lọ, atawọn dukia mi-in to wa ninu aafin naa.Akiolu sọrọ yii nigba to n sọrọ nibi ṣiṣi gbọngan igbalode Glover Hall Memorial, tijọba kọ si Opopona Broad, Marina, l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii.O lawọn nnkan toun padanu lasiko ti wọn ṣe akọlu si aafin oun pọ gidi, oun si fẹ ki ijọba apapọ ṣeranwọ fun ipinlẹ Eko lati ṣe atunkọ awọn nnkan ti wọn bajẹ lasiko yanpọnyanrin ọhun.“Ma a fọwọ si ohunkohun to maa mu itẹsiwaju ba ilu Eko. Mo ti parọwa si ijọba apapọ lati ran ilu Eko lọwọ latari awọn nnkan ta a padanu lasiko wahala yẹn. Iṣẹlẹ to waye logunjọ si ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun to kọja yẹn, baayan lọkan jẹ gidi. Ohun ta a padanu nipinlẹ Eko kuro ni wasa.“Ọpọ ile ni wọn dana sun, titi kan awọn mọto ti a fi n pawo wọle. Mo le sọ ọ ni gbangba bayii pe miliọnu meji owo dọla ati miliọnu mẹtadinlogun owo naira ni wọn ji laafin mi, yatọ si ti ọpa aṣẹ atawọn dukia mi-in ti wọn ko lọ.“Awọn to huwa buruku yii iba ma ṣe bẹẹ ka ni wọn mọ itumọ ohun ti wọn ṣe yẹn ni. Ṣugbọn gẹgẹ bii baba ti mọ jẹ, mi o ni i fi wọn gegun-un” Bayii ni Ọba Akiolu wi."},{"question":"質量はほとんどゼロであり、とらえることが非常に難しい中性の素粒子で、ノーベル物理学賞の小柴昌俊氏の研究テーマでもあるのは何でしょう？","answer":"ニュートリノ (neutrino)です。"},{"question":"Waxaad seegtaa daawooyinka la siiyo dadka nafaqo xumada qabo?","answer":"1. Vitamin A.2. Albendazole3. Mebendazole4. Measles vaccine5. Iron/folate6. Amoxicillin, gentamycin, iyo chlorophenicol."},{"question":"ब्रिटीश पार्लमेंटने रेग्युलेटिंग अॅक्ट कोणत्या वर्षी पास केला ?","answer":"इ.स. 1773"},{"question":"Escribe la continuación de este texto : Durante la Guerra de Crimea, Forey dirigió la división que estuvo a cargo del Sitio de Sebastopol en 1854. En la guerra franco-austriaca de 1859, participó en las batallas de Montebello y Solferino... ","answer":"Donde destacó por someter a las últimas posiciones austriacas, situadas cerca de la villa de Favriano."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe PIB (harinkarena faobe)?","answer":"Ny harinkarena faobe (PIB) dia mandrefy ny tontalin'ny sandan'ny entana sy serivisy vokarina ao amin'ny firenena iray mandritra ny fe-potoana iray."},{"question":"Oğuz Atay kimlerden etkilenmiştir?","answer":"- Ahmet Hamdi Tanpınar- Halid Ziya Uşaklıgil- Vüs'at O. Bener- Sabahattin Ali- Kemal Tahir- Yusuf Atılgan- Robert Musil- Hermann Hesse- Franz Kafka- Marcel Proust- Samuel Beckett- James Joyce- Vladimir Nabokov- Fyodor Mihayloviç Dostoyevski"},{"question":" Iza no mpilalao sarimihetsika nilalao tao amin'ny King Kong tany am-boalohany tamin'ny 1933 ?","answer":"I Fay Wray no mpilalao sarimihetsika nilalao tao amin'ny King Kong tany am-boalohany tamin'ny 1933."},{"question":"வினா:  மீன்கள் இல்லாத ஆறு எது? ","answer":"விடை : ஜோர்டான் ஆறு. குறிப்பு:           ஜோர்டான் நதியின் சிறப்புகளில் ஒன்று இது 360 கிலோமீட்டருக்கும் அதிகமான நீளம் கொண்டது, ஆனால் அதன் முறுக்கு போக்கு காரணமாக, அதன் மூலத்திற்கும் சவக்கடலுக்கும் இடையிலான உண்மையான தூரம் 200 கிலோமீட்டருக்கும் குறைவாக உள்ளது. 1948 க்குப் பிறகு, இந்த நதி இஸ்ரேலுக்கும் ஜோர்டானுக்கும் இடையிலான எல்லையைக் குறித்தது, கலிலி கடலின் தெற்குப் பகுதியிலிருந்து கிழக்கு (இடது) கரையிலிருந்து அபிஸ் நதி பாயும் இடம் வரை.   இருப்பினும், 1967 முதல், இஸ்ரேலிய துருப்புக்கள் மேற்குக் கரையை ஆக்கிரமித்தபோது (அதாவது, ஐபிஸ் நதியுடன் சங்கமிக்கும் இடத்திற்கு தெற்கே உள்ள மேற்குக் கரைப் பகுதி), ஜோர்டான் நதி தெற்கே கடல் வரை போர்நிறுத்தக் கோடாக நீண்டுள்ளது.           கிரேக்கர்கள் ஆலோன் நதியை அழைத்தனர், சில சமயங்களில் அரேபியர்கள் அதை அல்-ஷரியா (\\"குடிநீர் இடம்\\") என்று அழைத்தனர். கிறிஸ்தவர்கள், யூதர்கள் மற்றும் முஸ்லிம்கள் ஜோர்டான் நதியை வணங்குகிறார்கள். அதன் நீரில்தான் இயேசு புனித ஜான் பாப்டிஸ்டால் ஞானஸ்நானம் பெற்றார். இந்த நதி எப்போதும் ஒரு மத சரணாலயமாகவும் ஞானஸ்நானம் செய்யும் இடமாகவும் இருந்து வருகிறது.         ஜோர்டான் நதிக்கு மூன்று முக்கிய ஆதாரங்கள் உள்ளன, இவை அனைத்தும் ஹெர்மோன் மலையின் அடிவாரத்தில் உருவாகின்றன. இவற்றில் மிக நீளமானது 1800 அடி உயரத்தில் லெபனானில் உள்ள ஹஷ்பயாவுக்கு அருகில் உள்ள ஹஷ்பானி ஆகும். (550மீ) பனியாஸ் ஆறு கிழக்கிலிருந்து சிரியா வழியாக செல்கிறது. நடுவில் டான் நதி உள்ளது, அதன் நீர் குறிப்பாக புத்துணர்ச்சியூட்டுகிறது.              இஸ்ரேலுக்குள், இந்த மூன்று ஆறுகளும் ஹுலா பள்ளத்தாக்கில் சந்திக்கின்றன. ஹுலா பள்ளத்தாக்கு சமவெளி முதலில் ஏரிகள் மற்றும் சதுப்பு நிலங்களால் ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்பட்டது, ஆனால் 1950 களில் சுமார் 60 சதுர கிலோமீட்டர்கள் வடிகால் செய்யப்பட்டு விவசாய நிலங்களை உருவாக்கியது. 1990களில், பள்ளத்தாக்கு தளத்தின் பெரும்பகுதி சிதைந்து, பகுதிகள் நீரில் மூழ்கின.             ஏரி மற்றும் சுற்றியுள்ள சதுப்பு நிலத்தை பாதுகாக்கப்பட்ட இயற்கை இருப்புப் பகுதியாக வைக்க முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது, மேலும் சில தாவரங்கள் மற்றும் விலங்கினங்கள், குறிப்பாக புலம்பெயர்ந்த பறவைகள், அப்பகுதிக்கு திரும்பியது. பள்ளத்தாக்கின் தெற்கு முனையில், ஜோர்டான் நதி ஒரு பசால்ட் தடுப்பு வழியாக ஒரு பள்ளத்தாக்கை வெட்டுகிறது. இந்த நதி கலிலேயா கடலின் வடக்கு கரையை நோக்கி செங்குத்தாக பாய்கிறது.ஜோர்டான் நதி உருவாக்கம்:     ஜோர்டான் நதி ஜோர்டான் பள்ளத்தாக்கிற்கு மேலே உள்ளது, இது இஸ்ரேலுக்கும் ஜோர்டானுக்கும் இடையில் பூமியின் மேலோட்டத்தில் உள்ள ஒரு தாழ்வானது, இது மியோசீன் காலத்தில் உருவானது, அரேபிய தட்டு வடக்கே நகர்ந்தபோது மற்றும் இன்றைய ஆப்பிரிக்காவில் இருந்து கிழக்கு நோக்கி நகர்ந்தது. சுமார் 1 மில்லியன் ஆண்டுகளுக்கு பிறகு, நிலம் உயர்ந்தது மற்றும் கடல் பின்வாங்கியது. கிழக்கு-மத்திய ஜோர்டான் பள்ளத்தாக்கில் ட்ரயாசிக் மற்றும் மெசோசோயிக் அடுக்குகள் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.இஸ்ரேல் நதி:    ஜோர்டான் ஆறு சந்தேகத்திற்கு இடமின்றி அருகிலுள்ள கிழக்கின் வறண்ட பகுதிகளில் ஒன்றின் நடுவில் ஓடுகிறது. பெரும்பாலானவை வளமான நிலம் மேற்குக் கரையிலும், ஜோர்டான் ஆற்றின் கிழக்கு மற்றும் மேற்குக் கரையிலும் காணப்படுகிறது. இந்த படுகையில் நீங்கள் ஈரமான மத்திய தரைக்கடல் பகுதிகள் முதல் வறண்ட பகுதிகள் வரை இனங்கள் வாழ்வதற்கு ஏற்றவாறு காணலாம். போன்ற மீன்களும் உள்ளன மொல்லஸ்க்ஸ் மெலனோப்சிஸ் அம்மோனிஸ் y மெலனோப்சிஸ் கோஸ்டாட்டா மற்றும் ஓட்டுமீன்கள் போன்றவை பொட்டமன் பொட்டாமியோஸ் மற்றும் எமரிட்டா இனத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள். படுகையில் கொறித்துண்ணிகள் போன்ற பாலூட்டிகள் வசிக்கின்றன மஸ் மாசிடோனிகஸ் மற்றும் யூரேசிய நீர்நாய் (லூத்ரா லூத்ரா); போன்ற பூச்சிகள் கலோப்டெரிக்ஸ் சிரியாக்கா மற்றும் சினாய் புல்ஃபிஞ்ச் போன்ற பறவைகள் (கார்போடகஸ் சினோய்கு).            தாவரங்களைப் பொறுத்தவரை, புதர்கள், புதர்கள் மற்றும் புற்கள் ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்துகின்றன, மற்றும் புள்ளிகளில் உயரமாக வளரும் ஆலிவ் மரங்கள், சிடார், யூகலிப்டஸ், கருவேலமரங்கள் மற்றும் பைன்கள், மற்றும் கடைசி இடங்களில் முட்கள் நிறைந்த புதர்கள் வளரும்.பொருளாதார முக்கியத்துவம்:ஜோர்டான் நதியின் நீர் இஸ்ரேலின் இரண்டாவது மிக முக்கியமான நீர் ஆதாரமாகும். பெரும்பாலான நீர் விவசாயம் மற்றும் பண்ணைக்கு நிதியளிக்கப் பயன்படுகிறது, மேலும் ஆற்றின் மக்கள்தொகை பெருகும் மற்றும் பொருளாதாரம் வளர்ச்சியடையும் போது, ​​குடியிருப்பாளர்களின் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்ய நீர் இறைப்பது அவசியம். ஜோர்டான் நதியிலிருந்து 50 மில்லியன் கன மீட்டர் தண்ணீரை ஜோர்டான் மட்டும் பெறுகிறது.  விவசாயம் மற்றும் வீட்டு உபயோகத்திற்கு தண்ணீர் தேவை அதிகம்; மறுபுறம், தொழில்துறையின் தண்ணீர் தேவை மிகவும் சிறியது. இது முக்கியமாக அகபா வளைகுடா தொழில்துறை மண்டலம் மற்றும் சவக்கடல் பகுதியில் உள்ள தொழில்களின் எண்ணிக்கை மற்றும் அளவு அதிகரிப்பு காரணமாகும்.ஜோர்டான் நதி:ஒரு காலத்தில் தெளிவான மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பான நதியாக இருந்த ஜோர்டான் நதி இப்போது மிகவும் மாசுபட்ட மற்றும் அதிக உப்புத்தன்மை கொண்ட நீர்நிலையாக உள்ளது. கொள்கையளவில், இந்த நதி உலகின் மிக அடர்த்தியான மக்கள்தொகை மற்றும் நீர் பற்றாக்குறை பகுதிகளில் ஓடுகிறது, எனவே அதன் இயற்கை வளங்களின் பயன்பாடு பெரும்பாலும் அதன் மீளுருவாக்கம் திறனை மீறுகிறது. ஆற்றின் ஓட்டம் அதன் அசல் ஓட்டத்தில் 2% ஆக குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது என்று மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. அதிக ஆவியாதல், வறண்ட காலநிலை மற்றும் அதிகப்படியான உந்தி உமிழ்நீருக்கு வழிவகுக்கிறது. சுருக்கமாக, ஜோர்டான் நதியின் எதிர்காலம் மற்றும் அதன் படுகையில் உள்ள மக்கள் மீது மக்கள் அக்கறை கொண்டுள்ளனர்.கடுமையான சுற்றுச்சூழல் பிரச்சினைகளைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்காக, நதி வளங்களின் நிலையான மேலாண்மையில் கவனம் செலுத்த சில அமைப்புகளும் அரசாங்கங்களும் ஒன்றிணைந்துள்ளன. மத்திய கிழக்கின் ஒரு பொதுவான வறண்ட பகுதியில் உள்ள ஒரு நன்னீர் ஓடை, ஜோர்டான் நதி அதன் அருகில் வசிக்கும் மில்லியன் கணக்கான மக்களுக்கு ஒரு முக்கியமான, தனித்துவமான மற்றும் விலைமதிப்பற்ற வளமாகும்.அதன் நீரைப் பயன்படுத்தும் நாடு அதன் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட ஓட்டத்தில் கிட்டத்தட்ட 98% இழந்துவிட்டது (இஸ்ரேல், சிரியா, ஜோர்டான் மற்றும் பாலஸ்தீனம்) இன்னும் சில ஆண்டுகளில் வறண்டு போகும். உறுதியான மற்றும் பயனுள்ள நடவடிக்கைகள் இல்லாமல். இயேசு ஞானஸ்நானம் பெற்ற ஜோர்டான் நதியின் சரிவுக்கு இஸ்ரேல், சிரியா மற்றும் ஜோர்டான் காரணம், இது இப்போது வானத்திற்கு திறந்திருக்கும் சாக்கடையாகும், இதன் மூலம் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான கன மீட்டர் கழிவு நீர் பாய்கிறது. கலிலி கடல் மற்றும் சவக்கடல், தெற்கே 105 கிலோமீட்டர் தொலைவில் உள்ள நீர், ஆண்டுக்கு கிட்டத்தட்ட 1.300 பில்லியன் கன மீட்டர் வீதம் காலி செய்யப்படுகிறது.இஸ்ரேல் அரசு தொடர்ந்து தண்ணீரை மாற்றுகிறது. இது உள்நாட்டு பயன்பாடு மற்றும் விவசாய உற்பத்திக்கான ஓட்டத்தில் சுமார் 46,47% ஆகும்; சிரியா 25,24%, ஜோர்டான் 23,24% மற்றும் பாலஸ்தீனம் 5,05%. எனவே, ஜோர்டான் நதி இனி உயர்தர புதிய நீரின் நிலையான ஆதாரமாக இல்லை, மேலும் அதன் ஓட்டம் இப்போது வருடத்திற்கு 20-30 மில்லியன் கன மீட்டரை எட்டுகிறது.நமது சூரியனை உன்னிப்பாகக் கவனித்து, 250 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலான வரலாற்றுப் பதிவைக் கொண்ட விஞ்ஞானிகளின் கூற்றுப்படி, 1755 முதல், ஏப்ரல் 2023 முதல் சூரிய செயல்பாட்டின் அளவு சமீபத்திய தசாப்தங்களில் முன்னோடியில்லாத வகையில் தீவிரத்தை எட்டியுள்ளது. இந்த சிறப்பு வல்லுநர்கள் சூரியனின் மேற்பரப்பில் நிகழும் சிக்கலான இயக்கங்களை உன்னிப்பாகப் பதிவு செய்கிறார்கள். சூரிய புள்ளிகள் உருவாகும் நிகழ்வு டெர்மினேட்டர் விளைவு என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. இருப்பினும், பலருக்கு தெரியாது டெர்மினேட்டர் விளைவு என்ன. எனவே, டெர்மினேட்டர் நிகழ்வு என்ன, அதன் குணாதிசயங்கள் மற்றும் பின்விளைவுகள் என்ன என்பதைச் சொல்ல இந்தக் கட்டுரையை அர்ப்பணிக்கப் போகிறோம்.குறியீட்டு:சமீபத்திய மாதங்களில், சூரிய செயல்பாட்டில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அதிகரிப்பு உள்ளது, சூரியனின் வாழ்க்கைச் சுழற்சியின் உச்சம், 2025 ஆம் ஆண்டின் நடுப்பகுதியில் எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டது, எதிர்பார்த்ததை விட விரைவில் நெருங்குகிறது. ஏப்ரலில் கவனிக்கப்பட்ட ஒரு சுவாரஸ்யமான நிகழ்வு வழக்கத்தை விட குறைந்த அட்சரேகைகளில் அரோராக்கள் தோன்றுவதாகும் சமீபத்திய புவி காந்த புயல்களின் தீவிரத்தை குறிக்கிறது. இது எதிர்பார்த்ததை விட ஒரு வருடம் முன்னதாகவே \\"சூரிய உச்சநிலை\\" கட்டம் வந்திருக்கலாம் என்று விஞ்ஞானிகள் சந்தேகிக்க வழிவகுத்தது.பூமியிலிருந்து பார்க்கும்போது சூரியன் ஒரு மாறாத கோளமாகத் தோன்றினாலும், அது உண்மையில் அதன் செயல்பாட்டில் ஏற்ற இறக்கங்களுக்கு உட்பட்டு சிக்கலான இயக்கவியலைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. நமது நட்சத்திரத்தின் உள்ளே, ஹைட்ரஜன் மற்றும் ஹீலியம் போன்ற சூடான வாயுக்கள் மின் கட்டணங்களைக் கொண்டு செல்கின்றன, இது குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வலிமையுடன் காந்தப்புலங்களை உருவாக்க வழிவகுக்கிறது. இந்த வாயுக்கள் நகரும் போது, ​​காந்தப்புலக் கோடுகள் நீண்டு, பின்னிப்பிணைந்து, சுழன்று, மறுசீரமைத்து, சூரியனின் மேற்பரப்பில் சூரிய செயல்பாடு என்று அழைக்கப்படுவதை உருவாக்குகிறது.ஒரு சூரிய சுழற்சியின் நீளம் தோராயமாக 11 ஆண்டுகள் ஆகும் மற்றும் கண்டறியப்பட்டு பதிவு செய்யப்படும் சூரிய புள்ளிகளின் எண்ணிக்கையின் ஏற்ற இறக்கத்தை பகுப்பாய்வு செய்வதன் மூலம் தீர்மானிக்கப்படுகிறது.. சூரிய செயல்பாட்டின் நிலை சீராக இல்லை மற்றும் அதிக செயல்பாட்டின் காலங்கள் (மாக்சிமா என அறியப்படுகிறது) மற்றும் உறவினர் அமைதியான காலங்கள் (மினிமா என அழைக்கப்படுகிறது) ஆகியவற்றுக்கு இடையில் ஏற்ற இறக்கமாக இருக்கும். இந்த ஏற்ற இறக்கங்கள் சூரிய சுழற்சி எனப்படும் ஒரு முறையைப் பின்பற்றுகின்றன, இது பொதுவாக சுமார் 11 ஆண்டுகள் நீடிக்கும், இருப்பினும் ஒவ்வொரு சுழற்சியின் நீளம் மற்றும் ஆற்றல் நிலைகள் மாறுபடும். ஒவ்வொரு சுழற்சியின் போதும், சூரியனின் காந்தப்புலம் அதன் வடக்கு மற்றும் தென் துருவங்களின் தலைகீழ் மாற்றத்திற்கு உட்படுகிறது.வலுவான காந்த செயல்பாட்டை வெளிப்படுத்தும் சூரியனின் பகுதிகள் சூரிய புள்ளிகள் என்று அழைக்கப்படுகின்றன. இந்த சூரிய புள்ளிகள் விஞ்ஞானிகளுக்கு வழங்குகின்றன சூரியன் வெளியிடும் ஒளி, ஆற்றல் மற்றும் பொருள் பற்றிய மதிப்புமிக்க தகவல்கள், சூரிய சுழற்சியைக் கண்காணிக்கவும் அளவிடவும் அனுமதிக்கின்றன.பூமியை எதிர்கொள்ளும் சூரியன்:ஒரு சூரிய சுழற்சியின் தொடக்கத்தில், மிகக் குறைந்த எண்ணிக்கையிலான சூரிய புள்ளிகளால் வகைப்படுத்தப்படும் குறைந்தபட்ச சூரிய செயல்பாட்டின் காலம் உள்ளது. காலப்போக்கில், செயல்பாட்டின் நிலை மற்றும் இடங்களின் எண்ணிக்கை இரண்டும் படிப்படியாக அதிகரிக்கும். சுழற்சியின் நடுப்பகுதியைச் சுற்றி, சூரிய அதிகபட்சம் அடையப்படுகிறது, இது அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான புள்ளிகளால் குறிக்கப்படுகிறது. இந்த உச்சத்திற்குப் பிறகு, ஒரு புதிய சுழற்சியின் தொடக்கத்தைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில், சூரிய குறைந்தபட்ச நிலைக்குத் திரும்புவதன் மூலம் சுழற்சி முடிவடையும் வரை புள்ளிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை குறையத் தொடங்குகிறது.மிக சமீபத்திய சூரிய குறைந்தபட்சம் டிசம்பர் 2019 இல் நடந்தது, இது தற்போதைய சுழற்சியின் தொடக்கத்தைக் குறித்தது, இது எண் 25 என அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. ஆரம்பத்தில், 2025 இல் செய்யப்பட்ட மதிப்பீடுகளின் அடிப்படையில் 2020 இல் சூரிய ஒளி அதிகபட்சம் ஏற்படும் என்று வல்லுநர்கள் கணித்துள்ளனர். இருப்பினும், சமீபத்திய அவதானிப்புகள் இந்த கட்டத்தில் எதிர்பார்த்ததை விட அதிக அளவிலான செயல்பாட்டைக் காட்டுகின்றன என்பதைக் காட்டுகின்றன. விரைவில் சந்தித்தார்.அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள வளிமண்டல ஆராய்ச்சிக்கான தேசிய மையத்தின் (NCAR) இயக்குனர் ஸ்காட் டபிள்யூ. மெக்கின்டோஷின் கருத்துப்படி, சுழற்சியின் சூரிய உச்சம் 25 எதிர்பார்த்ததை விட ஒரு வருடம் முன்னதாக அதன் அதிகபட்ச கட்டத்தை அடைந்தது. இதன் விளைவாக, நமது சூரியன் அதிக சக்தி வாய்ந்த புவி காந்த புயல்களை உருவாக்குகிறது. இந்த ஆண்டின் இறுதியிலும் 2024 ஆம் ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்திலும் சூரிய செயல்பாடு அதிகரிக்கும் என்று நிபுணர்கள் கணித்துள்ளனர், இது \\"டெர்மினேட்டர் விளைவு\\" தோற்றத்துடன் ஒத்துப்போகிறது.சன்ஸ்பாட்கள்:சூரியனுக்குள் இரண்டு ஒரே நேரத்தில் மற்றும் பின்னிப்பிணைந்த சூரிய சுழற்சிகள் இருப்பதை ஒரு ஆய்வு விவரிக்கிறது.இந்த சுழற்சிகள் தடையின்றி மாறுகின்றன, மற்றொன்று வெளிவரும்போது மற்றொன்று மறைந்துவிடும். இந்த மாற்றம் சூரிய செயல்பாட்டின் அதிகரிப்பு மற்றும் சூரிய புள்ளிகள் உருவாவதில் முடிவடைகிறது, இது ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்கள் \\"டெர்மினேட்டர் விளைவு\\" என்று அழைக்கப்படும் ஒரு நிகழ்வு ஆகும். 1903 ஆம் ஆண்டில் விஞ்ஞானி வில்லியம் லாக்யரால் சூரிய சுழற்சிகளை ஒன்றுடன் ஒன்று சேர்க்கும் கருத்து முதலில் முன்மொழியப்பட்டது. இந்த நிகழ்வுகளை விவரிக்க \\"டெர்மினேட்டர்\\" என்ற வார்த்தையை உருவாக்கியவர்.அதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, 2012 இல் ஆவணப்படுத்தப்பட்ட டெர்மினேட்டர் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படும் மிக சமீபத்திய சக்திவாய்ந்த சோலார் எஜெக்டாவின் தாக்கத்திலிருந்து நமது கிரகம் காப்பாற்றப்பட்டது. சூரியப் புள்ளியின் காந்த உறைக்குள் சூரிய ஒளி அல்லது வெடிப்புடன் தொடங்கி. இதன் விளைவாக, தீவிர X-கதிர்கள் மற்றும் புற ஊதா கதிர்வீச்சு மூலம் பூமி விரைவாக குண்டுவீசப்படுகிறது, வளிமண்டலத்தின் மேல் அடுக்குகளின் அயனியாக்கம் ஏற்படுகிறது.டெர்மினேட்டர் விளைவின் விளைவுகள்:இந்த நிகழ்வுகளுக்கு மத்தியில், சூரியன் \\"பிளாஸ்மா சுனாமிகள்\\" என்று அழைக்கப்படுவதை உருவாக்கும் திறன் கொண்ட காந்தப்புலங்களின் மோதல்களை வெளியிடுகிறது. இந்த பிளாஸ்மா அலைகள் அனைத்தும் நேரடியாக பூமியை நோக்கி செலுத்தப்பட்டால், அதன் விளைவுகள் மிகப்பெரிய அளவில் சீர்குலைந்து பேரழிவை ஏற்படுத்தும். இதன் விளைவுகள் குறிப்பாக இருக்கும் உலகளாவிய தகவல் தொடர்பு மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பத்தில் கடுமையான இடையூறுகள், குறிப்பிடத்தக்க இடையூறு மற்றும் குறைபாட்டை ஏற்படுத்துகின்றன.சூரியனின் நிலையற்ற பகுதிகளிலிருந்து ஆற்றல்மிக்க கொரோனல் வெகுஜன வெளியேற்றங்கள் சூரிய மண்டலத்தின் வழியாகச் சென்று வளிமண்டலத்துடன் தொடர்பு கொள்ளும்போது நமது கிரகத்தின் பாதுகாப்பாகச் செயல்படும் பூமியின் காந்த மண்டலம் சீர்குலைந்து, புவி காந்தப் புயல்களை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது.சூரியப் புயல்களின் தாக்கம் ரேடியோ சிக்னல்கள், செயற்கைக்கோள்கள் மற்றும் விண்வெளிப் பயணங்களில் குறுக்கிடுவதைத் தாண்டியது. இந்த சக்திவாய்ந்த நிகழ்வுகள் பூமியில் உள்ள தகவல் தொடர்பு அமைப்புகளை சீர்குலைத்து, ஜிபிஎஸ் அமைப்புகளின் செயல்பாட்டை பாதிக்கின்றன, மின் உற்பத்தி நிலைய செயல்பாடுகளுக்கு இடையூறாக மற்றும் விமானப் பாதுகாப்பை சமரசம் செய்கின்றன. இருப்பினும், சூரிய புயல் டெர்மினேட்டர் விளைவைக் கொண்டிருந்தால், விளைவுகள் இன்னும் தீவிரமானதாக இருக்கும் மற்றும் பேரழிவு தரும் நிதி இழப்புகளை ஏற்படுத்தும்.இத்தகைய நிகழ்வு உலகளாவிய மின் தடைகளைத் தூண்டும் ஆற்றலைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, இது மின்மாற்றிகளுக்கு விரிவான சேதத்தை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது மற்றும் நமது அன்றாட வாழ்க்கையை ஆதரிக்கும் மின் உள்கட்டமைப்பை கடுமையாக பாதிக்கிறது. பூமியைப் பாதிக்கும் டெர்மினேட்டர் நிகழ்வின் நிகழ்தகவு ஒப்பீட்டளவில் குறைவாக இருந்தாலும், அதன் சாத்தியமான தாக்கத்தை குறைத்து மதிப்பிட முடியாது."},{"question":"Smiths හොඳ සංගීත කණ්ඩායමක්ද?","answer":"Smiths යනු 1980 ගණන්වල එංගලන්තයෙන් පැමිණි වඩාත්ම විවේචනාත්මක පැසසුමට ලක් වූ සංගීත කණ්ඩායමකි. සාමාන්‍යයෙන් \\"ඉන්ඩි රොක්\\" සංගීත කණ්ඩායමක් ලෙස වර්ගීකරණය කරන ලද, සංගීත කණ්ඩායම 1984 සිට 1987 දී වෙන් වන තෙක් ඇල්බම 4 ක් නිකුත් කරන ලදී. සංගීත කණ්ඩායමේ සාමාජිකයින්, විශේෂයෙන් මොරිසි සහ ජොනී මාර්, සාර්ථක ඒකල වෘත්තීය ජීවිතයක් ගත කරනු ඇත."},{"question":"س19 - شحال العدد ديال الصمامات فقلب الإنسان ؟","answer":"ج19 - 4 ديال صمامات"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai anjing tersepit di pagar\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud seseorang yang dalam kesusahan serba salah halnya"},{"question":"Kgope","answer":"Ke monna yo a se nago mosadi."},{"question":"在加拿大，安大略省安全帶法例規定，行駛時旅客和駕駛必須繫上安全帶？","answer":"正確，是必須的。"},{"question":"Atsakyk į šį sudėtingą klausimą: Kas yra „Blockchain“ technologija?","answer":"Atsakymas: tai skaitmeninė ekonominių operacijų duomenų bazė, kurioje gali būti saugomi ne tik finansiniai įrašai, bet iš esmės visi vertę turintys duomenys (pinigų likučiai, nuosavybės teisės, tapatybė, vertybiniai popieriai, draudimo įrašai, medicininiai įrašai ir pan.). Ši duomenų bazė yra decentralizuota ir veikia plačiame kompiuterių tinkle, o ne viename centriniame serveryje. Duomenų bazės įrašai saugomi duomenų blokuose, kurie tarpusavyje sujungti į vientisą duomenų blokų grandinę. Kuomet prie esamos blokų grandinės prijungiamas naujas duomenų blokas, šiame bloke esantys duomenys, daugiau niekada negali būti pakeisti."},{"question":"উচ্চশ্রেণির উদ্ভিদে একটি নির্দিষ্ট অঙ্গ রয়েছে যা বংশবৃদ্ধির পাশাপাশি প্রাকৃতিক সৌন্দর্য এবং অর্থনৈতিক সমৃদ্ধির সহায়ক। উক্ত অঙ্গটির পরিবর্তিত রূপ জীবের পুষ্টি উপাদানেও মুখ্য ভূমিকা পালন করে।উদ্দীপক অনুসারে অঙ্গটি কীভাবে প্রাকৃতিক সৌন্দর্য ও প্রাকৃতিক ভারসাম্যের পাশাপাশি অর্থনৈতিক সমৃদ্ধির সহায়ক— বিশ্লেষণ কর।","answer":"উদ্দীপকের উচ্চশ্রেণির উদ্ভিদে প্রাপ্ত নির্দিষ্ট অঙ্গটি হলো ফুল। ফুল হলো প্রজননের জন্য রূপান্তরিত বিশেষ ধরনের বিটপ এবং উচ্চশ্রেণির উদ্ভিদের প্রজনন অঙ্গ। একটি আদর্শ ফুল পুষ্পাক্ষ, বৃতি, দলমণ্ডল, পুংস্তবক ও স্ত্রীস্তবক দিয়ে গঠিত। পুংস্তবক ও স্ত্রীস্তবক প্রজননে সরাসরি অংশ নেয় এবং অন্যান্য স্তবকগুলো পরোক্ষভাবে প্রজননে সহায়তা করে। দলমণ্ডলের প্রতিটি খণ্ডকে বলা হয় পাপড়ি। এগুলো সাধারণত রঙিন হয়। বিভিন্ন উদ্ভিদের পাপড়ির রং বিভিন্ন হয়। এর ফলে রঙের বৈচিত্র্যতার সৃষ্টি হয়। এসব বিভিন্ন উদ্ভিদের সমারোহে প্রাকৃতিক সৌন্দর্য বৃদ্ধি পায়। আবার সমস্ত জীবজগত উদ্ভিদের ওপর নির্ভরশীল। আর, উদ্ভিদের বংশবিস্তার নির্ভর করে ফুলের উপর। উদ্ভিদ গ্যাসীয় আদান-প্রদানের মাধ্যমে বায়ুমন্ডলে অক্সিজেন ও কার্বন ডাই অক্সাইডের অনুপাত ঠিক রাখে। এছাড়া সকল প্রাণী প্রত্যক্ষ বা পরোক্ষভাবে খাদ্যের জন্য উদ্ভিদের উপর নির্ভর করে। তাছাড়া কোন স্থানের বাস্তুতন্ত্র গড়ে উঠে উদ্ভিদকে কেন্দ্র করে। অর্থাৎ পরোক্ষভাবে ফুল প্রাকৃতিক ভারসাম্য রক্ষায় অবদান রাখে। অপরদিকে, নিষেকের পরবর্তীতে ফুলের বিভিন্ন অংশ রূপান্তরিত হয়ে বিভিন্ন অংশ গঠন করে। যেমন- গর্ভাশয় ফলে, ডিম্বক বীজে পরিণত হয়। ফুল, ফল, শস্য, ইত্যাদি রপ্তানি করে প্রচুর বৈদেশিক মুদ্রা অর্জিত হচ্ছে। তাই বলা যায়, প্রাকৃতিক সৌন্দর্য, প্রাকৃতিক ভারসাম্য এবং অর্থনৈতিক সমৃদ্ধিতে ফুলের গুরুত্ব অপরিসীম।"},{"question":"புதிர்:  நாக்கு இல்லாவிட்டால் இவனுக்கு வேலையில்லை அவன் யார்?","answer":"விடை: மணி "},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Schweiz damlandslag i basket representerar Schweiz i basket på damsidan. Laget","answer":"deltog första gången i Europamästerskapet 1938, där man förlorade alla matcher."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ॥ਬਿਖਿਆ ਬਿਆਪਿਆ ਸਗਲ ਸੰਸਾਰੁ ॥ਬਿਖਿਆ ਲੈ ਡੂਬੀ ਪਰਵਾਰੁ ॥੧॥ਰੇ ਨਰ ਨਾਵ ਚਉੜਿ ਕਤ ਬੋੜੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਤੋੜਿ ਬਿਖਿਆ ਸੰਗਿ ਜੋੜੀ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸੁਰਿ ਨਰ ਦਾਧੇ ਲਾਗੀ ਆਗਿ ॥ਨਿਕਟਿ ਨੀਰੁ ਪਸੁ ਪੀਵਸਿ ਨ ਝਾਗਿ ॥੨॥ਚੇਤਤ ਚੇਤਤ ਨਿਕਸਿਓ ਨੀਰੁ ॥ਸੋ ਜਲੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਕਥਤ ਕਬੀਰੁ ॥੩॥੨੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 328 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਭਗਤ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸਾਰਾ ਜਹਾਨ ਹੀ ਮਾਇਆ (ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ) ਨਾਲ ਨੱਪਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ; ਮਾਇਆ ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਕਟੁੰਬ ਨੂੰ (ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਡੋਬੀ ਬੈਠੀ ਹੈ ।੧। ਹੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ! ਤੂੰ (ਆਪਣੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ) ਬੇੜੀ ਕਿਉਂ ਰੜੇ ਥਾਂ ਤੇ ਹੀ ਡੋਬ ਲਈ ਹੈ? ਤੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਤੋੜ ਕੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਨਾਲ ਗੰਢੀ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੈਂ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। (ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ) ਅੱਗ ਲੱਗੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ (ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ) ਦੇਵਤੇ ਤੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸੜ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ । (ਇਸ ਅੱਗ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਾਂਤ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਨਾਮ-ਰੂਪ) ਪਾਣੀ ਭੀ ਨੇੜੇ ਹੀ ਹੈ, ਪਰ (ਇਹ) ਪਸ਼ੂ (ਜੀਵ) ਉੱਦਮ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਪੀਂਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।੨। (ਉਹ ਨਾਮ-ਰੂਪ) ਪਾਣੀ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਪਰਗਟ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ,ਕਬੀਰ ਆਖਦਾ ਹੈ— ਉਹ (ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ-) ਜਲ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ ਅੱਗ ਉਸੇ ਜਲ ਨਾਲ ਬੁਝ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ) ।੩।੨੪।\\""},{"question":"விமானத்தின் உள்ள கருப்புப் பெட்டியின் நிறம் என்ன? 1. பச்சை 2. கருப்பு 3. ஆரஞ்சு 4. நீலம்","answer":"விமானத்தில் இருப்பது உண்மையில் கறுப்புப் பெட்டி அல்ல. நிஜத்தில் இது ஆரஞ்சு வர்ணமுடையது. ஒரு விமானம் விபத்தில் தீப்பற்றிக் கொண்டால், எல்லாமே தீயில் கருகி கறுப்பாகி விடுமல்லவா? இந்த நிலையில் இந்தக் கருவைியக் கண்டுபிடிப்பது எளிதல்ல. எனவேதான் அதை ஆரஞ்சு வர்ணத்தில் வைத்துள்ளார்கள்.1950க்கு முன் இது கண்டுபிடிக்கப்படவில்லை. ஆரம்பத்தில் விமானச் செயற்பாடுகளைப் பதிவது ஓர் உலோகத் துண்டு என்ற நிலையிலிருந்து மாறி, மெமரி சிப்புகள் கொண்ட, நவீன “கறுப்பு பெட்டியாக” இது இப்பொழுது மாற்றம் கண்டுள்ளது.@தற்பொழுதெல்லாம் கறுப்புப் பெட்டிகளை விமானத்தில் இரு பகுதிகளாகப் பொருத்துகிறார்கள். ஒன்று பைலட்டின் காக்பிட்டில் இருப்பது இது! . இது அவரது உரையாடல்களைப் பதிந்து கொள்ளும். மற்றையது விமானத்தின் செயற்பாடுகளை பதிவு செய்யும். விமானம் எந்தளவு உயரத்தில் இருக்கின்றது, என்ஜின் செயற்பாடுகள், விமானம் பறக்கும் வேகம் போன்ற தகவல்கள் இதில் பதிவாகும்..விமான விபத்தின் இறுதி 2 மணி நேரத் தகவல் பரிமாற்றங்களை(அதிகாரிகளுக்கும் கட்டுப்பாட்டு அறைகளுக்கும் இடையிலான) இது பதிவு செய்யும்.இந்தக் கருப்புப் பெட்டிகள் டைட்டானியம் என்ற உலோகத்தால் செய்யப்படுகின்றன. விமானத்திற்கு எவ்வளவு சேதம் ஏற்பாட்டாலும், இந்தக் கறுப்புப் பெட்டி சேதமாகி விடக்கூடாது என்பதற்காக, இப்படியொரு உறுதியான உலோகத்தால், கறுப்புப் பெட்டியைத் தயாரிக்கிறார்கள்..இந்த வலிமையான கறுப்புப் பெட்டியை 10 அடி துாரத்தில் இருந்து 200 கிலோ எடை கொண்ட ஒரு கூர்மையான ஆயுதத்தால் தாக்கினால் சேதம் ஏதும் ஏற்படாது என்று சொல்லும் அளவிற்கு, இந்தப் பெட்டி மிக உறுதி வாய்ந்தது. 20,000 அடி உயரத்திலிருந்து துாக்கி எறிந்தாலும், இதனுள் சேமித்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருக்கும் தகவல்களுக்கு எந்த வித சேதமும் ஏற்படாது என்றும் சொல்லப்படுகின்றது. அது மட்டுமா? விமானம் தீப்பற்றி எரிந்தாலும் சேதப்படுத்தி முடியாத அளவுக்கு, 1100 டிகிரி செல்ஸியஸ் வெப்பத்தைத் தாங்கும் திறன் இந்தப் பெட்டிக்கு உண்டு. கடலுக்குள் போய்விட்டாலும் தொடர்ந்து 30 நாட்களுக்கு தகவல்களுக்கான சமிக்ஞைகளை கட்டுப்பாட்டு அறைக்கு அனுப்பிக் கொண்டே இருக்கும்.இதில் ஒரு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க விடயம் என்னவென்றால் கறுப்புப் பெட்டி விமானத்தில் இருந்தால் மட்டுமே விமானத்தைக் கண்டுபிடிக்க முடியும். தவறினால், இந்தப் பெட்டி மாத்திரமே கிடைக்கும்.@பொதுவாக விமானத்தின் வால்பகுதி விபத்துக்களில் பெருஞ் சேதம் காண்பதில்லை என்ற அடிப்படையில், இந்த கறுப்புப் பெட்டிகளை, வால் பகுதியிலேயே பொருத்துகிறார்கள். அல்ட்ராசவுண்ட் சிக்னல் கொண்டதாக இந்தப் பெட்டி இருப்பது, தண்ணீருக்கடியில் இதைத் தேடுவதற்கு பெரும் உதவியாக இருக்கும்.டேவிட் வாரன் என்ற அவுஸ்திரேலியரே இந்தக் கறுப்புப் பெட்டியை உலகுக்கு அறிமுகம் செய்தவர். தனது தந்தையை விமான விபத்தொன்றில் இழந்த நிகழ்வே, இந்தக் கண்டுபிடிப்பிற்கான உத்வேகத்தை அவருக்கு அளித்தது. ஒன்றின் இழப்பில் இன்னொன்றை அடைதல் என்பது இதுதான் போலும்."},{"question":"Port of Spain moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Port of Spain moy péeyu réwum Trinité-et-Tobago"},{"question":"වැනිලා  අස්වනු හා පසු අස්වනු පිළිවෙත් ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"පරාගනයෙන් මාස 8-9 කට පසු කරල් මේරීම සිදු වේ. අස්වනු නෙළීම ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් නොවැම්බර් සිට දෙසැම්බර් දක්වා සිදු කෙරේ. කොළ පැහැති කරලෙහි කෙළවර කහ පැහැයට හැරෙන විට සහ පහළ කෙළවරේ කරල් විවෘත වන විට අස්වනු නෙලීම සඳහා සුදුසුම කාලයයි. අස්වැන්න නෙළීමේදී පරිණත කරල් පමණක් නෙලිය යුතුය. හොඳින් පැසුණු කරල් 60 ත් 70 ත් අතර ප්‍රමාණයක් අවශ්‍ය වන අතර සැකසූ කරල් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 1 ක් සෑදීම සඳහා අමු කරල් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 6 ක් අවශ්‍ය වේ. කරල් අවම වශයෙන් 6cm විය යුතු අතර වඩා හොඳ තත්ත්වයේ කරල් 10cm ට වඩා වැඩි විය යුතුය. පරාගණයෙන් මාස 2 කට පසු කුඩා කරල් (සෙන්ටිමීටර 10 ට අඩු) පොකුරුවලින් ඉවත් කළ යුතු අතර පොකුරක් තුළ කරල් 8-10 ක ප්‍රමාණයකට පමණක් ඉඩ දී අනෙක් සියලුම කරල් ඉවත් කළ යුතුය. කරල උඩු අතට නැමීමෙන් කඩා ගත යුතු අතර, කැඩුම් මතුපිටෙහි දිලීර හානි වළක්වා ගැනීම සඳහා කතුර හෝ පිහියක් ලෙස භාවිතාකර අස්වැන්න නෙලීම නොකළ යුතුය.අස්වැන්න – වගා කිරීමෙන් වසර 3 කට පසු හෙක්ටයාරයකට කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 500 – 800 ක් සහ උපරිම අස්වැන්න අවුරුදු 7- 8 ක කාලයක් ඉක්වන විටදීය. පිරිසැකසුම් කිරීමේ ක්‍රම කිහිපයක් ඇතත් සෑම ක්‍රමයකම මූලික පියවර සමාන වේ.මැලවීම – සුවඳ සහ රසය නිපදවීමේදී එන්සයිම ප්‍රතික්‍රියා ආරම්භ කරයි. කරල් දුඹුරු පැහැයට හැරේ.වෑස්සීම – හානිකර පැසවීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා එන්සයිම ප්‍රතික්‍රියා ඉහල නැංවීම සඳහා ඉක්මනින් වියලීමට සැලැස්වීමට සහ තද දුඹුරු පැහැයට හුරු කරල් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩි කිරීම සිදු කරයි.වියළීම – සෙමින් වියළීම. කරල් ඒවායේ මුල් බර තත්වයෙන් තුනෙන් එකක් කරා ළඟා වේ.තත්වාරෝපණය – අපේක්ෂිත සුවඳ සහ රසය පූර්ණ ලෙස වර්ධනය වීමට ඉඩ දීම සඳහා සංවෘත පෙට්ටි තුල මාස තුනක් හෝ ඊට වැඩි කාලයක් ගබඩා කර තබා ගැනේ.ලෝක වෙළඳපොලේ වැනිලාවල වාණිජ වටිනාකම තීරණය කරන ලක්ෂණය වන්නේ සකස් කළ වැනිලා කරල්වල සුවඳ සහ රසය වේ. උපරිම සුවඳ සහ රසය මෙන්ම භෞතික පෙනුම ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීම සඳහා පිරිසැකසුම් කළ යුතුය. හොඳින් මේරූ වැනිලා කරල් නෙලා ගත් පසු ඒවා සකස් කිරීම සඳහා ගෙන ගොස් ප්‍රමාණය හා තත්වය අනුව වර්ග කරනු ලැබේ. වර්ග කළ කරල් විශාල උණු වතුර බඳුන්වලට (සෙල්සියස් අංශක 63) දමා ඉක්මනින් ජලය ඉවත් කරයි. එසේ රත් වූ කරල් තද පැහැති කපු රෙදිවලින් ඔතා ගන්නා අතර දිනකට පසු පැයක පමණ කාලයක් විවෘත හිරු එළියේ පතුරුවලින්/රීප්පවලින් සකස් කල වේදිකා මත තබා වියලා ගනු ලැබේ. සතියක් පමණ, දිනකට පැය දෙකක් අව්වේ කරල් වියළීම සිදු කරන අතර එසේ වේලා ගන්නා සෑම අවස්ථාවකදීම ඒවා කපු රෙද්දක ඔතා තැබේ. මෙම අවස්ථාව වනවිට වැනිලා කරල් තරමක් නම්‍යශීලී භාවයකින් යුක්ත වී ඇත. ඊළඟ මාස දෙක තුනක කාලය තුළ වැනිලා කරල් සෙවන සහිත ස්ථානයක රාක්ක මත හෝ හොඳින් වාතාශ්‍රය ඇති කාමරවල අතුරා තැබෙන්නේ සම්පූර්ණ රසය හා සුවඳ වර්ධනයවීම සඳහා වේ. සකස් කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියට පසුව හොඳින් වාතාශ්‍රය ලැබෙන ස්ථානයක දී වර්ග කර ඒවා නැව්ගත කිරීමට මිටි බැඳීමට ප්‍රථම ඒවායේ දිග අනුව ශ්‍රේණිගත කරනු ලැබේ. මේ කාලය වන විට වැනිලා කරලේ සුවඳ විශිෂ්ට තත්වයට පත්ව තිබේ"},{"question":"Inona ny fanalavana ny FIBATA?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny FIBATA dia: FItateram-BAhoakan'anTAnanarivo. Nisy manodidina ny taona 1979 izy io."},{"question":"请问“不知有汉,何论魏晋”是什么意思？","answer":"这句谚语字面上的意思是不知道有汉朝,三国魏及晋朝就更不知道了，是用来形容因长期脱离现实,对社会状况特别是新鲜事物一无所知，也形容知识贫乏,学问浅薄。"},{"question":"\\"Аксиома \\"cөзүнүн кыргызча түшүндүрмөсү кандай?","answer":"Аксиома бул:1. илимде - далилсиз эле кабыл кылына турган жобо; 2. шексиз чындык"},{"question":"Which is the largest country by land area with one region?","answer":"The largest country by land area with only one time zone is China. While China's vast territory spans five geographical time zones, the entire country officially follows a single standard time known as Beijing Time (GMT+8). This policy, despite the wide east-west spread of the country, means that local time can be significantly out of sync with solar time, especially in the western regions of China."},{"question":"Miêu tả về nhà thơ Vũ Đình Liên.","answer":"Vũ Đình Liên (12/11/1913- 18/1/1996) sinh tại Hà Nội, nhưng quê gốc ở thôn Châu Khê, xã Thúc Kháng, huyện Bình Giang, tỉnh Hải Dương.Vũ Đình Liên là một trong những nhà thơ lớp đầu tiên của phong trào Thơ mới. Ngoài thơ ông còn hoạt động trong lĩnh vực lý luận, phê bình văn học và dịch thuật. Ông là hội viên sáng lập Hội nhà văn VN. Một số bài thơ: Ông đồ, Lòng ta là những hàng thành quách cũ, Luỹ tre xanh, Người đàn bà điên ga Lưu xá... Sơ thảo lịch sử văn học Việt Nam (cùng Nhóm Lê Quý Đôn – 1957), Nguyễn Đình Chiểu (1957)…- Chữ Nho và nghệ thuật viết chữ Nho (thư pháp).+ Chữ Nho còn gọi là chữ Nôm cũ là hệ thống văn tự ngữ tố dùng để viết tiếng Việt. Chữ Nôm được tạo ra dựa trên cơ sở là chữ Hán (chủ yếu là phồn thể), vận dụng phương thức tạo chữ hình thanh, hội ý, giả tá của chữ Hán để tạo ra các chữ mới bổ sung cho việc viết và biểu đạt các từ thuần Việt không có trong bộ chữ Hán ban đầu. Chữ Nôm bắt đầu hình thành và phát triển từ thế kỷ 10 đến thế kỷ 20.+ Nghệ thuật thư pháp: Thư pháp xuất hiện hầu như đồng thời với sự hình thành văn tự bởi nhu cầu trình bày trang nhã và minh bạch văn bản. Công cụ chính tạo nên thư pháp là bút và chất liệu lưu trữ văn tự, mà sau được hiểu gồm mực và giấy. Thư pháp gia thường không nhất thiết phải là bậc trí giả nhưng ít nhiều được coi trọng nhờ vốn học vấn đủ để biên chép và họ có khả năng đẩy văn tự lên tầm nghệ thuật."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada soalan yang rumit ini: Polk County, bandar kedua paling ramai penduduk di Florida adalah lokasi pusat beli-belah mana?","answer":"Pusat Beli-belah Winter Haven"},{"question":"విసర్జక వ్యవస్థలో కలిగే అవరోధాలకు గల కారణాలు తెలుసుకొనేందుకు నాలుగు ప్రశ్నలు తయారు చేయండి.","answer":"విసర్జక వ్యవస్థలో అవరోధాలు ఎలా ఏర్పడతాయి?అవరోధాలు ఏర్పడటానికి దారితీసే పరిస్థితులు ఏమిటి?ఆహారపదార్థాలకు, అవరోధాలకు ఉన్న సంబంధం ఏమిటి?అవరోధాల వలన సంభవించే పరిస్థితులు ఏమిటి?"},{"question":"පැයකට මිනිත්තු කීයක් තිබේද?","answer":"පැයකට මිනිත්තු  60ක් පවතී."},{"question":"జాతి, జాతీయతల మధ్య వ్యత్యాసాలు ఏవి ?","answer":"జాతి, జాతీయతల మధ్య కింద అంశాలలో వ్యత్యాసాలు ఉన్నాయి.జాతిజాతి అనేది రాజకీయ భావన.జాతి అనేది ఎల్లప్పుడూ రాజకీయంగా సంఘటితమైన రాజ్యాన్ని సూచిస్తుంది.జాతి అనే భావన ఎల్లప్పుడూ స్వతంత్రతను కలిగి ఉంటుంది.జాతీయత లేకుండా జాతి అనేది ఉండదు.జాతిగా ఏర్పడిన ప్రజలు రాజ్య శాసనాలకు విధేయులుగా ఉంటారు.జాతీయతజాతీయత అనేది మానసిక భావన.జాతీయత అనేది ఎల్లప్పుడూ అసంఘటితమైన, అతి సులభమైన భావన.జాతీయత అనే భావన స్వతంత్రతను కలిగి ఉండదు.జాతి లేకుండా జాతీయత ఉంటుంది.జాతీయతగల ప్రజలు జాతిగా రూపొందేవరకు, రాజ్యాంగ చట్టాలు ఉండవు. అయితే స్వీయ ప్రయోజనాల దృష్ట్యా ప్రజలు కొన్ని ఉమ్మడి నియమాలను అనుసరిస్తారు."},{"question":"ජාත්‍යන්තර ඔලිම්පික් දිනය කවදාද?","answer":"ජූනි 20"},{"question":"حمید سوریان کیست؟","answer":"حمید سوریان ریحان‌پور (زادهٔ ۲ شهریور ۱۳۶۴) کشتی‌گیر پیشین و مدیر ورزشی ایرانی است که در سمت نایب‌رئیس فدراسیون کشتی ایران فعالیت کرده‌است. سوریان یکی از بهترین کشتی‌گیران تاریخ رشته کشتی فرنگی به شمار می‌رود و نیز از نظر کیفیت مدال، بهترین کشتی‌گیر ایرانی تمام ادوار است. سوریان در دوران فعالیت حرفه‌ای خود در دستهٔ ۵۵ کیلوگرم کشتی فرنگی، برندهٔ مدال طلای المپیک ۲۰۱۲ لندن و قهرمان شش دورهٔ مسابقات قهرمانی کشتی جهان شده‌است. او به طور پیاپی پنج دوره قهرمان جهان شده و در سطح آسیا نیز قهرمان کشتی آسیا در سال‌های ۲۰۰۷ و ۲۰۰۸ است. سوریان در ادبیات ورزشی ایران به سبب قهرمانی‌هایش به «ژنرال هفت ستاره» معروف شده است."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--उडाला तर कावळा, बुडाला तर बेडूक","answer":"एखाद्या गोष्टीची परीक्षा होण्यासाठी काही काळ वाट पहावी लागते."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన వాక్యాన్ని వ్యతిరేకార్థక వాక్యంగా రాయండిఅందరూ ఒక్కసారిగా మాట్లాడుతున్నారు.","answer":"అందరూ ఒక్కసారిగా మాట్లాడడం లేదు."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഞാൻ എങ്ങനെ ഒരു ഫർണിച്ചർ കൂട്ടിച്ചേർക്കും?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: 1. എല്ലാ ഭാഗങ്ങളും ഹാർഡ്‌വെയറും നിരത്തുക. 2. നിർദ്ദേശങ്ങൾ നന്നായി വായിക്കുക. 3. വ്യത്യസ്ത ഘടകങ്ങൾ തിരിച്ചറിയുകയും ക്രമീകരിക്കുകയും ചെയ്യുക. 4. നൽകിയിരിക്കുന്ന ഉപകരണങ്ങൾ ഉപയോഗിച്ച് ഘട്ടം ഘട്ടമായുള്ള നിർദ്ദേശങ്ങൾ പാലിക്കുക. 5. നൽകിയിരിക്കുന്ന ക്രമം അനുസരിച്ച് ഓരോ ഭാഗവും കൂട്ടിച്ചേർക്കുക. 6. എല്ലാ കണക്ഷനുകളും രണ്ടുതവണ പരിശോധിച്ച് ഏതെങ്കിലും അയഞ്ഞ സ്ക്രൂകൾ ശക്തമാക്കുക."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Giá xăng dầu thế giới Theo Oilprice, lúc 6 giờ ngày 1-8 (giờ Việt Nam), giá dầu Brent giao tháng 10 được giao dịch ở mức 103,6 USD/thùng, giảm 0,35 USD, tương đương 0,34 %. Cùng thời điểm, giá dầu thô WTI của Mỹ được giao dịch ở mức 98,07 USD/thùng, giảm 0,57 %, tương đương 0,56 USD. Tuần trước, lo ngại thiếu hụt nguồn cung, đồng bạc xanh suy yếu, sự tăng trở lại của thị trường chứng khoán, và việc Cục Dự trữ Liên bang Mỹ (Fed) \\"mạnh tay\\" tăng lãi suất tới 0,75 điểm phần trăm đã đẩy giá \\"vàng đen\\" liên tục leo dốc. Tính cả tuần, dầu thô Brent đã \\"bỏ túi\\" tới gần 7 USD, dầu thô WTI tăng gần 4 USD. Cả hai mặt hàng dầu này đã trải nghiệm một tuần giá \\"phi mã\\". Dù \\"leo dốc\\", cả dầu Brent và WTI đều ghi nhận khoản giảm hằng tháng lần thứ hai liên tiếp với Brent mất khoảng 4% và WTI giảm gần 7% trong tháng 7. Cũng trong tuần trước, không phải lúc nào giá dầu cũng tăng. Có thời điểm, giá dầu đã trượt dốc còn bởi thông tin Nga đang thắt chặt nguồn khí đốt đến châu Âu qua đường ống Nord Stream 1 khiến công suất của đường ống này giảm chỉ còn 1/5. Sự giảm công suất này đã làm dấy lên lo ngại Moscow sử dụng năng lượng như một vũ khí để đạt được mục đích của mình. Tuần này, mọi con mắt đang đổ dồn vào cuộc họp của Tổ chức các nước xuất khẩu dầu mỏ và các đồng minh (OPEC+) vào ngày 3-8 để xem liệu tổ chức này có \\"bơm\\" thêm dầu cho thị trường dầu","answer":"đang thắt chặt. Theo Bloomberg, đây là lần đầu tiên trong năm, OPEC+ không có chính sách rõ ràng nào trước khi nhóm họp và điều này có thể làm cho cuộc họp thêm phần thú vị. Điều này cho phép nhóm đánh giá đúng đắn về những gì thế giới thực sự cần. Nhiều chuyên gia dự đoán OPEC+ sẽ giữ nguyên mức sản lượng dầu đã cam kết hồi tháng 4-2020 bởi một thực tế rằng sản lượng của nhóm đang ngày một giảm vì nhiều thành viên không thể đáp ứng được hạn ngạch sản xuất của mình. Theo số liệu gần đây nhất, trong tháng 5, nhiều thành viên của OPEC+ chỉ \\"bơm\\" được khoảng 2,7 triệu thùng/ngày. Chỉ có duy hai thành viên của OPEC+ là Ả Rập Xê-út và Các tiểu vương quốc Ả Rập thống nhất (UAE) là có năng lực dự phòng đáng kể. Tuy nhiên, vẫn còn đó nhiều câu hỏi liệu hai thành viên này có thể làm được bao nhiêu. Giá xăng dầu trong nước Giá bán lẻ xăng dầu trong nước ngày 1-8 cụ thể như sau: Xăng E5 RON 92 không quá 25.073 đồng/lít; xăng RON 95 không quá 26.070 đồng/lít; dầu diesel không quá 24.858 đồng/lít; dầu hỏa không quá 25.246 đồng/lít và dầu mazut không quá 16.548 đồng/kg. Dữ liệu từ Bộ Công Thương cho biết giá xăng thành phẩm bình quân trên thị trường Singapore cập nhật đến ngày 26-7 tiếp tục giảm so với kỳ trước. Theo đó, xăng RON 92 giảm xuống mức khoảng 108 USD/thùng, RON 95 ở mức 111 USD/thùng. Mức này giảm khoảng 4-5% so với kỳ điều chỉnh trước đó. Giá dầu có lúc giảm về mốc 123 USD/thùng. Nhiều chuyên gia dự báo, tại kỳ điều hành giá chiều nay (1-8) của liên Bộ Tài chính - Công Thương, giá xăng có thể giảm khoảng 200-350 đồng/lít, giá dầu có khả năng giảm từ 600-850 đồng/lít. Mức giảm này còn phụ thuộc vào việc trích lập Quỹ bình ổn giá xăng, dầu. Nếu cơ quan quản lý chi Quỹ bình ổn nhiều thì giá xăng, dầu trong nước chỉ giảm rất nhẹ. Nếu đúng như dự báo, giá xăng trong nước sẽ có lần giảm thứ 4 liên tiếp. Tính từ đầu năm đến nay, giá xăng dầu đã trải qua 19 lần điều chỉnh giá, trong đó có 13 lần tăng và 6 lần giảm. MAI HƯƠNG"},{"question":"கேள்வி:பெருமுத்தரையர்கள் பற்றிய குறிப்புகள் அமைந்துள்ள நூல் யாது?(1) இன்னா நாற்பது                                  (2) நான்மணிக்கடிகை(3) நாலடியார்                                            (4) சிறுபஞ்சமூலம்","answer":"பதில்:(3) நாலடியார்"},{"question":"دوره ابتدایی در مدارس ایران چند سال است؟","answer":"در حال حاضر در ایران، دوره ابتدایی یا دوران دبستان به دو دوره ۳ ساله (دورهٔ اول یعنی اول تا سوم ابتدایی و دورهٔ دوم یعنی چهارم تا ششم ابتدایی) که روی هم شش سال تحصیلی می‌باشد، تقسیم بندی شده است که پس از گذشت این ۶ سال در این مقطع آموزشی، دانش‌آموزان وارد دورهٔ متوسطه اول می‌شوند."},{"question":"ዴቪድ, ጃክ እና ማርክ በአንድ ኩባንያ ውስጥ ባልደረቦች ናቸው. ዴቪድ ጃክን ይቆጣጠራል፣ እና ጃክ ማርክን ይቆጣጠራል። ዴቪድ ከጃክ የበለጠ ደሞዝ ያገኛል። ከላይ ከተገለጹት መግለጫዎች ምን ማለት ይቻላል?ሀ. ጃክ ከማርቆስ የበለጠ ደሞዝ ያገኛል።ለ. ዳዊት ልክ እንደ ማርቆስ ደሞዝ ያገኛል።ሐ. አንድ ሰራተኛ ከራሱ የበለጠ ደሞዝ የሚያገኘውን ይቆጣጠራል።መ. አንድ ሰራተኛ ከራሱ ያነሰ ደሞዝ የሚያገኘውን ይቆጣጠራል።","answer":"ትክክለኛው መልስ መ. አንደኛው ሠራተኛ ከራሱ ያነሰ ደሞዝ የሚያገኘውን ሌላውን ይቆጣጠራል ። "},{"question":"Quem foi o primeiro presidente negro dos Estados Unidos?","answer":"Barack Obama."},{"question":"Wace kasa ce ta fi yawan fitar da shinkafa a 2021?","answer":"kasar Indiya ce ta fi yawan fitar da shinkafar a 2021."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk sira labu? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan:  1 biji labu kuning saiz sederhana, 1/2 sudu teh kapur makan, 1/2 cawan gula pasir, 5 helai daun pandan, Secubit garam, Secubit serbuk kulit kayu manis (opsyenal)Cara penyediaan:1. Belah labu, kupas kulit, buang bijinya dan potong mengikut pangsanya.2. Rendamkan labu dalam air kapur (supaya isi labu menjadi pejal) selama 1-2 jam. Kemudian bilas dantuskan.3. Potong daun pandan agar muat periuk.Cara memasak:1. Susun daun pandan di dasar periuk, untuk aroma dan elakkan labu dari hangus.2. Susun kepingan labu di dalam periuk dan kemudian taburkan gula di atas labu. Ulangi untuk setiaplapisan.3. Masakkan dengan api perlahan. Tidak perlu masukkan air kerana labu akan mengeluarkan air biladimasak.4. Padamkan api bila labu empuk dan air gula likat dan berkilat.5. Angkat dan biarkan sejuk.6. Simpan dalam peti sejuk dulu sebelum dihidang"},{"question":"Dalam konteks undang-undang di Malaysia, apakah perbezaan antara “AKTA”, “ORDINAN”, “ENAKMEN”, “PERATURAN”?","answer":"“AKTA” adalah undang-undang yang diperbuat oleh Parlimen Malaysia iaitu badan perundangan negara di peringkat Persekutuan. Undang-undang yang diluluskan oleh Parlimen dan menerima perkenan DiRaja (“Royal Assent”) dikenali sebagai “AKTA” bermula daripada 10 September 1959 sehinggalah sekarang. Bagi undang-undang yang diluluskan oleh Parlimen Malaysia daripada 1 April 1946 sehingga 10 September 1959, undang-undang tersebut dikenali sebagai “Ordinan”.Contoh Akta yang diperbuat oleh Parlimen Malaysia adalah:(a) Akta Polis 1967;(b) Akta Pencegahan dan Pengawalan Penyakit Berjangkit 1988;(c) Kanun Tanah Negara (Akta 56);(d) Kanun Tatacara Jenayah (Akta 593). “ORDINAN” adalah undang-undang yang diperbuat sama ada oleh: (a) Yang Di-Pertuan Agong ketika pengisytiharan darurat dibawah Fasal 150(2) Perlembagaan Persekutuan; atau(b) Parlimen di peringkat Persekutuan daripada 1 April 1946 sehingga 10 September 1959 (dahulu dipanggil sebagai Federal Legislative Council); atau(c) Dewan Undangan Negeri Sarawak daripada pra 16 September 1963 sehingga kini; atau(d) Dewan Undangan Negeri Sabah sehingga 16 September 1963 dan selepas itu Fasal 26 (2) Perlembagaan Negeri dipinda dengan menamakan undang-undang diperbuat oleh Dewan Undangan Negeri sebagai “Enakmen”. Seksyen 3 Enakment Tafsiran dan Klausa Umum 1963 juga mentafsirkan Enakmen sebagai undang-undang yang diperbuat oleh Dewan Undangan Negeri.Kini, penggunaan nama “Ordinan” bagi undang-undang yang diperbuat oleh Parlimen Malaysia dan DUN Sabah tidak lagi dipakai kecuali negeri Sarawak masih mengekalkan pemakaian “Ordinan” bagi setiap undang-undang yang diperbuat oleh DUN Sarawak.Contoh Ordinan yang diperbuat oleh Yang-Dipertuan Agong adalah:(a) Emergency (Public Order and Prevention of Crime) Ordinance 1969 – telah dimansuhkan pada tahun 2013Contoh Ordinan yang diperbuat oleh Parlimen adalah: (a) Prevention of Crime Ordinance 1959 – telah dipinda pada tahun 1983 dengan menamakan semula sebagai Prevention of Crime Act 1959.Contoh Ordinan yang diperbuat oleh DUN Sabah adalah:(a) Administrative Divisions Ordinance Cap. 167(b) Adoption Ordinance 1960Contoh Ordinan yang diperbuat oleh DUN Sarawak adalah:(a) Administrative Areas Ordinance 2007(b) Inquests Ordinance 1937 “ENAKMEN” adalah undang-undang yang diperbuat oleh badan perundangan negeri dikenali sebagai Dewan Undangan Negeri bagi semua negeri-negeri di Malaysia kecuali Sarawak. Sabah mula menamakan undang-undang negeri sebagai Enakmen selepas 16 September 1963 iaitu selepas Fasal 26 (2) Perlembagaan Negeri dipinda dengan menamakan undang-undang diperbuat oleh Dewan Undangan Negeri sebagai “Enakmen”.Contoh Enakmen yang diperbuat oleh DUN Sabah adalah:(a) Animal Enactment 2015(b) Fatwa Enactment 2004(c) Old Age Assistant Enactmen 1982“PERATURAN” adalah undang-undang subsidiari/kecil diperbuat oleh badan eksekutif (seperti Menteri, Majlis Daerah, Lembaga dan lain-lain) di bawah kuasa yang diwakilkan kepada mereka oleh Parlimen atau Dewan Undangan Negeri melalui Akta ibu. Ciri-ciri utama undang-undang subsidiari ini adalah undang-undang subsidiari tidak boleh melangkaui had yang telah ditetapkan oleh Akta ibu dan hendaklah diwartakan (gazette) sebagai pemberitahuan umum.Contohnya, Akta Pencegahan dan Pengawalan Penyakit Berjangkit 1988 sebagai Akta ibu memberi kuasa kepada Menteri untuk memperbuat Peraturan yang difikirkan perlu oleh Menteri. Contoh peraturan-peraturan di bawah Akta Pencegahan dan Pengawalan Penyakit Berjangkit 1988 ini adalah Peraturan-peraturan Pencegahan dan Pengawalan Penyakit Berjangkit (Langkah-langkah di dalam Kawasan Tempatan Jangkitan) (No.4) 2020."},{"question":"தொகைக் சொற்களைக் கொண்டு பத்தியைச் சுருக்குக.சேர, சோழ, பாண்டிய அரசர்களிடம் யானைப்படை, குதிரைப்படை, தேர்ப்படை, தரைப்படை ஆகியவை இருந்தன. அவர்கள் மா, பலா, வாழை ஆகிய கனிகளுடன் விருந்தோம்பல் செய்தனர். கிழக்கு, மேற்கு, வடக்கு, தெற்கு ஆகிய திசைகளில் அவர்களின் ஆட்சிப்புகழ் பரவியிருந்தது. தமிழகத்தின் குறிஞ்சி, முல்லை, மருதம், நெய்தல் ஆகிய நிலங்களில் உள்ள புலவர்கள் இவ்வரசர்களை இம்மையிலும் மறுமையிலும் வாழ்கவென்று வாழ்த்தினர்.","answer":"மூவேந்தர்களிடம், நாற்படைகளும் இருந்தன. முக்கனிகளுடன் விருந்தோம்பல் செய்தனர். நாற்றிசைகளிலும் அவர்களின் ஆட்சி புகழ் பரவியிருந்தது. தமிழகத்தின் ஐவகை நிலங்களிலும் உள்ள புலவர்கள் இவ்வரசர்களை இருமையிலும் வாழ்கவென்று வாழ்த்தினர்."},{"question":"Bu metin hangi önemli olayla ilgilidir:Çekoslovakya millî futbol takımı formasını giyen futbolcu, 1932–1948 yılları arasında 26 maçta millî takımda yer aldı ve bu maçlarda 8 gol attı. 1934 ve 1938 FIFA Dünya Kupası'nda, Çekoslovakya millî futbol takımı kadrosunda yer aldı.","answer":"1938 FIFA Dünya Kupası"},{"question":"DISASTERChapter 3","answer":"DISASTERChapter 3\\"Who are you?\\" Nelson asked the caller.\\"Please give my wife the phone, I want to talk to her\\", replied the caller.Nelson looked at Neme; she turned her face to the other side immediately.\\"Who is your wife? What's her name?\\"\\"Chinemerem nah, Neme, Neme, Neme... please give her the phone\\". Nelson ended the call; he faced Neme.\\"For how long now Neme?\\" He asked with a teary voice.\\"I don't know Nelson, you're the cause of all these, you pushed me.\\"\\"I, Nelson, pushed you? Okay, leave my house and never return\\", e barked.\\"I will leave, I am tired.Let me go and meet Alex. I love Alex and he is the father of my unborn child\\", Neme cried picking her handbag.\\"The father of your unborn child. I see ... leave this place right now before I frustrate your life this moment.\\"Neme looked at him from head to toe, sighed and walked away from him.\\"Neme\\", he called.\\"Get behind me you, Satan\\",  she replied and walked faster.Neme got home, she sat down crying uncontrollably. She wished Alex never called, she has messed up her marriage, she doesn't even know the real father of her unborn childHer mum opened the door, she came in with AlexWhat are you doing here Alex? Neme shoutedI came to check up on you,who picked your call today? Why was he asking me those questions? He askedWhich of the questions do you want me to answer,Alex please leave, leave now...I'm going nowhere Neme,why are you ch.....You're the caller I guess,who are you and Neme wh....What's the problem please? Mrs Cynthia asked shockedI am Neme's husband..they responded at the same timeNeme held her hair,ran inside her room and locked the doorI don't know you young man.. said Mrs CynthiaMe? You don't know me Mrs Cynthia? Alex shouted with anger written all over his faceNelson sighed and went to meet NemeNeme please we need to talk...Talk about what initially? Talk about what Nelson, after cheating on me with Dora, Nelson I am done... she replied from insideI'm sorry Neme,but who is that guy,why is he claiming to be your husband,are you married to him? Neme please open the door..Nelson just leave,I'll be going to the hospital to abort this pregnancy, Nelson I am tired, what did I ever do to you? You just paid my bride price weeks ago and here you are cheating on me,why can't you wait after the wedding you can then cheat as you like, please leave, beside you asked me to leave your house too so leave hereYou are also cheating, Neme we can fix things please, forgive me and I'll forgive you too,I can't afford to loose you..He pleaded still knocking on the doorYou can't afford to loose me,why did you cheat on me?Dora drugged me, she did...he liedNeme stood up, unlocked the door and stared at himYou disgust me Nelson,I forgive you but.... where's Alex? Has he gone?Who is Alex? The guy out there? He askedNeme didn't reply, she pushed Nelson and went to the parlourWhat was the meaning of that Neme,why do you want to bring shame upon this family? You're always disgracing yourself,who was that? Her mum thundered I don't know him mum.. she replied turning to face NelsonLet's go please.. she said going outsideI'm sorry for what just happened, Neme is always causing confusion at times... Mrs Cynthia said patting himIt's mum,see you later..he answered and leftEveryone was busy preparing for Neme and Nelson's wedding, Nelson was in his room in the hotel where he lodged with his friends when Dora came inHi Dora..Dan greetedHi Dan, what's up with you guys? She waved laughingWe are cool,you look pretty..Sam complimentedThank youuuuu, Nelson we need to talkTalk about what initially? Can't you see I'm busy? He askedNelson, this wedding is not going to holdNelson and his friends stared at each other, the whole room was quiet like a graveyard "},{"question":"Où sur le corps humain se trouvent le plus de glandes sudoripares ?","answer":"La plus forte concentration de glandes sudoripares sur le corps humain se trouve sur la paume des mains et sur la plante des pieds. Ces zones sont respectivement appelées surfaces palmaire et plantaire. Les glandes sudoripares de ces régions sont chargées d’aider à réguler la température corporelle grâce au processus de transpiration."},{"question":"ما هو عدد التكبيرات في الركعة الأولى في صلاة العيد؟، (ستة، سبعة، تسعة، خمسة)","answer":"الإجابة:سبعة"},{"question":"Fa maninona ny gidro/varika no mila arovana ?","answer":"ny gidro/varika dia mila arovana satria :    Voalohany indrindra dia mampiroborobo ny toe-karena Malagasy izy ireny noho ny fizahan-tany. Ny ankamaroany ny mpizaha tany dia mirodorodo mankaty amintsika mba hizaha sy hijery izany hoe gidro/varika izany satria dia eto amintsika ihany maneran-tany no hahitana azy ireny.  Fanampin’izany, dia betsaka ary tsy voatanisa  ireo Malagasy  sy ankohonana mivelona amin’izany fizahan-tany izany : raha tsy hitanisa afa tsy ny mpitondra mpizaha-tany, ireo miasa amin’ny trano fandraisam-bahiny sy fisakafoanana lehibe. Ireo miasa amin’ny parka sy ireo mpanao asa tanana madinika izay mivelona amin’ny fivarotany izany amin’ireo vahiny.    Manarakarak’izany dia ny fiarovana azy ireny ihany koa dia miteraka mazava ho azy ny fiarovana ny tontolo ianana, ny fiarovana ny ala izay toeram-ponenany.  Marihina fa ny ala dia miantoka ny fahaveloman-dra Olombelona.  Ka ny fitsinjovana azy ireny dia mitsinjo ihany koa ny ho aviny ny taranaka fara aman-dimby any aoriana.    Manaparitaka ny voankazo satria tsy vitan’ny hoe toerana fatoriny sy fonenan’ny varika/Gidro ihany ny hazo fa lasa sakafony ihany koa – ” Seed dispersers” moa no fiantso ireo izay manao izany. Misy ny fikarohana manaporofo fa malaky kokoa ny fanirin’ny voankazo avy amin’ny tain’ireo varika ireo.    Mpitati-bovobony (agent pollinisateur) ho an’ny karazan-kazo sasany koa ny varika satria amin’ny  alalan’ny fikarohany ny mamy (nectar) amin’ ilay voninkazo no mahatonga ny vony lahy sy vahy hifandra. Noho izany dia mandray anjara amin’ny fitazonana ny karazan-kazo ao an’ala ireo varika ireo.    Mari-pandrefesana/pilazana (indicateurs) amin’ny  hatsarana na fiharatsian’ny ala koa ny fisian’ireo varika hita amina faritra iray. Rehefa tsy ao intsony ireo dia tsy manana izay fambara izay intsony ny olombelona."},{"question":"Complete o seguinte texto:  Marcelo aparece nas fontes pela primeira vez em , quando foi eleito pontífice. Foi ainda tribuno da plebe em e pretor de duas províncias, a Hispânia Citerior e Hispânia Ulterior, em , durante a","answer":"Terceira Guerra Macedônica. Neste período, segundo Estrabão, fundou uma colônia romana em Córdoba, o que contradiz as evidências arqueológicas, que indicam um assentamento muito mais antigo. É provável que ele estivesse se referindo a uma refundação romana."},{"question":"රෝමයේ පළමු අධිරාජ්‍යයා කවුද?","answer":"ඔගස්ටස්"},{"question":"As palavras \\"farto\\" e \\"fator\\" são anagramas?","answer":"Sim, as palavras \\"farto\\" e \\"fator\\" são anagramas, pois a ordem das letras de uma das palavras pode ser reorganizada e dar origem à outra palavra."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਰਾਗੁ ਗਉੜੀ ਅਸਟਪਦੀਆ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ਗਉੜੀ ਗੁਆਰੇਰੀੴ ਸਤਿਨਾਮੁ ਕਰਤਾ ਪੁਰਖੁ ਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਨਿਧਿ ਸਿਧਿ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਨਾਮੁ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ਪੂਰਨ ਪੂਰਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਬਿਖੁ ਮਾਰਿ ॥ਤ੍ਰਿਕੁਟੀ ਛੂਟੀ ਬਿਮਲ ਮਝਾਰਿ ॥ਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਮਤਿ ਜੀਇ ਆਈ ਕਾਰਿ ॥੧॥ਇਨ ਬਿਧਿ ਰਾਮ ਰਮਤ ਮਨੁ ਮਾਨਿਆ ॥ਗਿਆਨ ਅੰਜਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦਿ ਪਛਾਨਿਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਇਕੁ ਸੁਖੁ ਮਾਨਿਆ ਸਹਜਿ ਮਿਲਾਇਆ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲ ਬਾਣੀ ਭਰਮੁ ਚੁਕਾਇਆ ॥ਲਾਲ ਭਏ ਸੂਹਾ ਰੰਗੁ ਮਾਇਆ ॥ਨਦਰਿ ਭਈ ਬਿਖੁ ਠਾਕਿ ਰਹਾਇਆ ॥੨॥ਉਲਟ ਭਈ ਜੀਵਤ ਮਰਿ ਜਾਗਿਆ ॥ਸਬਦਿ ਰਵੇ ਮਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਲਾਗਿਆ ॥ਰਸੁ ਸੰਗ੍ਰਹਿ ਬਿਖੁ ਪਰਹਰਿ ਤਿਆਗਿਆ ॥ਭਾਇ ਬਸੇ ਜਮ ਕਾ ਭਉ ਭਾਗਿਆ ॥੩॥ਸਾਦ ਰਹੇ ਬਾਦੰ ਅਹੰਕਾਰਾ ॥ਚਿਤੁ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਰਾਤਾ ਹੁਕਮਿ ਅਪਾਰਾ ॥ਜਾਤਿ ਰਹੇ ਪਤਿ ਕੇ ਆਚਾਰਾ ॥ਦ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਭਈ ਸੁਖੁ ਆਤਮ ਧਾਰਾ ॥੪॥ਤੁਝ ਬਿਨੁ ਕੋਇ ਨ ਦੇਖਉ ਮੀਤੁ ॥ਕਿਸੁ ਸੇਵਉ ਕਿਸੁ ਦੇਵਉ ਚੀਤੁ ॥ਕਿਸੁ ਪੂਛਉ ਕਿਸੁ ਲਾਗਉ ਪਾਇ ॥ਕਿਸੁ ਉਪਦੇਸਿ ਰਹਾ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਇ ॥੫॥ਗੁਰ ਸੇਵੀ ਗੁਰ ਲਾਗਉ ਪਾਇ ॥ਭਗਤਿ ਕਰੀ ਰਾਚਉ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਇ ॥ਸਿਖਿਆ ਦੀਖਿਆ ਭੋਜਨ ਭਾਉ ॥ਹੁਕਮਿ ਸੰਜੋਗੀ ਨਿਜ ਘਰਿ ਜਾਉ ॥੬॥ਗਰਬ ਗਤੰ ਸੁਖ ਆਤਮ ਧਿਆਨਾ ॥ਜੋਤਿ ਭਈ ਜੋਤੀ ਮਾਹਿ ਸਮਾਨਾ ॥ਲਿਖਤੁ ਮਿਟੈ ਨਹੀ ਸਬਦੁ ਨੀਸਾਨਾ ॥ਕਰਤਾ ਕਰਣਾ ਕਰਤਾ ਜਾਨਾ ॥੭॥ਨਹ ਪੰਡਿਤੁ ਨਹ ਚਤੁਰੁ ਸਿਆਨਾ ॥ਨਹ ਭੂਲੋ ਨਹ ਭਰਮਿ ਭੁਲਾਨਾ ॥ਕਥਉ ਨ ਕਥਨੀ ਹੁਕਮੁ ਪਛਾਨਾ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਸਹਜਿ ਸਮਾਨਾ ॥੮॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 220 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਨਾਮ ਤੇਰੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ (ਆਤਮਕ) ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਹੀ ਮੇਰੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ (ਰਿੱਧੀਆਂ) ਸਿੱਧੀਆਂ ਹੈ ।੧।ਮੈਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਮਾਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ । ਹੁਣ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਵਿਆਪਕ ਦਿੱਸ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।(ਉਸ ਮਤਿ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਅੰਦਰਲੀ ਖਿੱਝ ਮੁੱਕ ਗਈ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੋਈ ਮਤਿ ਮੇਰੇ ਚਿੱਤ ਵਿਚ ਕਾਰੀ ਆ ਗਈ ਹੈ (ਲਾਭਵੰਦੀ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ) । ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ ਸਿਮਰ ਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਵਿਚ) ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਗਿੱਝ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਹੁਣ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਰਹਿ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਉਹ (ਆਤਮਕ) ਸੁਰਮਾ ਲੱਭ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸਹਜ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, (ਹੁਣ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ) ਮੰਨ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹੀ (ਆਤਮਕ) ਸੁਖ (ਸਭ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ ਸੁਖ ਹੈ) ।(ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਵਾਲੀ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਬਾਣੀ ਨੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਮੁਕਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ(ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੀਜ ਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਮਜੀਠ ਵਰਗੇ ਪੱਕੇ ਰੰਗ ਵਾਲਾ) ਲਾਲ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ । ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਰੰਗ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਸੁੰਭੇ ਦੇ ਰੰਗ ਵਰਗਾ ਕੱਚਾ, ਸੂਹਾ ਦਿੱਸ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ । (ਮੇਰਾ ਉਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ) ਨਜ਼ਰ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ, ਮੈਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਉਤੇ ਅਸਰ ਕਰਨੋਂ) ਰੋਕ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਮੇਰੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਲੋਂ) ਪਰਤ ਪਈ ਹੈ, ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਤ-ਕਾਰ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ (ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲੋਂ) ਮਰ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਤਮਕ ਜਾਗ ਆ ਗਈ ਹੈ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਮੈਂ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ, ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਪਾ ਚੁਕਾ ਹੈ ।(ਆਤਮਕ) ਆਨੰਦ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਸਦਾ ਲਈ) ਤਿਆਗ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ । ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮੌਤ ਦਾ ਡਰ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਕਰਕੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਮਾਇਕ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਦੇ) ਚਸਕੇ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਹਨ, (ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਨਿੱਤ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਾਲਾ) ਝਗੜਾ ਮਿਟ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਰਹਿ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ । ਮੇਰਾ ਚਿੱਤ ਹੁਣ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਨਾਮ) ਨਾਲ ਰੰਗਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਮੈਂ ਹੁਣ ਉਸ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਗਿਆ ਹਾਂ ।ਜਾਤਿ-ਵਰਨ ਅਤੇ ਲੋਕ-ਲਾਜ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਧਰਮ-ਕਰਮ ਬੱਸ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਹਨ । ਮੇਰੇ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ) ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਤਮਕ ਸੁਖ ਮਿਲ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।੪।(ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ, ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ!) ਮੈਨੂੰ ਤੈਥੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ (ਪੱਕਾ) ਮਿੱਤਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ । ਮੈਂ ਹੁਣ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ, ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਭੇਂਟ ਕਰਦਾ ।ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਤੋਂ ਸਾਲਾਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੁੱਛਦਾ । ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਦੇ ਪੈਰੀਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਗਦਾ ਫਿਰਦਾ । ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਦੇ ਉਪਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਨਹੀਂ ਜੋੜਦਾ ਫਿਰਦਾ ।੫।(ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਨੇ ਹੀ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਤੇਰੇ ਗਿਆਨ ਦਾ ਸੁਰਮਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਮੈਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਚਰਨੀਂ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹਾਂ । (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ, ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਮੈਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੀਖਿਆ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਭੋਜਨ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ । ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਇਹ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਅੰਕੁਰ ਫੁੱਟਿਆ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਅਸਲ ਘਰ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ) ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਬੈਠਾ ਹਾਂ ।੬।(ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਵਿਚ ਮੇਰੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਟਿਕ ਗਈ ਹੈ, ਮੇਰੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਚਾਨਣ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਮੇਰੀ ਜਿੰਦ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਜੋਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ । (ਮੇਰੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਉੱਕਰਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਗੁਰ-ਸ਼ਬਦ (ਰੂਪ) ਲੇਖ ਹੁਣ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਪਰਗਟ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮਿਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ।ਮੈਂ ਕਰਤੇ ਤੇ (ਕਰਤੇ ਦੀ) ਰਚਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਤਾਰ-ਰੂਪ ਹੀ ਜਾਣ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, (ਮੈਂ ਕਰਤਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਦਾ ਰਚਨਹਾਰਾ ਜਾਣ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ) ।੭।ਮੈਂ ਕੋਈ ਪੰਡਿਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਾਂ, ਮੈਂ ਚਤੁਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਾਂ, ਮੈਂ ਸਿਆਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਾਂ, (ਭਾਵ, ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਵਿਦਵਤਾ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ਸਿਆਣਪ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਿਆ) ਤਾਹੀਏਂ ਮੈਂ (ਰਸਤੇ ਤੋਂ) ਖੁੰਝਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ, ਭਟਕਣਾ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਿਆ । ਮੈਂ ਕੋਈ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦਾ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—) ਮੈਂ ਤਾਂ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਨੂੰ ਪਛਾਣਿਆ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਸਮਝਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਤੁਰਨਾ ਹੀ ਸਹੀ ਰਸਤਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਅਡੋਲ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਗਿਆ ਹਾਂ ।੮।੧।\\""},{"question":"질문: 개그맨이 되려면 어떻게 해야해요? 답:","answer":"공채 시험이 폐지된 결과 다양한 경로를 통해 개그맨이 됩니다. 예를 들어, 대학로 개그 무대에서 공연을 하거나, 유튜브 등 SNS에서 활동할 시 방송국 PD가 접촉을 하거나 지인연결 형식으로 데뷔를 하게 됩니다."},{"question":"Kí ni ẹṣin ọ̀rọ̀?","answer":"Òwe"},{"question":"Quais são os idiomas oficiais da Bélgica?","answer":"A Bélgica tem três idiomas oficiais distintos: neerlandês, francês e alemão. A língua neerlandesa é popularmente denominada \\"holandês\\", mas este é tecnicamente um dialeto do neerlandês, falado na região histórica chamada Holanda, parte dos Países Baixos."},{"question":"Kaum India di Malaysia biasanya beragama __________.","answer":"Hindu"},{"question":"இளநீர் குடிப்பதினால் ஏற்படும் நன்மைகள் யாவை?","answer":"இளநீர் என்பது வெயில் காலம் மட்டுமன்றி அனைத்து பருவநிலைகளிலும் மக்கள் அருந்துகின்றனர். காரணம் அதில் உள்ள மினரல்கள் உடலுக்கு தேவையான ஆற்றலை அளிக்கின்றன. அந்த வகையில் தினமும் இளநீர் அருந்துவதன் நன்மைகள் தீமைகள் பற்றி விரிவாக அலசுகிறது இந்தக் கட்டுரை.வெயில் காலத்தில் இளநீர் தவிர்க்க முடியாத தேவை. அது வெயிலின் வெப்பத்தைத் தனிக்கக் கூடிய இயற்கை நீர். ”வெயில் காலத்தில் உடலுக்குத் தேவையான எலக்ட்ரோலைட்ஸ் நீர்சத்து மூலமாக வெளியேறுகிறது. அதை மீண்டும் உடலுக்கு அளிக்க இளநீர்தான் சரியான உதவுகிறது. உடலுக்குத் தேவையான பொட்டாசியம் , சோடியம், கால்சியம் போன்ற மிரல்ஸ் மூலமாக எலக்ட்ரோலைட்ஸ் கிடைக்கின்றன “ என்கிறார் ஊட்டச்சத்து நிபுணர் பிரீத்தி ராஜ். இவர் வூட்டு நியூட்ரீஷியன் கிளீனிக்கின் நிறுவனர் மற்றும் மருத்துவராக இருக்கிறார்.இளநீரை தினமும் அருந்துவதால் ஆபத்து என்பதெல்லாம் உண்மை கிடையாது என்று பிரீத்தி ஒரு ஆய்வையும் மேற்கோள் காட்டுகிறார். ”அதில் தொடர்ந்து 60 நாட்கள் இளநீர் அருந்துவதால் உடல் எடைக் குறைவதைக் கண்டறிந்துள்ளனர். மேலும் உடலுக்கு மிக முக்கியமான இன்சுலினை தூண்டி வேலை செய்ய வைக்கிறது. அதை தூண்டுவதற்கான ஊட்டச்சத்து இளநீரில் அதிகம் என்கிறது அந்த ஆய்வு”.அதேபோல் இளநீரில் சர்க்கரையின் அளவு அதிகம் என்னும் வதந்தியும் பரப்பப்படுகிறது. அதற்கு பிரீத்தி “ எத்தனைப் பெரிய இளநீராக இருந்தாலும் அதில் அதிகபட்சமாக 250 ML சர்க்கரைதான் இருக்கும். இதே நீங்கள் மற்ற சாஃப்ட் ட்ரிங்குகளை குடிக்கும்போது அதில் குறைந்தபட்சம் 20 டீஸ்பூன் சர்க்கரை இருக்கிறது. இளநீர் கார்போஹைட்ரேட்டுகளும் குறைவக இருப்பதால் உடலுக்கு ஆரோக்கியமானதே என்கிறார்.இளநீர் அருந்தும் முறை :இளநீரை அருந்தும்போது வெறும் நீரை மட்டும் குடிக்காமல் அதன் வழுக்கையையும் சேர்த்து உண்ண வேண்டும் என்கிறார் பிரீத்தி “ இளநீரின் சத்து முழுமையாக உடலுக்குக் கிடைக்கவேண்டுமெனில் வழுக்கையோடு சேர்த்து குடிக்க வேண்டும். இளநீரில் பொட்டாசியம், கால்சியம் இருந்தாலும் வழுக்கையில் மற்ற ஊட்டச்சத்துகள் அதிகமாக இருக்கின்றன. உதாரணமாக உடலுக்குத் தேவையான கொழுப்புச் சத்து, சருமத்தை பளபளக்கச் செய்யும்வைட்டமின்கள், உடல் எடையைக் குறைக்கக்கூடிய ஆற்றல் சத்துகள் போன்றவை அதிகமாக இருக்கின்றன. வெளிநாடுகளிலும் இளநீரை அருந்தியபின் வழுக்கையை உணவுபோல் உண்ணுகின்றனர். விளையாட்டுப் பயிற்சியாளர்கள் மற்றும் உடற்பயிற்சியாளர்களும் இந்த முறையையே பின்பற்றப்படுகிறது.” என்கிறார்.இன்று பலருக்கும் இதயப் பிரச்னை, இரத்தக் கொதிப்பு போன்ற பிரச்னைகள் பொட்டாசியத்தின் குறைப்பாடால் ஏற்படக் கூடியது. இதைத் தவிர்க்க இளநீர் தினமும் அருந்துவது நல்லது.இரத்தக் கொதிப்பு உள்ளவர்களுக்கு அதிகமாக கால்சியம் மற்றும் பொட்டாசியம்தான் அதிகமாகத் தேவைப்படும். அவர்களுக்கும் இந்த இளநீர் நல்ல மருந்தாக இருக்கும். சிறுநீரகக்கல் பிரச்னை வராமலும் தடுக்கும் எனக் குறிப்பிடுகிறார். குறிப்பாக பெண்களுக்குதான் சிறுநீரகப் பிரச்னை அதிகமாக ஏற்படுகிறது. அவர்கள் இளநீரை எடுத்துக் கொள்வது நல்லது எனவும் பரிந்துரைக்கிறார்."},{"question":"「神に帰依した者」という意味がある、イスラム教の信者を指す言葉は何でしょう？","answer":"ムスリムです。"},{"question":"మతసామరస్యం  మీద వ్యాసం రాయండి.","answer":"భారతీయ సమాజంలోని వ్యక్తులకు మతం అనేది పుట్టుక నుండి సంక్రమిస్తుంది. అదే విధంగా మతము యొక్క ప్రభావం వ్యక్తిపై పుట్టుక నుండి మరణించే వరకు ఉంటుంది. ప్రపంచంలో అధిక ప్రభావం కలిగిన ముఖ్యమైన మతాలన్నీ భారతదేశంలో ఉన్నాయి. ఎవరికి వారు వారి మతం గొప్పదిగా భావించడం జరుగుతుంది. ఒకనాటి సమాజాన్ని క్రమబద్ధం చేయడానికి, ఆనాటి సమాజంలో శాంతిభద్రతలు కాపాడుకోవడానికి మతాన్ని ప్రవేశపెట్టడం జరిగింది. భారతదేశంలో ఉన్న మతాలను ఏడు రకాలుగా విభజించవచ్చు.1) హిందూమతం, 2) ముస్లింమతం, 3) క్రైస్తవమతం, 4) బౌద్ధమతం, 5) జైనమతం, 6) సిక్కుమతం, 7) పార్సీ, యూదుమతం. భారతీయ సమాజంలో హిందూమతం వారే ఎక్కువగా ఉన్నప్పటికీ అనేక కారణాలవల్ల మతాల మధ్య వ్యత్యాసాలు, సంఘర్షణలు రోజురోజుకు పెరిగిపోతున్నాయి. ఈ విధమైన మతతత్వానికి అనేక కారణాలున్నాయి. వాటిలో ముఖ్యమైనవి : 1) ప్రజలలో స్వార్థబుద్ధి 2) మహమ్మదీయులలో ఆర్థిక బలహీనతల కారణంగా మైనార్టీలకు ఎక్కువ సౌకర్యాలను కలిగించాలనే వారి వాదన 3) ప్రాంతీయతత్త్వం మొదలైన కారణాలవల్ల భారతీయ సమాజంలో మతతత్త్వం వెర్రితలలు వేస్తోంది. మతతత్వానికి మరొక ముఖ్యకారణం మతంతో రాజకీయాలు మిళితమై ఉండటం.మతాన్ని రాజకీయాల్లో చేర్చటంవల్ల భారత్ నుండి పాకిస్థాన్ విడిపోయింది. నేడు సిక్కుమతం వారు భారత్ నుండి విడిపోయి స్వతంత్ర దేశంగా ఏర్పడతామని అనేక సంవత్సరాలుగా ఉద్యమిస్తూనే ఉన్నారు. మరో ప్రక్క ‘రామజన్మభూమి – బాబ్రీ మసీదు’ వివాదం మతసమస్యగా తయారయింది. భారతదేశంలో మతకలహాలు తరచూ సంభవిస్తూనే ఉన్నాయి. అల్ప సంఖ్యాకులకు, అధిక సంఖ్యాకులకు మధ్య పరస్పర విశ్వాసం, సామరస్యం లోపించడంతో ఈ భయానక వాతావరణం ఏర్పడి అల్లర్లు, అలజడులు, ఆస్తినష్టం, ప్రాణనష్టం తరచు ఏర్పడుతూనే ఉన్నాయి. వివిధ రాజకీయ పక్షాలు పాక్షిక ప్రయోజనాల సాధన కోసం మతకలహాలను ఒక ఆయుధంగా ఉపయోగించుకొంటున్నాయి.ఈ విధమైన పరిస్థితులను చక్కదిద్దాలంటే ప్రజలు చైతన్యవంతులై రాజకీయ నాయకుల బూటకపు మాటలకు మోసపోక పరమత సహనం కలిగిఉండాలి. మత సామరస్యంతో అందరూ కలిసిమెలసి జీవించడం నేర్చుకోవాలి."},{"question":"ඇපල් සමාගම විසින් 2023 වර්ෂ​යේ සැප්තැම්බර් මස එළිදක්වන ලද අලුත්ම iPhone ජංගම දුරකථනය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඇපල් සමාගම විසින් 2023 වර්ෂ​යේ සැප්තැම්බර් මස එළිදක්වන ලද අලුත්ම iPhone ජංගම දුරකථනය iPhone 15 දුරකථනයයි."},{"question":" Inona no karazana antsantsa lehibe indrindra?","answer":"Ny antsantsa trozona no karazana antsantsa lehibe indrindra."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਃ ੩ ॥ਜਿਨੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਿਆ ਤਿਨੀ ਨਾਉ ਪਾਇਆ ਬੂਝਹੁ ਕਰਿ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ਸਦਾ ਸਾਂਤਿ ਸੁਖੁ ਮਨਿ ਵਸੈ ਚੂਕੈ ਕੂਕ ਪੁਕਾਰ ॥ਆਪੈ ਨੋ ਆਪੁ ਖਾਇ ਮਨੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹੋਵੈ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਵੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸਬਦਿ ਰਤੇ ਸੇ ਮੁਕਤੁ ਹੈ ਹਰਿ ਜੀਉ ਹੇਤਿ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 86 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਸਮਝ ਲਵੋ (ਭਾਵ, ਵੇਖ ਲਵੋ), ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਹੋਈ ਕਾਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਹੀ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਤੇ ਸੁਖ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਕਲਪਣਾ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ‘ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਖਾ ਜਾਏ (ਭਾਵ, ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਨਿਵਾਰੇ) ਤਾਂ ਮਨ ਸਾਫ਼ ਹੰੁਦਾ ਹੈ’—ਇਹ ਵਿਚਾਰ (ਭੀ) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ (ਉਪਜਦੀ ਹੈ)  ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਮੁਕਤ ਹਨ, (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਬਿਰਤੀ ਜੁੜੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।੨।\\""},{"question":"Haa, wọn ni ọmọ Ibo yii ki ika bọ ọmọ ọdun marun-un labẹ, wọn ti wọ ọ de teṣan o","answer":"Ni agọ ọlọpaa Festac l’Ekoo ni ọkunrin ọmọ Ibo kan ti n wo pakopako bayii, lẹyin ti ọwọ tẹ ẹ nibi to ti n fi ika ro ọmọ ọdun marun-un labẹ.Nnamadi Emdriuokhe, ni wọn pe orukọ ẹ, agbegbe Festac, l’Ekoo gan-an niṣẹlẹ ọhun ti waye. Wọn lo pẹ ti ọkunrin ọmọ Ibo yii ti maa n ra ounjẹ lọwọ iya ọmọ to n ṣe iṣekuṣe pẹlu ẹ yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe, nibi to ti n fika ro ọmọ naa labẹ ni ẹjẹ ti bẹrẹ si jade, n lawọn eeyan ba ki i mọle, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i lu u bii ẹni maa ku!Ọkunrin kan lagbegbe naa, Ọlagunju ̀Ọladele, ti iṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju ẹ lo gbe e sori ẹrọ alatagba, ohun to si kọ sibẹ ni pe, ṣọja kan lo gba a kalẹ lọwọ awọn eeyan ti wọn fẹẹ lu u pa, nigba tọwọ tẹ ẹ.O ni lojuẹsẹ naa lawọn obi ọmọ ọhun ti fọrọ ọhun to teṣan ọlọpaa leti, ṣugbọn ti awọn yẹn naa tun n beere owo lọwọ wọn, ki wọn too le gba ọrọ wọn silẹ.Siwaju si i, o ni, nibi ti ọkunrin to hu iwa ọdaran yii ti fẹẹ fowo bọ awọn eeyan ọhun ninu loun ti dide sọrọ ọhun, oun si ti gbe e lọ si teṣan ọlọpaa to wa ni Festac bayii."},{"question":"问：在1100-1200年间，哪位法国国王领导了第三次十字军东征？","answer":"答：在1100-1200年间，法国国王路易七世领导了第三次十字军东征。"},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut. Siapakah inspirasi untuk watak dalam filem Paid in Full?","answer":" Cerita dalam filem Paid in Full adalah berdasarkan Alpo Martinez"},{"question":"アメリカ大統領選挙が行われる曜日は必ず決まっていますが、何曜日でしょう？","answer":"火曜日です。"},{"question":"\\"මහා  නිකුම්බිලා  දේවිය\\" කියන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"ප්‍රත්‍යාංගිරා (සංස්කෘත: प्रत्यङ्गिरा, Pratyaṅgirā), අතරවාන භද්‍රකාලි, නරසිංහී, සිංහමුඛී සහ නිකුම්බලා ලෙසද හඳුන්වනු ලබන්නේ, ශක්තිවාදය හා සම්බන්ධ හින්දු දේවතාවියකි. ඇය නරසිංහගේ කාන්තා ශක්තිය සහ භාර්යාව ලෙස විස්තර කෙරේ.ත්‍රිපුර රහසට අනුව, ඇය ත්‍රිපුර සුන්දරීගේ කෝපයේ නිර්මල ප්‍රකාශනයයි. වේදවල, ප්‍රත්‍යංගිරා අථර්ව වේදයේ සහ මන්ත්‍ර මන්ත්‍රවල දේවතාවිය වන අතරවාන භද්‍රකාලිගේ ස්වරූපයෙන් නිරූපණය කෙරේ. නරසිංහ යනු සප්තමාත්‍රික මාතෘ දෙවඟනන්ගේ කොටසකි."},{"question":"mhembwe hadzi inonzi chii?","answer":"dimbura"},{"question":"📚Дүйнөдөгү аялдардын арасында белгилүү болгон инсандар?","answer":"Ямайкадагы Порция Симпсон-Миллер жетектеген оппозициялык Улуттук элдик партия 2011-жылдын декабрындагы шайлоодо чоң ажырым менен алдыга оозуп чыккан. Симпсон-Миллер Ямайканын биринчи аял премьер-министри болуп 2006-жылы шайланган."},{"question":"Mina ngiyakwazi ukuvika. Wayengeke alithole ikhanda lami. (ahleke)We mame! Kuvike bani? Kanti ezikoleni zaseThekwini nanelusa yini?Musa ukudlala lapha wena.Futhi akazange ashaye ndawo uDlamini lapho kuwe kodwa nguweowabhayiziswa uvalo maqede wazishayisa obondeni. (ahleke)(sakunengwa) Wayebheda lowo enkantolo. Yizindlela eziphansi njezakhe lezo zokuphika icala. Sizobona kodwa ukuthi azophelelaphi lamanga awashoyo. Futhi masihlukane nale ndaba kaDlamini ngobaiyanginenga.1. Yini ekhombisa ukuthi uMbandlwa usengcono? Sekela ngamaphuzuAMABILI.","answer":"Akasabhandishile ekhanda./ Akasawathwele amawashingi.• Usekwazi ukuhamba ibanga elide. "},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：什么是二胡，它在中国民乐中的地位如何？","answer":"答案：二胡是中国传统的拉弦乐器，具有悠扬的音色和丰富的表现力。在中国民乐中，二胡被广泛使用，并常作为独奏乐器或与其他乐器合奏，为音乐增添动情和哀怨的情感。"},{"question":"ප්‍රාණවාචී අප්‍රාණවාචි වගේ මිනිස්සු සහ අනෙකුත් හැමදෙයක්ම වෙන්කරලා  පෙන්වන්න සිංහලෙන් භාවිතා කරන පදය මොකක් ද? මිනිසුන් එක කොටසක් වෙන්න ඕනෙ සතුන් සිවුපාවන් ගස් කොලන් මේ හැමදෙයක්ම තවත් කොටසක් වෙන්න ඕනෙ.","answer":"මනුෂ්‍ය සහ අමනුෂ්‍ය කියූ විට ඒ බෙදීම තිබෙන නමුත් අමනුෂ්‍ය යන්න ව්‍යවහාර වන්නේ මනුෂ්‍ය පෙනුම ඇතැයි සැලකෙන අමනුෂ්‍යයන්ට පමණයි.මනුෂ්‍යයා සහ පරිබාහිර ජීවීන් ලෙස වර්ග කළ හැකියි ඔබේ අවශ්‍යතාව සඳහා."},{"question":"لماذا خلق الله النجوم؟\\t","answer":"خلقها لثلاث: زينة للسماء، ورجوماً للشياطين وعلامات يهتدى بها في البر والبحر."},{"question":"Munyika ipi yaungawana renje reNegev?  ","answer":"Negev Desert iri munyika yeIsrael. Iyi nzvimbo yakaoma uye inokatyamadza inofukidza chikamu chikuru cheIsrael yokumaodzanyemba."},{"question":"Mikä on salmonella?","answer":"Salmonellat ovat yleisiä, eläinten kantamia bakteereja, jotka voivat aiheuttaa suolisto- ja yleisinfektioita.Salmonellan serotyyppejä tunnetaan yli 2 500.  Yleisimmät Suomessa ihmisille tautia aiheuttavat salmonellan serotyypit ovat S. Enteritidis ja S. Typhimurium."},{"question":"Tiṣa fipa ba ọmọ ọdun mejila lo pọ n’Ilọrin, awọn ọlọpaa ti mu un","answer":"Ọwọ ọlọpaa agbegbe Adewọle, niluu Ilọrin, ti tẹ olukọ ẹni ọdun mejilelọgbọn kan, Ahmed Yusuf, to n gbe ni Gaa-Odota, lori ẹsun pe o fipa ba ọmọ ọdun mejila kan laṣepọ.Afurasi ọhun toun pẹlu obi ọmọbinrin naa jọ jẹ ayalegbe ni wọn lo fọgbọn fa oju iyẹn mọra lati ṣe aburu to wa lọkan rẹ.ALAROYE gbọ pe aimọye igba lo ti ba ọmọ naa lo pọ ko too di pe ọwọ palaba rẹ ṣẹgi.Gbogbo igba ti Yusuf fi n ba ọmọ yii laṣepọ ni tipa, o maa n halẹ mọ ọn pe ko gbọdọ sọ fun ẹnikẹni. O ni to ba sọ, ọjọ naa lo maa ri aye mọ.Ibẹru ohun to sọ yii ni ko jẹ ki ọmọbinrin naa le sọ fun ẹnikẹni. Ṣugbọn eyi ti Yusuf ṣe gbẹyin lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ni akara rẹ fi tu sepo.Bawọn ayalegbe yooku ṣe mu afurasi naa ni wọn wọ ọ lọ si tesan ọlọpaa lati ṣalaye ara rẹ.ALAROYE tiẹ gbọ pe awọn obi rẹ ti n sa gbogbo ipa lati mu ki obi ọmọbinrin naa jawọ lori ẹjọ ọhun, ṣugbọn awọn yẹn ta ku pe o gbọdọ jẹ iya to ba tọ si i.Nibi ti wọn ni kinni ọhun le de, ẹgbẹ awọn agbẹjọro obinrin, International Federation of Women Lawyers (FIDA), ti da si ọrọ naa, wọn ni awọn yoo tọpinpin ẹjọ naa titi tile-ẹjọ yoo fi ṣedajọ ododo fun afurasi naa."},{"question":"Rispondi alla seguente domanda:\\"Cos'è un Patrimonio dell'Umanità?\\"","answer":"Un patrimonio dell'umanità, ufficialmente definito patrimonio mondiale, è un sito registrato nella lista del patrimonio mondiale, o nella sua accezione inglese World Heritage List, della Convenzione sul patrimonio dell'umanità. La Convenzione, adottata dalla Conferenza generale dell'UNESCO il 16 novembre 1972, ha lo scopo di identificare e mantenere la lista dei siti che rappresentano delle particolarità di eccezionale importanza da un punto di vista culturale o naturale. Il Comitato della Convenzione, chiamato Comitato per il patrimonio dell'umanità, ha sviluppato dei criteri precisi per l'inclusione dei siti nella lista."},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang paling sesuai untuk soalan berikut. Manakah antara berikut merupakan adab menggunakan telefon awam?A. Meletakkan semula telefon ke gagang telefon selepas menggunakannyaB. Menghempas telefon dengan kuat kerana marahC. Membuang sampah di tempat tersembunyi di pondok telefonD. Membiarkan sahaja jika telefon rosak tanpa membuat aduan","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah A. Meletakkan semula telefon ke gagang telefon selepas menggunakannya"},{"question":"Miksi pakkanen kiristyy muutamia asteita kun aurinko aamulla nousee?","answer":"Lämpötila on alimmillaan selkeällä ja puolipilvisellä säällä yleensä vähän sen jälkeen, kun aurinko nousee. Yöllä lämpöenergiaa katoaa maan pinnalta. Kun aurinko nousee, lämpötila alkaa kohota. Aluksi aurinko paistaa kuitenkin niin alhaalla, ettei se lämmitä. Selkeinä öinä lämpötila maan pinnan lähellä on yleensä alempi kuin ylempänä ilmakehässä eli on ns. maanpintainversio.\\"Kylmä kakku\\" maanpinnan lähellä on hyvin ohut tyynellä säällä, joten se häviää helposti esimerkiksi auringon lämmittäessä tai tuulen voimistuessa. Pienikin energian muutos aiheuttaa suuren vaikutuksen, kun se kohdistuu ohueen ilmakerrokseen. Tällöin lämpötila voi aamutuimaan auringon nousun aikaan laskea alas ja nousta sitten nopeasti kun aurinko nousee. Ilmankosteus vaikuttaa asiaan. Jos on kosteaa, muodostuu helposti sumua tai sumupilveä ja lämpötilan lasku pysähtyy. Ilman tiheyteen asia vaikuttaa niin, että kylmä ilma on raskaampaa ja esimerkiksi laaksopaikkoihin virtaa ylempää kylmää ilmaa.Ilmatieteen laitoksen mittausasemilla lämpötilaa mitataan yleensä kahden metrin korkeudessa. Maan pinnan lähellä voi olla useita asteita kylmempää kuin kahden metrin korkeudessa. Auringonnousu aiheuttaa sen, että ilman pystyliikkeet lisääntyvät, jolloin maanpinnan läheltä kulkeutuu kylmempää ilmaa ylemmäksi, minkä seurauksena kahden metrin korkeudessa lämpötila laskee hieman, ennen kuin auringonsäteily pääsee ilmaa lämmittämään."},{"question":"Rispondi alla seguente domanda:\\"Qual è l'habitat del colibrì ali di zaffiro?\\"","answer":"Il colibrì ali di zaffiro (Pterophanes cyanopterus) è diffuso sui rilievi andini di Bolivia, Colombia, Ecuador e Perù, ad altitudini comprese tra 2.600 e 3.700 m."},{"question":"நற்றிணை நூலின் உரையாசிரியர் யார்? அவர் எங்கு யாரிடம் திண்ணைக் கல்விக் கற்றார்?","answer":"நற்றிணை நூலின் உரையாசிரியர் பின்னத்தூர் நாராயணசாமி. பின்னத்தூர் அருகே உள்ள கிருஷ்ணாபுரம் முத்துராம பாரதி திண்ணைப் பள்ளிக்கூடத்தில் இலவசமாகக் கற்றார்."},{"question":"Ọzara","answer":"Olundị - íkpa"},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một câu hỏi với chủ đề là Methamphetamine và có liên quan tới nội dung của đoạn văn này: \\"Mặc dù hiếm khi được kê đơn, methamphetamine hydrochloride được Cơ quan Quản lý Thực phẩm và Dược phẩm Hoa Kỳ (FDA) chấp thuận để điều trị rối loạn tăng động thiếu chú ý và béo phì dưới tên thương mại Desoxyn\\"? ","answer":"\\"Một số cách sử dụng hợp pháp của chất methamphetamine hydrochloride được Cơ quan Quản lý Thực phẩm và Dược phẩm Hoa Kỳ (FDA) chấp thuận là gì?\\""},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هي السور اللي بدات بالحمد ؟","answer":"الإجابة: الفاتحة و الأنعام و الكهف و سبأ و فاطر"},{"question":"中央アジアを探検し、楼蘭（ろうらん）遺跡やロプノールを発見したことで知られるスウェーデンの探険家は誰でしょう？","answer":"スウェン・ヘディン"},{"question":"વસાવા બોલી વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"વસાવા બોલીનો ઉદભવ કઇ ભાષામાંથી થયો તે જાણવું મુશ્કેલ છે. પરંતુ આ ભાષા ભાષા તાપી નદી તેમ જ નર્મદા નદીના ખીણ પ્રદેશ તેમ જ તેની વચ્ચેના વિસ્તારમાં વસતા આદિવાસીઓ પૈકીના વસાવા જાતિના લોકોની પરાપૂર્વથી સામાજીક વહેવારમાં વપરાતી પરંપરાગત બોલી છે. પરંતુ આ બોલી બોલનારા વસાવા લોકોની વસ્તી ગુજરાતમાં વિશેષ છે. આ બોલી ખાસ કરીને દક્ષિણ ગુજરાતના રાનીપરજ વિસ્તારના તાપી જિલ્લા અને સુરત જિલ્લાના ઉમરપાડા તથા નર્મદા જિલ્લાના ડેડીયાપાડા તેમજ નેત્રંગ તાલુકામાં વધુ બોલાય છે. આ બોલીમાં તેમાં થોડા શબ્દો ગુજરાતી ભાષા જેવા તથા થોડા શબ્દો સંસ્કૃત તથા મરાઠી ભાષા જેવા છે.ઉચ્ચારણ:વસાવા બોલીમાં બહુવચન હોતું નથી. તેથી આ બોલીમાં દાદાને પણ તુ અને પુત્રને પણ તુ કહીને બોલાવવામા આવે છે. સાંભળવામાં આ બોલી તોછડી લાગે છે. આ બોલીમાં વાક્યને અંતે વા બોલાય છે, જે આ બોલીનું વૈવિધ્ય છે તેમ જ તુંકારામાં બોલવા છતાં મીઠી લાગે છે. ઉપરાંત આજ ભાષા થાેડા થાેડા અંતરે અલગ રીતે બાેલાય છે. જેવી કે દેહવાલી (ખાનદેશી), આંબુડી, ખાટાલીયે, માવચી વગરે.કેટલાક શબ્દો:બા - પિતાદીહુ - દીયરયા - માતાડાયલો - જેઠદાદો - ભાઈનોંદહે - નંણદબોંઅહી - બહેનપોજાહા - ભાભીપોયરો - પુત્રપોયરી - પુત્રીમાટી / જમાહ - પતીથૈ / નાડી - પત્નીહાવળી - સાસુહારહો - સસરોજીજી - માસીહાલોસ - સાળોઆજલી - દાદીઆજલો - દાદાપાવડીહુ - જીજાજીવ્યાકરણ:અન્ય ભાષાની જેમ વસાવા બોલીમાં પણ ત્રણ કાળનો (વર્તમાનકાળ, ભવિષ્યકાળ અને ભુતકાળ) ઉપયોગ કરીને બોલી બોલાય છે.દાત.હું જાઉ છુ - આંઇ જાહું (વર્તમાન કાળ)હું જઈશ - આંઇ જાહીં (ભવિષ્યકાળ)હું ગયો હતો - આંઇ ગેઇલો (ભુતકાળ)કર્તા - ક્રિયાપદ - કર્મ:હું - આંઇતુ - તુતમે - તુઅમે - આમાંતે, તેણી - એલો, એલીતેઓ - એપલા"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Sao Việt 1/8: Sao Việt 1/8: NSND Tự Long háo hức chăm con trai mới sinh","answer":"Sao Việt ngày 1/8: NSND Tự Long chia sẻ khoảnh khắc chăm sóc cậu con trai vừa chào đời. \\"Cả nhà ta cùng yêu thương nhau / Xa là nhà gần nhau là cười\\", anh hài hước chú thích cho bức ảnh. Thúy Ngọc"},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: Ülkenin bağımsızlığını kazanmadan önce Fransa adına çavuş rütbesi ile II. Dünya Savaşı ve","answer":"Cezayir Bağımsızlık Savaşı'na katılan Andriamahazo, Madagaskar'ın bağımsızlığını kazanması sonrasında ülkesine dönmüştür. 1972 yılında Antananarivo'nun askeri valisi olarak atanan Andriamahazo, 1975 yılında devlet başkanı Ratsimandrava'nın görevi başında suikast sonucu öldürülmesi neticesinde \\"Milli Askeri Liderlik Komitesi Başkanı\\" sıfatı ile Madagaskar devlet başkanı olmuştur. Andriamahazo devlet başkanlığı makamını 15 Haziran 1975 tarihine kadar sürdürmüş, bu süreçte gerçekleşen askerî darbe sonrasında görevinden Didier Ratsiraka lehine çekilmiştir."},{"question":"Тил жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Тилден жыгылгыча, буттан жыгыл."},{"question":"வினா :விடை சென்னை உயர்நீதிமன்றத்தின் மதுரைகிளை எந்த ஆண்டு தொடங்கப்பட்டது?","answer":" விடை :2004"},{"question":"Bergson, toplumları başlıca iki grupta toplar: açık toplumlar ve kapalı toplumlar. Kapalı toplumda, üyeler birbirine kenetlenmiştir; kendi toplulukları dışındakilere karşı ya kayıtsız ya da saldırgan bir tavır geliştirirler. Daima dar ve ....... olan bu tür toplumlar, ilkel toplumlarda görülen birçok özelliği de bünyelerinde taşırlar. Açık toplum ise insanlığı bütünüyle kucaklayan toplum çeşididir.Bu parçada boş bırakılan yere, düşüncenin akışına göre, aşağıdakilerden hangisi getirilmelidir?A) dışa dönük B) dışlayıcı C) değişken D) korunaksız E) gerçekçi","answer":"Kapalı toplumlardan bahseden bu metinde boşluğun yerine gelmesi en uygun sıfat dışlayıcıdır. Bu yüzden, B seçeneği doğru cevaptır."},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"વા વાયા ને વાદળ ઊમટ્યાં\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"વા વાયા ને વાદળ ઊમટ્યાં,ગોકુળમાં ટહુક્યા મોર,મળવા આવો સુંદીરવર શામળિયા.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"વા વાયા ને વાદળ ઊમટ્યાં,ગોકુળમાં ટહુક્યા મોર,મળવા આવો સુંદીરવર શામળિયા.તમે મળવા તે ના’વો શા માટેનહીં આવો તો નંદજીની આણ ... મળવા.તમે ગોકુળમાં ગોધન ચોરંતા,તમે છો રે સદાના ચોર ... મળવા.તમે કાળી તે કામળી ઓઢંતા,તમે ભરવાડના ભાણેજ ... મળવા.તમે વ્રજમાં તે વાંસળી વાજંતા,તમે ગોપીઓના ચિત્તના ચોર ... મળવા.મહેતા નરસિંહના સ્વામી શામળિયા,એમને તેડી રમાડ્યા રાસ ... મળવા."},{"question":"Mozika avy aiza ny kilalaky?","answer":"Ny kilalaky dia mozika avy any amin'ny faritra atsimo andrefan' i Madagasikara."},{"question":"\\"વિકાસનો સફર\\" નામ ની બાળવાર્તા .","answer":"\\"વિકાસનો સફર\\" અહેવાલ એક છોકરો હતો જે ગામના એક છોકરાના પરિવારમાં જન્મેલો હતો. તેમના પિતાએ પ્રતિષ્ઠાનો મોટો મૂદો રાખ્યો હતો અને તેમનો સમાજમાં ગૌરવ છેડતા રહ્યાં.અહેવાલનો દિલ વિજયભરવાનો ઇચ્છુક રહ્યો. પરંતુ, તેમના ગામના કેટલાક લોકો તેની અસફળતાને ચીંઘડાવવાનો પ્રયાસ કરી રહ્યાં. બધી બધી પરીક્ષાઓમાં અહેવાલ સફળ રહ્યો હતો, પરંતુ તેમના દિલમાં એક અનામોલ ખોટું છેડી રહ્યું.એકદિવસ, એક ગુરુકુલમાં અહેવાલને એક મુખ્ય પ્રાધિકૃત સાથે મળી. પ્રાધિકૃતે તેમને તેના દિલના ખોટામાં પરિચિત કરવાનો સમય લેવાનો નિર્ણય કર્યો. તેમને સહેજે કહ્યું, \\"તારી યોજનાઓ શક્તિશાળી છે, પરંતુ તારા દિલની સાથે સાથે વર્તન પણ કરવું જોઈએ.\\"પરંતુ, અહેવાલનો દિલ જોઈએ એવું નથી. તેમનો અહંકાર અને ઈર્ષ્યાને તેમને અવગણવાનો સમય આવ્યો. પરંતુ, પછીથી તેમનો દિલ બદલવાનો શરૂ થયો. તેમને અવગણવાનો અને સહેનોનો સમય મળ્યો. પ્રતિષ્ઠાની મોટાઈ છોડવાનો પ્રયાસ કરી રહ્યો અને તેમને સફળતા મળી."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\" Na Miaina Eo Amin'ny Fotoana _ Aza, Dia Miezaha Ihany Mba Ho Tafita\\"","answer":"\\" Na Miaina Eo Amin'ny Fotoana Sarotra Aza, Dia Miezaha Ihany Mba Ho Tafita\\""},{"question":"සෛල පටල සෑදී ඇති ප්‍රධාන ද්‍රව්‍ය තුන නම් කරන්න.","answer":"සෛල පටල සෑදී ඇති ප්‍රධාන ද්‍රව්‍ය තුන පහත දැක්වේ.1. පොස්පො ලිපිඩ - පොස්පො ලිපිඩ අණු වලට ජලකාමී හිසක් (ධ්‍රැවීය කොටස) සහ ජල භීතික වල්ගයක් (ධ්‍රැවීය නොවන කොටස) පවතී.2. ප්‍රෝටීන - පාරපටල/සම්පූර්ණ ප්‍රෝටීන, වාහක ප්‍රෝටීන, පර්යන්ත ප්‍රෝටීන, ප්‍රෝටීන අණුවලටද ජලකාමී සහ ජල භීතික කොටස් පවතී.3. කාබෝහයිඩ්‍රේට - ප්ලාස්ම පටලයේ බාහිර පෘෂ්ඨයේ අතු බෙදුනු කෙටි පොලිසැකරයිඩ දාම ලෙස පවතී. වැඩිපුරම පවතින්නේ ග්ලයිකෝප්‍රෝටීන යම් පොලිසැකරයිඩ දාම කිහිපයක් සමග සම්බන්ධවයි.සෛල ප්ලාස්ම පටලයේ බාහිර පෘෂ්ඨයේ පවතින කාබෝහයිඩ්‍රේට අණු සියලේ එකතුව ග්ලයිකො කැලික්සය වේ. මෙය අර්ධ පාරගමය නොහොත් වරනීය පාරගමය පටලයකි ( සෛල පටලය හරහා තෝරාගත් ද්‍රව්‍ය වලට පමනක් ගමන් කිරිමට හැක)"},{"question":"భాగస్వామ్య వ్యాపారము, సమిష్టి హిందూ కుటుంబ వ్యాపారాలకు మధ్యగల తేడాలను తెలపండి.","answer":"సమిష్టి.హిందూ కుటుంబానికి, భాగస్వామ్యానికి మధ్య గల తేడాలు:భాగస్వామ్య సంస్థ,స్థాపన: భాగస్తుల మధ్య ఒప్పందము.సభ్యుల సంఖ్య: కనిష్ట సభ్యుల సంఖ్య 2 గరిష్ట సభ్యుల సంఖ్య బ్యాంకింగ్ వ్యాపారాలయితే 10, ఇతర వ్యాపారాలయితే 20.నిర్వహణ: భాగస్తులందరూ లేదా అందరు తరపున కొందరు వ్యాపారాన్ని నిర్వహిస్తారు.ఋణబాధ్యత: భాగస్తుల ఋణభాధ్యత వ్యక్తిగతం, సమిష్టిగతము, అపరిమితము.లాభాల పంపిణీ: ఒప్పందము ప్రకారము లాభనష్టాలను పంపిణీ చేస్తారు.రద్దు: భాగస్తుని విరమణ, మరణం లేదా దివాలా తీయడం వలన భాగస్వామ్య ఒప్పందము రద్దవుతుంది.మైనర్ భాగస్తుడు: చట్టము ప్రకారము మైనరు భాగస్తుడు కాలేడు.సభ్యులను భాగస్తులు అంటారు.అధికారము: సంస్థ తరపున వ్యవహరించ- డానికి భాగస్తులకు ప్రచ్ఛన్న అధికారము ఉంటుంది.నూతన సభ్యులు: సహభాగస్తుల అంగీకారముతో కొత్త వారిని భాగస్తులుగా చేర్చుకోవచ్చు.సమిష్టి హిందూ కుటుంబముహిందూ చట్టము ద్వారా ఏర్పడుతుంది.కనిష్ట సభ్యుల సంఖ్య లేదు. సహవారసుల సంఖ్యకు పరిమితి లేదు.కర్త మాత్రమే నిర్వహణను చేపడతాడు.కర్త ఋణబాధ్యత అపరిమితము. సహవారసుల ఋణబాధ్యత వారి వాటాలకే పరిమితము. 5. సహవారసుల జనన, మరణాల ద్వారా లాభ నష్టాల వాటా మారుతూ ఉంటుంది.ఎవరు మరణించినా వ్యవస్థ రద్దు కాదు. కుటుంబము విడిపోతే వాటాలను పంచడం జరుగుతుంది.మైనరు అయినా ఉమ్మడి కుటుంబములో సహవారసుడు అవుతాడు.సభ్యులను సహవారసులు అంటారు.సహవారసులకు ప్రచ్ఛన్న అధికారము ఉండదు.సహవారసులు అంగీకరించినా బయటి వారిని సహవారసులుగా చేర్చుకొనడానికి వీలులేదు."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và trả lời câu hỏi: \\"Xung đột Hamas - Israel gia tăng là nguyên nhân khiến giá vàng tăng?\\"Đoạn văn: Giá vàng thế giới kết thúc phiên giao dịch hôm 3/11 ở mức 1.992,5 USD một ounce, sau khi có thời điểm trong phiên vượt 2.000 USD. Đà tăng của kim loại quý được giới phân tích dự đoán sẽ tiếp diễn vào tuần này do lo ngại xung đột tại Trung Đông và hầu hết các ngân hàng trung ương lớn trên thế giới, trong đó có Cục Dự trữ liên bang Mỹ (Fed) ngừng tăng lãi suất.Giá vàng thường diễn biến ngược chiều với lãi suất, do kim loại này không trả lãi cố định. Vì thế, nếu Fed không tiếp tục nâng lãi, vàng sẽ hưởng lợi.Các nhà phân tích và đầu tư tham gia khảo sát của Kitco News đều tỏ ra lạc quan về triển vọng của vàng tuần này. Trong 15 nhà phân tích Phố Wall tham gia khảo sát của Kitco News, có 9 chuyên gia (60%) dự báo vàng tăng trong tuần tới, trong khi chỉ một người nói kim loại này sẽ giảm giá. Năm ý kiến (33%) nói thị trường sẽ đi ngang.Về phía các nhà đầu tư tham gia cuộc thăm dò trực tuyến, 64% kỳ vọng giá vàng tiếp đà tăng, 22% cho rằng vàng sẽ giảm, còn 14% trung lập về triển vọng ngắn hạn của kim loại quý này.Tháng này, giá vàng tăng mạnh do xung đột Israel - Hamas. Phiên 27/10, giá có lúc chạm 2.009 USD - cao nhất kể từ tháng 5. Tổng cộng, giá đã tăng 8%, tương đương gần 150 USD, kể từ khi xung đột tại Trung Đông nổ ra ngày 7/10.","answer":"Đúng. Tháng 10, giá vàng tăng mạnh do xung đột Israel - Hamas."},{"question":"kan moo toppandoo woon ki rayoon Kustër ca wild west show bu Bufaloo ?","answer":"William Frederick Cody."},{"question":"Cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Qué equipo ganó la Serie Mundial de 2016?. ","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es el resultado y el ganador de la Serie Mundial de béisbol en el año 2016. "},{"question":"Apakah perbezaan antara anime dan kartun?","answer":"Antara perbezaan yang ketara ialah :1. Kartun dibuat untuk ditonton oleh kanak-kanak, sementara anime pula terbahagi kpd beberapa rating kelas usia melalui kandungan yang dipersembahkan sama ada dari segi jalan cerita yang rumit difahami atau sebagainya. Kebanyakan film atau  kartun yang dibuat oleh Barat dan negara-negara selain Jepun adalah untuk tontonan kanak-kanak atau bergeneral keluarga. Berbeza dengan Anime. Karya animasi buatan Jepun ini hadir dengan berbagai Rating Usia. Bahkan beberapa anime dengan genre tertentu seperti Ecchi dan Gore sengaja dibuat untuk tontonan 17 tahun keatas . Meskipun produknya sama-sama dalam katogeri animasi.2. Anime diangkat dari Manga dan Game manakala Kartun banyak yang ceritanya original majoriti cerita anime diangkat dari cerita manga (komik Jepun) seperti Naruto dan One Piece atau dari cerita game seperti God Eater dan Final Fantasy. Sementara cerita Kartun banyak yang diangkat dari cerita original. Beberapa komik tentang film kartun yang beredar dipasaran adalah setelah film kartunnya ditayangkan seperti Spongebob dan Upin Ipin.3. Perbezaan Anime merupakan produk jepun, sementara kartun adalah produk animasi luar dari jepun. Namun jika diteliti dengan lebih mendalam, sebenarnya anime sangat jauh berbeza dengan kartun.4. Genre anime jauh lebih beragam dibandingkan kartun kerana kartun dibuat sebagai tontonan kanak-kanak maka genre ceritanya sangat terbatas. Banyak aspek yang membatasi idea cerita kartun. Atas sebab terbahagi dalam pelbagai macam rating usia, maka anime hadir dalam banyak sangat genre, bahkan hingga ada genre dewasa yang tidak boleh ditonton oleh kanak-kanak seperti genre hentai dan gore.5. Cerita anime cenderung lebih serius dibandingkan dengan kartun. Jika film kartun kebanyakan mengangkat cerita komedi dan parodi ringan yang tujuan utamanya membuat penontonnya tertawa, terhibur. Anime hadir dengan banyak pilihan cerita yang cenderung serius yang dapat membuat penontonnya berfikir, ngeri, geli, bernafsu, sedih dan sebagainya.6. Gambar anime cenderung lebih terperinci dibanding kartun kerana anime cenderung memaparkan cerita yang lebih serius, maka design karakter dan lingkungannya cenderung dibuat dengan lebih teliti dibandingkan dengan kartun yang lebih mengutamakan aspek “lucu.”7. Kartun biasanya happy ending, sementara anime endingnya  yang tidak dijangka kerana kepelbagaianya. Dari kisah dongeng hingga yang rekaan semata-mata seperti Spongebob, semuanya berakhir dengan happy ending. Sementara anime memiliki ending yang sangat beragam. Beberapa anime seperti Code Geass, Akame Ga Kill, dan Terraformars berakhir dengan banyak kematian sadis."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி பற்றி குறிப்பு வரைக  .","answer":"சிக்கனமே செல்வம், தகுதிக்கு மேல் வாழ்வதே தரித்திரம் என்பதை மனத்தில் இருத்தல் வேண்டும்.பெரியார் ஈ.வெ, இராமசாமி  (செப்டம்பர் 17, 1879 – டிசம்பர் 24, 1973), அனைவராலும் இராமசாமி ,ஈ.வெ.ரா தந்தை பெரியார் அல்லது பெரியார் என்று அழைக்கப்படும் இவர்,திராவிட சமூகச் சீர்திருத்தவாதி அவர் திராவிட இயக்கம்,சுய மரியாதை இயக்கம் ஆகியவற்றை நிறுவினார். அவர் மக்கள் தமது சமுதாயத்தை பரிபூரணமாக்க சீர்திருத்தம் அவசரத் தேவையாக உள்ளது என்பதை உணர வேண்டும் என்று விரும்பினார்.அரசு அரசியல் கட்சிகள்,மற்றும் சமூக தொழிலாளர்கள் சமுதாயத்தில் உள்ள அவலங்களை கண்டு அவற்றை களையும்  நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டும் என விரும்பினார்.   "},{"question":"Tobbacco i Älvsjö har följande öppettider:Måndag-Fredag\\t09:30–20.00Lördag\\t11:15–18.00Söndag\\t11:30–16.00Är dom öppna på Onsdagar kl 13?","answer":"Ja, öppettiderna är Måndag-Fredag är 09.30-20.00 vilket innebär att de är öppna på onsdagar kl 13."},{"question":"Nọ́mbà gidi","answer":"Nínú Ìmọ̀ Ìṣirò nọ́mbà gidi (real number) ni a mọ̀ sí àwọn nọ́mbà tí a Ko lè gé, gẹ́gẹ́ bí nọ́mbà oníyemẹ́wàá (decimals) tí kò lópin. Fún àpẹẹrẹ 2.4871773339…. Àwọn nọ́mbà gidi jẹ́ nọ́mbà oníìpín, nọ́mbà bí 42 àti −23/129, àti nọ́mbà aláìníìpín, nọ́mbà gbòngbò alágbára-méjì]] 2 (square root) tí wọ́n sì ṣeé fihàn gẹ́gẹ́ bí ojúàmì (point) ní orí ìlà nọ́mbà tó gùn ní àìlópin.A ń pe àwọn nọ́mbà gidi bẹ́ẹ̀ láti lè ṣèyàtọ̀ sí àwon nọ́mbà tósòro (complex number). Ní ayé àtijọ́ àwọn onímọ̀ ìṣirò mọ nọ́mbà tó rújú gẹ́gẹ́ bí nọ́mbà afòyemọ̀ (imaginary number).Nọ́mbà gidi lè jẹ́ onípìín tàbí aláìnípìín; Ó lè jẹ́ nọ́mbà Ọ̀jíbírà tàbí nọ́mbà t tí kò ní ònkà (transcendental number); bẹ́ẹ̀ sì ni wọ́n lè jẹ́ nọ́mbà tódájú, ni odi tàbí kí wọ́n jẹ́ òdo.A n fi nomba gidi se iwon awon opoiye to je wiwapapo (continuous). O se se ka fi won han gege bi nombamewa to ni itelentele (sequence) eyonomba (digit) ti ko lopin lapa otun ojuami nombamewa (decimal point); a le fi won han bayi 324.823211247…. Awon ami bintin meta to wa leyin nomba yi tumosi pe awon eyonomba miran si n bo leyin.Bakanna, awon nomba gidi tun ni idamo meji ti papa elesese (ordered field) ni, be ni won si ni idamo ti a mo si ipari l'oke tokerejulo (least upper bound). Akoko so fun wa pe awon nomba gidi ni papa kan, pelu aropo, isodipupo ati isepinpin pelu awon nomba ti ki se odo ti won le je elesese lapapo ni ori ila nomba lona to ni ibamu po mo aropo ati isodipupo. Ekeji so fun wa pe ti akojopo nomba gidi ti ki se ofo (empty) ba ni ipari l'oke (upper bound), o gbudo ni ipari l'oke tokerejulo. Awon mejeji yi lapapo ni won se'tumo nomba gidi patapata. Lati inu won ni awon idamo nomba gidi yioku ti jade wa. Fun apere a le fihan pe gbogbo polynomial (alamipupo) alagbara nomba siseku pelu nomba ibamulo (coefficient) gidi yio ni gbongbo gidi; ati pe ti a ba s'aropo gbongbo alagbarameji idin okan (minus one) po mo nomba gidi lati fun wa ni nomba tosoro, esi yi ni a n so pe o je titi ninu aljebra.A n se iwon ninu Imo Sayensi Alagbamu (physical science) gege bi won ba n sunmo nomba gidi to. Bo tile je pe awon nomba ti a n lo fun eyi je ida nombamewa (decimal fraction) ti won duro fun awon nomba oniipin, nipa kiko won sile gege bi nombamewa fihan pe won n sunmo nomba gidi kan.A n so pe nomba gidi se sesiro ti igbese isiro ti a mo si Algorithm ba wa ti yio mu eyonomba re wa. Nitoripe bo tile wu ki awon algorithm re o po to, won niye pato (countable), sugbon awon nomba gidi ko niye (uncountable), nitori eyi opo ninu awon nomba gidi ni won ko se sesiro.Ero onka Komputa le sunmo nomba gidi nikan. L'apapo won le s'oju fun awon inuakojopo (subset) awon nomba oniipin pato kan, nipa lilo nomba ojuami tonlefo (floating point) tabi nomba ojuami soso (fixed point), be sini awon nomba oniipin yi n je lilo lati sunmo awon iye gidi ti won sunmo won.Awon onimo isiro n lo ami R (tabi �{displaystyle mathbb {R} } tabi Unicode ℝ) lati se'duro fun akojopo gbogbo nomba gidi. Ami ikosile Rn n tokasi aaye elegbe-n pelu ipoidojuko (coordinate) gidi won. Fun apere awon iye R3 je nomba gidi meta ti won tokasi ipo kookan ninu aaye elegbe meta (3 dimension).A lé mú nomba gidí wa gégé bí àkótán àwon nomba oniìpín ni ònà tó jé pé ìtèntèle nomba kan se fẹsíwájú pèlú nombámèwa tàbí nombáméjì (binary) báyí {3, 3.1, 3.14, 3.141, 3.1415,...} f'enuko sí nomba pàtò gidí kan.E je ki R ki o duro fun akojopo gbogbo nomba gidi. Nitorie:Akojopo R je papa kan. Eyi tumosi pe a le se aropo ati isodipupo ninu re.Papa R je elesese. Eyi tumosi pe a ni apapo elesese ≥ to je pe, fun gbogbo nomba gidi x, y ati z:ti x ≥ y nitorie x + z ≥ y + z;ti x ≥ 0 ati y ≥ 0 nitorie xy ≥ 0.Eseese yi je akotan Dedekind. Eyi tumosi pe gbogbo abeikojopo S (subset) ti ki se ofo, fun R pelu ipari l'oke ninu R ni ipari l'oke tokerejulo (least upper bound or supremum) kan ninu R.Idamo to gbeyin yi lo seyato larin nomba gidi ati nomba oniipin. Fun apere akojopo awon nomba oniipin ti alagbarameji won din si 2 ni nomba oniipin ipari l'oke (apere 1.5) sugbon won ko ni nomba onipin ipari l'oke tokerejulo, nitoripe gbongbo alagbarameji 2 ko se pin.TitanIdi pataki ti a tun se seyato awon nomba gidi ni pe won ni gbogbo opin (limit). A le so pe won \\"\\"tan\\". Eyi tumosi bawonyi:Itelentele kan (xn) nomba gidi ni a n pe ni ìtẹ̀léntẹ̀lé Cauchy to je pe fun ε > 0, nomba odidi N kan wa to je pe ijinnasi (distance) |xn − xm| kere ju ε eyun to ba je pe n ati m tobi ju N lo. Ni ede mi, itelentele je itelentele Cauchy ti awon afida (element) xn re ba sunmo ara won gbagba.Itelentele (xn) foriko po si opin x to ba je pe fun ε > 0, nomba odidi N kan wa to je pe ijinnasi |xn − x| kere ju ε lo, to ba je pe n tobi ju N lo. Ni ede miran, itelentele kan ni opin x ti awon afida (element) re ba sunmo x gbagbagba.A ri bayi pe gbogbo itelentele ti o n foriko si oju kanna ni itelentele Cauchy.Gbogbo itelentele Cauchy fun nomba gidi je eyi to n foriko si oju kanna.Bayi wipe awon nomba gidi \\"tan\\".S'akiyesi pe awon nomba onipin ko lo tan o. Fun apere itelentele 1, 1.4, 1.41, 1.414, 1.4142, 1.41421, …) je ti Cauchy sugbon won ko foriko si nomba oniipin. (Eyi yatosi nomba gidi ti won foriko si gbongbo alagbarameji 2).Nitoripe awon opin wa fun awon itelentele Cauchy ni isiro Kalkulosi fi se e se, ti o si wulo. Ona kan ti a fi le sewadi boya itelentele kan ni opin ni ki a yewo boya o je itelentele Cauchy, nitoripe a ko le mo opin yi tele.Eyi fihan pe itelentele Cauchy ni o je. A ti mo bayi pe itenlentele ohun foriko si opin kan bi a ko ba ti e le so opin ibi ti o foriko si."},{"question":"கையொப்பம்     எனும் நூலை இயற்றியவர்?                                                                                                                            ","answer":"விடை : புவியரசு"},{"question":"கிராம்பினால் ஏற்படும் பயன்கள்  சிலவற்றை  எழுதுக .","answer":" பயன்கள்:  1. கிராம்பு மற்றும் உப்பை பசும்பாலில் அரைத்து அந்தப் பசையைத் தடவினால் தலைவலி பறந்துவிடும்.     தலையிலுள்ள நீரை உப்பு உறிஞ்சி எடுப்பதால் தலைபாரம் குறைந்து குணம் கிடைக்கிறது.2.  கண் இமைகளில் ஏற்படக்கூடிய அழற்சிகளை போக்க கிராம்பை நீரில் உரசி அந்த நீரைப்     பயன்படுத்தினால் குணம் கிடைக்கும்.3.  சமையலுக்கும், கறிகளுக்குச் சுவையூட்டவும், கறி மசாலா வகைகள் தயாரிக்கவும் கிராம்பு முக்கியம்.    வாசனைத் தயாரிப்பு, சோப்புத் தயாரிப்பிலும் இது பயன்படுகிறது."},{"question":"7 Ficil oo ay habboon tahay Inaad samayso mar walba ","answer":"Xanaaq waa dareen ka dhasha shucuur adag, waxuuna la xiriiraa waxyaabaha qaar ee sababa raaxo la’aan iyo in qofku uu caroodo, xanaaqu wuxuu ka mid yahay 6 da dareen ee aasaasiga ah sida farxad, xanaaq, la yaab, baqdin iyo karaahiyo.Xanaaqu waa dareen nagu dhiira geliya inaan noqono qofka iskaafiya, hasayeeshee mararka qaar waxaa jirta jawaab celin daran oo ka dhalata xanaaqa, taas oo uu qofku ka qoomameeyo marka ay shucuurtiisu degto, sidaa daraadeed waa muhiim in qofku uu is baro sida loo maareeyo jawaab celinta ka dhalata xanaaqa.1. Fasax qaado isla marka aad dareentid inaad xanaaqsantahay.Waxaad fasax ka qaadataa wax walba oo aad sameyneysid markaas, iyo wax walba oo kaa careyn kara si aad u dejisid dareenkaaga.Mar walbo xusuusnoow qasab ma ahan inaad ujawaabtid ama aad wax ka qabatid xaaladda markaas taagan kaqaado fursad aad ku nasatid oo aadna uga fekertid xaalada markaas taagan oo waxaad ku dhahdaa naftaada “Waxaan usoo laabanaa arintaan 10 daqiiqo kadib marka aan dego”Hadii aad xanaaqdid adigoo jooga goobta shaqada, usoo bax dibadda si aad uqaadatid neecaaw wanaagsan, hadii aad xanaaqdid adigoo jooga gurigaaga isku day inaad gashid qol kale oo aad ku nasatid amaba suuliga si aad uheshid jawi aad kaligaaga ku sugan tahay kadib na kafeker marxalada taagan.2. U ogolaaw naftaaada iney dareento xaanaqa.Xanaaqa waa dareen caadi ah oo dadka dhan ay dareemaan, sidaa darteed sii naftaada waqti yar ay ku dareento xanaaqa si aad u aqbashid xaalada kula soo gudboonaatay oo aadna horay uga sii socotid, marka aad horay uga dhaqaaqdid isku day ineysan kugu soo laaban dareenka xanaaqaas, kana dhaadhici naftaada inaad horay uga dhaqaaqday.3. Qaado neef qota dheer.Neefsasho qota dheer waa tilaabooyinka ugu muhiimsan ee la qaado si loo kordhiyo ogsijiinta dhiiga, sababtoo ah hadii ay siyaado ogsijiinta dhiiga waxaa siyaada geedi socodka maskaxda.Tiri ilaa saddex adigo jiidayya neefta, istaaji oo tiri ilaa saddex inta aadan soo bixin hawadaXaqiiji neefsadhadaas iney balaariso sambabada iyo calooshaadaSii wad neefsashada ilaa aad ka dareentid inaad degtay4. Is tusi muqaal wanaagsanHadii aad wali dareemeysid inaadan degin, qiyaas adigoo jooga meel muuqaal ku farxad geliya leh, kana feker iftiin keeda, neecaawdeeda iyo quruxdeeda, waa caadi hadii ay tahay muqaal aad aragtay caruur nimadaadii.5. Is bar inaad kula hadashid naftaada hadal wanaagsan.Bedel ku samee sida aad uga fekertid waxyaabaha qaar oo ah si xun, una bedel inaad uga fekertid si wanaagsantusaale ahaan bedel fikirka ku saabsan qofka kaa xanaajiyay xiligi aad gaariga waday oo ah “xayawaankaas wuu ijiiri gaaray maanta, gaariga ayuuna iga buusay”Ubedel “Miskiin kaas maanta wuu deg deg sanaa waxaana laga yaabaa inuu dhakhtarka kadaahsanaa, laakin alxamdulillah Eebe waa ibad baadiyay”6.Samee dhaqdhaqaaqa jirkaJimicsiga ayaa muhiimad wayn u leh caafimaad qabka jirka bani aadamka guud ahaan, dhaqdhaqaaq jirka oo la joogteeyo waxay xakameeysaa dareenada qaar uu xanaaqu ka mid yahay. Jimicsiyada ama dhaqdhaqaaqyada u wanaagsan xanaaqa waxaa kamid ah.Orodka, Kubadda cagta oo aad ciyaarto, Dabaasha, Kubadda kolayga oo aad ciyaarto, Jimicsiga misaanka, Jimicsiga feerka.7. Seexo hurdo kugu filan.Hurdada waa shey aasaasi u ah jirka, hadii laga tagana waxay sababtaa in dareemaha qofka ay khalkhalaan.Dadka weyn waxay ubaahan yihiin 7-8 saacadadood oo hurdo ah si caafimaad qabka jirka iyo maskax ay u noqoto mid sareeysa, hurdada oo nuqsaanta waxay qeyb"},{"question":"Berne moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Berne moy péeyu réwum Suisse"},{"question":"Ọkunrin kan lọọ hu oku olokuu l’Abẹokuta, nibi to ti n hu u lo ku si","answer":"Titi dasiko yii lawọn eeyan ṣi n sọ pe boya iku ojiji to pa ọkunrin yii lasiko to n hu oku olokuu niboji, n’Ibẹrẹkodo, l’Abẹokuta, yoo kọ awọn yooku rẹ to n ṣiṣẹ ibi ọhun lọgbọn.Ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, niṣẹlẹ yii waye niboji oku ti wọn maa n sin awọn Musulumi si, n’Ibẹrẹkodo, niluu Abẹokuta. Ọwọ oru lọkunrin ti ko sẹni to mọ orukọ rẹ naa ji lọ si saaree oku ọhun, o si ko awọn irinṣẹ ti yoo fi hu oku dani.Ṣugbọn nibi to ti n hu oku naa lọwọ ni wọn ni o ti ṣubu sinu saaree ọhun, bẹẹ ni ko le tẹsiwaju ninu iṣẹ to n ṣe naa mọ.Ẹjẹ tilẹ bẹrẹ si i jade lẹnu rẹ bi wọn ṣe wi, nigba tawọn alaboojuto si debẹ ni wọn ri i pe ẹni to waa hu oku olokuu ti ba oku nile, oun funra rẹ si ti dẹni to n ba ara ọrun ṣe.Nigba to n ba awọn akọroyin sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ yii, Imaamu agba Oke-Ọna, Alaaji Musiliu Nasir, ṣalaye pe kutu hai lawọn kan waa sọ foun pe ẹni kan waa hu oku nitẹ oku awọn Musulumi, n’Ibẹrẹkodo. Boya ori lo fẹẹ ge, boya gbogbo ara oku naa lo si fẹẹ di sapo ni, wọn ṣaa ni nibi to ti n ṣe e lọwọ lo ti ṣubu sinu saaree naa, o si ti ku patapata.Ọkunrin kan bayii to ni oun ko fẹẹ darukọ oun, ṣalaye fun ALAROYE pe itosi iboji naa ni ile oun wa, oun si maa n ri ohun to n ṣẹlẹ nibẹ daadaa.O ni ni nnkan bii aago meji aabọ oru ọjọ Sannde yii, oun kofiri ẹnikan niboji naa, ara si fu oun nigba toun ri i bo ṣe n ṣe. O ni ṣugbọn ẹru n ba oun, oun ko le jade loru naa. Afi bi ilẹ ṣe mọ tawọn ba oku ọkunrin kan to ki ori bọ saaree to n hu lọwọ, bẹẹ lawọn nnkan to fi n hu ori oku naa si wa lẹgbẹẹ rẹ nibẹ.Awọn ọlọpaa ni wọn waa gbe oku naa lọ bi wọn ṣe wi. Awọn irinṣẹ ti wọn si ni wọn ba lẹgbẹẹ ọkunrin naa ni ada, ọbẹ kan ti wọn lo mu gidi ati foonu rẹ to wa lapo rẹ nigba to ku iku ojiji naa."},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள்- செப்டம்பர் 11, 2001","answer":"அன்று அமெரிக்கா மீதான தாக்குதலுக்குப் பின்னர் ஒசாமா பின்லேடன் மற்றும் ஆப்கானிஸ்தானில் தலிபான்கள் வேட்டையாடப்பட்டபோது அல் ஜசீரா மேற்கில் பலரின் கவனத்திற்கு வந்தது. இது ஒசாமா பின்லேடன் மற்றும் தலிபான்களிடமிருந்து பெறப்பட்ட ஒளிப்படங்களை ஒளிபரப்பியது. சிலர் வலையமைப்பை பயங்கரவாதிகளுக்கு குரல் கொடுத்ததாக விமர்சித்தனர். அதிக அரபு பார்வையாளர்களைக் கொண்டிருப்பதால் அதற்கு ஒளிநாடாக்கள் வழங்கப்பட்டதாக நிறுவனம் கூறியது."},{"question":"મકર સંક્રાંતિ ઉત્સવ વિશે વિગતવાર જણાવો.","answer":"મકરસંક્રાંતિ એ ભારતનો કૃષક તહેવાર છે. ભારત અને એશિયાનાં અન્ય દેશોમાં પણ આ દિવસને પાકની લણણી સાથે જોડવામાં આવ્યો છે. સૂર્ય એક રાશીમાંથી બીજી રાશીમાં સ્થાનાંતર કરે તેને સંક્રાંતિ કહે છે. આ પ્રમાણે વર્ષમાં કુલ બાર સંક્રાંતિઓ થાય છે. પરંતુ સૂર્ય ધનુ રાશી માંથી મકર રાશીમાં સ્થાનાંતર કરે છે. ત્યારે મકરસંક્રાંતિ શરૂ થાય છે જે ૧૪ જાન્યુઆરીની આસપાસ નો સમય હોય છે. ઇ.સ.૨૦૧૬નાં જાન્યુવારી મહિનામાં ખગોળીય દૃષ્ટીએ મકરસંક્રાંતિ ૧૪ જાન્યુવારીના બદલે ૧૫ જાન્યવારીના દિવસે હતી. આ ના સમયે સૂર્ય પૃથ્‍વી આજુબાજુની પોતાની પરિભ્રમણ ની દિશામાં પણ પરિવર્તન કરી થોડોક ઉત્તર દિશા તરફ ખસે છે. આમ, સૂર્ય ઉત્તર તરફ ખસતો હોવાથી આ દિવસને ઉત્તરાયણ તરીકે ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. ઉત્તરાયણ નો પ્રારંભ ૨૧ થી ૨૨ ડીસેમ્બર થી થાય છે. મોટા ભાગ ના લોકો મકરસંક્રાંતિ અને ઉત્તરાયણ એકજ દિવસે હોય તેમ માને છે. લગભગ ૧૮૦૦ વર્ષ પહેલા મકરસંક્રાંતિ અને ઉત્તરાયણ એકજ સાથે થતી હતી, તેથી હાલ પણ લોકોમાં મકરસંક્રાંતિ અને ઉત્તરાયણ માટે ગેરસમજ હોય શકે છે. મકર સંક્રાતિને શુભ મુહુર્ત માનવામાં આવે છે, આથી મકર સંક્રાતિને આ શુભ સમયની શરૂઆત રૂપે ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. અલગ અલગ સંસ્કૃતિઓમાં આ ઉજવણી અલગ અલગ રીતે કરવામાં આવે છે. ભારત સરકાર દ્વારા મકર સંક્રાતિને પણ રાષ્ટ્રીય તહેવારોમાં ગણવામાં આવ્યો છે. પરંપરા અને અનુષ્ઠાનો: મકર સંક્રાતિએ જ્ઞાનની દેવી મા સરસ્વતીની પૂજા, આદર કરવાનો પણ તહેવાર છે. જીવનનાં લક્ષ્યો પુરા કરવાની ઇચ્છા રાખનાર માટે આ આદર્શ સમય મનાય છે. મકરસંક્રાંતિનો મહત્વપુર્ણ સમય, પરિવર્તનનો, જુનું તજી અને નવું અપનાવવાનો સમય છે. ગુજરાતમાં આ સમયે છડેલા ધાન્યની અને તલની મિઠાઇઓ, ખાધ પદાર્થો બનાવી અને દાન કરવામાં આવે છે. ગુજરાતમાં આ દિવસે ઘઉં, બાજરી કે જુવારને છડીને તેનો ખીચડો બનાવવામાં આવે છે, બહેન-દિકરી તથા અન્ય લોકોને ખીચડો ખવડાવવાથી પુણ્ય મળે છે તેવી માન્યતા ગુજરાતીઓમાં પ્રવર્તે છે આ ઉપરાંત ઘઉંની ધુધરી કરીને ગાયોને ખવડાવવામાં આવે છે. ભારતનાં અન્ય પ્રાંતોમાં આજનાં દિવસે માલિક પોતાનાં નોકરોને અન્ન,વસ્ત્ર અને ધન વગેરે સામગ્રી દાન-ભેટ સ્વરૂપે આપે છે.મકરસંક્રાંતિનાં પછીનાં દિવસે પશુ-પ્રાણીઓ,ખાસતો ગાયને પણ યાદ કરાય છે.નાની બાળાઓનાં હસ્તે પશુ,પક્ષી અને માછલીઓને ભોજન ખવડાવાય છે.આ દિવસે યાત્રા-પ્રવાસ કરવો અનુચિત મનાય છે,કારણકે આ દિવસ કુટુંબ-પરિવારનાં મિલન અને પરિવાર માટે સમર્પણનો છે.આ દિવસે ગુરુજનો પોતાનાં શિષ્યોને આશિષ આપે છે. ઉજવણી: મકરસંક્રાંતિ એ \\"આનંદ અને પતંગનો\\" તહેવાર છે. કરસંક્રાંતિ એ દિવસ છે જ્યારે તમામ ઉંમરનાં લોકો હ્રદયમાં ખુશી અનુભવતા, સુંદર વસ્ત્ર પરિધાન કરી અને વહેલી સવારથી જ પોતાના ઘરની છત અને અગાશીઓ પર ચઢી હર્ષ અને ઉલ્લાસભેર પતંગ ઉડાડવાનો આનંદ માણે છે. આખો દિવસ \\"કાપ્યો છે!\\" \\"એ કાટ્ટા!\\" \\"લપેટ લપેટ\\" જેવી વિવિધ કિકિયારીઓ સાંભળવા મળે છે. આકાશ ઇન્દ્રધનુષની માફક રંગબેરંગી પતંગો વડે છવાઇ જાય છે. ગુજરાતીઓ આ દિવસે તલ સાંકળી (તલ અને ગોળ માંથી બનાવેલી વાનગી) અને 'ચિકી' (એક મિઠાઇ) ખુબ ખાય અને ખવડાવે છે.ગુજરાત રાજ્ય તેની સાંસ્કૃતિક વિવિધતા અને તહેવારો માટે જાણીતું છે. આમ મકરસંક્રાંતિ એ બધા લોકો માટે મહત્વનાં તહેવારોમાંનો એક છે. આ એક હળીમળીને સંયુક્ત રીતે આનંદ માણવાનો તહેવાર છે. લોકો આખો દિવસ પોતાની પતંગ ઉડાડવાની કલાનું અન્ય ઉડતી પતંગોને કાપીને પ્રદર્શન કરે છે. રાત્રે પણ આ ક્રમ આનંદભેર ચાલતો રહે છે. શોખીનો રાત્રે કાળા અંધારા આકાશમાં સફેદ પતંગો અથવા પતંગ સાથે બાંધીને 'ફાનસ'(કાગળનો દિવો) ઉડાડે છે જેને અમદાવાદમાં 'ટુક્કલ' તરિકે ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. મકરસંક્રાંતિનો બીજો દિવસ 'વાસી ખીહર' તરીકે મનાવાય છે. આમ સતત બે દિવસ આ આનંદમય તહેવારની ઉજવણી ચાલે છે. પરંતુ આ વસ્તુની ખાસ નોંધ લેવી કે, મોટા ભાગે જ્યારે મકર સંક્રાંતિ ની વાત કરવામા આવે છે ત્યારે ઉત્તરાયણ તહેવારને સંબોધવામા છે."},{"question":"Àṣà Yorùbá","answer":"Àṣà Yorùbá jẹ́ ọ̀nà tí àwọn ẹ̀yà [Yorùbá] ń lò láti fi gbé èrò, ìmọ̀, àti ìṣe wọn kalẹ̀ tí ó sì bá àwùjọ wọn mu ọ́nà tí ó gun gẹ́gẹ́. Tàbí kí á sọ wípé Àṣà ni ohun gbogbo tó jẹ mọ́ ìgbé ayé àwọn ènìyàn kan, ní àdúgbò kan, bẹ̀rẹ̀ lórí èrò, èdè, ẹ̀sìn, ètò ìṣèlú, ètò ọrọ̀ ajé, ìsẹ̀dá ohun èlò, ìtàn, òfin, ìṣe, ìrísí, ìhùwàsí, iṣẹ́-ọnà, oúnjẹ, ọ̀nà ìṣe nǹkan, yíyí àyíká tàbí àdúgbò kọ̀ọ̀kan padà. Pàtàkì jùlọ ẹ̀sìn ìbílẹ̀, eré ìbílẹ̀, àti iṣẹ́ ìbílẹ̀. Gbogbo àwọn nǹkan wọ̀nyí ni wọ́n kó'ra jọ pọ̀ ń jẹ́ àṣà. [1] Bí a bá ń sọ̀rọ̀ nípa àṣà àti ìṣe Yorùbá, a ń sọ̀rọ̀ lórí àwọn ohun tí a ń mú enu bà ni ìhùwàsí àti ìrísí wa láàrín àwùjọ. Nínú ogún-lọ́gọ̀ àwọn àṣà àti ìṣe tí ó ń bẹ nílẹ̀ Yorùbá, ọ̀kan pàtàkì ni' Àṣà ìkíní nílẹ̀ Yorùbá. Èyí jẹ́ ohun tí gbogbo àwọn ẹ̀yà tí ó kú ní agbáyé fi ma ń ṣàdáyanrí ọmọ káàrọ̀-o kò-jíire bí tòótọ́ ní gbogbo ayé tí wọ́n bá dé.Àṣà ìkíni jẹ́ àṣà tí ó gbajúgbajà nílẹ̀ Yorùbá, àṣà yí sì ní í ṣe pẹ̀lú ìgbà àti àkókò. Ó ní í ṣe pẹ̀lú ohun tí ó ń sẹlẹ̀ ní déédé àsìkò náà. Bí Yorùbá bá jí láàárọ̀, ọmọdé tí ó bá jẹ́ ọkùnrin, yóò wà lórí ìdọ̀bálẹ̀, nígbà tí èyí tí ó bá jẹ́ obìnrin yóò wà lórí ìkúnlẹ̀, wọn a sì kí àwọn òbí wọn tàbí ẹni tí ó bá ti jùwọ́n lọ ní gbogbo ọ̀nàNílẹ̀ Yorùbá, gbogbo àsìkò ni ó ní ìkíni tirẹ̀, ṣùgbọ́n ọmọdé ni ó kọ́kọ́ máa ń kí àgbà. Èyí tí kò bá ṣe bẹ́ẹ̀, ìgbàgbọ́ Yorùbá ní wí pé irú ọmọ bẹ́ẹ̀ kò ní ẹ̀kọ́ tàbí, wọ́n kọ́ ọ ní'lé, kò gbà ni. Bí ó bá jẹ́ ìgbà ayẹ̣yẹ bíi ìsìnkú àgbà, nítorí Yorùbá kì í ṣe òkú ọ̀dọ́, ẹhìnkùnlé ni wọ́n máa ń sin òkú ọ̀dọ́ sí. Ìgbàgbọ́ wọn ni pé, òfò ni ó jẹ́ fún àwọn òbí irú ẹni bẹ́ẹ̀. Wàyí, bí ó bá jẹ́ òkú àgbà, wọn á ní, \\"Ẹ kú ọ̀fọ̀, ẹ kú ìsìnkú, Olórun yóò mú ọjọ́ jìnnà sí'ra o.\\" Bí ó bá jẹ́ ayẹyẹ Ìkómojáde/Ìsọmọlórúkọ, wọn á ní, \\"Ẹ kú ọwọ́lómi o.\\" Bákan náà, oríṣiríṣì àkókò ni ó wà nínú odún. Àkókó òfìnkìn, Àkókò ọyẹ́, Àkókò oòrùn (Summer), Àkókò òjò, gbogbo wọ̀nyí sì ni àwọn Yorùbá ní bí a ṣe ń kí'ni fún. Ẹ jẹ́ kí á gbẹ́ àṣà ìsìnkú yẹ̀wò.Gẹ́gẹ́ bí a ti sọ ṣáájú wípé ó ní àwọn òkú tí Yorùbá máa ń ṣe ayẹyẹ fún, àwọn bíi òkú àgbà, nítorí wọ́n gbà wí pé, olóògbé lọ sinmi ni, àti wí pé, wọ́n lọ'lé. Yorùbá gbàgbọ́ pé, ọjà ni ayé, ṣùgbọ́n ọ̀run ni ilé.Bí ó bá jẹ́ òkú ọ̀dọ́ tàbí ọmọdé, òkú ọ̀fọ̀ àti ìbànújẹ́ ló jẹ́. Wọ́n á gbà wí pé, àsìkò rẹ̀ kò tíì tó. Yorùbá máa ń ná owó àti ara sí ìsìnkú àgbà, pàápàá bí olóògbé náà bá jẹ́ ẹni tí ó ní ipò àti ọlá nígbà tí ó wà láyé, tí ó sì tún bí ọmọ. Ìsìnkú àwọn wọ̀nyí máa ń lárinrin, ayé á gbọ́, òrun á sì tún mọ̀ pẹ̀lú.Ní ayé àtijọ́, bí aláwo bá kú, àwọn àwọn Olúwo ní ń sìnkú irú ẹni bẹ́ẹ̀. Wọn á pa adìyẹ ìrànà, wọn á sì máa tu ìyẹ́ rẹ bí wọ́n ṣe ń gbé òkú rẹ̀ lọ. Lẹ́yìn tí wọn bá sin òkú tán, àwọn aláwo náà á sun adìye náà jẹ. Ìdí rèé tí Yoòbá fi máa ń sọ wí pè, \\"Adìyẹ ìrànà kì í ṣ'ọhun à jẹ gbé.\\" Nítorí pé, kò sí ẹni tí kò ní kú.Ọ̀fọ̀ ni ó máa ń jẹ́ tí ìyàwó ilé bá sáájú ọkọ rẹ̀ kú. Yorùbá gbàgbọ́ pé, ọkọ ló máa ń sáájú aya rẹ̀ kú, kí ìyàwó máa bójú tó àwọn ọmọ. Fún ìdí èyí, bí okùnrin bá kú, àwọn ìyàwó irú ẹni bẹ́ẹ̀ máa ṣe opó pẹ̀lú ìlànà àti àṣà Yorùbá. Ogójì ọjọ́ tàbí jù bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ ni wọ́n máa ń fi ṣe opó. Lẹ́yìn ìsìnkú, àwọn àgbà ilé ni wọ́n máa pín ogún olóògbé fún àwọn ọmọ rẹ̀, bí ó bá jẹ́ òkú olọ́mọ. Àmọ́ tí kò bá bí’mọ, àwọn ẹbí rẹ̀, ní pátàkì jùlọ, àwọn ọmọ ìyá rẹ̀ tí ó jù ú lọ ní wọ́n máa pín ogún náà láàárín ara wọn. Ó tún jẹ́ àṣà Yorùbá òmíì kí wọn máa ṣú opó olóògbé fún àwọn àbúrò rẹ̀, láti fi ṣe aya.Ohun tí ó jẹ́ orírun àṣà ni ‘àrà’, ó lè dára tàbí kí ó burú. Ìpolówó Èkìtì – iyán rere, ọbẹ̀ rere; Ìpolówó Oǹdó Ẹ̀gi – (dípò Iyán) ẹ̀bà gbọn fẹẹ. Àṣà Oǹdó ni kí wọ́n máa pe iyán ní ẹ̀bà, nítorí pé èèwọ̀ wọn ni, wọn kò gbọdọ̀ polówó iyán ní àárín ìlú.Àṣà jẹ mọ́ ìgbàgbọ́, bí àpẹẹrẹ; Olódùmarè,àbíkú, àkúdàáyà, iṣẹ́-ọnà tí a lè fojú rí tàbí fẹnu sọ.A lè pín àṣà sí ìsọ̀rí mẹ́ta, èyí tí ó jẹ mọ́:(a) Ọgbọ́n ìmọ̀, ète, tàbí ètò tí à ń gbà ṣe nǹkan. Bí àpẹẹrẹ:Ilà kíkọ,Irun dídì, àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ.(b) Iṣẹ́-ọnà. Àpẹẹrẹ:Igi gbígbẹ́,Igbá fínfínIlé kíkọ́Ẹní híhunAra dídá /fínfín àti bẹ̀ẹ́ bẹ̀ẹ́ lọ.(d) Bí a ṣe ń darí ìhùwàsí àwọn ẹgbẹ́ tàbí ẹ̀yà kan.Lára àbùdá àṣà ni pé:(a) Kò lè è súyọ láìsí ènìyàn, ìdí ni wípé ẹ̀mí àṣà gùn ju ti ènìyàn lọ.(b) Ó jẹ mọ́ ohun tí a lè fojú rí;(d) Àṣà kọ̀ọ̀kan ló ní ìdí kan pàtó.ÀLÀYÉ NÍPA ÀṢÀ(a) Àṣà lè jẹyọ nínú oúnjẹ: Òkèlè wọ́pọ̀ nínú oúnjẹ wa. Àkókó kúndùn ẹ̀bà, Ìlàjẹ fẹ́ràn púpurú,Igbó ọrà kìí sì í fi láfún òṣèré.(b) Àṣà lè jẹyọ nínú ìtọ́jú oyún, aláìsà,òkú; ètò ẹbí, àjọṣepọ̀; ètò ìṣàkóso àdúgbò, abúlé tàbí ara dídá nípa iṣẹ́-ọnà.AÁYẸ TÍ Ó DE BÁ ÀṢÀBí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé àṣà máa ń yí padà nípa aṣo wíwọ̀, ìgbéyàwó, àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ, lóde-òní, ètò ẹ̀kọ́ àti ìwà ọ̀làjú tó gbòde kan ti ṣe àkóbá fún àṣà ní àwọn ọ̀nà wọ̀nyí:(a) Ìwọsọ wa kò bójú mu mọ́.(b) Àṣà ìkíni wa kò ní ọ̀wọ̀ nínú mọ́.(d) Kí’yàwó ilé má mọ oúnjẹ ìbílẹ̀ ṣè mọ́.(e) A kò mọ ìtumọ̀ àrokò tí a ń kọ́ àwọn ọmọ wa mọ́.(ẹ) A kò fi èdè abínibí wa kọ́ àwọn ọmọ wa mọ́.ÀWỌN Ọ̀NÀ TÍ ÀṢÀ MÁA Ń GBÀ YÍPADÀ(a) Bí àṣà tó wà nílẹ̀ bá lágbára ju èyí tó jẹ́ tuntun lọ, èyí tó wà tẹ́lẹ̀ yóò borí tuntun. Bí àpẹẹrẹ, aṣọ wíwọ̀.(b) Àyípadà lè wáyé bí àṣà tó wà nílẹ̀ tẹ́lẹ̀ bá dógba pẹ̀lú àṣà tuntun, wọ́n lè jọ rìn pọ̀. Bí àpẹẹrẹ, àṣà ìgbéyàwó.(d) Bí àṣà tuntun bá lágbára ju èyí tó wà nílẹ̀ tẹ́lẹ̀, yóò sọ àṣà ti àtẹ̀hìnwá di ohun ìgbàgbé. Bí àpẹẹrẹ, bí a ṣe ń kọ́'lé.Tí a bá wá wò ó fínnífínní, à á ri wí pé, àṣà, lọ́pọ̀lọpọ̀ ìgbà máa ń dá lé:(a) Ìmọ̀ ìṣe sáyẹ́ǹsì(b) Ìṣe jẹun wa(d) Ìsọwọ́ kọ́lé(e) Iṣẹ́ ọwọ́ ní síṣeÀKÍYÈSI:Èdè àwọn ènìyàn jẹ́ kókó kan pàtàkì nínú àṣà wọn. Kò sí ẹ̀gbọ́n tàbí àbúrò nínú àṣà àti èdè. Ìbejì ni wọ́n. Ọjọ́ kan náà ni wọ́n délé ayé nítorí pé kò sí ohun tí a fẹ́ sọ nípa àṣà, tí kì í ṣe pé èdè ni a ó fi gbé e kalẹ̀. Láti ara èdè pàápàá ni a ti lè fa àṣà yọ. A lè fi èdè Yorùbá sọ ohun tó wà lọ́kàn ẹni, a lè fi kọrin, a lè fi kéwì, a lè fi jọ́sìn, àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ. Láti ara àwọn nǹkan tí à ń sọ jáde lẹ́nu wọ̀nyí ni àṣà wa ti ń jẹyọ. Ara èdè Yorùbá náà ni òwe àti àwọn àkànlò-èdè gbogbo wà. A lè fa púpọ̀ nínú àwọn àṣà wa yọ láti ara òwe àti àkànlò èdè.Nítorí náà, èdè ni ó jẹ́ òpómúléró fún àṣà Yorùbá. Àti wí pé, òun ni ó fà á tí ó fi jẹ́ pé, bí àwọn ọmọ Odùduwà ṣe tàn kálẹ̀, orílẹ̀-èdè kan ni wọ́n, èdè kan náà ni wọ́n ń sọ níbikíbi tí wọ́n lè wà. Ìṣesí, ìhùwàsí, àṣà àti ẹ̀sìn wọn kò yàtọ̀. Fún ìdí èyí, láìsí ènìyàn, kò le è sí àṣà rárá.àsà jẹ́ nnkan gbòógì fún ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ èdè ṣùgbọ́n àwọn yorùbá mu ní ọ̀kúnkúndùn kí gbogbo wa sì gbe lárugẹ"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai anjing melintang denai\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya ialah seseorang yang sombong (gembira)."},{"question":"सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल.","answer":"मुख्यपृष्ठव्यक्तीSardar Vallabhbhai Patel essay in Marathi | सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल.Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel essay in Marathi | सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल.Hostशनिवार, सप्टेंबर १२, २०२०नमस्कार मित्रांनो आज आम्ही सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल ह्या विषयावर मराठी निबंध घेऊन आले आहोत. सरदार वल्लभाई पटेल या मराठी निबंध मध्ये आम्ही वल्लभभाई पटेल यांच्या जीवन कार्याचे वर्णन केले आहे, आणि कसे त्यांना सरदार ही उपाधी मिळाली ह्याचे वर्णन केले आहे. चला मित्रांनो निबंधाला सुरुवात करूया.Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Marathi essay Imageसरदार वल्लभाई पटेल.सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल भारतीय राष्ट्रीय काँग्रेसचे एक वरिष्ठ नेता होते आणि भारतीय गणराज्य स्थापन करणाऱ्या मधून एक होते. वल्लभभाई झावेरभाई पटेल यांचा जन्म ३१ ऑक्टोंबर १८७५ मदे नाडियाद, गुजरात मध्ये झाला होता. त्यांच्या वडिलांचे नाव झावेरभाई आणि आईचे नाव लाढबाई होते.वल्लभभाई पटेल यांचे वडील झावेरभाई हे एक शेतकरी होते त्यांनी भारतीय स्वातंत्र्याच्या पहिल्या युद्धामध्ये झाशी च्या राणी च्या सेनेमध्ये कार्य केले होते. सरदार पटेल ने आपले सुरुवातीचे शिक्षण आपल्या स्थानिक शाळेमधून आपल्या वडिलांबरोबर शेतीचे काम करत पूर्ण केले होते. सरदार पटेल लहानपणापासूनच एक बुद्धिमान, सहाशी आणि दृढ संकल्प ठेवणारे माणूस होते. ते नेहमी अन्यायाविरुद्ध आवाज उठवत असे. ह्याच गुणांमुळे त्यांना वकील बनायचे होते.पैशांची कमी असूनही सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल यांनी आपल्या मित्रांकडून पुस्तके मागून वकिलीचा अभ्यास केला आणि जिल्हा वकिलीची परीक्षा ते पास झाले. त्यांनी गोधरा, गुजरात मध्ये आपली वकिली करायला सुरुवात केली. १९०२ मध्ये ते वलसाड येथे आले आणि जिल्हा मुख्यालय मध्ये यशस्वीपणे आठ वर्ष गुन्हेगारीवर वकिली केली जेणेकरून त्यांनी आपल्या परिवाराला आर्थिक रुपाने स्थिर केले.पैशांची कमी दूर केल्यानंतर त्यांनी झवेरबा यांच्याशी लग्न केले, त्यांना दोन मुले होती. सन १९१० मध्ये उच्च शिक्षण प्राप्त करण्यासाठी ते लंडनला गेले आणि तिथे परीक्षांमध्ये प्रथम आले. मग ते भारतात परतल्यावर अहमदाबाद येथे वकिली करू लागले.जेव्हा सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल १९१७ मध्ये महात्मा गांधीजींना भेटले तेव्हा त्यांचे जीवन पूर्णपणे बदलून गेले जेव्हा त्यांनी गांधीजींचे स्वतंत्र भारताचे स्वप्न आणि अहिंसा चे तत्त्वज्ञान बघितले. सन १९१८ मध्ये गुजरातच्या खेडा येथे भयंकर दुष्काळ पडला होता. म्हणून शेतकऱ्यांनी इंग्रज सरकारला कर माफी करण्याचे निवेदन केले पण इंग्रज सरकारने ते नकारले. तेव्हा सरदार पटेल यांनी शेतकऱ्यांचे नेतृत्व केले आणि शेतकऱ्यांना कर नाही देण्यास सांगितले. सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल यांच्यासमोर इंग्रज सरकारला माघार घ्यायला लागली आणि कर माफ करावा लागला, हे सरदार पटेल चे पहिले मोठे यश होते.बार्डोली सत्याग्रह च्या निमित्ताने सन १९२८ मध्ये गुजरात मध्ये एक प्रमुख किसान आंदोलन झाले होते, ज्याचे नेतृत्व स्वतः सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल यांनी केले होते. या आंदोलनापुढे इंग्रज सरकारला माघार घ्यायला पडला होता आणि सरदार पटेल मुळे शेतकऱ्यांचा विजय झाला होता. या सत्याग्रहाच्या यशानंतर लोकांनी वल्लभाई पटेल यांना \\"सरदार\\" ही उपाधी दिली होती, ज्याचा अर्थ आपला मुख्य किंवा आपला राजा असा होतो. तेव्हापासून त्यांना सरदार वल्लभाई पटेल या नावाने ओळखले जाऊ लागले.सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल ने खूप सारे इंग्रज सरकारच्या विरोधात आंदोलने केली. १९४२ मध्ये महात्मा गांधीजींच्या भारत छोडो आंदोलन मध्ये सरदार पटेल ने आपले पूर्ण सहकार्य केले होते. त्यांना याच कारणामुळे तुरुंगामध्ये सुद्धा झाला लागले होते.स्वातंत्र्याच्या आधी भारता ५८४ राज्यांमध्ये वाटला गेला होता. सरदार पटेल ने या राज्यांना एकत्रित आणल्यावर ती जोर दिला होता आणि सर्व राज्यांना इंग्रज सरकार विरुद्ध होण्यास सांगितले होते. ते पूर्ण देशाला एक करण्याच्या प्रयत्नांमध्ये होते. त्यांना Iron Man of India \\"पोलादी पुरुष\\" ही उपाधी दिली होती कारण भारतात चे राज्य आपण आज बघतो ते आज सरदार पटेल मुळेच आहेत.१९४७ मध्ये स्वतंत्र भारताचे ते पहिले उपप्रधानमंत्री आणि गृहमंत्री बनले. त्यांनी IAS आणि IPS ची स्थापना करण्यामध्ये सहाय्य केले होते म्हणून त्यांना भारतीय सेवेचा संरक्षक संत असेही सांगितले जाते. १५ डिसेंबर १९५० मध्ये हृदय विकाराच्या झटक्याने त्यांचा मृत्यू झाला. त्यांच्या अंतिम संस्कारासाठी दहा लाखापेक्षा जास्त लोक आले होते. त्यांना त्यांच्या कार्यामुळे \\"भारतरत्न\\" हा पुरस्कार देण्यात आला होता. भारतात खूप सारे महाविद्यालय आणि संस्था त्यांच्या नावाने उघडण्यात आल्या आहेत. गुजरात मध्ये सरदार सरोवर बांध आहे, जो नर्मदा नदीवर स्थित आहे तिथे सरदार पटेल यांचा विश्वा मध्ये सर्वात उंच पुतळा बांधण्यात आला आहे, \\"स्टॅच्यू ऑफ युनिटी\\" या नावाने तो प्रसिद्ध आहे. सरदार वल्लभाई पटेल यांचा जन्मदिवस \\"राष्ट्रीय एकता दिवस\\" ह्या रूपाने साजरा केला जातो."},{"question":"Sikap Abu yang menganiaya Zubaidah yang telah membantunya diibaratkan sebagai _____","answer":"Bagai melepaskan anjing tersepit"},{"question":"Σε ποιο σημαντικό γεγονός αναφέρεται το κείμενο: Στις 18 Νοεμβρίου 1940, κατά τη διάρκεια του Ελληνο-ιταλικού πολέμου (1940) και κατά την εκτέλεση διατεταγμένης αποστολής περιπολίας με α/φ PZL P.24 της Μοίρας Διώξεως, ενεπλάκη σε αερομαχία με ιταλικά αεροπλάνα διώξεως στην περιοχή Ιβάν Αλβανίας, Β.Α της Κορυτσάς.","answer":"Αερομαχία κατά την διάρκεια του Ελληνο-ιταλικού πολέμου."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Ketinggian orang kerdil.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah pendek. "},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"இல்வாழ்க்கை என்பது ஓர் ஆண், ஒரு பெண், இருவரும் சமநிலையில் இருந்து சமமாக அனுபவிப்பதாகும்."},{"question":"¿Qué es Pi, un número racional o irracional?","answer":"El número Pi es irracional, por cuanto su parte decimal es infinita y no periódica. Su valor aproximado es de 3,1416 y es la razón entre el perímetro de una circunferencia y su diámetro."},{"question":"පහත පද පෙරළි වලට කෙලිනම් විසඳුම දෙන්න. තාන්කාරය ","answer":"කාන්තාරය"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air diminum sembiluan\\"?","answer":"Kesedihan yang menyebabkan tidak enak makan dan minum"},{"question":"Waa maxay Biology? ","answer":"Biology waa cilmiga barashada noolaha iyo xiriirka uu la lee yhy deegaanka. waa cilmi ballaaran kaas oo fallanqeeya qaab dhismeedka, shaqada, koriinshaha iyo dhaqamada noolayaasha."},{"question":"ताराको जिवनकालको अन्त्यतिरको अवस्थालाई के भनिन्छ ?","answer":"न्यूट्रन स्टार"},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn, Phó Giám đốc Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên – Huế, Thủ trưởng Cơ quan Cảnh sát điều tra Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên - Huế, cho biết lực lượng công an đã vận động thành công nghi phạm dùng súng cướp tiệm vàng ở chợ Đông Ba (TP Huế) ra đầu thú vào lúc 14 giờ ngày 31-7. Nghi phạm có tên là Quốc, có sử dụng súng AK sau khi nổ súng cướp tiệm vàng ở đường Trần Hưng Đạo trước chợ Đông Ba (TP Huế) thì đã ôm súng chạy xuống cố thủ dưới gầm cầu Gia Hội. Sau đó, đối tượng này di chuyển vào trốn ở khu vực nhà lục giác tại công viên Trịnh Công Sơn ở phường Gia Hội, TP Huế cách cầu Gia Hội vài trăm mét. Khi bị lực lượng bố ráp, truy bắt, đối tượng Quốc đã xin được gặp riêng Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn để trình bày. Ngay lập tức, Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn đã vào nói chuyện, động viên và đối tượng này đã buông súng ra đầu thú.","answer":"\\"Phó Giám đốc Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên – Huế Tiết Lộ Chi Tiết Vụ Bắt Nghi Phạm Cướp Tiệm Vàng tại Chợ Đông Ba\\""},{"question":"Lễ khai ấn chính thức bắt đầu vào khung giờ nào?","answer":"Vào giờ Tý (khoảng 23h) ngày 14 tháng Giêng, lễ khai ấn được bắt đầu với nghi thức rước hòm ấn từ nội cung đền Cố Trạch sang đền Thiên Trường. Sau khi lễ khai ấn được thực hiện bởi 14 cụ cao niên thôn Tức Mặc (phường Lộc Vượng) kết thúc, khách thập phương vào đền Thiên Trường để tế lễ, xin lá ấn với mong muốn một năm mới thành đạt và phát tài. Trước nghi lễ khai ấn, chương trình lễ hội diễn ra từ ngày 11 tháng Giêng với lễ rước Kiệu Ngọc Lộ cùng các nghi lễ tại chùa Phổ Minh, đền Thiên Trường. Ngày 12 tháng Giêng là lễ rước Nước, tế Cá từ đền Cố Trạch về đền Thiên Trường."},{"question":"தேனை உட்கொள்ளும்போது கவனிக்க வேண்டிய விஷயங்கள் என்னென்ன?","answer":"1. தேனை சூடான உணவு பொருட்களுடன் கலக்கக் கூடாது.2. தேனை சூடாக்குவதை தவிர்க்க வேண்டும்.3. வெப்ப நிலை அதிகமாக உள்ள இடங்களில் வேலை செய்பவர்கள் தேன் உட்கொள்வதை தவிர்க்க வேண்டும்.4. தேனை மழை நீர், கடுகு, நெய் மற்றும் காரமான உணவு வகைகளுடன் ஒருபோதும் கலக்கக் கூடாது.தேன் பல மலர்களின் மதுரம் கலந்த ஒரு கலவையே. அதில் நச்சு தன்மை வாய்ந்த மலர்களும் அடங்கும். நஞ்சு பொதுவாக கார மற்றும் உஷ்ண குணங்களையே கொண்டிருக்கும். ஆகவே தேனை கார மற்றும் சூடான உணவு பொருட்களுடன் கலக்கும் போது இந்த நச்சு தன்மைகள் மேலோங்கும் சாத்தியக்கூறு உள்ளது.தேனில் விட்டமின் பி1, பி2, பி3, பி5, பி6, சி, இ முதலிய வைட்டமின்களும் மற்றும் அயோடின், கால்சியம், கந்தகம், இரும்பு, சோடியம், மெக்னீசியம், தாமிரம், குளோரின், பொட்டாசியம், சுண்ணாம்புச்சத்து, பாஸ்பரஸ், உப்பு, குளுகோஸ், லெவுகோஸ், லாக்டிக் அமிலம், டார்டாரிக் ஆஸிட், சிட்ரிக் அமிலம், க்ளாரிக் அமிலம் போன்ற இதர வகையான சத்துப்பொருள்களும் உள்ளன. இவையாவும் நம் உடல் வளர்ச்சிக்குத் தேவை. தேன், பிறந்த குழந்தைகள், கர்ப்பிணிப் பெண்கள், பாலூட்டும் தாய்மார்கள், முதியவர்கள், விளையாட்டு வீரர்கள், நோயுற்றவர்கள் என அனைவருக்கும் ஏற்ற இயற்கை உணவுதான். இருப்பினும் பலர் தேனைப் பற்றி பல வதந்திகளைப் பரப்புவது முற்றிலும் அறியாமையே."},{"question":"Inona ny firenena tokana nanana sainam-pirenena misy loko tokana ihany ? ","answer":"Ny firenena Libya no hany nanana sainam-pirenena amin'ny loko tokana, izay niloko maitso. "},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Quanh vụ việc một công ty tổ chức Team Building ở bãi biển Cửa Lò \\"sung quá\\" để chị em cởi áo lót làm phương tiện lấy nước, hiện vẫn chưa hạ nhiệt trong dư luận. Có rất nhiều nội dung tranh luận khiến các diễn đàn mạng nảy lửa, số đông cư dân mạng vẫn thấy \\"ấm ức\\" khi mức phạt hành chính còn thấp, chưa đủ sức nặng răn đe. Nhiều tài khoản vẫn miệt mài chia sẻ đoạn video quay được ở bãi biển Cửa Lò khi trò chơi \\"lấy nước\\" đang diễn ra. Video được chia sẻ đến đâu, số đông nhiệt tình để lại bình luận đến đó. Tâm điểm của những cuộc bàn luận, tranh cãi là về những phụ nữ (được so sánh với rất nhiều hình ảnh khác nhau như: đuông dừa, mướp, bụng ngấn...). Không ai để lại bất kỳ lời bình luận nào về việc những người đã lén quay video, phát tán video đó, có nên bị xử phạt hay không? Nếu việc những phụ nữ để ngực trần bị cho là phản cảm nơi công cộng thì việc ghi hình lại một hành động phản cảm, và phát tán video phản cảm lên mạng xã hội, chẳng lẽ lại vô tội? Tiến sĩ về văn hóa - biên kịch Đặng Thiếu Ngân bày tỏ quan điểm: \\"Tôi cảm giác nhiều người đang cảm thấy rất hả hê với vụ việc xảy ra ở bãi biển Cửa Lò. Họ đua nhau bình luận khiếm nhã về hình thể phụ nữ. Đọc nhiều lời bình luận, tôi thấy sợ. Ví như có người nói, con gái 20 cởi thì được, còn hình ảnh ở video chỉ là \\"mướp\\", \\"đuông dừa\\"... Không chỉ đàn ông, rất nhiều phụ nữ cũng thể hiện sự hả hê với sự việc. Tôi không lý giải được\\". Biên kịch Đặng Thiếu Ngân đặt câu hỏi về vấn đề bình đẳng giới: \\"Đàn ông cởi trần - đâu phải ai cũng đẹp? Nhưng họ không bị chỉ trích, không bị miệt thị ngoại hình, không bị xúc phạm. Trong khi, phụ nữ để ngực trần, đang phải hứng chịu sự phản ứng theo tôi là \\"khủng khiếp\\" của cộng đồng mạng. Ở nhiều bãi tắm công cộng, hình ảnh đàn ông diện đồ bơi không đẹp, xộc xệch vẫn có,  nhưng không ai chỉ trích, chê bai? Vậy tại sao lại được phép bình phẩm về hình thể của phụ nữ, nhất là trong tình trạng họ để lộ thân thể ở hoàn cảnh không phải vì mục đích khoe vẻ đẹp thân thể? Tôi nghĩ, họ không đáng phải chịu sự phán xét của dư luận chỉ vì hình thể xấu\\". Trao đổi với Lao Động, Tiến sĩ - Biên kịch Đặng Thiếu Ngân nói: \\"Trên bãi biển không hề có biển cấm ghi dòng chữ \\"cấm cởi trần\\", \\"cấm phụ nữ để ngực trần\\". Họ cũng đã xin lỗi và chịu án phạt. Vậy những người đã đứng xem, quay lại hình ảnh họ, ngang nhiên đăng hình ảnh họ lên mạng xã hội để chê cười, miệt thị, xúc phạm ngoại hình... thì không một ai phán xét, hay bị đặt vấn đề xử phạt. Tại sao lại như vậy? Nếu ai đó thấy những phụ nữ ấy phản cảm, có thể lại nhắc nhở họ, thậm chí có thể báo bảo vệ nhắc nhở. Lỗi của những người phụ nữ ấy tôi không bàn thêm, nhưng họ không đáng bị bêu riếu, xúc phạm dữ dội như vậy\\". Việc số đông cộng đồng mạng cùng xúc phạm, miệt thị ngoại hình những phụ nữ, còn có dấu hiệu của việc \\"làm nhục người khác\\". Về luật, tội làm nhục người khác còn có thể bị phạt tù theo Điều 121 Bộ luật Hình sự 1999. Tuy nhiên, Tiến sĩ Văn hóa – biên kịch Đặng Thiếu Ngân cho rằng: \\"Sự việc càng trở nên đáng sợ khi cộng đồng mạng vừa đông đảo, vừa hung hãn, lại vừa ẩn danh, không lộ diện\\". Khi xảy ra một sự vụ, hiệu ứng đám đông được lan truyền rất nhanh. Chỉ đến khi, người bị bêu rếu, miệt thị trên khắp mạng xã hội là em gái, chị gái... hay bất kỳ người thân nào của chúng ta, chúng ta mới thấm thía được hết, sự \\"khủng khiếp\\" của mặt trái trên mạng xã hội.","answer":"Quay và phát tán video vụ \\"ngực trần\\" ở Cửa Lò có đáng bị xử phạt?"},{"question":"-Jereo ity fanambarana ity :« Tsy zakako ny olona amin’io finoana io. Manakorontana fiarahamonina ireo.Misarona fankahalana ve izany fanambarana izany ?","answer":"Eny, mankahala olona manana finoana na tsy mitovy finoana aminao izany."},{"question":"Lê Đại Hành là vua đầu tiên của Việt Nam thực hiện nghi lễ nào?","answer":"Lê Đại Hành rất coi trọng phát triển nông nghiệp. Năm 987, vua tổ chức cày tịch điền để làm gương, khuyến khích nhân dân chăm lo sản xuất nông nghiệp. Đại Việt sử ký toàn thư ghi: \\"Đinh Hợi, mùa xuân, vua bắt đầu cày ruộng tịch điền ở núi Đọi, được một chĩnh nhỏ vàng, lại cày ở núi Bàn Hải, được một chĩnh nhỏ bạc, vì thế đặt tên ruộng là Kim Ngân\\".Sách Lịch sử Việt Nam khẳng định Lê Đại Hành là vua đầu tiên mở đầu cho một nghi lễ \\"tịch điền\\". Các vương triều sau đã tiếp tục noi theo để khuyến khích phát triển sản xuất nông nghiệp.Ngoài ra, ông còn quan tâm phát triển thủ công nghiệp và thương nghiệp, chú trọng tổ chức quân đội."},{"question":"அட்டிலா பற்றி கூறவும்","answer":"அட்டிலா என்பவர் ஊணர்களின் ஆட்சியாளராக 434 முதல் 453 வரை திகழ்ந்தவர் ஆவார். இவர் பொதுவாக ஊணன் அட்டிலா என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். நடு மற்றும் கிழக்கு ஐரோப்பாவில் ஊணர்கள், ஆசுத்திரகோத்துகள், ஆலன்கள், பல்கர்கள், மற்றும் பிறரை உள்ளடக்கிய ஒரு பழங்குடியினப் பேரரசின் தலைவனாகத் திகழ்ந்தார். உலக வரலாற்றின் மிக சக்திவாய்ந்த ஆட்சியாளர்களில் ஒருவராகக் கருதப்படுகிறார்.இவரது ஆட்சியின் போது, மேற்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு உரோமைப் பேரரசுகளுக்கு மிகுந்த அச்சத்தை ஏற்படுத்திய எதிரிகளில் ஒருவராகத் திகழ்ந்தார். இவர் தன்யூபு ஆற்றை இரு முறை கடந்தார். பால்கன் குடாவைச் சூறையாடினார். ஆனால் கான்ஸ்டண்டினோபிலை இவரால் கைப்பற்ற இயலவில்லை. இவரது பாரசீகப் படையெடுப்பு தோல்வியில் முடிந்தது. 441ஆம் ஆண்டில் கிழக்கு உரோமைப் (பைசாந்தியப்) பேரரசு மீது படையெடுத்தார். அதில் வெற்றி கண்டார். இவ்வெற்றியால் மேற்கு உரோமைப் பேரரசின் மீது படையெடுக்கும் துணிவைப் பெற்றார். அக்காலத்தில் உரோமானியக் கௌல் என்று அழைக்கப்பட்ட தற்போதைய பிரான்சையும் வெல்ல முயன்றார். 451இல் ரைன் ஆற்றைக் கடந்தார். அரேலியானம் (ஆர்லியன்சு) வரை அணி வகுத்துச் சென்றார். ஆனால் கட்டலவுனியச் சமவெளி யுத்தத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டார்.இறுதியாக இத்தாலி மீது படையெடுத்தார். வடக்கு மாகாணங்களை முற்றிலுமாக அழித்தார். ஆனால் இவரால் உரோமைக் கைப்பற்ற இயலவில்லை. உரோமானியர்களுக்கு எதிராக மேற்கொண்ட படையெடுப்புகளுக்குத் திட்டமிட்டார். ஆனால் 453ஆம் ஆண்டு இறந்தார். அட்டிலாவின் இறப்பிற்குப் பிறகு, இவரது நெருங்கிய ஆலோசகரான கெபிதா இனத்தைச் சேர்ந்த அர்தரிக்கு ஊண ஆட்சிக்கு எதிராக ஒரு செருமானியக் கிளர்ச்சிக்குத் தலைமை தாங்கினார். இதற்குப் பிறகு, ஊணப் பேரரசு சீக்கிரமே வீழ்ச்சியுற்றது. ஆனால் செருமானிய மரபுவழி வீரக் கதைகளில் ஒரு கதாபாத்திரமாக அட்டிலா தொடர்ந்து வாழ்ந்தார்."},{"question":"Алманбет эмне үчүн Бээжинден качып чыгат?а) Алманбет энеси Экзер атасы Соорундукка мусулман дининеөтүшүн суранса, баш тартат. Атасынын буйругу боюнча колго түшүрүлмөкчү болгондо качып чыгат.б) Алманбеттин эли каршы болуп, өлтүрмөкчү болгондо качып чыгатв) Душмандары жерин басып алып, Алманбетти колго түшүрмөкчү болгондо качып чыгатг) Алманбет достору менен кастташып, аларга күчү жетпей качып чыгат","answer":"Алманбет эмне үчүн Бээжинден качып чыгышынын себеби төмөндөгүчө:Алманбет энеси Экзер атасы Соорундукка мусулман динине өтүшүн суранса, баш тартат. Атасынын буйругу боюнча колго түшүрүлмөкчү болгондо качып чыгат. Туура жообу а) варианты болот."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai ayam bertelur di atas padi, mati kelaparan\\"?","answer":"Peribahasa ini bermaksud hidup susah di negeri mewah."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai rotan, asal berinsang dicucuk sahaja\\"?","answer":"\\"Bagai rotan, asal berinsang dicucuk sahaja\\" bermaksud orang yang tidak memilih pekerjaannya atau perbuatannya."},{"question":"\\"प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रशोधन\\" भनेको के हो?","answer":"\\"प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रशोधन\\" भाषाविज्ञान, कम्प्यूटर विज्ञान, र कम्प्यूटर र मानव भाषा बीचको अन्तरक्रियासँग सम्बन्धित कृत्रिम बुद्धिमत्ताको एक अन्तःविषय उपक्षेत्र हो, विशेष गरी कम्प्यूटरलाई प्राकृतिक भाषा डेटाको ठूलो मात्रामा प्रशोधन र विश्लेषण गर्न कसरी प्रोग्राम गर्ने।"},{"question":"Soalan: Siapakah penyanyi utama Go West?","answer":"Peter Cox"},{"question":"ලංකාවේ උසම වේල්ල කුමක්ද?","answer":"වික්ටෝරියා වේල්ල(මීටර 122)"},{"question":"కింది వాటిని జతపరచండి.1) వాటిని ఇనప్పెట్టెలో పెట్టి తాళాలు వేసి\\tఅ) చేదర్థకం2) కాపలా కాస్తూ హాయిగా తిని కూర్చో\\tఆ) శత్రర్థకం3) మానసికంగా ఎదిగినట్లైతే\\tఇ) ప్రశ్నార్థకం4) నిర్భయంగా జీవించాలని ఆశించడం తప్పా?\\tఈ) క్వార్ధకం","answer":"1) వాటిని ఇనప్పెట్టెలో పెట్టి తాళాలు వేసి\\tఈ) క్వార్ధకం2) కాపలా కాస్తూ హాయిగా తిని కూర్చో\\tఅ) చేదర్థకం3) మానసికంగా ఎదిగినట్లైతే\\tఆ) శత్రర్థకం4) నిర్భయంగా జీవించాలని ఆశించడం తప్పా?\\tఇ) ప్రశ్నార్థకం"},{"question":"Napisz pytanie do fragmentu: \\"W buddyzmie termin karma jest używany wobec tych działań, które wywodzą się z intencji (sanskryt: cetanā, Pali: cetana) nieoświeconej istoty. \\". ","answer":"Przykładowe pytanie może brzmieć: \\"Co oznacza karma w buddyzmie?\\"."},{"question":"அடைக்கப்பட்ட கதவுகளின் முன்னால்… என்னும் நூல்","answer":"இராஜீவ் காந்தி கொலை வழக்கில் தண்டிக்கப்பட்ட அ. ஞா. பேரறிவாளனுக்கு தாயாரான அற்புதம் அம்மையாரைப் பேட்டி கண்டு அனுசிரீ என்னும் இதழாளர் மலையாளத்தில் எழுதிய நூலின் தமிழ் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு நூல் ஆகும். ஓவியரும் எழுத்தாளரும் கவிஞருமான யூமா. வாசுகி இந்நூலை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்த்திருக்கிறார். மொழிபெயர்ப்பாளர் குறிப்பு \\"மனசாட்சி என்ற ஒன்றை நோக்கி..\\" என்னும் தலைப்பிலும் . சென்னை நூலாசிரியர் அனுசிரீயின் முன்னுரை \\"இந்தத் தாயின் வார்த்தைகளைக் கேளுங்கள்…\\" என்னும் தலைப்பிலும் நூலின் முன்பகுதியில் உள்ளன. பேரறிவாளன், முருகன், சாந்தன் ஆகிய மூவரையும் அனுசீரியும் ‘ஓபன்’ (Open) என்னும் இதழின் உதவியாசிரியர் சர்சினாவும் வேலூர் சிறையில் சந்தித்ததைப் பற்றிய கட்டுரை \\"வித்தியாசமான சந்திப்பு...\\" என்னும் தலைப்பிலும் இராஜீவ் கொலை வழக்கில் தீர்ப்பு வழங்கிய உச்சநீதிமன்ற முன்னாள் நீதிபதி கே. டி. தாமஸ் மலையாள இதழான மாத்யமம் வார இதழுக்கு வழங்கிய பேட்டி \\"நீதிபதிகள் கடவுள்கள் அல்ல...\\" என்னும் தலைப்பிலும், பேரறிவாளனின் வாக்குமூலத்தைப் பதிவு செய்த சி.பி.ஐ.யின் முன்னாள் அதிகாரி தியாகராசன் ஆனந்த விகடன் இதழுக்கு வழங்கிய பேட்டி \\"பேரறிவாளன் ஒரு நிரபராதி!\\" என்னும் தலைப்பிலும் இந்நூலில் பின்னிணைப்பாகக் கொடுக்கப்பட்டு உள்ளன."},{"question":"Суроо: ДНКнын соттук-медициналык жана кылмыш иликтөөлөрүндөгү ролу кандай?","answer":"Жооп: ДНК анализи соттук-медициналык экспертизада инсандарды аныктоо, кылмыштарды ачуу жана инсандардын ортосундагы генетикалык байланыштарды түзүү үчүн колдонулат."},{"question":"Ndiani akahwina mazita matanhatu akateedzana eWimbledon muma1980?","answer":"Mutambi wetenesi wekuSweden Björn Borg akawana mubairo unoshamisa wekuhwina mazita matanhatu akateedzana eWimbledon muma1980s. Kutonga kwaBorg pamatare ehuswa eWimbledon kwakamuwanira nzvimbo munhoroondo yetenisi. Akawana zita rake rekutanga reWimbledon muna 1976 uye akaenderera mberi achikunda kusvika 1980. Matambiro aBorg akasiyana nevamwe, anoratidzirwa nemaoko ake maviri kumashure uye nehunyanzvi hwekutanga, hwakamuita simba rinotyisa panhandare yetenisi. Kubudirira kwake kuWimbledon uye maitiro ake pamutambo zvakabatsira kunhaka yake semumwe wevatambi vetennis vakakura kwazvo nguva dzese."},{"question":"வள்ளுவர் கோட்டம்  எங்கு உள்ளது ?","answer":"சென்னை நுங்கம்பாக்கம் சுற்றுவட்டாரத்தில் கோடம்பாக்கம் உயர் சாலை மற்றும் கிராம சாலை சந்திப்பில் வள்ளுவர் கோட்டம் அமைந்துள்ளது."},{"question":"chipaso cha nthochi","answer":"Nthochi ndi chipatso chachitali, chodyedwa - mwachilengedwe ndi mabulosi - opangidwa ndi mitundu ingapo ya maluwa akuluakulu a herbaceous mumtundu wa Musa. M'mayiko ena, nthochi zomwe zimagwiritsidwa ntchito kuphika zimatha kutchedwa ma \\"plantains\\", kuzisiyanitsa ndi nthochi zina. Chipatsocho chimakhala chosinthasintha kukula kwake, mtundu wake, ndi kulimba kwake, koma nthawi zambiri chimakhala chachitali komanso chopindika, chokhala ndi mnofu wofewa wodzaza ndi wowuma wophimbidwa ndi mphonje, yomwe imatha kukhala yobiriwira, yachikasu, yofiira, yofiirira, kapena yofiirira ikakhwima. Zipatsozo zimakula m’mwamba m’magulumagulu pafupi ndi pamwamba pa mbewuyo."},{"question":"Inona ny andro manaraka ny Talata ?","answer":"Alarobia ny andro manaraka ny Talata."},{"question":"420 को 20% को नतिजा पत्ता लगाउनुहोस्।","answer":"420 को 20% 84 बराबर छ।"},{"question":"Was ist die größte Stadt von Europa?","answer":"Die Antwort ist nicht ganz eindeutig. Wenn es um das \\"geographische Europa\\" geht, liegt Moskau mit über 17 Millionen Einwohnern an erster Stelle. Für Städte in der Europäischen Union ist es derzeit Paris, mit knapp über 11 Millionen Einwohnern."},{"question":"කිහිරි වනය යනු ?","answer":"කිහිරි යනු ඉතා  දැඩි ශක්තියක් ඇති ලී වර්ගයකි. උම්මග්ග ජාතකයෙ එන කිහිරි දණ්ඩෙහි අග මුල සෙවීම පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්නය පැරණි සාහිත්‍ය කිහිරි පිළිබඳ කියවෙන එක් අවස්ථාවකි.කිහිරි ගස් සහිත වනය කිහිරි වනය යි.මෙය ඉතා  දැඩි වනාන්තරයක් පිළිබඳ අදහසක් ඉදිරිපත් කරයි"},{"question":"ما هو أثقل الحيوانات الموجودة على كوكب الأرض ؟","answer":"الجواب : قد تعتقد أن الفيل هو أثقل الحيوانات على الأرض !! ولكن بالحقيقة الحوت الأزرق هو أثقل الحيوانات على كوكب الأرض"},{"question":"麦当劳的经营方式是什么？","answer":"全球化的特许经营"},{"question":"Кыргыз кыздарынын улуттук баш кийимдери кайсылар?","answer":"Такыя ,үкү топу ,шөкүлө."},{"question":"தலையில் ஏற்படும் பொடுகை நீக்கும் வழி என்ன?","answer":"பலசரக்குக் கடையில் காய்ந்த வேப்பம்பூ கிடைக்கும். உப்பு கலக்காத வேப்பம்பூ 50 கிராம் கேட்டு வாங்கி, அதை 100 கிராம் தேங்காய் எண்ணெயில் போட்டு நன்கு காய்ச்ச வேண்டும். இளம் சூடு பதத்திற்கு ஆறியதும், வேப்பம் பூவுடன் சேர்த்து எண்ணெயை தலையில் நன்றாகத் தேய்த்து அரை மணிநேரம் ஊறிக் குளித்தால், பொடுகு பிரச்னை தீரும். அதிகம் பொடுகு உள்ளவர்கள், வாரத்திற்கு ஒரு முறையோ, இரண்டு முறையோ, மூன்று வாரங்கள் குளித்தால் பொடுகு சுத்தமாக நீங்கி விடும்."},{"question":"強制的に責任を取らせることを、昔の武士の制裁方法にちなんで「何を切らせる」というでしょう？","answer":"詰め腹（つめばら）です。"},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk kangkung goreng belacan dengan udang? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: 1 ikat sayur kangkung (lebihkurang 400 gm), 15 ekor udang segar, 4 ulas bawang putih, 4 biji bawang merah, 8 biji cili padi (kurangkan kalau tak nak pedas), 1 biji cili hijau, 1 cm belacan, Garam dan gula secukup rasa, Minyak masak untuk menumisCara penyediaan:1. Potong kangkung ikut suka, bersihkan dan asingkan bahagian batang dan daun. Tuskan.2. Tumbuk atau kisar bawang putih, bawang merah, cili padi dan belacan.3. Bersihkan udang dan hiris serong cili hijauCara memasak:1. Panaskan minyak dalam kuali dan tumiskan bawang merah, bawang putih, cili api, belacan yang telahditumbuk/kisar sehingga naik bau.2. Masukkan udang, batang kangkung, garam, gula dan serbuk perasa jika mahu. Kacau goreng sehinggaudang kemerahan.3. Masukkan pula bahagian daun kangkung serta cili hijau dan kacau seketika.4. Angkat dan hidangkan panas-panas."},{"question":"Olee ụcha ha na-eji eme ihe? N'iburu ajụjụ nke mbụ n'uche, dee ihe gbara ya gburugburu bụ́ nke ga-enye azịza ya. Ọ nwere ike ịbụ 1 - 20 ahịrịokwu. Ihe ndị gbara ya gburugburu:","answer":"E webatara nsụgharị nke akara ngosi ABC maka nkwalite maka oge 2013-14 n'oge ngosi nke netwọkụ ahụ na Mee 14, 2013, ma webatara ya na ikuku na June 17 (ọ bụ ezie na ụfọdụ ndị mmekọ mejuputara atụmatụ ọhụrụ ahụ tupu mgbe ahụ), dịka akụkụ nke nhazi nke njirimara ABC site n'aka ụlọ ọrụ LoyalKaspar. Akara ahụ emelitere na-ebu ihe ngosi dị mfe karịa ụdị nke gara aga, ma nwee mkpụrụedemede nke yiri nke mbụ nke Paul Rand nke akara ngosi okirikiri. A na-egosipụta akara ngosi ahụ na ikuku, n'ịntanetị na mbipụta mgbasa ozi na ụdị anọ agba: a na-eji ụdị ọla edo eme ihe na ntụrụndụ na-elekwasị anya (dịka ABC.com, WATCH ABC, na site na ABC Studios) na ahụhụ na ihuenyo; a na-eji ụdị igwe ojii na ọchịchịrị na-acha anụnụ anụnụ eme ihe site na ABC News; a na-eji ụdị uhie uhie maka ESPN na ABC, ebe a na-eji ụdị anọ ahụ eme ihe na mgbasa ozi na ndị mmekọ. E mepụtara ụdị edemede ọhụrụ, \\"ABC Modern\\" (nke sitere n'ike mmụọ nsọ nke akara ngosi ahụ), maka iji ya na mgbasa ozi na ihe nkwado ndị ọzọ."},{"question":"Com qual metal, a platina é associada, quando encontrada?","answer":"A platina pode ser encontrada na forma metálica. Desta forma nativa é encontrada como grãos arredondados, ou achatados, denominados pepitas de platina. Em geral é encontrada associada com outros metais como o titânio, o ósmio, o irídio, o paládio e o ródio, ou na forma de óxido. Na forma combinada é encontrada principalmente no mineral sperrilita."},{"question":"2 kez ek tercih yapılır mı?","answer":"“Boş kalan kontenjanlar için ilave bir tercih fırsatı tanınarak” TYT Puanı 140 ve üzerinde olan adaylar ile AYT/YDT Puanı 170 ve üzerinde olan adaylar için ikinci ek yerleştirme işlemleri esnasında tercihte bulunma imkânı verilmiştir."},{"question":"Iza moa ny mpanjakavavy malagasy nanohitra ny fitaoman’i Eoropa tamin’ny taonjato faha-19?","answer":"Ranavalona I no mpanjakavavy malagasy nanohitra ny fitaoman’i Eoropa tamin’ny taonjato faha-19"},{"question":"\\"මේ ඉර හඳ යට හමුවී\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"මේ ඉර හඳ යට හමුවී ආදරයෙන්කතා කරපු අය සෙනේ වඩපු අයළඟ පාතකවත් නෑමේ ඉර හඳ යට හමුවීඅද නුඹ කොතැනද අද මා කොතැනදදන්නේ නෑ නුඹ මටත් හොරාජීවන මහ මග සටන් වැදී ඇතනාඳුනනා පෙම්වතුන් වෙලාදැන හඳුනා ගත් කාලේ ඉඳලාළබැඳි දයාවෙන් සිටිය නිසාඅප වෙනුවෙන් අප නමින් හෙලන්නටහෙටටත් කඳුලක් ඉතිරි වෙලාඑඩ්වඩ් ජයකොඩිරඹුකන සිද්ධාර්ථ හිමිඑම්. ආර්. චූලසිංහ "},{"question":"意大利的莫利塞區的首府在哪裡？","answer":"在坎波巴索。"},{"question":"Конвертер деген эмне ?","answer":"Конвертер (лат. converto - өзгөртөм, башкага айландырам) - эритилген чоюндан аба же кычкылтек менен үйлөтүү аркылуу болотту жана штейн аркылуу аба үйлөтүү менен жезди алууга арналган аппарат.Кара металлургияда эриген чоюнду аба менен астынан (к. Бессемер процесси) жана кычкылтек менен үстүнөн (к. Кычкылтектуу конвертер процесси) үйлөтүүчү Конвертер болуп айырмаланат. Астынан үйлөтүүчү Конвертер корпус, цапфа, патрубок, аба кутусу, редуктор, түп жана фурмадан турат. Бессемер Конвертеринен айырмаланып, чоюнду кычкылтек менен үстүнөн үйлөтүүдө корпустун түбү туюк болуп, форма жана аба кутусу жасалбайт, жогору жагынан шлем (капкак) кийгизилет.Конвертердин сыйымд. 100 - 350 т. Корпустун ичине доломит кирпичи коюлат. Конвертерди иштетүүдөн мурда кирпич күйгүзүлөт. Бир коюлган кирпич 450 - 600 жолу эритүүгө чыдайт. Кычкылтек бири бирине кийиштирилген түтүк аркылуу берилет. Конвертер эсептеп чыгаруучу машина менен башкарылат.Түстүү металлургияда цилиндр формасындагы Конвертер колдонулат. Анын диаметри 3 - 4 м, уз. 6 - 9 м, сыйымд. 40 - 100 г. Болот корнусуна магнезит кирпичи коюлат да, магнезит катмары менен С. Конгантиев. капталат. Аба бериле турган фурма астына жайгаштырылат."},{"question":"Lẹyin ti ọkọ ti tọju ọmọ fun ọdun mẹfa niyawo ṣẹṣẹ sọ pe ale lo ni in l’Ago-Arẹ","answer":"Ninu oṣu kejila, ọdun 2009, ni Ọgbẹni Adewale Babatunde ṣegbeyawo alarinrin pẹlu Omidan Ashiata Ọmọlọla niluu Agọ-Arẹ, nijọba ibilẹ Atisbo, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, ti wọn si bura pe awọn yoo ṣe oloootọ si ara awọn.Ṣugbọn ọrọ ko ri bi wọn ṣe ro mọ bayii latari ẹsun iwa aiṣootọ ti wọn fi kan Ashiata, ọmọ ọdun mẹrinlelogun, latari bi wọn ṣe fura pe oyun ọmọ kẹta to wa nikun ẹ, wọn lọkọ ẹ kọ lo loyun ọhun fun, wọn ni ale lo ni in.Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ to kọja yii, lakara tu sepo lori ẹsun ọhun, nigba ti baba agbalagba to porukọ ara ẹ ni Tirimisiyu Ọlaoye, to jẹ ale obinrin naa, de lati ilu Ọyọ pe oun fẹẹ gba ọmọ oun.Ninu alaye ti Ọgbẹni Adewale Arẹmu, ẹni ọdun mejidinlọgọta ti i ṣe baba ọkọ iyawo ṣe f’ALAROYE pẹlu awọn oṣiṣẹ ọfiisi awọn to n tọju ọmọ orukan (Welfare), to wa laduugbo Balako, niluu Ṣaki, o ni ileewe girama ni ọmọ oun ati iyawo rẹ yii ti pade ara wọn, ti wọn si funra aọn loyun.O tẹsiwaju pe ọmọ mẹta, Easter, ọmọ ọdun mẹtala, Isiah Adewale, ọmọ ọdun mẹsan-an ati Peter Adewale, ọmọ ọdun mẹfa lo wa laarin wọn.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, lẹyin ti wọn bi ọmọ keji ni ọkọ iyawo, Ọgbẹni Adewale, tẹsiwaju ninu ẹkọ rẹ nileewe gbogbo-niṣe Poli Ibadan, to si fi iyawo rẹ sẹnu ẹkọṣẹ awọn aṣerunlọṣọọ.Ọgbẹni Arẹmu ni ko pẹ, ko jinna, tawọn ọrẹ Ashiat ni ko maa bọ niluu Ọyọ lati maa waa ṣiṣẹ paki (Cassava). O ni laarin oṣu mẹfa to fi wa niluu Ọyọ lawọn gbọ pe o ri ọkunrin kan, wọn si jọ n ṣe wọle-wọde, ẹni ọhun ni wọn lo fun un loyun ọmọ kẹta lai jẹ ki ọkọ rẹ, Adewale, mọ si i, wọn lo tun bẹrẹ si i laṣepọ pẹlu ọkọ rẹ.Kẹrẹkẹrẹ, ọjọ ikunlẹ pe, lakooko to bi ọmọ naa siluu Ibadan, lọdọ Adewale, ọkọ rẹ, Ọgbẹni Arẹmu, ni ọpọlọpọ owo loun na, yatọ si ti ounjẹ toun n fi ranṣẹ si wọn loorekoore, pẹlu arugbo ara oun.O ni ijọloju lo jẹ foun pe boun ṣe ṣe wahala lori Ashiata to, abuku ati ẹgbin loun ri latọdọ awọn obi rẹ, oun ko le gbagbọ pe ọmọ naa le maa f’ọbẹ ẹyin jẹ ọmọ oun niṣu, latari bi Tirimisiyu ṣe waa yọju pe oun loun lọmọ tawọn ti n tọ lati bii ọdun mẹfa sẹyin.Nigba ti wọn bi Ashiata Ọmọlọla leere bọrọ ṣe jẹ, ko mọ ohun to maa sọ mọ, wọn ni niṣe lo n tẹwọ pe ki wọn fori ji oun, o ni loootọ ni ki i ṣe ọkọ oun lo loyun ọmọ kẹta.O ni idi niyi toun fi n fẹ idajọ ododo lori ọrọ naa, oun si ti ṣetan lati yọnda Peter fun baba rẹ ti wọn ba ti le san miliọnu mẹwaa naira foun fun itọju latinu oyun ati inawo toun ṣe lati ọdun mẹfa sẹyin, tori ọmọ oun (Adewale) ti loun o fẹẹ ri ọmọ ale naa ati iyawo alagbere naa mọ.Ọjọ Mọnde ọsẹ to n bọ ni ileeṣẹ Welfare sun ipade awọn mọlẹbi mejeeji pẹlu baba ọmọ naa si, wọn si ti fiṣẹlẹ yii to awọn agbofinro leti."},{"question":"வினா : திருக்குறளில் உள்ள மொத்த இயல் எண்ணிக்கை?","answer":"விடை: 9"},{"question":"ඉන්දුනීසියාවේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"ජකර්තා"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Musée du Louvre. ","answer":"Is ceann de na músaeim is mó agus is cáiliúla ar an domhan í an Musée du Louvre nó Louvre i bPáras, an Fhrainc. Tá sé suite i lár Pháras idir an tSéin agus an Rue de Rivoli. Tá an lár-clós ar an Axe historique. Osclaíodh an Palás de Louvre don phobal ar dtús ar 8 Samhain, 1793 i rith Réabhlóid na Fraince. Ar an 21 Lúnasa 1911, goideadh an Mona Lisa, pictiúr de chuid Leonardo da Vinci, ó Louvre."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న: రష్యన్ విప్లవం ఆ సమాజంలో ఎన్నో మార్పులను తెచ్చింది. అవి ఏమిటి ? వాళ్ళు ఎదుర్కొన్న సవాళ్ళు ఏమిటి?","answer":"రష్యన్ విప్లవం సమాజంలో ఎన్నో మార్పులను తెచ్చింది. 1917లో ప్రారంభమైన రష్యన్ విప్లవం ఫలితంగా 1920 నాటికి అనేక మార్పులు జరిగాయి.1. జార్ చక్రవర్తుల పాలన దూరమై ఉదారవాదులు, రాచరిక కుటుంబాల వాళ్ళు పరిపాలన చేపట్టారు.2. రష్యాలో “బోల్షివిక్”లు లెనిన్ నాయకత్వంలో అనేక విప్లవాత్మక మార్పులకు శ్రీకారం చుట్టారు.3. షరతులు లేని శాంతిని నెలకొల్పి, భూమినంతటినీ జాతీయం చేసి దానిని రైతులందరికీ పంచిపెట్టడం జరిగింది.4. ధరలను నియంత్రించి కర్మాగారాలు, బ్యాంకులను జాతీయం చేశారు.5. స్టాలిన్ ఆధ్వర్యంలో రష్యాను బలమైన శక్తిగా మార్చి, పంచవర్ష ప్రణాళికలతో ప్రణాళికాబద్ధ ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థను చేపట్టారు.ఎదుర్కొనే సవాళ్ళు :1. భూముల ఏకీకరణ సందర్భంగా పెద్ద రైతులు వ్యతిరేకించగా హింస, మరణశిక్షలు అమలుచేశారు.2. 1929-30 లో తీవ్ర కరవు ఎదురై, చాలా పెద్ద సంఖ్యలో ప్రజలు చనిపోయారు.3. స్వేచ్ఛా మార్కెట్ కి అనుమతి లేకుండాపోయింది.4. ప్రపంచ ఆర్థిక మాంద్యం సమయంలో కర్మాగారాలు మూతబడి, వేలాదిమంది నిరుద్యోగులుగా మారారు.5. సాధారణ ప్రజాస్వామిక స్వేచ్ఛ లేదు."},{"question":"मानवाच्या शरीरातील नॅफ्रोन्स मध्ये युरीन बनविण्याचा योग्य घटनाक्रम कोणता ?A. सिलेक्टीव रिअॅबसॉर्बशन, ट्युबुलर सिक्रिशन आणि अल्ट्राफिल्ट्रेशन B. अल्ट्राफिल्ट्रेशन, टयुबुलर सिक्रिशन आणि सिलेक्टीव रिअॅबसॉर्बशनC. अल्ट्राफिल्ट्रेशन, सिलेक्टीव रिअॅबसॉर्बशन आणि ट्युबूलर सिक्रिशन D. टयुबुलर सिक्रिशन, सिलेक्टीव रिअँबसॉर्बशन आणि अल्ट्राफिल्ट्रेशन","answer":"C. अल्ट्राफिल्ट्रेशन, सिलेक्टीव रिअॅबसॉर्बशन आणि ट्युबूलर सिक्रिशन "},{"question":"\\"UAsakhe ukhumkile\\" guqulela lentetha kwisingesi/English.","answer":"The Xhosa sentence \\"UAsakhe ukhumkile\\" translates to \\"Asakhe lost her tooth\\"."},{"question":"Bolanle Ninalowo","answer":"Bọ́láńlé Nínálowó tí gbogbo ènìyàn mọ̀ sí Nínò (tí wọ́n bí ní Ọjọ́ keje oṣù karùn-ún ọdún 1980) jẹ́ gbajúmọ̀ òṣèré sinimá àgbéléwò àti onímọ̀ Ìsirò-owó ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà, ṣùgbọ́n tí ó ń gbé ní orílẹ̀-èdè Amẹ́ríkà. Bí ó ṣe ń ṣeré tíátà, bẹ́ẹ̀ náà ló jẹ́ akọrin.A bí Nínálowó sí ìlú Ìkòròdú ni ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó lórílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà. Kí óó dèrò ìlú-ọba ó kàwé àkóbẹ̀rẹ̀ àti sẹ̀kọ̀ndìrì rẹ̀ ní ìlú Èkó.Gẹ́gẹ́ bí a ṣe sọ síwájú, Nínálowó jẹ́ onímọ̀ Ìsirò-owó, nítorí ìdí èyí, ó kọ́kọ́ ṣíṣe ni ilé-ìfowópamọ́ gẹ́gẹ́ bí Aṣèṣirò-owó (Accountant) fún ìgbà díẹ̀ ní orílẹ̀-èdè Amẹ́ríkà kí ó tó dára pọ̀ mọ́ ìṣe eré sinimá àgbéléwò ṣíṣe lórílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Bákan náà, nígbà tí ó padà sí Nàìjíríà, ó tún bá ilé-ìfowópamọ́ Guaranty Trust Bank ṣíṣe kí ó tó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ tíátà. Nínálowó kò fi bẹ́ẹ̀ rọ́wọ́ mú nígbà tí ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ sinimá àgbéléwò gẹ́gẹ́ bí olóòtú, ṣùgbọ́n lọ́dún 2014, ní ó ṣẹ̀ṣẹ̀ wá di gbajúmọ̀ nídìí ìṣe sinimá àgbéléwò."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত অনুচ্ছেদ সম্পূর্ণ করুন :ছাত্রাবস্থাতেই স্বাধীনতা আন্দোলনে যোগ দিয়েছিলেন তিনি। বহরমপুর অনুশীলন সমিতির তরুন সংগঠকদের মধ্যে একজন ছিলেন ত্রিদিব। ১৯৩০ সালে চট্টগ্রাম অস্ত্রাগার লুন্ঠনের","answer":"ঘটনায় আত্মগোপন করেন। কিছুদিন পরে ধরা পড়ে ১৯৩৭ সাল পর্যন্ত কারাবাস করতে হয়। জেলে ১৯৩৩ সালে বিএ ও ১৯৩৬ সালে অর্থনীতি তে এমএ পাশ করেন। ১৯৩৭ থেকে ১৯৪০ এই তিন বছর নেতাজী সুভাষচন্দ্র বসুর ঘনিষ্ঠ সহযোগী হিসেবে কাজ করেছেন তিনি।"},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang paling sesuai untuk mengisi tempat kosong dalam ayat berikut: Usia Nirmala __ 12 tahun pada tahun April nanti. Pilihan:  A) padat-padat B) genap-genapC) nyaris-nyarisD) bulat-bulat","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah B) genap-genap"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي زاوية الانخفاض؟","answer":"الإجابة: هي الزاوية المحصورة بين خط البصر والخط الأفقي عندما ترصد جسمًا منخفضًا."},{"question":"\\"Mankarary fo ahy ny mieritreritra ny nahazo an-janako.\\"Inona no fihetseham-po asehon'io fanambarana io?","answer":"Maneho alahelo io fanambarana io satria milaza mivantana ny tsy fahazakana trangan-javatra izay nihatra tamina olona akaiky."},{"question":"Comment puis-je répondre à la question d’entretien d’embauche suivante : Que pourraient dire vos proches de vous ?","answer":"En répondant à cette question, le candidat doit montrer qu’il est humble, modeste et qu’il sait prendre du recul sur lui-même.Il faut savoir se mettre en avant sans trop en faire.Par exemple:“Mes proches savent que je suis quelqu’un de loyal et de fidèle”"},{"question":"Dada el siguiente nombre de una receta y los ingredientes. Enumere los pasos para realizar el plato: Frijoles Colombianos, con los siguientes ingredientes:2 lbs de frijoles rojos grandes3 cubos de caldo de polloAgua suficiente que cubra los frijoles1 cebolla picada finamente1lb de tocino, cocido (opcional)Sobre de condimento para frijoles (opcional)1 zanahoria rallada1 tomate grande pelado cortado en cubitos2 plátanos verdes cortados en cuadritosSal y comino al, gusto","answer":"1. Antes de la preparación, lava los frijoles y déjalos en remojo (que queden cubiertos por el agua) por cerca de un día para que se suavicen. Guarda el agua porque se vuelve a utilizar para cocinar.2. Al día siguiente, coloca los fríjoles en la olla de presión con todos los ingredientes por casi 1 hora.* Si utilizas una olla convencional, lo ideal es cocinar por unas 3 horas a fuego bajo.3. Retira de la olla y sirve."},{"question":"لدي نص غير مشكل، قم بتشكيله: بخلاف منكر الواجب الظني أيمنكر وجوبه فإنه لا يكفر للشبهة فيه أما إذا أنكر أصل مشروعيته المجمع عليها بين الأمة فإنه يكفر فقد صرح المصنف في باب الوتر والنوافل أن من أنكر سنة الفجر يخشى عليه الكفر ثم رأيته في القنية في باب ما يكفر به نقل عن الحلواني لو أنكر أصل الوتر وأصل الأضحية كفر ثم.","answer":"النص المشكل: بِخِلَافِ مُنْكَرِ الْوَاجِبِ الظَنِيِ أَيْمُنْكَرِ وُجُوبِهِ فَإِنَهُ لَا يَكْفُرُ لِلشُبْهَةِ فِيهِ أَمَا إذَا أَنْكَرَ أَصْلَ مَشْرُوعِيَتِهِ الْمُجْمَعِ عَلَيْهَا بَيْنَ الْأُمَةِ فَإِنَهُ يَكْفُرُ فَقَدْ صَرَحَ الْمُصَنِفُ فِي بَابِ الْوِتْرِ وَالنَوَافِلِ أَنَ مَنْ أَنْكَرَ سُنَةَ الْفَجْرِ يُخْشَى عَلَيْهِ الْكُفْرُ ثُمَ رَأَيْته فِي الْقُنْيَةِ فِي بَابِ مَا يَكْفُرُ بِهِ نَقْلٌ عَنْ الْحَلْوَانِيِ لَوْ أَنْكَرَ أَصْلَ الْوِتْرِ وَأَصْلُ الْأُضْحِيَةِ كَفَرَ ثُمَ."},{"question":"Igbimọ oluwadii ni Abba Kyari ki i ṣe onijibiti o","answer":"Igbimọ tijọba gbe kalẹ lati ṣewadii ẹsun iwa jibiti ati lilẹdi apo pọ pẹlu ọdaran, eyi ti wọn fi kan igbakeji kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa, Abba Kyari, ti sọ pe ọrọ ko ri bi wọn ṣe n pariwo ẹ, wọn lọkunrin naa ko jẹbi awọn ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an, o si ṣee ṣe kijọba kọ jalẹ lati fa a le orileede Amẹrika to n beere ẹ lọwọ.Olobo kan to ta ileeṣẹ oniroyin ayelujara Dailygist sọ pe abajade iwadii tileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ṣe fun Abba Kyari fihan pe loootọ lo ba afurasi ọdaran to n jẹjọ ẹsun jibiti ayelujara l’Amẹrika nni, Ramon Ọlọrunwa Abass, tawọn eeyan mọ si Hushpuppi, sọrọ, ṣugbọn awọn o ri ẹri kan to fidi mulẹ pe wọn jọ lọwọn ninu iwa jibiti kan.Olobo naa sọ pe ko si ọrọ fifi Abba Kyari ṣọwọ sorileede Amẹrika kun awọn aba ti wọn sinu abajade iwadii wọn. Wọn ni ijiya eyikeyii ti wọn ba fẹẹ fi jẹ igbakeji kọmiṣana ti wọn ti da lọwọ kọ yii, ko ni nnkan kan i ṣe pẹlu iwa jibiti rara.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ile-ẹjọ giga kan lorileede Amẹrika lo paṣẹ fun ileeṣẹ ọtẹlẹmuyẹ wọn lọhun-un, FBI (Federal Bereau of Investigation) pe ki wọn lọọ mu afurasi ọdaran naa wa s’Amẹrika latari bi Hushpuppi ṣe darukọ ẹ pe o mọ nipa awọn jibiti kan toun lu, ati awọn jọ n ṣe apapin ni.Iwe ti FBI fi ṣọwọ sijọba Naijiria pe ki wọn yọnda Abba Kyari fawọn lo mu kileeṣẹ ọlọpaa gbe igbimọ oluṣewadii kan dide, eyi ti Igbakeji Ọga agba patapata funleeṣẹ ọlọpaa, DIG Joseph Egbunnike, ṣe alaga rẹ, ti wọn si jabọ iwadii wọn fun ijọba nipari oṣu kẹjọ to kọja yii.Amọ ṣa o, ileeṣẹ Aarẹ ati minisita feto idajọ ni yoo pinnu igbesẹ to kan lori ọrọ naa."},{"question":"Atatürk çiçeği evde nereye konur?","answer":"Aynı şekilde güneş ışığına doğrudan maruz kalmayı sevmeyen bitki, aydınlık ortamlardan hoşlanıyor. Hem hafif serin hem de doğrudan güneş ışığına maruz kalmayacak bir ortam olarak pencerelerin iç pervazları bu bitki için en ideal alanları oluşturuyor."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: ഒരു ബാങ്ക് അക്കൗണ്ടിൽ നിന്ന് മറ്റൊന്നിലേക്ക് ഇലക്ട്രോണിക് ആയി പണം ട്രാൻസ്ഫർ ചെയ്യുന്ന പ്രക്രിയ എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഇലക്ട്രോണിക് ഫണ്ട് ട്രാൻസ്ഫർ (EFT) എന്നത് ഒരു ബാങ്ക് അക്കൗണ്ടിൽ നിന്ന് മറ്റൊന്നിലേക്ക് ഇലക്ട്രോണിക് ആയി പണം ട്രാൻസ്ഫർ ചെയ്യുന്ന പ്രക്രിയയാണ്, ഇത് പലപ്പോഴും ഓൺലൈൻ ബാങ്കിംഗ് പ്ലാറ്റ്‌ഫോമുകളിലൂടെയോ മൊബൈൽ ബാങ്കിംഗ് ആപ്പുകളിലൂടെയോ ചെയ്യാന് കഴിയും."},{"question":"Title: రైతులకు మోదీ వరాలు ప్రకటిస్తారా? వ్యవసాయాన్ని పట్టాలెక్కిస్తారా?nSummary: మోదీ ప్రభుత్వం మరి కొద్ది గంటల్లో 2018-19 ఆర్థిక సంవత్సరానికి గాను బడ్జెట్ ప్రవేశపెట్టనుంది. లోక్‌సభ ఎన్నికలకు ముందు ఇదే చివరి బడ్జెట్ కావడంతో ఇది ప్రజాకర్షక బడ్జెట్‌గా ఉండొచ్చని భావిస్తున్నారు.nArticle (Max 500 characters):","answer":"ఆర్థిక మంత్రి అరుణ్ జైట్లీ దృష్టి ఓ వైపు వచ్చే సంవత్సరం జరుగనున్న ఎన్నికల మీదా, మరోవైపు ద్రవ్య లోటును పూడ్చుకోవడం పైనా ఉండక తప్పదు.బడ్జెట్ ప్రవేశపెట్టడానికి ముందుగా, ప్రస్తుత ప్రభుత్వం ముందు ఇంకా ఏమేం సవాళ్లున్నాయో చూద్దాం: రైతుల ఆదాయాలను పెంచడం ఓ సవాలేవ్యవసాయంనోట్ల రద్దు తర్వాత దేశంలో వ్యవసాయం పరిస్థితి దిగజారిందని చెబుతున్నారు. \\"వ్యవసాయ రంగాన్ని మళ్లీ పట్టాల మీదకు ఎలా ఎక్కించడమన్నది ఈ ప్రభుత్వం ముందున్న అతి పెద్ద సవాలు\\" అని ఆర్థికవేత్త అరుణ్ కుమార్ అన్నారు."},{"question":"Kisa fotosentèz ye?","answer":"Nou kapab di ke fotosentèz la se yon prosesis  ki itilize limyè solèy la, ak lòt sibstans òganik k pou bay plant yo enèji . le swa fotosentèz la absòbe  yon gaz ki rele  diyoksid kabòn(CO2) epi pou li prodwi yon lòt gaz ki rele oksijèn. fotosentèz la fèt pandan 2 faz, yon faz klè ak yon faz somb."},{"question":"Чыйрак деген эмне?","answer":"чыйрак –өзүнө тың, колунан бардык иш келет дегендей сөз. "},{"question":"\\"Pelayanan bus DAMRI sangat baik\\". Apakah klasifikasi sentimen dari kalimat ulasan atau opini di atas? (Positif/Negatif/Netral)Jawaban:","answer":"Opini tersebut termasuk sentimen positif karena mengandung kata bermakna positif, yaitu: sangat baik."},{"question":"Rabe-Rabe farauta?","answer":"Yanayin yadda da ake gudanar da farauta da kuma irin kayan aikin da ake amfani da su shi ne abin lura wajen rarraba ta. Daga ciki akwai:Farautar mutum ɗaya: Akwai mutane kamar maharba da ke amfani da makamai irin su kwari da baka, daga baya kuma suka ƙara da bindiga, waɗanda basu da wata sana’a in banda shiga daji su kaso dabbobi domin ci da kuma sayarwa.Farautar Gangami: Farauta ce da ake gudanar da ita ta hanyar haɗa gangamin jama’a waɗanda ka iya zamowa daga gari guda ko kuma garuruwa su haɗu a wani daji domin gudanar da wannan sana’a ta farauta. Su irin waɗannan mutane sune ke amfani da makamai da suka haɗa da gora, kere, sanda, barandami, gariyo, bindiga, kwari-da-baka, wuƙa, adda, da sauransu.Idan aka shirya irin wannan farauta kai ka ɗauka yaƙi za a fita. A irin wannan farauta ce ake faɗa tsakanin abokan gaba.Sharani: Farauta ce da yawanci yara ne ke yin ta a dajin da bashi da girma da kuma duhu, yawanci akan yi irin wannan farauta a lokacin rani. Samari da yara masu ƙwazo su ke yin wannan farauta. Sukan kaso dabbobi irin su zomo, bushiya, muzuru, yanyawa, gafiya, maciji da sauran ƙananan dabbobin da ba sa nisa da gari.Ba a cika nisa da gari ba wajen gudanar da wannan farauta. Haka nan kuma ana ma gudanar da ita da daddare musamman lokacin da farin wata yake tsaka da haske."},{"question":"Madaxa Lalbaad: Xuquuqda, Xorriyaadka Aasaasiga Ah Ee Qofka Iyo Xaddidaadooda.Qodobka 22aad. Xaqa Ka-qaybgalka Siyaasadda.","answer":"Qodobka 22aad. Xaqa Ka-qaybgalka Siyaasadda.(1) Muwaaddin kastaa wuxuu xaqu leeyahay in uu ka qayb-qaato arrimaha guud ce dadweynaha. Xaqa kan waxaa ka mid ah: (a) Inuu samaysan karo ama ka mid noqon karo xisbi siyaasadeed, kana qayb-qaadan karo hawlihisa; (b) In xisbi siyaasadecd gudihisa looga dooran karo jago kasta.(2) Muwaaddin kasta po buuxtya shoruudaha sharciga tilmaamayo wuxuu xaq u leeyahay inuu wax doorto, lana doorto.(3) Xuaquuqda ku xusan faqradaha iyo ce qodobkan waa in loogu dhaqmaa si waafaqsan Dastuurkan iyo sharci Baarlamaanka Federalka."},{"question":"Ñaata la Senegaal yaatoo (superficie) ?","answer":"Senegaal yaatoowaayam toolu na ci 196 712 km2."},{"question":"Menene sunan filin jirgin saman kasa da kasa a Accra?","answer":"Kotoka International Airport, Filin jirgin sama na Kotoka (KIA), asalin filin jirgin sama ne na soja da Sojojin saman Burtaniya suka yi amfani da shi a lokacin yakin duniya na biyu a 1946."},{"question":"වායුගෝලයේ වැඩිපුර්රම අඩංගු වාතය","answer":"නයිට්‍රජන්"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Balla Mór na Síne","answer":"Is séadchomhartha ársa é Balla Mór na Síne, suite i dtuaisceart na tíre. Tá an Balla ar an struchtúr is faide ar domhan. Tá sé 21,196 ciliméadar ar fad (sin 43 uair go leith níos faide ná Éire).Deir daoine gur féidir leis na spásairí é a fheiceáil ón spás agus iad ag taisteal thart ar an domhan, más fíor sin ar chor ar bith.Tá Balla Mór na Síne breis agus 2,300 bliain d’aois. Thóg Impirí na Síne an balla ollmhór seo mar go raibh siad ag iarraidh a naimhde ón taobh thuaidh a choimeád amach.D’oibrigh suas le milliún duine ar an mballa agus ghlac sé 2,000 bliain é a chríochnú. Cé gur tógadh an Balla Mór le muintir na Síne a chosaint, fuair go leor Síneach bás agus iad á thógáil. Tá spéis as cuimse ag daoine sa Bhalla Mór agus tugann na céadta míle turasóir cuairt air gach bliain. Tógadh é le daoine a choimeád amach as an tSín, ach sa lá atá inniu ann, cabhraíonn an Balla go mór leis na céadta míle duine a mhealladh ansin. "},{"question":"請回答這個問題：什麼是地質學中的「岩層」？","answer":"答案：岩層是地球地殼中由相似岩石組成的水平或近水平的層狀結構，是地質學研究中的重要單位，可用於推斷地層的年代和環境。"},{"question":"O ti di eewọ, awọn Fulani ko gbọdọ fi maaluu jẹ oko oloko mọ o-awọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba","answer":"Nibi ipade tawọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba ṣe pẹlu awọn Mayyeti Allah niluu Akurẹ, nipinlẹ Ondo, ni wọn ti fẹnu ko pe fifi maaluu jẹ’ko lalẹ tabi loru ti di eewọ kaakiri awọn ipinlẹ to wa ni ilẹ Yoruba gẹgẹ bi Gomina Akeredolu ṣe sofin lọjọ diẹ sẹyin.Alaga awọn gomina kaakiri ilẹ Naijiria to tun jẹ gomina ipinlẹ Ekiti, Kayọde Fayẹmi, lo dari ipade naa.Ohun ti eyi tumọ si ni pe ki i ṣe ipinle Ondo nikan ni fifofin de awọn Fulani darandaran lati maa da maaluu lalẹ tabi loru ti mulẹ, kaakiri awọn ipinlẹ ilẹ Yoruba ni.Bakan naa ni wọn ṣofin pe awọn Fulani darandaran to ba wa ni ipinlẹ kọọkan gbọdọ forukọ silẹ lọdọ ijọba ipinlẹ ti wọn ba wa.Yatọ si eyi, wọn tun fofin de awọn Fulani darandaran yii pe wọn ko gbọdọ maa lo awọn ọmọ keekeeke ti wọn ko ti i dagba lati maa da ẹran kiri. O si di eewọ fun ẹnikẹni ninu awọn darandaran yii lati wọ igbo ọba lọna ti ko ba ofin mu.Siwaju si i, wọn ni ko ni i si aaye fun awọn awọn Fulani darandaran lati kan maa da ẹran kaakiri ibi to ba wu wọn, nitori igbesẹ bẹẹ le da wahala silẹ laarin awọn ati awọn agbẹ. Wọn rọ awọn ẹgbẹ darandaran awọn Fulani yii lati ṣe amulo ọna igbalode ti wọn fi n daran nipa kikọ ibujẹ ẹran igbalode.Lara ohun ti wọn tun fẹnu ko le lori ni mimu eto aabo dan-in-dan-in nipa lilo awọn ọna mi-in fun eto aabo lati ran ijọba lọwọ.Fayẹmi waa sọ pe ko si ẹnikẹni to le awọn darandaran yii, nitori ọpọ wọn lo ti pe nilẹ Yoruba daadaa, awọn to n jẹ kiri inu igbo to n hu iwa ọdaran ni awọn ko fẹ niluu mọ.Wọn fi kun un pe ẹnikẹni to ba huwa ọdaran gbọdọ jiya to tọ si i lai fi ti ẹya ti iru ẹni bẹẹ ti wa tabi iru ẹni to jẹ lawujọ ṣe."},{"question":"Awọn ọlọdẹ yari l’Ọṣun, wọn lawọn o ba Amọtẹkun ṣiṣẹ papọ mọ","answer":"Agbarijọpọ ẹgbẹ awọn ọlọdẹ nipinlẹ Ọṣun, (Hunters Group of Nigeria, Osun State Chapter) ti kede pe kaka ki ekute ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun ṣe akapo ẹkun awọn, ki onikaluuku rọra ṣe ọdẹ rẹ lọtọọtọ latari iyanjẹ ọlọkan-o-jọkan ti oju awọn ti ri.Alakooso ẹgbẹ naa l’Ọṣun, Nurein Hammed, lo sọrọ yii fawọn oniroyin niluu Oṣogbo l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii. O ṣalaye pe owo ẹgbẹ naa to to miliọnu marundinlọgbọn naira ni awọn adari ikọ Amọtẹkun ko jẹ.Hammed ṣalaye pe lasiko igbele Koronafairọọsi to waye lọdun to kọja ni aparutu naa ṣẹlẹ lai tiẹ wo bi awọn ṣe n fi ẹmi ṣiṣẹ fun aabo awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ọṣun.O ni awọn ko lee ṣiṣẹ papọ labẹ awọn alakooso Amọtẹkun nipinlẹ Ọṣun mọ nitori pe iyanjẹ naa ti pọ ju, ṣugbọn awọn ko ni i dẹkun igbogun-ti ẹnikẹni to ba fẹẹ da omi alaafia ipinlẹ yii ru.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, “Ẹgbẹ wa yoo maa tẹsiwaju lati fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu awọn ikọ alaabo to ku l’Ọṣun lati gbogun ti awọn kọlọransi, tori ohun ti a ti bura lati ṣe ni, ṣugbọn a ko le ṣiṣẹ yii labẹ awọn Amọtẹkun.“Lasiko igbele Korona ati ti iwọde EndSars, ọpọlọpọ awọn aala ipinlẹ yii la daabo bo, ti a si ri i pe alaafia jọba kaakiri ipinlẹ Ọṣun.“Lopin gbogbo rẹ, ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun gbe miliọnu lọna mẹrinlelogoji naira kalẹ fun wa gẹgẹ bii ọkan lara awọn to wa labẹ Amọtẹkun, ṣugbọn miliọnu mẹẹẹdogun naira pere la ri gba.“Ẹni to jẹ alakooso nigba naa ṣi wa lara awọn alakooso Amọtẹkun, nitori naa, a ko nigbagbọ kankan ninu wọn mọ lati ba wọn ṣiṣẹ papọ nitori iṣẹ wa gba ka fi ọkan kan ṣiṣẹ.”Gbogbo igbiyanju wa lati gbọ ti ẹnu alakooso Amọtẹkun nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Ajagun-fẹyinti Bashir Adewinbi, ni ko so eso rere nitori ko gbe ipe lori foonu rẹ."},{"question":"సాపేక్ష వ్యాకోచ డిమాండ్ గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"ఒక వస్తువు ధరలో వచ్చే అనుపాతపు మార్పు కంటే డిమాండ్ పరిమాణంలో వచ్చే అనుపాతపు మార్పు ఎక్కువగా ఉంటే దానిని సాపేక్ష వ్యాకోచ డిమాండ్ అంటారు. ఇక్కడ వ్యాకోచత్వం విలువ ‘1’ కంటే ఎక్కువగా ఉంటుంది."},{"question":"కింది పదాలను విడదీయండి. సంధి పేరు రాయండి.అ) సర్వోదయంఆ) ఊహాతీతంఇ) ఆయాచోట్లఈ) తేవాలనిఉ) మరొకటి","answer":"అ) సర్వోదయం = సర్వ + ఉదయం – గుణసంధిఆ) ఊహాతీతం = ఊహ + అతీతం – సవర్ణదీర్ఘ సంధిఇ) ఆయాచోట్ల = ఆ + ఆచోట్ల – యడాగమ సంధిఈ) తేవాలని = తేవాలి + అని – ఇత్వసంధిఉ) మరొకటి = మరి + ఒకటి – ఇత్వసంధి"},{"question":"Tóm tắt văn bản sau: Cuộc thi ảnh Kinh tế tuần hoàn 2023 được tổ chức nhằm tìm kiếm các tác phẩm nhiếp ảnh tiêu biểu, có giá trị tuyên truyền lợi ích, tầm quan trọng của kinh tế tuần hoàn trong sử dụng tài nguyên thiên nhiên, giảm ô nhiễm, suy thoái môi trường, ứng phó với biến đổi khí hậu; đồng thời tạo động lực nâng cao chất lượng công tác thông tin, tuyên truyền về kinh tế tuần hoàn trên các phương tiện thông tin đại chúng. Các tác phẩm ảnh dự thi đã chuyển tải thông điệp rõ ràng, mang đến những góc nhìn mới lạ, độc đáo, thể hiện được tầm quan trọng của kinh tế tuần hoàn trong việc sử dụng tài nguyên thiên nhiên, giảm ô nhiễm, suy thoái môi trường, ứng phó với biến đổi khí hậu,...Theo Phó viện trưởng Viện Chiến lược, chính sách TN-MT - Trưởng ban giám khảo cuộc thi Nguyễn Trung Thắng, trong những năm qua, kinh tế tuần hoàn được thực hiện ở nhiều lĩnh vực khác nhau, mang lại những lợi ích kinh tế - xã hội và môi trường và gắn liền với sự phát triển bền vững ở nhiều quốc gia trên thế giới. Phát triển kinh tế tuần hoàn cũng nhằm tạo động lực cho đổi mới sáng tạo và cải thiện năng suất lao động, hướng tới nền kinh tế xanh và phát triển bền vững.Ở Việt Nam, phát triển kinh tế tuần hoàn đã trở thành nhu cầu cấp bách và xu thế tất yếu của tiến trình phát triển xã hội. Năm 2022 đặt dấu mốc quan trọng cho sự khởi động của kinh tế tuần hoàn, với việc luật Bảo vệ môi trường 2020 chính thức có hiệu lực và Đề án Phát triển kinh tế tuần hoàn Việt Nam chính thức được phê duyệt. Tuy nhiên, để thực sự đưa nền kinh tế bước vào quá trình chuyển đổi tuần hoàn, nhiều yếu tố cần được chuẩn bị.Để kinh tế tuần hoàn có thể phát triển mạnh mẽ hơn và có định hướng trong thời gian tới, bên cạnh việc cần làm là nghiên cứu và tạo ra các công nghệ, kỹ thuật tiên tiến; là hoàn thiện thể chế chính sách pháp luật chưa đạt quy chuẩn thì việc nâng cao, tăng cường nhận thức về kinh tế tuần hoàn là vô cùng quan trọng. Trong bối cảnh đó, Tạp chí Môi trường của Viện Chiến lược, Chính sách tài nguyên và môi trường, Bộ TN-MT đã phối hợp cùng C Asean để tổ chức cuộc thi ảnh Kinh tế tuần hoàn 2023.Tổng kết cuộc thi, ông Phạm Đình Tuyên, Phó tổng biên tập Tạp chí Môi trường, Trưởng ban tổ chức cuộc thi, cho biết, sau gần 2 tháng diễn ra cuộc thi (từ ngày 15.7 - 4.8), Ban tổ chức đã nhận được 919 tác phẩm của 148 tác giả đến từ 37 tỉnh, thành phố trong cả nước. Trong đó, TP.HCM có số lượng tác giả tham dự đông nhất, với 17 tác giả.","answer":"Ngày 21.9, tại Hà Nội đã diễn ra lễ trao giải cuộc thi ảnh Kinh tế tuần hoàn 2023. Đây là cuộc thi do Tạp chí Môi trường (Bộ TN-MT) và Tổ chức C Asean đồng tổ chức."},{"question":"දේවවේදයේ අර්ථ දැක්වීම කුමක්ද?","answer":"“දේවවේදය” යන වචනය ඉංග්‍රීසි බසින් “Theology” ලෙස සකස්වී ඇත්තේ ග්‍රීක වචන දෙකක් එකතුවීමෙනි, එහි තේරුම වන්නේ “දෙවියන් වහන්සේ පිළිබඳව ඉගෙනගැනීම” යනුයි. කිතුනු දේවවේදය මගින් දෙවියන් වහන්සේව ශුද්ධ ලියවිල්ල තුළ දක්වන ආකාරයටම අනාවරණය කිරීම (ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට) එහි වෑයම වේ. කිසිදා දේවවේදයකින් දෙවියන් වහන්සේ හා එතුමන්ගේ ක්‍රියාවන් නිශ්චිතවම විදහා දැක්වීමට හැකියාවක් නොමැති අතර එයට හේතුව වන්නේ දෙවියන් වහන්සේ අපට වඩා උසස් හා සදාතනික තැනැන් වහන්සේ නිසාය. දේවවේදය යනු අන් කසිවක් නොව දෙවියන් වහන්සේගේ වචනය ගැඹුරින් අධ්‍යයනය කොට දෙවියන් වහන්සේ තමන් වහන්සේ පිළිබඳව අනාවරණය කර තිබෙන දේ අධ්‍යයනය කිරීමයි. මෙම අධ්‍යයනය මගින් දෙවියන් වහන්සේ සියල්ලෙහි මැවුම්කරු බවත්, සියල්ල දරා සිටින්න හා සියලු දෙයහි විනිශ්චකරුවාණන් ලෙසට අපට දැන ගත හැක. එතුමන් අල්ෆා සහ ඔමේගාය, ආරම්භය හා අවසානයයි. සෑම කිතුනුවෙක්ම දේවවේදය ඉගෙන ගැනීමට උනන්දු විය යුතු අතර, ඒ තුලින් ප්‍රේමය, අවනතවීම හා සදාකාලිකව අපගේ ජීවිත ප්‍රීතියෙන් ගෙවන්නාවූ තැනැන් වහන්සේ පිළිබඳව දැන ගැන්මකට පැමිණිය හැක."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Binatang apa yang selalu penat?","answer":"Jawapan : Anjng kerana ia selalu mengeluarkan lidahnya."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕੁ ॥ਸੁਖੀ ਬਸੈ ਮਸਕੀਨੀਆ ਆਪੁ ਨਿਵਾਰਿ ਤਲੇ ॥ਬਡੇ ਬਡੇ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀਆ ਨਾਨਕ ਗਰਬਿ ਗਲੇ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 278 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਗਰੀਬੀ ਸੁਭਾਉ ਵਾਲਾ ਬੰਦਾ ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ, ਤੇ ਨੀਵਾਂ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਸੁਖੀ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਵੱਡੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ, ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਗਲ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।\\""},{"question":"Inty misy lahatsoratra:Misy fomba roa ny fikarakarana tambavy izay hita amin’ity boky ity dia ny fanotrehana sy ny fitanehana. Ireo dia samy mampiasa rano, ary mila tavanina avokoa alohan’ny ampiasa azy. Ny habeny dia miova araka ny fangarony sy ny aretina izay tiana hotsaboina.Miresaka momba ny inona io lahatsoratra io?","answer":"Miresaka momba ny karazana tambavy sy ny mahasamy hafa azy io lahatsoratra io."},{"question":"ලෙමන්ග්‍රාස් සඳහා  අවශ්‍ය  පාංශු සහ දේශගුණික අවශ්‍යතා   මොනවද?","answer":"පස:හොඳින් ජලය බැස යන වැලි පස වඩාත් සුදුසු වන අතර ඝන මැටි පස ලෙමන්ග්‍රාස් වර්ධනයට සුදුසු නැත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අඩු පෝෂක සහිත පස් වර්ග බොහොමයක් ලෙමන්ග්‍රාස් සඳහා සුදුසු වන නමුත් ඉහළ ප්‍රමාණයක හියුමස් සහිත පස් වලින් ඉහළ අස්වැන්නක් ලබා ගත හැකිය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, පතන ඉඩම්, ආන්තික තේ ඉඩම්, දැඩි ලෙස ඛාදනය වූ ඉඩම් සහ වෙනත් කිසිදු බෝගයක් වගා කිරීමට නුසුදුසු ඉඩම්වල පවා ලෙමන්ග්‍රාස් වගා කළ හැකිය.දේශගුණය:ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෑම දේශගුණික කලාපයකම එය සාර්ථකව වගා කළ හැකි නමුත් අධික හිරු රශ්මියෙන් යුත් නිවර්තන උණුසුම් ප්‍රදේශ වඩාත් සුදුසුය.උන්නතාංශය – මුහුදු මට්ටමේ සිට මීටර් 100-1200 දක්වාඋෂ්ණත්වය – 25ºC – 30ºCවර්ෂාපතනය – දැඩි නියඟ හා දැඩි සුළං සහ ලැව්ගිනි වලට ප්‍රතිරෝධී වේ. හොඳින් ව්‍යාප්ත වූ වර්ෂාපතනය අඟල් කිහිපයක් වුවත් ප්‍රමාණවත් වේ. අධික වර්ෂාපතනය තෙල් අස්වැන්න අඩු කරයි.ලෙමන්ග්‍රාස් ඉහළ සෙවණක් යටතේ, සිසිල් දේශගුණයක සහ ඉතා සාරවත් පසක වගා කරන විට තෙල්වල ප්‍රමාණය හා ගුණාත්මකභාවය අඩුවේ."},{"question":"«خودرو دیفرانسیل جلو است» یعنی چه؟","answer":"امروزه در خودروهای دیفرانسیل جلو ( خودروهایی که چرخهای جلو در آنها محرک است)، سیستم گیربکس و دیفرانسیل با یکدیگر یکپارچه شده داخل یک مجموعه قرار دارند."},{"question":"Gökhan Zan çocuğu var mi?","answer":"Gökhan Zan'ın oğlu 'Bora' dünyaya..."},{"question":"අංකිත පරිගණකයක් මඟින් සිදුකරන ප්‍රධාන කාර්යයන් මොනවද ?","answer":"ආදාන ලෙස දත්ත ලබා ගැනීම.දත්ත සහ උපදෙස් ගබඩා කර අවහය වූ විට භාවිතා කිරිම.දත්ත සකස්කර ප්‍රයෝජනවත් තොරතුරු බවට පත් කිරිම.තොරතුරු ප්‍රතිදානය කිරීම.ඉහත පියවර හතර පාලනය."},{"question":"za umoyo ndi thanzi ku dziko la Malawi","answer":"Dziko la Malawi lili ndi zipatala zapakati, zigawo ndi zipatala. Mabungwe aboma amapereka chithandizo chaumoyo ndi mankhwala kwaulere, pomwe mabungwe omwe si aboma amapereka chithandizo ndi mankhwala polipira. Madokotala wamba amapereka chithandizo chotengera ndalama ndi mankhwala. Ndondomeko za inshuwaransi yaumoyo zakhazikitsidwa kuyambira 2000. Dzikoli lili ndi makampani opanga mankhwala omwe ali ndi makampani anayi omwe ali ndi anthu payekha. Cholinga cha umoyo wa dziko la Malawi ndi “kupititsa patsogolo thanzi, kupewa, kuchepetsa ndi kuchiritsa matenda, komanso kuchepetsa kufala kwa imfa msanga mwa anthu”."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Ny _ dia fahalalana ny zava-niseho tamin' ny andro lasa","answer":"\\"Ny tantara dia fahalalana ny zava-niseho tamin' ny andro lasa"},{"question":"A palavra \\"anã\\" é um palíndromo?","answer":"Sim, pois ao ler de trás para frente, excluindo o acento, temos a mesma palavra."},{"question":"忙しく動き回ることを、太鼓の音に例えて「何舞い」というでしょう？","answer":"てんてこ舞い"},{"question":"Waa Maxay Baarley? ","answer":"Baarluhu waa gashaantida qoyska."},{"question":"வினா:  மின்கடத்தாப் பொருளுக்கு உதாரணம். 1.அலுமினியம்  2.கார்பன்  3.கண்ணாடி  4.தங்கம்","answer":"விடை:3.கண்ணாடி  விளக்கம்:கண்ணாடி என்று பொதுவாகக் குறிப்பிடும்போது இது, சாளரங்கள், போத்தல்கள், மூக்குக் கண்ணாடிகள் போன்றவற்றின் உற்பத்தியில் பயன்படுவதும்; கடினத்தன்மை கொண்ட, உடையக்கூடிய, ஒளியை ஊடுசெல்ல விடக்கூடிய, பளிங்குருவற்ற திண்மமுமான பொருளொன்றைக் குறிக்கிறது. தொழில்நுட்ப அடிப்படையில், கண்ணாடி என்பது குளிர்ந்து பளிங்காகாமல் திண்மமாகிய கனிமப் பொருட் கலவை ஆகும். பெரும்பாலான கண்ணாடிகள் சிலிக்காவை முக்கிய கூறாகவும், கண்ணாடி உருவாக்கியாகவும் கொண்டுள்ளன. அறிவியல் அடிப்படையில் கண்ணாடி என்பது நெகிழிகள், பிசின்கள், பிற சிலிக்காவைக் கொண்டிராத பளிங்குருவற்ற திண்மங்கள் போன்ற எல்லாப் பளிங்குருவற்ற திண்மங்களையும் குறிக்கப் பயன்படுவதுண்டு. இது தவிர மரபு வழியான உருக்கும் நுட்பங்கள் தவிர்ந்த வேறு முறைகளையும் கவனத்துக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்வது உண்டு. எனினும், கண்ணாடி அறிவியல் கனிம பளிங்குருவற்ற திண்மங்களை மட்டுமே உள்ளடக்குகின்றது. கரிம பளிங்குருவற்ற திண்மங்கள் பல்பகுதிய அறிவியல் துறையுள் அடங்கும்.கண்ணாடி இன்று பல்வேறு அறிவியல் துறைகளிலும், தொழில் துறைகளிலும் முக்கிய பங்காற்றுகின்றது. இதன் ஒளியியல் இயல்புகளும், பிற இயற்பியல் இயல்புகளும் இதனைத் தட்டைக் கண்ணாடி, கொள்கலக் கண்ணாடி, ஒளியியல் மற்றும் ஒளிமின்னணுவியல் சார்ந்த பொருட்கள், சோதனைச்சாலைக் கருவிகள், வெப்பக்காவலிகள், வலிதாக்கல் கண்ணாடி இழைகள், கலைப் பொருட்கள் போன்றவற்றுக்கு உகந்த பொருளாக ஆக்குகின்றது.இது இன்று ஒரு முக்கியமான கட்டிடப் பொருளாக விளங்குகிறது. கண்ணாடி கிறித்துவுக்கு முன் 4000 ஆண்டுகளிலேயே அறியப்பட்டிருந்ததாகக் கருதப்படினும், கட்டிடப் பொருள் என்ற அளவில் இதன் பயன்பாடு 18 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டுக்குப் பின்னரே குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அளவில் இருந்தது. கடந்த நூற்றாண்டிலேயே இது பெருமளவு வளர்ச்சி பெற்று இன்றைய நிலையை அடைந்ததெனலாம். கண்ணாடி, இன்றைய கட்டிடங்களில், நவீனத்துவத்தின் பிரதிபலிப்பாக விளங்குகிறது."},{"question":" hadraawi maxaa loogu bixiyey ","answer":" waxa loogu bixiyey wuu hadal badnaa carabta ayaa u bixisey"},{"question":"¿Cuál es el nombre oficial de México?","answer":"El nombre oficial de México es Estados Unidos Mexicanos."},{"question":"من الشاعر الذي لقب(الببغاء)؟","answer":"أبو الفرج عبدالواحد بن نصر النصيبني هو واحد الاديب وشاعر عاش فالعصر العباسي تولد تقريبا ف 313 هجريه وكانت الولادو دياله فمدينه نصيبين اللي كاينه حاليا فالحدود التركيه وهو من اصول ديال بني مخزوم من قبيله قريش وكيتلقب بالببغاء لانه عندو واحد العيب اصاب اللسان ديالو وكانت عندو صله مع سيف الدوله فحلب وكان كايسافر بين حلب ودمشق وبغداد وتماك فين تلاقى بالمتنبي. وفي الاخير استقر في الموصل وتوفى سنه 398 هجريه"},{"question":"Cé hé Penny Marshall. ","answer":"Ba bhan-aisteoir agus stiúrthóir Meiriceánach í Carole Penny Marshall, a rugadh ar an 15 Deireadh Fómhair 1943. Cailleadh í ar an 17 Nollaig 2018 de bharr fadhbanna a bhain le diaibéiteas."},{"question":"கேள்வி : இவர் யாருடைய பற்றின் காரணமாக தனது பெயரை மாற்றினார்? ","answer":"பதில் : பாரதிதாசன்."},{"question":"ప్రభుత్వ ఖర్చు వివరాలను, మీ ప్రాంత వార్తాపత్రికల్లో సేకరించి జాబితా రాయండి.","answer":"విద్యారంగం – 1200 కోట్లుఆరోగ్యరంగం – 400 కోట్లువ్యవసాయరంగం – 1000 కోట్లుగృహ నిర్మాణం, పట్టణాభివృద్ధి – 300 కోట్లుగ్రామీణాభివృద్ధి – 400 కోట్లువిద్యుత్, నీటి పారుదల వరదల నియంత్రణ – 600 కోట్లుఎరువుల సబ్సిడీ – 200 కోట్లురైల్వేలు, రవాణా, కమ్యూనికేషన్స్ – 600 కోట్లు.రక్షణ రంగం – 700 కోట్లుపరిపాలన ఖర్చులు – 800 కోట్లు"},{"question":"O ṣẹlẹ, awọn eeyan Okelisa fi ayajọ ranṣẹ sawọn to n ji waya ina wọn l’Ondo","answer":"Pẹlu ibinu lawọn eeyan agbegbe Okelisa, niluu Ondo, fi tu jade lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, oni lati fẹhonu han si bi awọn ole kan ṣe n fi igba gbogbo ji waya ina wọn ka lọ.Irọlẹ ana lawọn eeyan agbegbe ọhun kọkọ ko ara wọn jọ si idi ẹrọ amunawa ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ ka waya rẹ lọ naa, nibi ti wọn ti jiroro lori igbesẹ to yẹ ki wọn gbe lati fopin si iru iṣẹlẹ bẹẹ lọjọ iwaju.Gbogbo awọn agbaagba atawọn to mọ ọwọ yi pada to wa nibẹ ni wọn pa ẹnu pọ gbe awọn to n fi igba gbogbo sọ wọn sinu okunkun biribiri ọhun ṣepe ki wọn too lọọ fi iṣẹlẹ naa to awọn ọlọpaa teṣan Ẹnuọwa leti.Aarọ kutukutu oni ni wọn lọ si olu-ileeṣẹ BEDC to wa loju ọna marosẹ Ademulẹgun lati fi ẹdun ọkan wọn han awọn to n mojuto ina ọba niluu Ondo ọhun.Abilekọ Ileọla Ibrahim to ṣaaju awọn to n fẹhonu han yii di ẹbi waya ti wọn n ji ka naa le awọn oṣiṣẹ BEDC lori, o ni ko ṣee ṣe ki ẹni ti ko ba mọ nipa ina maa ṣe iru iṣẹ laabi bẹẹ kiri. Awọn waya ẹrọ amunawa to wa lawọn agbegbe bii Ọpẹoluwa, Surulere, Ade Super ati Okelisa lo ni awọn oniṣẹẹbi ọhun ka lọ laarin ọsẹ kan pere, eii to mu kawọn eeyan wa ninu okunkun lati igba naa.Gbogbo akitiyan wa lati ri Alukoro ileeṣẹ BEDC nipinlẹ Ondo ba sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ naa lo ja si pabo."},{"question":"เหตุการณ์สำคัญของข้อความต่อไปนี้คืออะไร: จากการแพ้ในนัดชิงชนะเลิศ 3 ทัวร์นาเมนต์ทีมชาติติดต่อกัน (ฟุตบอลโลก 2014, โกปาอาเมริกา 2015 และ โกปาอาเมริกา เซนเตนาริโอ) และเมื่อรวมครั้ง โกปาอาเมริกา 2007 ด้วย จะเป็นการแพ้นัดชิงชนะเลิศกับทีมชาติครั้งที่ 4 ของเมสซิ ทำให้เขาเจ็บปวดมาก และตัดสินใจประกาศเลิกเล่นทีมชาติในทันทีหลังจบเกม เขากล่าวว่า\\"ผมพยายามอย่างที่สุดแล้ว ทีมชาติกับผมมันจบลงแล้ว มันเจ็บที่ไม่ได้แชมป์ และออกไปทั้งที่ยังไม่ประสบความสำเร็จ ผมแพ้นัดชิงชนะเลิศมา 4 ครั้งแล้ว เป็น 3 ครั้งติดต่อกัน มันเป็นเรื่องเจ็บปวดและน่าเสียดาย เราพยายามแล้วแต่มันไม่ใช่ของเรา ก็เท่านั้น\\" หลังจาก เมสซิ และ มัสเชราโน ประกาศเลิกเล่นทีมชาติ มีการออกมาเรียกร้องให้เขาเปลี่ยนใจ เมื่อเขาเดินทางกลับมาถึงกรุงบัวโนสไอเรส ก็มีแฟนบอลทีมชาติอาร์เจนตินาไปรอต้อนรับพร้อมแคมเปญ \\"อย่าไปเลย เลโอ\\" กลายเป็นวาระแห่งชาติของอาร์เจนตินา ที่แม้แต่ประธานาธิบดีของอาร์เจนตินาในขณะนั้น เมาริซิโอ มากริ ยังออกมาขอร้องให้เขาอยู่ต่อ โดยกล่าวว่า \\"พวกเราโชคดี มันเป็นความสุขของชีวิต มันเป็นของขวัญจากพระเจ้า ที่ให้ประเทศที่รักฟุตบอลอย่างเรา มีนักฟุตบอลที่ดีที่สุดในโลกอยู่ ลิโอเนล เมสซิ เป็นสิ่งที่ดีที่สุดที่ประเทศเรามี พวกเราต้องดูแลเขา\\"","answer":"โกปาอาเมริกา เซนเตนาริโอ"},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள் - 2011-ஆம் ஆண்டில் பிரான்ஸ் தேசிய காற்பந்து அணிக்காக முதன்முறையாக விளையாடினார். இன்றுவரை 50 முறைகளுக்கு மேல் பங்கேற்றுள்ள இவர் யூரோ 2012","answer":"மற்றும் 2014 உலகக்கோப்பை காற்பந்து போட்டித்தொடர்களில் காலிறுதியை எட்டிய அணியில் இடம்பெற்றவர்."},{"question":" O que mede o ano-luz?","answer":"Distância."},{"question":"கேள்வி: புத்தரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"பதில்:பொறுமைதான் மிக உயர்ந்த பிரார்த்தனை.குறிப்பு :கௌதம புத்தர் என்பவர் கி.மு 563க்கும், கி.மு 483க்கும் இடையில் வாழ்ந்தவர். இவரை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டு பௌத்த சமயம் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது. இவர் கிறித்து பிறப்பதற்கு ஆறு நூற்றாண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பே வாழ்ந்திருக்கலாம் என்ற நம்பிக்கையை உறுதிப்படுத்தக்கூடிய, ஒரு பழமையான பௌத்த வழிபாட்டுத் தலத்தை தாம் கண்டறிந்துள்ளதாக நேபாளத்தில் உள்ள அகழ்வாய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். இவரது இயற்பெயர் “சித்தார்த்த கௌதமர்” என்பதாகும். பின்னர் இவர் ஞானம் பெற்று புத்தர் ஆனார். இவர் \\"சாக்கிய முனி\\" என்றும் அழைக்கப்பட்டார்.புத்த சமயத்தின் மிகவும் முக்கியமானவரென்ற வகையில், கௌதமருடைய வாழ்க்கையையும், வழி காட்டல்களையும், துறவிமட விதிகளையுமே, கௌதமரின் மறைவுக்குப்பின், சுருக்கி பௌத்த பிக்குகள் மனனம் செய்துவந்தார்கள். அவற்றுள் மிக முக்கியமானதாக தம்மபதம் விளங்குகிறது, பிற மத நூல்களைப் போன்று அல்லாமல் இந்நூல் மக்களின் சாதாரண பேச்சு வழக்கில் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது. மேலும் எளிய நடை இதன் சிறப்பம்சம் ஆகும். குரு - சீட பரம்பரையூடாக வாய்மொழி மூலம் கடத்தப்பட்டு வந்த இத்தகவல்கள், 100 வருடங்களுக்குப் பின்னர் திரிபிடகம் என்று வழங்கப்படும் நூலாக எழுத்துவடிவம் பெற்றது."},{"question":"Awọn Fulani tun ya wọ Ikọtun, ni Kwara, lawọn araalu ba le wọn pada","answer":"Ileeṣẹ aabo ẹni laabo ilu, NSCDC, ẹka tipinlẹ Kwara, ti ṣawari ibudo kan tawọn Fulani darandaran ti wọn wọ ilu wa laarin oru tẹdo si niluu Ikọtun, nipinlẹ Kwara.ALAROYE gbọ pe ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọjọ kọkanla, oṣu karun-un, lawọn araalu ṣadeede ri awọn Fulani ọhun pẹlu ọpọlọpọ ẹru ti wọn ru wa, nibi ti wọn gunlẹ si.Alukoro NSCDC, Babawale Zaid Afọlabi, sọ pe ilu Ikọtun lo ta ajọ naa lolobo nipa awọn ajeji ti wọn ṣadeede ri ti wọn n ya wọnu ilu wọn wa naa.O ni lai fi akoko ṣofo, Kabiyesi Olukọtun pe awọn ọdẹ, fijilante ilu atawọn ẹṣọ alaabo; ọlọpaa, NSCDC, DSS, si ipade pajawiri lati wa ọna bi wọn ṣe maa le awọn Fulani naa pada sibi ti wọn ti wa.Afọlabi ni nigba tawọn beere ohun ti wọn n wa, idahun wọn ni pe ilu Kaiama, nipinlẹ Kwara, lawọn ti wa, ibatan awọn kan to n jẹ Tambaya lawọn waa ba lati jọ maa gbe papọ ati ̀lati maa ṣiṣẹ oko.O ni lẹyin ipade naa ilu ni awọn ko fẹ wọn lọdọ awọn, ni wọn ba paṣẹ pe ki wọn pada sibi ti wọn ti n bọ ki ilẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, too ṣu."},{"question":"በእርግጥ የኤሌክትሪክ ኃይል ምንድን ነው? ሀ. የውሃ ፍሰት ለ. የአየር ፍሰት ሐ. የኤሌክትሮኖች ፍሰት መ. የአተሞች ፍሰት","answer":"ሐ"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Risteárd Ó Glaisne. ","answer":"Scoláire, múinteoir, fear léinn agus iriseoir ab ea Risteárd Earnán Ó Glaisne. Ba líonmhar a chuid scríbhinní – idir leabhair, phrós agus ailt iriseoireachta agus teastaíonn léitheoireacht leathan dá réir le tuiscint chruinn a fháil ar an bhfear agus ar a dhearcadh ar an saol. Bhí sé ildánach agus bhí suim aige i ngach gné de shaíocht agus de shaol na Gaeilge. D’éag se in aois 76 sa bhliain 2003. Rugadh Risteárd i gceantar Dhoire Garbh Thoir tamall ó Dhroichead na Bandan, Co. Chorcaí ar 2 Meán Fómhair 1927. Ba é an tríú duine é den cheathrar clainne a bhí ag George William Giles agus a bhean Sara Jane Vickery. Feirmeoirí ba ea a shinsir agus cónaí sa cheantar sin ar mhuintir Giles le 350 bliain um an taca seo.Modhach ab ea é agus fuair sé a chuid oideachais sa Scoil Ghramadaí Dhroichead na Bandan agus ina dhiaidh sin i gColáiste na Tríonóide i mBaile Átha Cliath.Ar an drochuair, tholg sé an eitinn bhuaibheach agus é ina leanbh óg, rud a rinne dochar dá chromán agus a d’fhág céim bhacaí ann ar feadh a shaoil."},{"question":"Apakah latar belakang NTV7 di Malaysia?","answer":"Natseven TV Sdn Bhd atau lebih dikenali sebagai NTV7 merupakan salah sebuah stesen televisyen swasta terestrial nasional di Malaysia yang menawarkan rancangan dalam Bahasa Melayu, Inggeris dan Mandarin. Ia memulakan siarannya pada 7 April 1998 di mana pada waktu ini belum lagi dilancarkan di negeri-negeri semenanjung Malaysia dan Sabah. Antara rancangan yang berkualiti dari NTV7 ialah My News Network. Pada 28 Oktober 2005, NTV7 dibeli oleh Media Prima pada harga pertimbangan RM90 juta.Dengan pengambilalihan oleh Media Prima, NTV7 berbeza dari stesen lain dalam industri penyiaran Malaysia dari segi ia berada dalam kategori jenama media bukan stesen televisyen (ironinya semua TV berbayar di Malaysia berada dalam kategori yang sama sambil memainkan peranannya sebagai penyedia TV berbayar). Program-program NTV7 diperlakukan sebagai produk di bawah jenama yang berkaitan - lebih sering disebut sebagai sabuk pengaturcaraan, dan dikendalikan oleh pasukan pengurus jenama.Konsep berdasarkan pelantikan juga baru bagi industri penyiaran Malaysia, di mana faktor-faktor, seperti siapa yang menonton dan bila, menentukan bila sebuah program ditempatkan dalam jadual TV. Stesen NTV7 ke udara pada julat frekuensi UHF menawarkan program bahasa Melayu, Inggeris dan Cina yang dihasilkan oleh produksi tempatan serta beberapa program dari luar negara.NTV7 menyiarkan pelbagai jenis rancangan contohnya drama, komedi (sitkom), rancangan berbentuk hiburan, rancangan permainan, program kanak-kanak dan lain-lain. Siaran berita juga disediakan dalam tiga bahasa iaitu Edisi 7, 7 Edition dan Mandarin 7. Rancangan ini telah ditamatkan siaran dan digantikan oleh Buletin 1:30 dan Buletin Pagi, hasil sumbangan TV3, manakala 7 Edition dan Mandarin 7 telah rasmi dihentikan dan telah rasmi semua program berita berbahasa Inggeris dan Cina akan dipindahkan ke Nightline di TV3 dan 8TV Mandarin News di 8TV.Logo NTV7 ini diolah daripada logo stesen penyiaran Amerika Syarikat, American Broadcasting Company (ABC). Malaysia menjadi negara pertama di Asia Tenggara yang memiliki versi sendiri rancangan ini.Saat ini NTV7 disiarkan dalam Frekuensi UHF. Di Lembah Klang, saluran UHF adalah 35 (dari Menara Kuala Lumpur) dan 37 (dari Gunung Ulu Kali). Penghantaran Frekuensi VHF juga terdapat di saluran 7 (dari Bukit Sungai Besi) tetapi hanya terdapat di Lembah Klang sahaja. NTV7 kini bersiaran di MYTV dan Unifi TV di saluran 107 dan di Astro di saluran 147. "},{"question":"Амнион деген эмне ?","answer":"Амнион (эмбр.) — амнион; каканактын ички чели, түйүлдүктү сыртынан чулгап  туруучу, суу толгон чел. Омурткалуу айбандарда (сойлоктордо, куштарда,  желиндүүлөрдө) кезигет. "},{"question":"Parí ìròyìn yìí:Lori iku Mohbad: Awọn ọlọpaa ti mu Naira MarleyAfaimọ ni ki i ṣe orin ‘kaabọ, ṣe daadaa lo de, a ti n reti rẹ’ lawọn ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko fi ki Afeez Faṣọla, tawọn eeyan mɔọ si Naira Marley kaabọ lati ilu oyinbo to ti n bọ, pẹlu bawọn agbofinro ọhun ṣe gan an lapa lati papakọ ofurufu Muritala Mohammed to wa niluu Ikẹja, nipinlẹ ọhun, lalẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọjọ kẹta, oṣu Kẹwaa ọdun 2023 yii, ti wọn si fi pampẹ ofin mu un lọ sakolo wọn.Eyi ko ṣẹyin iwadii ijinlẹ ti ikọ awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ẹlẹni mẹtala kan ti Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko gbe kalẹ lọsẹ meji sẹyin n ṣe lati tuṣu desalẹ ikoko,  ki wọn si wa fin-in idi koko iṣẹlẹ iku ojiji to pa gbajugbaja olorin taka-sufee nni, Oloogbe Ilerioluwa Ọladimeji Alọba, tawọn eeyan mọ si MohBad.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, SP Benjamin Hundeyin lo sọrọ yii di mimọ loju opo Twitter rẹ ti wọn n pe ni X bayii. O kọ ọ sori ẹrọ ayelujara ọhun pe:“A ti mu Azeez Faṣọla, ti inagijẹ rẹ n jẹ Naira Marley, a si ti mu un lọ si akata awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ fun iwadii ati ibeere gbogbo to tan mọ ohun ta a n wadii rẹ.” Ọrọ ṣoki to sọ ọhun ko ju bẹẹ lọ.Iwadii ALAROYE fihan pe nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an ku ogun iṣẹju lalẹ ọjọ Tusidee ọhun ni Naira Marley sọkalẹ ninu baaluu to gbe e gunlẹ si papakọ ofurufu n’Ikẹja, ko si ju iṣẹju diẹ lẹyin naa tawọn ọlọpaa ti wọn ti n duro de e mu un lọ taara sinu ọkọ wọn, ti wọn si gbe e lọ si ẹka ileeṣẹ itọpinpin wọn to wa ni Panti, lagbegbe Yaba, ibẹ ni igbakeji Kọmiṣanna, DCP Waheed Ayilara, ti ki i kaabọ, ti wọn si jọ wọnu ile lọ.","answer":"Ki wọn too mu un ni ọkunrin tawọn eeyan n fẹsun hihuwa aidaa si Mohbad kan ọhun ti kede ipadabọ rẹ si Naijiria loju opo ayelujara tuita rẹ lọjọ Tusidee naa, o ni tori koun le ran awọn ọlọpaa lọwọ lori iwadii iku Mohbad ti wọn n ṣe loun ṣe de, o ni inu oun dun si ki idajọ ododo waye lori iṣẹlẹ ọhun.Ẹ oo ranti pe ọkunrin yii, ati ọrẹ rẹ kan, Sam Larry, iyẹn Samson Balogun Eletu, wa lara awọn afurasi ti ẹnu n kun gidi lori iku ojiji to pa oloogbe Mohbad. Latigba tiṣẹlẹ buruku ọhun ti waye lọjọ kejila, oṣu Kẹsan-an, to kọja yii, lọpọ awuyewuye ti gba igboro kan lori ohun to ṣokunfa iku aitọjọ naa, tori ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlọgbọn pere ni oloogbe yii. Asiko ti irawọ rẹ si n tan ni oṣupa onkọrin naa wọọkun lojiji. Latigba naa lawọn eeyan kan ti pariwo ki wọn mu Naira Marley, ki wọn mu Sam Larry lori ẹrọ ayelujara.Amọ ṣa o, Naira Marley ti sọ ninu awọn fidio kan pe ọwọ oun ko si nidii iku oloogbe yii, o ni ọtọ ni ibi ti iku ẹ ti wa."},{"question":"ਔਰਤ ਫੁਟਪਾਥ 'ਤੇ ਡਿੱਗ ਗਈ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਸੀਮਿੰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਰਾਰ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਨਾਮ ਪੁਕਾਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਸੁਣਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਸੀਮਿੰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਰਾਰ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Ingakanani imali eyabelwa ukwakhiwa kodonga emngceleni weMelika neMexico?","answer":"Imali yakhona iyi. 21.6 bhiliyoni."},{"question":"ආලය යනු ගෘහයට තවත්  නමක්ද?","answer":"යම් දෙයක් ඇති තැන.ශාස්ත්‍ර ඇති තැන ශාස්ත්‍රාලයස්වර ඇති තැන ස්වරාලයහිම ඇති තැන හිමාලයවිද්‍යාව ඇති තැන විද්‍යාලයපොත් ඇති තැන පුස්තකාලයආලය යනු ගෘහවාචීපදයකි.දේව+ආලය,බුද්ධ+ආලය,කාර්ය+ආලය,ප්‍රතිමා+ආලය,ශාස්ත්‍ර+ආලය වචන නිදර්ශනයි."},{"question":"Торгун - cөзүнүн түшүндүрмөсү кандай ?","answer":"Торгун - жибек кездеме, бышык жибек,"},{"question":"Complete the following phrase:  Pada saat kematian tanpa keturunan laki-laki saudara tirinya, Raja Fernando I, pada bulan Oktober 1383, upaya keras dilakukan untuk menjamin suksesi Beatriz, putri tunggal Fernando. Sebagai Pewaris dugaan, Beatriz telah menikah dengan Raja Juan I dari Kastila, namun sentimen populer menentang pengaturan di mana Portugal hampir dapat dianeksasi oleh Kastila.","answer":"Perjuangan untuk mempertahankan kemerdekaan Portugal mencapai puncaknya dalam apa yang dikenal sebagai Krisis 1383-1385. Pada akhirnya, John dari Aviz berhasil naik takhta sebagai Raja John I dari Portugal pada tahun 1385, dan Portugal berhasil mempertahankan kemerdekaannya dari upaya aneksasi Kastila."},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన సినిమా పాటలోని ఒక భాగం యొక్క సాహిత్యంపై విశ్లేషణ చెయ్యండిఅంబా పరాకు దేవీ పరాకుమమ్మేలు మా శారదంబా పరాకుఅంబా పరాకు దేవీ పరాకుమమ్మేలు మా శారదంబా పరాకుఉమా మహేశ్వర ప్రసాద లబ్ధ పూర్ణ జీవనా గజాననా..బహుపరాక్ బహుపరాక్…చండభుజాయమండల దోధూయమాన వైరిగణా.. షడాననాబహుపరాక్ బహుపరాక్…","answer":"అంటూ కళాధిదేవతయైన సరస్వతి ప్రార్ధనతో ప్రారంభిస్తూ  తలపెట్టిన కార్యక్రమం నిర్విఘ్నంగా పూర్తవడానికి గణపతిని, తలచిన కార్యాన్ని నిర్వహించే శక్తిని ప్రసాదించమని సుబ్రహ్మణ్యుని ప్రార్ధిస్తూ  విజయవాడకు 60 కి.మీ.దూరంలో ఉంది కూచిపూడి గ్రామం. ఒకప్పుడు దీనిపేరు కుశీలపురం. అది కాలక్రమేణా కూచెన్నపూడిగా మారి కూచిపూడిగా స్ధిరపడిందని చరిత్రకారుల అభిప్రాయం.  ఈ స్తుతిలో మనం కూచిపూడి గ్రామ పరిసర ప్రాంతాల్లో ఉన్న దేవాలయాల్లోని మూర్తుల స్తుతి కూడా కనిపిస్తుంది."},{"question":" மயிலையார் ஓர் “ஆராய்ச்சிப் பேரறிஞர்” என்னும் கூற்றினைச் சான்றுகளுடன் கட்டுரைக்க.","answer":"முன்னுரை:• ஒவ்வொரு தேசிய இனமும் தன்னுடைய கடந்தகால வரலாற்றை அறிந்திருந்தால் மட்டுமே ‘ எதிர்கால இலக்குகளை அடைய முடியும்.• அத்தகைய இன வரலாற்றை இலக்கியம், தொல்லியல், கல்வெட்டு, பண்பாடு ஆகியவற்றின் அடிப்படையில் தரவுகளைத் தேடி எழுதிய ஆளுமைகளில் முக்கியமானவர் மயிலை சீனி. வேங்கடசாமி.• இதழ் ஆசிரியராக வாழ்க்கையைத் தொடங்கிய அவர், பள்ளி ஆசிரியராகப் பணியாற்றியபடியே எழுதி முடித்த புத்தகங்களே, தமிழர் தம் பழம்பெருமையை உணர, உதவும் புதையலாக விளங்குகிறது.தொடக்ககால ஆய்வுகள்:• 1934 இல் தெ. பொ. மீனாட்சி சுந்தரனார் சிந்தாதிரிப்பேட்டை உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளியில் நடத்திய தமிழ் ஆராய்ச்சி மாநாட்டில் ச.த. சற்குணர், கிறித்துவமும் தமிழும் என்ற பொருள் குறித்து உரையாற்றினார்.• அவ்வுரையைக் கேட்டுப் பெற்ற ஆர்வத்தினால் ‘கிறித்துவமும் தமிழும்’ என்னும் நூலை மயிலையார் எழுதினார். இதுவே அவருடைய முதல் நூலாகும்.• தமிழின் தொல் இலக்கியம், தொல் கலை, தொல்லெழுத்து ஆகியவற்றில் கொண்ட ஈடுபாடு காரணமாக, ‘பௌத்தமும் தமிழும்’, ‘சமணமும் தமிழும்’ ஆகிய நூல்களை அவர் இயற்றினார்.• சமயம், மானுடவியல், தமிழக வரலாறு, தொல்பொருள் ஆய்வு, கலை வரலாறு, மொழியாய்வு முதலான பல துறைகளிலும் இவர் கவனம் செலுத்தினார்.• குறிப்பாக, கல்வெட்டு ஆய்வில் இவருக்குப் பயிற்சி அதிகம். தமிழ் எழுத்தியலின் வளர்ச்சியை நன்குணர்ந்தவர். வட்டெழுத்து, கோலெழுத்து. தமிழ் பிராமி ஆகியவற்றில் புலமை பெற்றிருந்த காரணத்தால் சாசனங்களை அவரால் எளிதாக வாசிக்க முடிந்தது.• வரலாறு, இலக்கியம், கலையியல், சமயம் எனப் பல துறைகளிலும் நூல்களை எழுதியிருப்பது வேங்கடசாமியின் பன்முக அறிவை விளக்குகிறது.வரலாற்று ஆய்வு :• மகேந்திரவர்மன், நரசிம்மவர்மன் ஆகியோர் குறித்த நூல்களைத் தொடர்ந்து மூன்றாம் நந்திவர்மன் என்னும் பல்லவ மன்னனைப் பற்றியும் அவர் எழுதினார்.• தமிழில் அம்மன்னனைப் பற்றி எழுதப்பட்ட முதல் நூல் என்னும் பெருமையைப் பெற்றது.• சங்க கால மூவேந்தர்கள், கொங்குநாட்டு மன்னர்கள், துளு நாட்டு மன்னர்கள், களப்பிரர் மற்றும் இலங்கை குறித்த வரலாறு ஆகியவற்றையும் எழுதியுள்ளார்.• சங்க காலத்துக்குப் பிற்பட்ட காலத்தில் தமிழகத்தைக் களப்பிரர்கள் என்ற மன்னர்கள் ஆட்சி புரிந்தனர். இக்காலம் தமிழர்களின் வரலாற்றில் இருண்ட காலம் என்று மரபுவழிப்பட்ட வரலாற்று ஆசிரியர்கள் குறித்தனர்.• இம்மன்னர்கள் குறித்த ஆய்வை வேங்கடசாமி விரிவாக ஆராய்ந்து களப்பிரர் குறித்த புதிய கண்ணோட்டத்தைக் ‘களப்பிரர் ஆட்சியில் தமிழகம்’ என்னும் நூல் மூலம் வெளிப்படுத்தினார்.கலையியல் ஆய்வு:• கலையியல் சார்ந்து தமிழில் வெளியான பல நூல்களுக்கும் வேங்கடசாமியே வழிகாட்டியாக விளங்கினார்.• தமிழரது கலைத்திறனை எடுத்தோதும் ‘தமிழர் வளர்த்த அழகுக்கலைகள்’ என்னும் நூல், கவின் கலைகள் குறித்துத் தமிழில் வெளிவந்த முழுமையான முதல் நூல் ஆகும்.• இந்நூல் தமிழக அரசின் முதற்பரிசைப் பெற்றது. இறைவன் ஆடிய எழுவகைத் தாண்டவம். நுண்கலைகள், இசைவாணர் கதைகள் ஆகியவை கலை பற்றிய இவருடைய பிற நூல்கள் ஆகும். • தமது நூல்களின் படங்களைத் தானே வரைந்து வெளியிட்டது இவரது கலைத்திறனுக்குச் சான்றாகும்.கல்வெட்டு ஆய்வுகள்:• சங்ககாலத் தமிழக வரலாற்றில் சில செய்திகள், பழங்காலத் தமிழர் வணிகம், களப்பிரர் ஆட்சியில் தமிழகம், கொங்கு நாட்டு வரலாறு, தமிழ்நாட்டு வரலாறு – சங்க காலம் (அரசியல்) ஆகிய நூல்களையும் எழுதினார்.• ஆய்வுலகில் மயிலை சீனி. வேங்கடசாமியின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பங்களிப்பைக் கூற வேண்டுமானால் தமிழக வரலாற்றினைப் பல கோணங்களில் மீட்டுருவாக்கம் செய்ததைக் குறிப்பிடலாம். தமிழ்நாட்டு வரலாறு என்னும் நூல் இவருடைய மீட்டுருவாக்க முயற்சிக்குச் சரியான சான்றாகும்.• தமிழியலுக்குத் தேவையான பல்வேறு ஆவணங்களையும் தொகுத்து ஆய்வு செய்யும் பணியை இவர் மேற்கொண்டார். இப்பணியின் விளைவாக, சாசனச் செய்யுள் மஞ்சரி, மறைந்துபோன தமிழ்நூல்கள் ஆகிய நூல்களை எழுதினார்.பன்மொழிப் புலமை:• தமிழ் ஆய்வு மரபில், சொல் ஆய்வுகளை மேற்கொள்ளாத ஆய்வாளர் இல்லை. நீண்ட வரலாறு கொண்ட மொழியின் சொற்களில் இவ்வகையான ஆய்வுக்குரிய ஏதுக்கள் மிகுதியாகும். வேங்கடசாமி தொடர்ச்சியாக இத்தகைய சொல்லாய்வுப் பணியை மேற்கொண்டு வந்துள்ளார். ‘செந்தமிழ்ச் செல்வி’ என்னும் இதழில் அவர் எழுதிய சொல்லாய்வுக் கட்டுரைகள் ‘அஞ்சிறைத் தும்பி’ என்ற தொகுப்பாக வெளியிடப்பட்டது.• மகேந்திரவர்மன் இயற்றிய ‘மத்த விலாசம்’ என்ற நாடக நூலை ஆங்கிலம் வழியாகத் தமிழாக்கியுள்ளார்.• தமிழ்ப் பண்பாட்டிலும் தமிழர் வரலாற்றிலும் ஆழ்ந்த அக்கறை கொண்ட மயிலை சீனி. அவர்கள் தமிழர் பண்பாட்டின் தனித்தன்மையை நிறுவுவதில் உறுதியான பார்வை கொண்டவர்.ஆராய்ச்சிப் பேரறிஞர்:• மயிலை சீனியாரால் பல ஆய்வுகள் தமிழுலகுக்கு முதன்முதலாக வழங்கப்பட்டவை. இவரது ஆய்வுகள் அறிஞருக்கு மட்டுமன்றிப் பொதுமக்களுக்கும் அறிவு விருந்தோம்பியவை.• பல ஆய்வுகள் கிளைவிடுவதற்கு அடிமரமாக இருந்தவை. இவரது ஆய்வுகள், வேண்டாத நூலிது என்றோ நூலில் வேண்டாத பகுதி என்றோ ஒதுக்க முடியாத வகையில் இவரது எழுத்தாளுமை திகழ்ந்தது.முடிவுரை:• தமிழக வரலாற்றுக் கழகத்திலும் தமிழகப் புலவர் குழுவிலும் உறுப்பினராக இருந்து பெருந்தொண்டாற்றிய வேங்கடசாமிக்கு 1962இல் தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர் சங்கம் பாராட்டிக் கேடயம் வழங்கியது.• மதுரைக் காமராசர் பல்கலைக்கழகம் தமிழ்ப் பேரவைச் செம்மல்’ என்ற விருதினை அளித்தது.• தமது ஓயாத தேடலினாலும் கடுமையான உழைப்பாலும் அரிய ஆய்வு முடிவுகளைக் கொணர்ந்த இம்மாமனிதருக்கு அறிஞர்கள் கூடிச் சென்னை கோகலே மண்டபத்தில் மணிவிழா எடுத்து ஆராய்ச்சிப் பேரறிஞர்’ என்ற பட்டத்தை வழங்கினார்."},{"question":"Níbo ni ẹmu ògùrọ̀ tí má ń jáde?","answer":"Orí igi ọ̀pẹ"},{"question":"Categorize various traditional Japanese customs, including hanami, and their role in cultural celebrations.","answer":"සම්ප්‍රදායික ජපන් සිරිත් විරිත් සහ සංස්කෘතික සැමරුම් වලදී ඔවුන්ගේ කාර්යභාරය:1. හනමි (මල් බැලීම):    - භූමිකාව: චෙරි මල් සමය තුළ සමරනු ලබන අතර, එය චෙරි මල් වල තාවකාලික සුන්දරත්වය අගය කිරීම ඇතුළත් වේ. පිපෙන චෙරි ගස් යට විනෝද චාරිකා සඳහා මිනිසුන් එක්රැස් වන අතර, ප්‍රජාව පිළිබඳ හැඟීමක් සහ සොබාදහමේ සුන්දරත්වය අගය කරයි.2. ඔබන් උත්සවය:    - භූමිකාව: මුතුන් මිත්තන්ගේ ආත්මයන්ට ගෞරව කරන බෞද්ධ උත්සවයක්. පවුල් සොහොන්වලට ගොස්, පහන් දල්වා සාම්ප්‍රදායික නර්තනයට (බොන් ඔඩෝරි) සහභාගී වේ. එය පවුල් සහ මුතුන් මිත්තන්ගේ සම්බන්ධතාවයේ හැඟීමක් ඇති කරයි.3. ෂොගට්සු (අලුත් අවුරුද්ද):    - භූමිකාව: පූජනීය ස්ථාන පිරිසිදු කිරීම, අලංකාර කිරීම සහ සංචාරය කිරීම සම්බන්ධ ප්‍රධාන උත්සවයකි. එය නව ආරම්භයක් සනිටුහන් කරයි, hatsumode (පළමු සිද්ධස්ථාන සංචාරය) සහ සමෘද්ධිය සංකේතවත් කරන සම්ප්‍රදායික ආහාර වැනි ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සමඟින්.4. Gōnensai (වයසට එන දිනය):    - භූමිකාව: නීත්‍යානුකූල වැඩිහිටිභාවයේ වයස සනිටුහන් කරමින් වයස අවුරුදු 20 සම්පූර්ණ කරන අය සමරයි. වගකීම් සහ පරිණත බව අවධාරණය කරමින් සාම්ප්‍රදායික ඇඳුමින් සැරසී තරුණ වැඩිහිටියන් උත්සවවලට සහභාගි වෙති.5. Seijin-no-Hi (වයසට පැමිණෙන දිනය):    - භූමිකාව: Gōnensai හා සමානව, එය 20 වැනි සංවත්සරය සමරයි. තරුණ වැඩිහිටියන් උත්සවවලට සහභාගී වේ, වගකීම් පිළිබිඹු කරමින් සහ සැමරුම්වලට සහභාගී වේ.6. හීනා මත්සුරි (බෝනික්කන් උත්සවය):    - භූමිකාව: ගැහැණු ළමයින්ගේ යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා සමරනු ලැබේ. පවුල් විසිතුරු බෝනික්කන් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරන අතර ගැහැණු ළමයින් නපුරු ආත්මයන් දුරු කිරීමට සහ සමෘද්ධිමත් අනාගතයක් සහතික කිරීම සඳහා චාරිත්‍ර වාරිත්‍රවලට සහභාගී වේ.7. O-Bon (ආත්මයන්ගේ උත්සවය):    - භූමිකාව: මියගිය මුතුන් මිත්තන්ට ගෞරව කරයි. පවුල් පහන් දල්වා සොහොන් වෙත ගොස් නැටුම් සමඟ ආත්මයන් පිළිගනිති. ජීවත්ව සිටින අය සහ මියගිය අය අතර සම්බන්ධය සංකේතවත් කරයි.8. Shichi-Go-San (හත-පහ-තුන):    - භූමිකාව: වයස අවුරුදු 3, 5, සහ 7 දී දරුවන්ගේ වර්ධනය සමරයි. පවුල් පූජනීය ස්ථාන වෙත ගොස්, සෞඛ්‍යය සහ සමෘද්ධිය සඳහා යාඥා කරයි, සහ දරුවන් සම්ප්‍රදායික ඇඳුමෙන් සැරසී සිටිති.9. Ohanami Gyoretsu (Cherry Blossom Parade):    - භූමිකාව: චෙරි මල් සමයේ උත්සව පෙළපාලියක්, සම්ප්‍රදායික ඇඳුම්, සංගීතය සහ පාවෙන. චෙරි මල් සැමරීම වැඩි දියුණු කරයි.10. ගණේෂ (අලුත් අවුරුදු උදාව):     - භූමිකාව: නිවෙස් පිරිසිදු කිරීම, පන්සල්වලට යාම සහ සංකේතාත්මක ආහාර අනුභව කිරීම ඇතුළත් වේ. විහාරස්ථානවල ඝණ්ඨාර නාද කිරීම සංකේතවත් කරන්නේ පෙර වසරේ විපත් ඉවත් කර අලුත් අවුරුද්ද පිළිගැනීමයි.11.  සුකිමි (සඳ බැලීම):     - භූමිකාව: සරත් සෘතුවේ පුර පසළොස්වක පොහොය තුළ සමරනු ලැබේ. බොහෝ විට සෘතුමය ආහාර සහ සැරසිලි සමඟින් සඳෙහි සුන්දරත්වය අගය කිරීමට මිනිසුන් රැස් වෙති.12. Kadomatsu සහ Shimenawa (අලුත් අවුරුදු සැරසිලි):     - භූමිකාව: දීර්ඝායුෂ සහ සංශුද්ධතාවය සංකේතවත් කරන පයින් සහ උණ බම්බු වලින් සාදන ලද සැරසිලි. සෞභාග්‍යයට ආරාධනා කිරීම සහ නපුරු ආත්මයන් පලවා හැරීම සඳහා නව වසර තුළ පිවිසුම් දොරටුවල තබා ඇත.මෙම චාරිත්ර ජපන් සංස්කෘතිය තුළ වැදගත් කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කරයි, ප්රජාව පිළිබඳ හැඟීමක් පෝෂණය කිරීම, සම්ප්රදායන්ට ගරු කිරීම සහ ජීවිතයේ විවිධ පැතිකඩයන්, වර්ධනය සහ අධ්යාත්මිකත්වය සංකේතවත් කරයි."},{"question":"Zafirah ____________ apabila bahunya di__________ kuat oleh Nadia.","answer":"terkejut ... ditepuk"},{"question":"이었다와 이였다를 구별하는 방법이 받침이 있냐 없냐에 따라 다르다던데\\"여름\\"같은 경우엔 받침이 있으니까 여름이었다가 맞는건가요?여름이었다여름이였다두개 비교하니까 -이였다가 맞는것같기두 하고..헷갈리네용","answer":"'-이였다'는 없습니다. '-이었다'와 '-였다'만 있죠.말씀해주신 대로 체언에 받침이 있으면 '-이었다', 없으면 '-였다'가 붙습니다.ex) 여름이었다, 밤이었다, 그녀였다, 소리였다"},{"question":"તમારી શાળાને વર્ગપુસ્તકાલય માટે કેટલાંક પુસ્તકોની જરૂર છે. તે માટે જાણીતા પુસ્તકવિક્રેતાને પત્ર લખો.","answer":"[તમારી શાળા નુ નામ][તમારી શાળા નુ સરનામું][ઈ - મેઈલ][ફોન નંબર][તારીખ]પ્રતિ,વ્યવસ્થાપકશ્રી,[બુક સ્ટોર નુ નામ અને સરનામું]અમારી શાળાના વર્ગપુસ્તકાલય માટે નીચે જણાવેલાં પુસ્તકોની જરૂર છે:ગાલા વિશાલ શબ્દકોશ : ૩ નકલનવનીત ગુજરાતી નિબંધમાળા - ધોરણ ૮ : ૫ નકલનવનીત સામાન્ય જ્ઞાન : ૧૩ નકલ,ઉપર જણાવેલાં પુસ્તકો વી.પી.પી. દ્વારા અમારી શાળાના સરનામે મોકલી આપવા વિનંતી છે. બિલમાં યોગ્ય વટાવ આપશો એવી આશા છે. પુસ્તકોની વિગતવાર નોંધ સાથેનું બિલ જુદી ટપાલ દ્વારા મોકલી આભારી કરશોજી.આપના સહકારની અપેક્ષા સાથે.લિ.આપનો વિશ્વાસુ[તમારું નામ]"},{"question":"Me fale uma curiosidade sobre videogames","answer":"Qual é o videogame com a maior pontuação de todos os tempos, de acordo com o compilador de análises Metacritic? The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time"},{"question":"wanene masanin kimiyya?","answer":"masanin kimiyya kwararre ne wanda ke gudanar da tattara bincike don kara ilimi a wani yanki na musamman"},{"question":"காமாலை நோய்க்கு எலுமிச்சையை எவ்வாறு பயன்படுத்தலாம்?","answer":"மஞ்சள் காமாலை என்பது ஒரு மருத்துவ நிலை, இது உங்கள் தோலையும் உங்கள் கண்ணில் உள்ள வெள்ளை பகுதியையும் மஞ்சள் நிறமாக மாற்றும். எலுமிச்சை  ஒரு அற்புதமான பழமாகும், இது மஞ்சள் காமாலை நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட நோயாளிகளுக்கு மிகவும் பயனுள்ளதாக இருக்கும். எலுமிச்சை சாறு மற்றும் எலுமிச்சை இலைகளை வேகவைத்த தண்ணீரை உட்கொள்வது உங்கள் சேதமடைந்த கல்லீரலுக்கு தேவையான நிவாரணத்தை வழங்க உதவும். பெரும்பாலான நாடுகளில், மஞ்சள் காமாலை நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட நோயாளிகளை, நிறைய எலுமிச்சை சாறு உட்கொள்ளுமாறு மருத்துவர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர். எலுமிச்சைச் சாறுடன் சர்க்கரை கலந்து சாப்பிட்டு வர மஞ்சள் காமாலை, கண் நோய், ஆரம்ப கால யானைக்கால் நோய் ஆகியவை குணப்படும். எலுமிச்சம் பழங்களை ஊறுகாய் போடும் முறை தவறானது. கிச்சிலி மற்றும் நார்த்தங்காய் போன்ற எலுமிச்சங் காய்களையே ஊறுகாய் தயார் செய்ய சிறந்ததாகும். எலுமிச்சம் பழத்தோலை உலர்த்தி தூளாக்கி சம அளவுக்கு பொரித்த படிகாரம் சேர்த்து அரைத்து வைத்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும். உடலில் ஏற்படும் தேமல் என்ற சரும நோய்க்கு இப்பொடியுடன் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீர் சேர்த்து குழைத்து இரவு நேரத்தில் தேகத்தின் மேல்பூசி காலையில் குளித்து வர விரைவில் தேமல் மறையும்."},{"question":"பத்தியைப் படித்து தேவையான இடங்களில் நிறுத்தற்குறிகளை இட்டு எழுதுக:இளங்கோ அடிகள் சாத்தனாரிடம் முன்செய்த வினை நிறைவேறும் காலம் என்றீர்களே அவர்களுடைய முந்தைய வினை யாது அதன் விளைவு என்ன நிகழ்ந்த காலம் யாது அதை நீங்கள் அறிந்திருந்தால் கூறுக எனக் கேட்டார்.","answer":"“இளங்கோ அடிகள் சாத்தனாரிடம்” முன்செய்த வினை நிறைவேறும் காலம் என்றீர்களே! அவர்களுடைய முந்தைய வினை யாது? அதன் விளைவு என்ன? நிகழ்ந்த காலம் யாது? அதை நீங்கள் அறிந்திருந்தால் கூறுக எனக் கேட்டார்."},{"question":"متن زیر را کامل کنید:سرود آفتابکاران جنگل بارها توسط خوانندگان گوناگون مانند شقایق کمالی، شاهکار بینش‌پژوه، نیما مسیحا، پری زنگنه و … بازخوانی شده‌است. همچنین در کمپین انتخاباتی میر حسین موسوی برای انتخابات ریاست جمهوری سال ۱۳۸۸","answer":"از بازخوانی این سرود استفاده شده بود. پس از انتخابات، در اعتراض به سخنان محمود احمدی‌نژاد برنده انتخابات که معترضان به نتیجه رسمی را «چهار تا خس و خاشاک» نامید، برداشت تازه‌ای از آن به نام «نه خارم نه خاشاک» خوانده شد و در اینترنت منتشر شد."},{"question":" மணிமேகலை நூலை இயற்றியவர் யார் ?                                           ","answer":"விடை: சீத்தலைச்சாத்தனார்"},{"question":"Уркуя Салиева ким болгон?","answer":" Уркуя Салиева эжебиз Совет бийлигин чыңдоо үчүн күрөшкөндөрдөн. Кыргыз кыз-келиндеринин ичинен биринчилерден болуп комсомолго, кийин партияга өткөн. Эзүүчү таптарга каршы жана аялдарды азаттыкка чыгаруу үчүн күрөшкөн. Мүркүт айыл кеңешинин төрайымы болуп шайланган. Уркуя жаш болсо да, эл башкарып, басмачыларга сес көрсөткөндүгү, тайманбастыгы менен эле канча таалим-тарбия көрсөтүп турат. Элдин ырыскысын уурдашып, өз кара жандарын гана ойлогон басмачыларга каршы туруп, элдин таламын талашкандыгы үчүн акыры ошол тап душмандарынын колунан курман болгондугу тарыхта жана элдин эсинде калды."},{"question":"के रातो कलमले निलो रेखा खिच्न मिल्छ?","answer":"निलो कलमले रातो रेखा खिच्न मिल्दैन, किनकि रातो कलममा त रातो नै मसि हुन्छ।"},{"question":"Rumor has it that 0 హెక్టార్ల is the answer to ములగరువు గ్రామ విస్తీర్ణం ఎంత?","answer":"ములగరువు ఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ రాష్ట్రం, విశాఖపట్నం జిల్లా, గంగరాజు మాడుగుల మండలంలోని గ్రామం. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన గంగరాజు మాడుగుల నుండి 17 కి.మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన అనకాపల్లి నుండి 85 కి.మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 4 ఇళ్లతో, 13 జనాభాతో 0 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 7, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 6. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 0 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 6. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 584982[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 531029."},{"question":"Apakah peribahasa yang bermaksud \\"Keadaan (kekayaan, pangkat, dan lain-lain) itu tiada tetap\\"?","answer":"Peribahasa tersebut ialah adat pasang berturun naik"},{"question":"ਚੈਰਿਟੀ ਨੇ ਪੈਸਾ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਟੀਚਾ ਰੱਖਿਆ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਬੇਘਰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭੋਜਨ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਨਿਲਾਮੀ ਰੱਖੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਨਿਲਾਮੀ ਰੱਖੀ।"},{"question":"اكتب وصفة لعمل طبق كشرى.","answer":"إليك طريقة عمل الكشري المصري:المكونات:- 1 كوب رز مصري- 1 كوب عدس- 1 كوب مكرونة- 2 كوب ماء- 1 بصلة كبيرة، متقطعة شرائح- 4 فصوص ثوم، مفرومة- 2 ملعقة كبيرة صلصة طماطم- 1 ملعقة صغيرة ملح- 1/2 ملعقة صغيرة فلفل أسود- 1/4 ملعقة صغيرة بهارات الكشريالطريقة:1 - اغسلي الرز والعدس كويس.2 - ضعي الرز والعدس في جلة كبيرة مع الماء، وسيبيه على نار وسط لحد ما يغلي.3 - خففي النار، وسيبيه على نار خفيفة لمدة 20 دقيقة، أو لحد ما يستوي الرز والعدس.4 - وفي نفس الوقت، اسلقي المكرونة حسب التعليمات الموجودة على الكيس.5 - في قلاية كبيرة، سخني الزيت على نار وسط .6 - حطي البصل إلى القلاية، وقلبي لحد ما يبقي لونه ذهبي.7 - حطي الثوم إلى القلاية، وقلبي لمدة دقيقة.8 - حطي صلصة الطماطم، والملح، والفلفل الأسود، وبهارات الكشري، وقلبي لحد ما تتجانس المكونات.9 - سيبي الصلصة على نار خفيفة لمدة 5 دقائق.10 - صفي الرز والعدس المكرونة، وحطيها في طبق التقديم.11 - اسكبي الصلصة فوق الرزوالعدس المكرونة، وقدميها سخنة.ممكن تزييني الكشري بحبة بقدونس مفروم، أو بالثوم المعمر، أو بالبيض المقلي."},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 世界遺産になっている奈良県の法隆寺で8日、仏像のほこりを落とす「お身拭い」がありました。仏像にきれいになって新しい年を迎えてもらうために、毎年今ごろ行っています。お坊さんたちがお経を読んだあと、はたきなどを使って国宝の仏像などのほこりを丁寧に落としました。お寺に来ていた人たちは、ほこりを落とすのを見たり、仏像に祈ったりしていました。大分県から来た女性は「何も知らないで来ましたが、感動しました。朝早く来るといいこともあるんだなと思いました」と話していました。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。"},{"question":"A seguinte música pertence a qual banda brasileira? \\"Cálice.\\"","answer":"Chico Buarque e Milton Nascimento."},{"question":"अनन्तशास्त्रं बहुलाश्च विद्याः   अल्पश्च (स्वल्पश्च) कालो बहुविघ्नता च।यत्सारभूतं तदुपासनीयं    हंसो यथा क्षीरमिवम्बुमध्यात्","answer":"शास्त्राला अंत नाही आणि खूप विद्या आहेत, पण वेळ कमी असतो आणि अनेक अडचणी येत असतात त्यामुळे ज्याप्रमाणे हंस पक्षी पाण्यामधून दुधाचा अंश तेवढा काढून पिऊन घेतो त्याप्रमाणे आपण त्या विद्या आणि शास्त्रामधले सार घ्यायचे असते."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Tạm giữ hình sự cặp vợ chồng hành hạ bé gái 1 tuổi ở Hà Nội","answer":"Cơ quan Cảnh sát điều tra - Công an quận Đống Đa (Hà Nội) đã tạm giữ hình sự Đoàn Diệu Linh (26 tuổi, ở Sơn Tây, Hà Nội) và Hoàng Thế Vũ (28 tuổi, ở huyện Ba Vì - chồng Linh) về hành vi \\"Hành hạ người khác\\". Trước đó, ngày 28/7, Công an phường Láng Thượng, quận Đống Đa tiếp nhận tin báo từ Bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương về việc có một trường hợp bệnh nhân là cháu L.Q.Tr (SN 2021; quê ở xã An Dũng, huyện Đức Thọ, tỉnh Hà Tĩnh) nhập viện trong tình trạng tím tái, li bì và sốt cao, nghi bị ngược đãi, hành hạ. Qua điều tra, sơ bộ xác định: Ngày 21/7, mẹ cháu Tr là chị Lê Thị Lan H (SN 1994; HKTT: An Dũng, Đức Thọ, Hà Tĩnh) thuê Đoàn Diệu Linh (SN 1996; trú tại phường Chùa Thông, thị xã Sơn Tây, Hà Nội) trông cháu Tr với giá 3 triệu đồng/tháng tại ngõ 198 Xã Đàn, phường Phương Liên, quận Đống Đa, để đi làm công nhân tại Bắc Giang. Trong quá trình trông cháu Tr, do cháu bị sốt và quấy khóc nên Linh và Vũ đã dùng dây sạc điện thoại buộc chân, dùng que gỗ, búa nhựa đánh vào đầu, người, dùng chăn quấn vào người và dùng băng dính bịt miệng cháu Tr. Đến ngày 26/7, thấy cháu Tr mệt mỏi, khó thở, Vũ và Linh đã đưa cháu đến bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương cấp cứu. Theo Dân trí, bước đầu, các bác sĩ chuẩn đoán sốc nhiễm khuẩn, theo dõi chân tay miệng mức độ 4. Ngoài ra, trên thân thể bệnh nhân có các vết lằn tổn thương da tại vùng chân, tay, mông nghi bị bạo hành trước đó. Bé gái được vợ chồng Linh đưa đến bệnh viện và tự xưng là bố mẹ cháu. Hiện cháu Tr. đang điều trị tại khoa điều trị tích cực với tình trạng chuyển biến nặng. Ngày 28/7, mẹ cháu Tr. đã đến cơ quan điều tra để trình báo sự việc. Đối tượng hành hạ bé gái 1 tuổi sẽ bị xử lý ra sao? Phân tích vụ việc trên dưới góc độ pháp lý, Luật sư Lê Hồng Vân - Đoàn Luật sư Hà Nội cho biết trên báo An ninh thủ đô, theo Điều 140 Bộ Luật hình sự 2015 sửa đổi quy định, hành hạ người khác là đối xử tàn ác hoặc làm nhục người lệ thuộc mình và bị xử lý hình sự. Hành vi đối xử tàn ác là làm cho nạn nhân đau đớn về thể xác và đè nén, áp bức về tinh thần như bỏ đói, đánh đập,… và các hành vi đối xử tàn ác thường lặp đi lặp lại kéo dài trong khoảng thời gian nhất định. Nạn nhân của Tội hành hạ người khác là những người có quan hệ lệ thuộc với người có hành vi hành hạ nhưng không phải là quan hệ ông bà, cha mẹ, vợ chồng hay con cái mà là trong các quan hệ xã hội, tôn giáo, công việc… như quan hệ lệ thuộc giữa bác sĩ với bệnh nhân, học trò với thầy cô giáo, bảo mẫu với trẻ được trông giữ. Tội hành hạ người khác cấu thành hình thức tức là chỉ cần có hành vi phạm tội thì được xem là tội phạm hoàn thành. Mức phạt đối với danh này được chia thành 2 khung. Khung 1 là phạt cải tạo không giam giữ đến 3 năm hoặc phạt tù từ 3 tháng - 2 năm với trường hợp đối xử tàn ác hoặc làm nhục người lệ thuộc mình. Khung 2 phạt tù từ 1-3 năm nếu phạm tội thuộc một trong các trường hợp: Với người dưới 16 tuổi, phụ nữ mà biết là có thai, người già yếu, ốm đau hoặc người khác không có khả năng tự vệ; Gây rối loạn tâm thần và hành vi của nạn nhân mà tỷ lệ tổn thương cơ thể 31% trở lên... Về mặt chủ quan, người thực hiện hành vi hành hạ người khác có lỗi cố ý trực tiếp, tức là nhận thức rõ hành vi của mình là hành vi vi phạm quy định về quyền nhân thân, thấy trước được hậu quả của hành vi gây thiệt hại cho người khác. Ngoài việc phải chịu trách nhiệm hình sự, người có hành vi hành hạ trẻ em còn phải bồi thường cho cha mẹ hoặc người giám hộ của của trẻ số tiền để bù đắp những tổn thất vật chất thực tế và tổn thất tinh thần. Trường hợp cháu bé bị hành hạ tiên lượng xấu, dẫn đến tử vong mà cơ quan chức năng có đủ căn cứ xác định nguyên nhân xuất phát từ việc bị đánh đập, hành hạ, thì đối tượng thực hiện hành vi có thể bị truy cứu trách nhiệm hình sự về tội Giết người hoặc Cố ý gây thương tích có mức phạt cao nhất là 14 năm tù với tình tiết định khung là \\"làm chết người\\". * Mời quý độc giả theo dõi các chương trình đã phát sóng của Đài Truyền hình Việt Nam trên TV Online và VTVGo! Từ khóa:"},{"question":"Объясните понятие дифференциальных уравнений и приведите пример их применения в реальной жизни.","answer":"Дифференциальные уравнения - это уравнения, которые содержат производные каких-либо функций. Они широко используются для описания изменений величин в зависимости от других переменных. Примерами применения дифференциальных уравнений являются описание закона охлаждения Ньютона и прогнозирование понижения температуры горячей жидкости до значения комнатной температуры.Дифференциальные уравнения также играют ключевую роль в физике, инженерии, экономике и других областях, помогая моделировать и анализировать разнообразные процессы и явления в реальном мире."},{"question":"Ahoana ny fanamarinana ny voka-pifidianana hisorohana ny hosoka?","answer":"Avy amin'ny mpanara-maso tsy miankina, ny fisavana fiarovana ary ny fomba fanisana mangarahara."},{"question":"Regl öncesi döllenme olur mu?","answer":"Çiftler adet döneminden 1 gün önce yaşadıkları cinsel ilişkide de gebelik olmayacağını düşünebilir. Ancak adet döneminden bir gün önce yaşanan cinsel ilişkiyle vücuda giren spermler 3 gün boyunca rahim içinde canlı kalabilir ve doğurganlık özelliğini koruyabilir."},{"question":"Inona ary izany: ilay boka mitaingin-tseza?","answer":"Ny valiny dia mananasy."},{"question":"Fenoy ity ohabolana ity: \\"Aza zatra manao lalandririnina ___\\"","answer":"\\"Aza zatra manao lalandririnina ka fahavaratra avy no manao hitsin-dalana.\\""},{"question":"Àwo̩n Ò̩jò̩gbò̩n Nínú Èdè àti Lítírés̩ò̩ Yorùbá","answer":"Àwo̩n Ò̩jò̩gbò̩n Nínú Èdè àti Lítírés̩ò̩ Yorùbá Professors of the Yorùbá Linguistics, Language, Literature & CultureS/N Oruko Yunifasiti 1. Emeritus Professor Adeboye Babalola University of Lagos 2. Emeritus Professor Ayo Bamgbose University of Ibadan 3. Professor Oladele Awobuluyi Adekunle Ajasin University 4. Professor Sope Oyelaran Obafemi Awolowo University 5. Professor Wande Abimbola Obafemi Awolowo University 6. Professor Olatunde Olatunji University of Ibadan 7. Professor Akinwumi Isola Obafemi Awolowo University 8. Professor Kola Owolabi University of Ibadan 9. Professor Adegboyega Alaba University of Lagos 10. Professor Afolabi Olabimtan University of Lagos 11. Professor Bade Ajuwon Obafemi Awolowo University 12. Professor T. M. Ilesanmi Obafemi Awolowo University 13. Professor (Mrs.) Olutoye University of Lagos 14. Professor Adebisi Ogunsina University of Ilorin 15. Professor L. Olufemi Adewole Obafemi Awolowo University 16 Professor Rotimi Badejo University of Maiduguri 17. Professor Adedotun Ogundeji University of Ibadan 18. Professor Yinka Folorunso Lagos State University 19. Professor Goke Akinlabi University of Ibadan 20. Professor Bade Ajayi University of Ilorin 21. Professor Olabode University of Ibadan 22. Professor Sola Adebajo Ogun State Univeristy Ago-Iwoye 23. Professor S. O. Oyetade University of Ibadan 24. Professor (Mrs.) Oluyemisi Adebowale Adekunle Ajasin University Akungba 25. Professor Olusola Olateju University of Ibadan 26. Professor Jibola Abiodun Ekiti State University Ado-Ekiti 27. Professor Tunde Akinyemi University of Florida 28. Professor (Mrs.) Arinpe Adejumo University of Ibadan 29. Professor Francis Oyebade Adekunle Ajasin University Akungba 30. Professor Duro Adeleke University of Ibadan 31. Professor (Mrs.) Laide Sheba Obafemi Awolowo University 32. Professor Taiwo Olunlade Lagos State University 33. Professor O̩ladiipo Ajiboye University of Lagos 34. Professor Oye Taiwo University of Ibadan 35. Professor Lere Adeyemi University of Ilorin 36. Professor Harrison Adeniyi Lagos State University 37. Professor Felix Abidemi Fabunmi Obafemi Awolowo University 38. Professor George Olusola Ajibade Obafemi Awolowo University"},{"question":"ซูชิมีต้นกำเนิดมาจากประเทศอะไร","answer":"ซูชิมีต้นกำเนิดมาจากประเทศญี่ปุ่น"},{"question":"கேள்வி: காலநிலை மாற்றத்திற்கான சாத்தியமான தீர்வாக புவி பொறியியலைச் சுற்றியுள்ள நெறிமுறைகள் என்ன, மேலும் சில முக்கிய புவிசார் பொறியியல் திட்டங்கள் யாவை?","answer":"பதில்: புவிசார் பொறியியல் என்பது புவி வெப்பமயமாதலை எதிர்ப்பதற்கு பூமியின் காலநிலை அமைப்பில் வேண்டுமென்றே, பெரிய அளவிலான தலையீடுகளைக் குறிக்கிறது. இது ஒரு சர்ச்சைக்குரிய மற்றும் ஆபத்தான அணுகுமுறையாகக் கருதப்பட்டாலும், அது பல நெறிமுறைக் கருத்தாய்வுகளை எழுப்புகிறது. ஒரு முக்கிய கவலையானது எதிர்பாராத விளைவுகள் அல்லது தற்போதுள்ள சுற்றுச்சூழல் பிரச்சனைகளை அதிகப்படுத்துவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் ஆகும். கூடுதலாக, புவி பொறியியல் முயற்சிகளில் தாக்கங்களின் சீரற்ற விநியோகம் மற்றும் முடிவெடுக்கும் சக்தி ஆகியவை சமூக நீதி சிக்கல்களுக்கு வழிவகுக்கும். சில முக்கிய புவிசார் பொறியியல் திட்டங்களில் சூரிய கதிர்வீச்சு மேலாண்மை அடங்கும், இதில் ஸ்ட்ராடோஸ்பெரிக் ஏரோசல் ஊசி போன்ற நுட்பங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி சூரிய ஒளியை பூமியிலிருந்து பிரதிபலிக்கிறது மற்றும் கார்பன் டை ஆக்சைடு அகற்றுதல் முறைகள், இது நேரடி காற்று போன்ற தொழில்நுட்பங்கள் மூலம் வளிமண்டலத்தில் இருந்து அதிகப்படியான கார்பை அகற்றுவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. பிடிப்பு மற்றும் காடு வளர்ப்பு. நெறிமுறை கட்டமைப்புகள், வெளிப்படைத்தன்மை மற்றும் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பு ஆகியவை பொறுப்பான ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் புவி பொறியியல் தொழில்நுட்பங்களை பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு வழிகாட்டுவதில் முக்கியமானவை."},{"question":"දැව බිස්ස ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න.","answer":"(ආදී වාසින්) තමා වියලා ගත් දඩ මස් මී පැණිවල බහා තැබීමට දැව බෙන ප්‍රයෝජනයට ගත්හ. කෙමෙන් කෘෂිකාර්මික ජීවිතයට අවතීර්ණවීමෙන් පසුද දැව බෙන කෘෂිකාර්මික ප්‍රයෝජන පිණිස භාවිතා කරන්නට වූහ. දැව බෙන භාවිතයේ අවශ්‍යතාවය වූයේ බිත්තර වී සඳහා බවබෝග ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීමය. ස්වාභාවික බෙන සහිත ගස් ඇතුළතින් විශාලකර දැව බිස්ස තනාගෙන ඇත. අද දවස වන විට දැව බිහි බහුල වශයෙන් භාවිතා නොවේ. විශාල ගස් හිඟ විම ධාන්‍ය (ගබඩාකරණයේ) වෙනත් සරල​ ක්‍රම සංවර්ධනය විම ඊට හේතුවයි."},{"question":"ඉන්දීය පොප් ගායන ශිල්පිනී අලීෂා චිනායි විසින් 1995 දී නිකුත් කරනලද අතිශය ජනප්‍රියවූ සංගීත ඇල්බමය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ඉන්දීය පොප් ගායන ශිල්පිනී අලීෂා චිනායි විසින් 1995 දී නිකුත් කරනලද අතිශය ජනප්‍රියවූ සංගීත ඇල්බමය \\"Made in India\\" වේ."},{"question":"¿Cuál fue la primera película de Walt Disney?","answer":"Blancanieves y los siete enanitos el primer largometraje de Disney. Fue lanzado en 1937."},{"question":" No basquete, quantos pontos vale a cesta quando a bola é arremessada de fora do garrafão?","answer":"Em quadra, deve haver 6 jogadores. As equipes profissionais têm ainda 6 atletas no banco de reservas."},{"question":"ගාසා තීරයට තවත් මානුෂීය ආධාර රැගත් ලොරි පිටත්ව යයි","answer":"බටහිර නායකයින් සිවිල් වැසියන් ආරක්ෂා කළ යුතු බවට අවධාරණය කරන පසුබිම තුළ ගාසා තීරය වෙත තවත් ආධාර තොගයක් යවා තිබේ.මානුෂීය ආධාර රැගත් තවත් ට්‍රක් රථ 14ක් ගාසා තීරයට යැවූ බව එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානුෂීය කටයුතු පිළිබඳ ප්‍රධානී මාර්ටින් ග්‍රිෆිත්ස් නිවේදනය කළේය.ආධාර රැගත් ට්‍රක් රථ 14 කින් සමන්විත දෙවන මානුෂීය රථ පෙළට ගාසා තීරයට ඇතුළු වීමට අවසර ලද බව සඳහන් කරමින් මාර්ටින් ග්‍රිෆිත්ස් සඳහන් කළේ, මෙය ගාසාහි ජනතාව ලද \\"බලාපොරොත්තුවේ කුඩා ආලෝකයක්\\" බවය.Oxfam පුණ්‍යායතනය ආධාර යැවීමට අවසර දීම ගැන සිය ප්‍රසාදය පළ කළ නමුත් \\"දිනකට ට්‍රක් රථ කිහිපයක් යැවීම ප්‍රමාණවත් නොවන\\" බව අවධාරණය කළේය."},{"question":"No anime Fairy Tail, quem é Panther Lily?","answer":"Panther Lily é um Exceed, amigo de Gajeel Redfox, e membro da Fairy Tail Guild. Ele é conhecido por sua forma de pantera e sua força impressionante."},{"question":"ii sheeg tariikhda diinta islaamka?","answer":"Diinta Islaamka waxaa bilaabay sanadkii 610 Masiixi oo uu ku dhashay Nabiyow rasuulka Ilaahay, Muhammad ﷺ, ee ka soo jeeda Makkah, ee waddanka Suuriya. Waa diin ugu horreysay ee ku saabsan Tawxiidka (u ogolaanshaha Ilaah) iyo Risaaladda (rasuulka nabiyada).Muxuu ka mid yahay taariikhda diinta Islaamka?Bilaabidda: Nabiyow Muhammad ﷺ waa uu ku dhawaaqay noloshoodii qarnigii 6aad, halkaasoo uu ku soo jeediyay inuu dib u soo celiyo nabiyada. Waxay Soomaaliya ugu hambalyeeyeen oo u hor imaan jireen asxaabta Nabiga, sidaas darteed ayay kuwa Soomaaliyeed ugu heshiiyeen diintooda.Makkah: Markii uu Nabiyow Muhammad ﷺ ku dhashay, waxaa ku jirtay dagaal ka dhan ah dadka Makkah oo Muslimiin ah iyo kufriga. Waxay Muslimiintu ka mid ahaayeen Soomaaliya, halkaasoo ay ku jiraan kuwo ugu fiican oo ku hadla Afafka Carabiga, sidaas darteed ayay kuwa Soomaaliyeed ugu heshiiyeen diintooda.Hijra: Nabiyow Muhammad ﷺ iyo asxaabtiisa waxay ku soo noqdeen Madinah, oo lagu magacaabo Hijra. Markii hore ayay kuwa Madinah ugu imaan jireen muhaajiriin oo Muslim ah, oo ay ku jiraan kuwa Soomaaliyeed. Madinah waxay ka mid tahay meelaha ugu fiican oo horumarinta diintu iyo sharciyadda Islaamka ee Soomaaliya.Dagaalkii Badar: Markii uu Nabiyow Muhammad ﷺ ku noqday Madinah, waxaa ka bilowday dagaalkii Badar, oo ahayd dagaal ka dhan ah Muslimiinta iyo kufriga. Waxay Soomaaliya ugu hambalyeeyeen oo u hor imaan jireen Muslimiinta Badar, oo ka mid ahaa dagaalkii ugu horreeyey ee Muslimiinta.Dagaalkii Maki: Markii uu Nabiyow Muhammad ﷺ uu ku noqday Madinah, waxaa ka bilowday dagaalkii Maki, oo ahayd dagaal ka dhan ah Muslimiinta iyo kufriga. Waxay Soomaaliya ugu hambalyeeyeen oo u hor imaan jireen Muslimiinta Maki, oo ka mid ahaa dagaalkii ugu waaweyn ee Muslimiinta.Xayira Cali: Markii Nabiyow Muhammad ﷺ uu dhimatay, waxaa xilka nabigu uu ku hogaaminayey Xayira Cali, oo ahayd khaliifadka ugu horreeyey ee Muslimiinta. Xayira Cali waxaa ku habsaday in uu fuliyo sharciyadda Islaamka iyo xeerarka Islaamka ee ku saabsan ummadda.Taariikhda diinta Islaamka waxay sii kordhisay kuwaas oo dhan, waxaana ku salaysan dagaalkii Muslimiinta iyo kufriga, horumarka dhaqanka iyo sharciyadda Islaamka, iyo kuwo kale oo aad u badan oo ka mid ah taariikhda Muslimiinta."},{"question":"Maah maah Soomaliyeed?","answer":"Indhaha ayaa muujiya wixii Afka sheegi waayo."},{"question":"Ийгиликке жетиш үчүн кайсы сөздү  колдонбо керек?","answer":"Өкүнүчтүү-өкүнгөндөн пайда жок. Өкүнгөн менен айла жок. Башты мыкчып, бармак тиштегенден чыгар майнап болсо, көп адам ийгиликке жетишмек. Эгер сиз ийгиликке умтулган инсан болсоңуз өкүнүч сиз үчүн эмес. "},{"question":"\\"බුහුටි\\" යන වචනය පහදන්න","answer":"දක්ෂයම් කාර්යයක් කාර්යක්ෂමව හොඳින් සහ සිත් ඇදගන්නා ලෙසින් නිම කිරීම හෝ  ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම .ඔහු ඉදිරියේ බුහුටීපන්සිළු ද නොසිටී(ගුත්තිලය)"},{"question":"Ẹgbẹ́ àwọn tó ń kópa pàtàkì nínú ètò ìṣèlú l'áyé àti'jọ́ ni...","answer":"Ẹgbẹ́ ògbóni."},{"question":"Sürücü kursu derslerine gitmezsek ne olur?","answer":"Teorik derslere ve direksiyon derslerinde 5'te 1 oranında devamsızlık yapan adayların kurstan kayıtları silinecek. Bakanlık, devam durumunu sürekli takip edecek. Milli Eğitim Bakanlığı'na bağlı Özel Öğretim Kurumları Genel Müdürlüğü, Özel Motorlu Taşıt Sürücüleri Kursu Yönetmeliği Taslağı'nı hazırladı."},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity : \\"  Zanaky ny efa mangotraka, _\\".","answer":"\\"Zanaky ny efa mangotraka, tsy matahotry ny hangorovitsika\\". "},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Under 1800-talet minskade haciendasystemets betydelse, parallellt med att många tidigare spanska kolonier blev självständiga stater. I Dominikanska republiken delades storgodsen upp i mindre lantegendomar eller jordbruk. I Mexiko","answer":"försvann haciendasystemet 1917, efter Mexikos revolution 1911, och systemet försvann senare på liknande sätt även från Bolivia (jordbruksreformer 1969) och Peru (vänsterrevolutionen 1952)."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"உலகிலுள்ள எப்படிப்பட்ட மதக்காரனும், கடவுள் நம்பிக்கைகாரனும் நம்பிக்கைவாதி ஆவானே ஒழிய, அறிவுவாதி ஆகவே மாட்டான்."},{"question":"Sütçü İmam olayı hangi tarihte oldu?","answer":"Ortamı yatıştırmak ve kadınları kurtarmak isteyen Çakmakçı Said ve arkadaşları, Ermeni askerlerince vurularak yere düşer. Bu sırada gönüllü imamlık yaptığı mescidin altındaki dükkanda süt satan Sütçü İmam, tabancasını alarak düşmana karşı ilk kurşunu 31 Ekim 1919'da ateşler."},{"question":"दिए गए वाक्य का हिंदी में अनुवाद करें:\\"Create a multi-perspective narrative following the interconnected lives of characters in a bustling metropolis.\\"","answer":"दिये गये वाक्य का हिंदी अनुवाद येह हैं: \\"एक भड़कीले शहर में स्थित पात्रों के आपसी जीवन की बढ़ती जीवनीयों का पाठ्यक्रम बनाएं जिसमें एकाधिक दृष्टिकोण हों।\\""},{"question":"கற்பனைத் திறனையும், அறிவாற்றலையும், சிந்திக்கும் திறனையும் வளர்க்கும் வகையில் தரமான புத்தகங்கள் அதிகம் படிக்க வேண்டும் என்பதை வலியுறுத்தி கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தலைப்பில் ஒரு கட்டுரை வரைக.தலைப்பு: புத்தகம் என் நண்பன் ","answer":"முன்னுரைவரலாற்றில் புகழ்பெற்றவர்களுக்கு எல்லாம் வழிகாட்டியாய் நிற்பவை புத்தகங்கள். தொட்டு தொட்டு பார்த்தால் அது வெறும் காகிதம் தொடர்ந்து படித்தால் வாழ்வில் வெற்றியின் ஆயுதம் அதுவே புத்தகங்கள் ஆகும். “புத்தகங்களை நேசி ஒரு புத்தகத்தை தொடுகின்ற போது நீ ஒரு அனுபவத்தை பெறுவாய்.” என்கின்றார் திரைப்பட பாடலாசிரியரும் கவிஞருமான நா. முத்துக்குமார் அவர்கள். புத்தங்களே வாழ்வில் சிறந்த நண்பர்கள் ஆகின்றன.நமது கற்பனை திறன்மாணவர்களின் கற்பனைத் திறனை வளர்க்க ஒவ்வொருவரது வீட்டிலும், ஓர் நூல் நிலையம் அவசியம் இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று மறைந்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும், அறிவியல் விஞ்ஞானியுமான அப்துல்கலாம் கூறியுள்ளார். புத்தகம் நமது பழைய காலத்தை நினைத்து பார்த்து நிகழ்காலத்தின் அனுபவம் கொண்டு எதிர்காலத்தை நிர்ணயிக்கும் ஒரு சக்தியாக விளங்குகிறது. நாம் வரலாறு, கலாச்சாரம், கலை, அறிவியல், தொழில்நுட்பம் போன்ற நல்ல புத்தகங்களை படித்து, கற்றுத் தேர்ந்தால் தான் சமுதாயத்தில் அறிவில் சிறந்தவர்களாக முடியும்.சமூகத்தை புரட்டும் நெம்புகோல் உலகின் தலைசிறந்த நுால்கள் அந்தந்த இனத்தின், மொழியின் பண்பாட்டை அறிவிக்கும் கருவியாக பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. நுால்கள் என்பதை நாம் பெறும் தாளில் கோர்க்கப்படும்எழுத்துக்கள் என்று மட்டும் பார்க்கக் கூடாது. அது சமூகத்தை புரட்டிப்போடும் நெம்புகோல்கள் என உணர வேண்டும்.வளர்ச்சிக்கு வழிகாட்டிகற்பனைத் திறனையும், அறிவாற்றலையும், சிந்திக்கும் திறனையும் வளர்க்கும் வகையில் தரமான புத்தகங்கள் அதிகம் படிக்க வேண்டும். மற்றவருடைய அனுபவங்களையெல்லாம் படித்து தெரிந்து கொள்ளும் போது அவை வளர்ச்சிக்கு வழிகாட்டுபவையாக இருக்கும்.தங்களது பெற்றோர் நல்ல புத்தகங்களைப் படிக்கும் பழக்கத்தை பார்த்தால், பிள்ளைகளுக்கும் தாமும் நல்ல புத்தகங்களை படிக்க வேண்டுமென்ற ஆர்வம் வரும். அப்படி படித்த புத்தகங்களைப் பற்றி பெற்றோர் பிள்ளைகளிடம் விவாதிக்கும் பொழுது, அவர்களுக்கு புத்தகம் படிப்பதில் மிகவும் ஆர்வம் உருவாகும். நல்ல புத்தகங்களை படிப்பது வாழ்க்கையை மேம்படுத்தும் ஒரு செயலாகும்.நிலையான நண்பன்நாம் தினமும் அரைமணி நேரமாவது புத்தகம் படிக்கும் பழக்கத்தை வளர்த்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும். புத்தகம் நமக்கு நீடித்த ஒரு நிலையான நண்பனாக விளங்கும் புதிர்கள்தான் என விஞ்ஞானி ஆல்பர்ட் ஐன்ஸ்டீனுக்கு வாழ்க்கையில் மகிழ்ச்சியைச் கொடுத்த தாம். அதற்கு விடை தேடி இத்தனை சாதனைகளையும் அவர் சாதிப்பதற்கு அவருக்கு உறுதுணையாக இருந்தது புத்தகங்கள் தான்.வற்றாத நீர்படிக்கும் இடத்தை விட படிக்கும் போது மனம் தெளிவாகக் குழப்பமின்றி இருப்பதே முக்கியம். படித்த விடயங்களை அடிக்கடி மனத்திரையில் விடுவது நல்லது. “தொட்டனைத் தூறும் மணற்கேணி மாந்தருக்கு கற்றனைத்து ஊறும் அறிவு” என்றார் வள்ளுவர். அதாவது மணற்பாங்கான இடத்தில் உள்ள கிணற்று நீர் மீண்டும் மீண்டும் அதன் அளவுக்கு ஏற்பச் சுரக்கும் அதுபோல கற்ற கல்வியின் அளவுக்கும் கற்ற நூலின் அளவுக்கு ஏற்ப அறிவு வளரும். அப்படிப்பட்ட அள்ள அள்ளக் குறையாத, வற்றாத வளமாக என்றும் இருப்பது புத்தகங்கள் தான், அமைதியான பொறுமையான அறிவார்ந்த மற்றும் வளமான சமுதாயம் உருவாக அடிப்படைக் காரணமாக இருப்பதும் புத்தகங்கள் தான். எனவே வளமான வாழ்க்கைக்கு என்றும் உறுதுணையாக இருக்கும் புத்தகங்களைப் படிக்க வேண்டும்.முடிவுரைபல புத்தகங்களை படித்து அறிவை வளர்ப்பதன் மூலம் தன்னம்பிக்கை ஏற்படும். எனவே ஒவ்வொரு வீட்டிலும் நல்ல புத்தகங்கள் இருக்க வேண்டும். அப்படிப்பட்ட புத்தகங்களை தினமும் படிக்கும் வழக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்திக் கொள்ள வேண்டும். புத்தகங்கள் என்றென்றும் உங்களுக்கு உற்ற நண்பனாக திகழும். “நீரளவே ஆகுமாம் நீராம்பல் தான் கற்ற நூல் அளவே ஆகுமாம் நுண்ணறிவு” என்கின்றார் அவ்வையார். இதற்கிணங்க நல்ல புத்தகங்களைப் படித்து வாழ்வில் வளம் பெறுவோமாக!"},{"question":"what important event is this text about: ปฏิบัติการนอร์ทวินท์ () เป็นการรุกที่สำคัญครั้งสุดท้ายของเยอรมันในสงครามโลกครั้งที่สองบนแนวรบด้านตะวันตก มันได้เริ่มต้นเมื่อวันที่ 31 ธันวาคม ค.ศ. 1944 ในไรน์ลันท์-ฟัลทซ์, อาลซัส และลอแรนในทางตะวันตกเฉียงใต้ของเยอรมนีและทางตะวันออกเฉียงเหนือของฝรั่งเศส และได้สิ้นสุดลงเมื่อวันที่ 25 มกราคม ค.ศ. 1945","answer":"ปฏิบัติการนอร์ทวินท์"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਜੋ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹਰਿ ਦੀਬਾਣ ਸਿਉ ਸੋ ਸਭਨੀ ਦੀਬਾਣੀ ਮਿਲਿਆ ॥ਜਿਥੈ ਓਹੁ ਜਾਇ ਤਿਥੈ ਓਹੁ ਸੁਰਖਰੂ ਉਸ ਕੈ ਮੁਹਿ ਡਿਠੈ ਸਭ ਪਾਪੀ ਤਰਿਆ ॥ਓਸੁ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ਹੈ ਨਾਮੋ ਪਰਵਰਿਆ ॥ਨਾਉ ਪੂਜੀਐ ਨਾਉ ਮੰਨੀਐ ਨਾਇ ਕਿਲਵਿਖ ਸਭ ਹਿਰਿਆ ॥ਜਿਨੀ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇਆ ਇਕ ਮਨਿ ਇਕ ਚਿਤਿ ਸੇ ਅਸਥਿਰੁ ਜਗਿ ਰਹਿਆ ॥੧੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 87 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਦਰਬਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਿਆ (ਆਦਰ ਪਾਉਣ-ਯੋਗ ਹੋਇਆ) ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਸੰਸਾਰ ਦੇ) ਸਭ ਦਰਬਾਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਆਦਰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਥੇ ਉਹ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਥੇ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮੱਥਾ ਖਿੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮੂੰਹ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ (ਭਾਵ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕਰ ਕੇ) ਸਭ ਪਾਪੀ ਤਰ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਪਰਵਾਰ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਿਰ ਦੇ ਦੁਆਲੇ ਰੌਸ਼ਨੀ ਦਾ ਚੱਕ੍ਰ ਹੈ) (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਧਿਆਨ ਧਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਨਾਮ (ਜਪਣ) ਕਰ ਕੇ ਸਭ ਪਾਪ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਏਕਾਗਰ ਚਿੱਤ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਅਟੱਲ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਹਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੋਭਾ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਸ਼ਟਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ) ।੧੧।\\""},{"question":"Muguta ripi imba yekutanga yeopera yakavhurwa?","answer":"Imba yekutanga yeopera yeruzhinji yakavhurwa muVenice, Italy. Teatro San Cassiano, yakavhurwa muna 1637, inoonekwa seyokutanga opera imba yeruzhinji pasirese. Ichi chiitiko chenhoroondo chakaratidza chiitiko chakakosha mukuvandudzwa kweopera sechimiro cheunyanzvi, sezvo chaibvumira vateereri vakawanda kuti vauye kumitambo.Opera yakamboitwa munzvimbo dzinogara vanhu uye mumatare, asi kugadzwa kwedzimba dzeveruzhinji kwakaratidza shanduko mukuita kuti iyi nzira yevaraidzo iwanikwe nevanhu vakasiyana-siyana. Kubudirira kweTeatro San Cassiano kwakagadzira nzira yekuwanda kwedzimba dzeopera muEurope, zvichibatsira mukukura nekukurumbira kweopera sechiitiko chetsika."},{"question":"ما هي عاصمة بولندا؟","answer":"عاصمة بولندا هي وارسو."},{"question":"Cuntooyinka caafimaadka u ah Beerka?","answer":"CUNTOOYINKA UFIICAN CAFIMADKA BEERKA-----------------------------------------------------------------------Beerka, culeyskiisu waa qiyaastii 3 pounds dadka waaweyn ee caafimaadka qaba, waxaa uu ka mid yahay xubnaha ugu muhiimsan jirka, waxaa u mas’uul ka yahay shaqooyin badan oo la xiriira dheefshiidka, difaaca iyo keydinta nafaqada, iwm, kuwaasoo jirku u baahan yahay si uu u sii noolaado.Sidoo kale beerku waa qanjir sii daaya waxyaabaha jirku u baahan yahay. Run ahaantii beerku waa qeybta keli ah ee jirka ee isku ah xubin iyo qanjir.Beerka caafimaadka qaba wuxuu nadaamiyaa iskudhisyada dhiigga, wuxuu meesha ka saaraa ama banaanka u tuuraa waxyaabaha sunta ah ee dhiigga ku jira. Sidoo kale wuxuu keydiyaa fitimiinada, birta iyo sonkorta.Haddaba waxa idiin soo gudbinaynaa cuntooyinka nadiifiya beerka, waxaana ka mid ah;1. #ToontaToonta ama tuunta ayaa aad ugu fiican nadiifinta beerka, waxay firfircooni gelisaa dheecaano ku jira beerka oo ka caawiya inay banaanka u saaraan sunta. Sidoo kale Toonta ayaa ka kooban laba maaddo oo dabiici ah oo kala ah; allicin iyo selenium, kuwaasoo qeyb ka qaata habka nadiifinta, kana difaaca beerka dhaawaca sunta.Isticmaal toon cusub oo ceeriin ah ah si aad caafimaadka beerkaaga aad u hormariso, ha isticmaalin mid la dubay ama la shiiday.Cun maalintii 2 illaa 3 toon ceeriin ah, kuna darso cuntada.2. #CanabCanabka waxaa uu ku wanaagsan fitimiin C iyo qaar kale, wuxuu caawiyaa canabku habka dabiiciga ah ee nadiifinta beerka. Cab subax walba hal koob oo canab la miiray ah marka aad quraacaneyso.#FG: Haddii aad daawo isticmaaleyso, la tasho dhaqtar ka hor inta aadan qaadan cabitaankan waayo waxay la falgeli karaan daawada aad qaadatay.3. #LiintaLiimadu waxay nadiifisaa beerka waayo waxaa ku jira curiyaha D-Limonene, kaasoo caawiya oo firfircooni geliya dheecaanada beerka, intaas waxaa dheer in fitimiin C ku jira liinta uu ka caawiyo beerka inuu soo saaro dheecaano badan oo wanaajiya dheefshiidka. Joogto u cab liinta maalin walba, haddii aad doonto ku darso malab.4. #Shaaha #cagaaranMaalin kasta oo la cabo shaaha cagaaran, waxaa jirkaagu uu awood u helayaa inuu qashinka sunta iyo haraaga dufanka iska saaro, iyadoo uu kordhinayo heerka fuuq-celinta.Sanadkii 2002 daraasad lagu daabacay wargeyska caalamiga ah ee ka faalooda buurnida ayaa lagu sheegay in maaddo ku jirto shaaha cagaaran ay hagaajiso beerka. Sidoo kale cabitaanada wanaagsan ayaa beerka ka difaaca sunta banaanka uga timaada sida aalkolada.Cab maalintii 2 illaa 3 koob oo shaaha cagaaran ah, haddii aad doonto ku macaanso malab5. #AfokaadhoAfakaadhada waxay ka kooban tahay maaddooyin hoos u dhiga dhaawaca beerka sida lagu sheegay daraasad ay sameeyeen bulshada kiimikada ee mareykanka. waxay qudaartani qani ku tahay maaddada glutathione oo ah iskudhis uu beerku u baahan yahay oo ka nadiifiya sunta beerka si wanaagsana u shaqo geliya. Sidoo kale waxay afakaadhadu hoos u dhigtaa heerka dufanka dhiigga, iyadoo kor u qaadda dufanjka wanaagsan.Afokaadhada waxaa kale oo ku jira macaadin, fitimiino iyo nafaqooyin si guud u taageera caafimaadka guud ee beerka iyo hoos u dhigida baruurta.Cab 1 illaa 2 koob oo afakaadho ah todobaad walba dhowr bilood si ay u hagaajiyaan dhaawacyada beerka."},{"question":"भारतातील कोणते राज्य भारतातील खाद्य भांडार म्हणून ओळखले जाते?(A) उत्तर प्रदेश(B) हरियाणा(C) पंजाब(D) तामिळनाडू=>","answer":" (C) पंजाब"},{"question":"નીચેના ગુજરાતી ઉખાણાં નો જવાબ આપો:એક લાકડીની સાંભળો કહાણી,તેમાં ભરેલું છે મીઠું પાણી","answer":"શેરડી"},{"question":"Question: The pores in a leaf through which respiratory exchange of gases takes place are –Choose the appropriate answer:a. Xylemb. Stigmac. Lenticelsd. Stomata","answer":"Answer: (d)Stomata are the pores present on the leaf surface through which respiratory exchange of gases take place. Xylem transports water and minerals in plants. Lenticels are pores found on epidermis. Stigma is a part of the female reproductive part of a flower."},{"question":"🎥 Кыргыз тасмаларына салым кошкон Эрнест Абдыжапаров жөнүндө эмне айта аласыз?","answer":"📹 Эрнест Абдыжапаровдун тасмалары 20дан ашык эл аралык фестивалдарга катышкан. «Таранчы» кыскаметраждуу тасмасы бир нече фестивалдардын жана эл аралык кинематографиялык уюмдардын сыйлыктарын топтогон:Кыскаметраждуу тасмалардын эл аралык кинофестивалынын гран-приси, Драма, Греция - 1996FICC жана Германиянын Католик тасмасы сыйлыктары, кино Германии на кыскаметраждуу тасмалардын Оберхаузенск эл аралык фестивалында Германия — 1997C.I.C.A.E. сыйлыгы эң мыкты тасма үчүн — 1998«Айыл Өкмөтү» тасмасы бир нече фестивалдарда сыйлык алган:«Дидор» МКФ гран-приси, Душанбе, Тажикистан - 2004Эң мыкты сценарий үчүн сыйлык, «Киношок», Анапа, Орусия — 2004Эң мыкты режиссерлук үчүн сыйлык, МКФ «Новое кино. XXI век», Смоленск, Орусия — 2004Алтын жылдыз, Марракешедеги эл аралык кинофестиваль — 2005Жюрини атайы сыйлыгы, «Евразия», Алматы, Казакстан — 2005Мындан тышкары:Кыргызстан жаштары премиясынын лауреаты - 2001Гран-при номинациясы, чыгыш-батыш тасмасынын Котбусск фестивали — 2007, «Боз салкын» тасмасы үчүнЭң мыкты сценарий үчүн сыйлык, «Киношок» — 2008, «Боз салкын» тасмасы үчүн."},{"question":"Dokończ zdanie. Wybierz właściwą odpowiedź spośród podanych.Szereg, w którym uporządkowano chronologicznie wydarzenia, to:A. początek działalności ewangelizacyjnej św. Pawła Apostoła, prześladowanie chrześcijan przez cesarza Nerona, ogłoszenie wolności wyznania religii chrześcijańskiej w państwie rzymskim.B. ogłoszenie wolności wyznania religii chrześcijańskiej w państwie rzymskim, początek działalności ewangelizacyjnej św. Pawła Apostoła, prześladowanie chrześcijan przez cesarza Nerona.C. prześladowanie chrześcijan przez cesarza Nerona, ogłoszenie wolności wyznania religii chrześcijańskiej w państwie rzymskim, początek działalności ewangelizacyjnej św. Pawła Apostoła.D. ogłoszenie wolności wyznania religii chrześcijańskiej w państwie rzymskim,  prześladowanie chrześcijan przez cesarza Nerona, początek działalności ewangelizacyjnej św. Pawła Apostoła.","answer":"Poprawna odpowiedź to A."},{"question":"Intetha ethi \\"Siya gabaza\\" ithetha ukuthini ngesiXhosa.","answer":"Ithetha ukuba bahamba kakuhle."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Robert Devereux, 2ú Iarla Essex. ","answer":"Ba laoch míleata agus ceanán na banríona Eilís I é Robert Devereux, 2ú Iarla Essex (10 Samhain, 1565 - 25 Feabhra, 1601), ach tar éis feachtais neamhbhuach in aghaidh na reibiliúnaithe Éireannacha, le linn Chogadh na Naoi mBliana sa bhliain 1599, theip 'coup d'état' aige i gcoinne na banríona agus cuireadh chun báis é de thoradh ar a thréasa. "},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaan Suurada iyo Aayada ay ku jirto haweeneeyda lagu xusay Quraanka kariimka ah looguna magac daray (Imra-atu kharqaa) ama (Awil kharqaa)?","answer":"Waxaay ku jirtaa Suurada Al-Naxli Aayada 91 ee halkaa kafiiriya Inta qofood oo isku dayday in aay kajawaabaa waa 4 qofoodA/raxmaan D, Osman 2 ayuu kajawaabay,Xuseen C/lle 3 ayuu kajawaabay, Guure 1 ayuu kajawaabay, Q,qujuc 1 ayuu kajawaaba."},{"question":"Porfirio Díaz quería que el nuevo edificio fuera uno de los palacios legislativos más lujoso del mundo con más de 14.000 metros cuadrados.Pero en sus inicios, ese proyecto era aun más ambicioso y planeaba competir con el Capitolio en EE.UU.Durante su gobierno, el expresidente Porfirio Díaz, lanzó en 1897 una convocatoria internacional para construir la nueva sede que albergaría a la Cámara de Diputados y de Senadores en México y que al mismo tiempo se convertiría en un edificio para conmemorar el centenario del día de la Independencia, que se cumplía en 1910.Émile Bénard, un reconocido arquitecto francés, inició la construcción del Palacio Legislativo Federal.Díaz quería que el nuevo edificio fuera uno de los palacios legislativos más lujoso del mundo, con más de 14.000 metros cuadrados.Fue Émile Bénard, un reconocido arquitecto francés, quien se encargó de la realización del proyecto Palacio Legislativo Federal. Inspirado en los recintos del Capitolio de Estado Unidos y del ...Continuar el artículo por otros 4.000 caracteres como máximo:","answer":"... Parlamento de Budapest buscaba convertir al palacio en una obra con estética europea neoclásica.Pero el plan fue cambiando por el camino. Los primeros tropiezosEl lujoso Palacio Legislativo estuvo envuelto en varias polémicas debido a la poca claridad en el triunfo del arquitecto que realizaría el proyecto, además de las grandes sumas de dinero que requería su construcción. Émile Bénard buscaba convertir el palacio en una obra con estética europea neoclásica.El suelo lacustre de la Ciudad de México representó otro de los retos a vencer para la monumental obra debido a los hundimientos del subsuelo que se registran en la zona. \\"En 1906, la construcción de lo que iba a ser un lujoso edificio proyectado con la estética europea neoclásica comenzó con una masiva estructura metálica y tecnología de vanguardia para su cimentación\\", indica el portal web del Monumento a la Revolución.La estructura interna de la cúpula principal de lo que sería el Palacio Legislativo tuvo que ser reforzada debido a las condiciones del suelo.Se requirió mucho dinero para construir una plataforma de acero y concreto que pudiera mantener en pie el edificio.Estallido de la Revolución mexicanaLa primera piedra del edificio se colocó el 23 de noviembre de 1910, tan solo tres días después del inicio del movimiento revolucionario en México.La Revolución mexicana provocó que la obra del Palacio Legislativo Federal se suspendiera al quedarse sin recursos, que entonces fueron utilizados para combatir los levantamientos armados en el país.La construcción quedó abandonada por más de dos décadas al concluir el movimiento revolucionario en México.La construcción fue finalmente suspendida en 1912 y dejó abandonada su estructura metálica.La estructura quedó en el olvido por dos décadas en parte por querer borrar toda herencia del gobierno de Porfirio Díaz, indica el Museo de Monumento a la Revolución"},{"question":"ماهي أكبر بلد في أوروبا من حيث المساحة؟","answer":"فرنسا وتبلغ مساحتها 547,026 كم مربع"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਤੂ ਸਚਾ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਸਚੁ ਹੈ ਸਚੁ ਸਚੇ ਭਾਵੈ ॥ਜੋ ਤੁਧੁ ਸਚੁ ਸਲਾਹਦੇ ਤਿਨ ਜਮ ਕੰਕਰੁ ਨੇੜਿ ਨ ਆਵੈ ॥ਤਿਨ ਕੇ ਮੁਖ ਦਰਿ ਉਜਲੇ ਜਿਨ ਹਰਿ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਸਚਾ ਭਾਵੈ ॥ਕੂੜਿਆਰ ਪਿਛਾਹਾ ਸਟੀਅਨਿ ਕੂੜੁ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਕਪਟੁ ਮਹਾ ਦੁਖੁ ਪਾਵੈ ॥ਮੁਹ ਕਾਲੇ ਕੂੜਿਆਰੀਆ ਕੂੜਿਆਰ ਕੂੜੋ ਹੋਇ ਜਾਵੈ ॥੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 302 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਹਰੀ! ਤੂੰ ਸੱਚਾ ਤੇ ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈਂ, ਤੈਨੂੰ ਸੱਚ ਹੀ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਸੱਚੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਜੋ ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਮਦੂਤ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਢੁਕਦਾ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸੱਚਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਦਰਗਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਉੱਜਲੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, (ਪਰ) ਕੂੜ ਦਾ ਵਪਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਕੂੜ ਤੇ ਕਪਟ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹ ਪਿਛੇ ਸਿੱਟੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਬੜਾ ਕਲੇਸ਼ ਉਠਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਕੂੜਿਆਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ (ਦਰਗਾਹ ਵਿਚ) ਕਾਲੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੂੜ ਦਾ ਨਿਤਾਰਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬।\\""},{"question":"Дөңсөө деген эмне ?","answer":"Дөңсөө-кургактыктан же деңиз түбүндөгү түздүктөрдүн ондогон же жүздөгөн метрге которулуп турган жер."},{"question":"\\"Ny ezaka fikajiana ny tontolo iainana dia zava-dehibe manoloana ny fiovan'ny toetr'andro sy ny fahaverezan'ny biodiversity. Ny fikambanan'ny fiarovana dia miasa mba hiarovana ireo karazana tandindomin-doza, hamerenana ny tontolo iainana ary hiadiana amin'ny fandringanana ny toeram-ponenana. Na izany aza, ny fanamby dia misy ny sakana famatsiam-bola sy ny filàna fiaraha-miasa manerantany.\\"","answer":"Ny lohahevitra tamin'ny andalana teo aloha dia ny \\"Conservation and Biodiversity\\"."},{"question":"\\"Ny indostrian'ny fiara mandeha amin'ny herinaratra dia nitombo haingana tato anatin'ny taona vitsivitsy, miaraka amin'ny mpanamboatra fiara maro manolotra modely mandehe amin'ny herinaratra vaovao eny an-tsena. Mahazo laza ireo fiara mpiaro ny tontolo iainana ireo noho ny tombontsoa-ny ara-tontolo iainana sy ny fandaniana ambany kokoa. anjara amin'ny ho avin'ny fitaterana.\\"Inona no lohahevitr'ireo andalana ireo?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'ireo andalana teo aloha ireo dia ny \\"Fiara mandeha amin'ny herinaratra sy ny lazany mitombo.\\""},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 北海道の冬のイベント「さっぽろ雪まつり」が、4日から札幌市で始まりました。去年とおととしは、新型コロナウイルスの問題があって、オンラインで開きました。今年は2つの会場で、たくさんの人が楽しんでいます。大通公園の会場には、高さ10m以上ある大きな雪の像が5つあります。北海道に新しくできた野球場や、北海道で多く生まれる競馬の馬のデザインです。夜は、恐竜などの像をきれいな光でライトアップしています。建物の像などには、プロジェクションマッピングでいろいろな映像を映しています。韓国から来た男性は「やっと雪まつりに来ることができました。暗いところで雪が光っていてとてもきれいです」と話していました。さっぽろ雪まつりは11日までです。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。"},{"question":" Sheeg Magacii Caalimkii Muslinka Ahaa Ee Loo Yaqiinay Aabihii Cilmiga Kimistiriga(Chemistry) ?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Jaabir Bin Xayaan"},{"question":"پوښتنه: میږی په ټول اوړي کې سخت کار کاوه، خواړه یې ذخیره کول، پداسې حال کې چې مرغۍ د سندرو ویلو او لوبې کولو څخه خوند اخیست. کله چې ژمی راغی، ماڼی وږی و، او میږیان ډیر و. دا افسانه موږ ته د چمتووالي په اړه څه درس راکوي؟","answer":"ځواب: کیسه موږ ته د راتلونکي لپاره د سخت کار او پلان کولو اهمیت راکوي. د میږیانو لیوالتیا دا یقیني کړه چې د اړتیا په وخت کې کافي اندازه شتون لري، پداسې حال کې چې د تیږو د چمتووالي د نشتوالي له امله له ستونزو سره مخ و.اخلاق: د راتلونکي لپاره سخت کار او پلان جوړونه د بریالیتوب او امنیت لامل کیږي."},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Tsy zakako ireo mpiaro ny zon'ny biby ireo fa tia sehoseho fotsiny izy ireo.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Eny, kabary fankahalana ity fanambarana ity satria tsy ara-drariny no iantsoana ireo mpiaro ny zon'ny biby ho tia sehoseho."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa Isku Geynta Labadaan Tiro  6 + 3?","answer":"Isku Geynta Labadaan Tiro  6 + 3= Waa 9."},{"question":"Euskal Herriko ikurrak: Zer da lauburuaren garrantzia?","answer":"Lauburuak euskal kulturaren sinboloa da, harmonia eta oreka adierazten dituena."},{"question":"How to say Good afternoon in Bisaya?","answer":"Maayong hapon"},{"question":"క్రింది వానిలో ఎంజైమ్ లేని జీర్ణరసంA) పైత్యరసంB) జఠరరసంC) క్లోమరసంD) లాలాజలం","answer":"A) పైత్యరసం"},{"question":"கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சொற்களைக் கொண்டு பொருள்தரும் வகையில் ஒரு சொல்லில் தொடரைத் தொடங்குக. அத்துடன் அடுத்தடுத்துச் சொற்களைச் சேர்த்து, புதிய புதிய சொற்றொடர்களை உருவாக்குக. இறுதித் தொடர் அனைத்துச் சொற்களையும் சேர்த்ததாக அமைய வேண்டும்.காலங்களில் தெருவில் வைக்காதீர்கள் காப்புக் கம்பிகள் கவனக் குறைவுடன் ஆகியவற்றின் மீது காலை அறுந்த மழைக் மின்கம்பிகள்.1. வைக்காதீர்கள்2. ___________________ வைக்காதீர்கள்3. _________________________________________ வைக்காதீர்கள்4. __________________________________________________________ வைக்காதீர்கள்","answer":"1. வைக்காதீர்கள்2. மழைக் காலங்களில் அறுந்த மின்கம்பிகள் காப்புக் கம்பிகள் மீது காலை வைக்காதீர்கள்3. மழைக் காலங்களில் தெருவில் அறுந்த மின்கம்பிகள் காப்புக் கம்பிகள் மீது காலைவைக்காதீர்கள்4. மழைக் காலங்களில் தெருவில் அறுந்த மின்கம்பிகள் காப்புக் கம்பிகள் மீது கவனக் குறைவுடன் காலை வைக்காதீர்கள்"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Mangidy andro matetika andrenesana ...................................\\"","answer":"\\"Mangidy andro matetika andrenesana hoe marina entina mamadika ny marina\\""},{"question":"ලොව වැඩිම කාලයක් පැවති ශිෂ්ටාචාරය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"නයිල් නිම්න ශිෂ්ටාචාරය ( ක්‍රි.පූ . 3100 - ක්‍රි.පූ. 1070 )"},{"question":"Firy ny isan’ny tongotry ny sokatra?","answer":"Efatra ny isan’ny tongotry ny sokatra"},{"question":"கேள்வி : பெரு நாட்டின் நாணயம் எது ? ","answer":"பதில் : இன்டி."},{"question":"এই লেখাটি কোন গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ঘটনা সম্পর্কে ?প্রতি বছর তিনটি থেকে ছয়টি বিশেষ প্রদর্শনীর আয়োজন করা হয়, যাতে বিজ্ঞান এবং কলা(আর্ট) পরপর আসে। তারা ইতোমধ্যে বিভিন্ন বিষয়ে প্রদর্শনীর আয়োজন করেছে- \\"টয়লেট- মানব বর্জ্য এবং পৃথিবীর ভবিষ্যৎ \\", \\"টোকিও আকাশ বৃক্ষের নির্মাণযজ্ঞ \\" এবং \\"টার্মিনেটর প্রদর্শনী- যুদ্ধ নাকি সহাবস্থান? রোবট এবং আমাদের ভবিষ্যৎ\\"। ২০১২ সালের বিশেষ প্রদর্শনী \\"পৃথিবীর শেষ হয়ে যাওয়ার গল্প: ৭৩টি প্রশ্ন যার উত্তর আমাদের দিতেই হবে \\" এর গুরুত্বপূর্ণ বিষয় ছিল টোহুকু ভূমিকম্প এবং এর প্রভাব।","answer":"টোহুকু ভূমিকম্প |"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的電信系統是哪一個？","answer":"答案：摩洛哥的馬拉喀什電信系統"},{"question":"Kodi atate ndani malinga ndi Baibulo?","answer":"Udindo wa atate unachokera kwa Mulungu mwini, Atate wathu wa Kumwamba, ndipo ndi udindo waumulungu ndi mayitanidwe. Kukhala tate, tate wopeza, agogo, kapena tate wolera ndi mwayi wokhala ngati Mulungu, kukonda ndi kusamalira ana monga momwe Mulungu amatikondera ndi kutisamalira."},{"question":"\\"Адашкан койду бөрү жейт\\" деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи ?","answer":"Сиз суранган макал-лакаптын жообу мындай болушу мүмкүн : \\"Адашкан койду бөрү жейт. Адашкандын айбы жок, кайтып үйүрүн тапкан соң.\\""},{"question":"Is Signs Wat voor album in the sand?","answer":"Signs in the sand is een livealbum van Ron Boots. Het is de registratie van het optreden dat Boots verzorgde op 19 mei 2012 in de Grote of Sint-Bavokerk te Haarlem. Het totale concert werd verzorgd door een combinatie van Ron Boots, Remy en vrienden. De stijl van de muziek bestaat uit de twee varianten van een Berlijnse School voor elektronische muziek, Boots varieert tussen de stijlen van Klaus Schulze en jaren 70-Tangerine Dream. "},{"question":"Quân tốt mất tối thiểu bao nhiêu nước cờ để phong cấp?","answer":"5. Bàn cờ vua là hình vuông 8x8 ô, và các tốt lúc xuất phát đứng ở hàng 2 với Trắng, và hàng 7 với Đen. Tốt ban đầu có thể đi hai ô, nhưng sau khi rời khỏi vị trí xuất phát chỉ còn được đi một ô. Khi ăn, tốt luôn ăn chéo một ô. Tốt khi tới hàng 8 với Trắng hoặc hàng 1 với Đen sẽ được phong cấp ngay. Vì thế, quân tốt nào cũng mất tối thiểu là năm nước cờ để phong cấp. Nếu đi liên tục, tốt sẽ mất tối đa sáu nước để phong cấp."},{"question":"Waa maxay yac? ","answer":" Yacdu waa gashaantida qoyska."},{"question":"Gabowga Oo Aan Xidhnayn & Cunista Xaqa.","answer":"Sannad kasta, waxaan u dabaaldagnaa Bisha Dadka Waayeelka ah ee Maay! Bishii hore ee Maraykanka waxay ku beegan tahay 1963-kii markii Madaxweyne John F. Kennedy uu May u aqoonsaday bisha Senior Citizens. Markii dambe waxaa loo bixiyay Older Americans Month, taasoo sharfasa dadka da'da ah ee Mareykanka una dabaaldega wax qabadkooda bulshooyinkayada iyo qarankeena.Mawduuca waxaa dejiyay Maamulka Nolosha Bulshada (ACL). Mawduuca sanadkan waa \\"Aging Unbound, taas oo bixisa fursad lagu sahamiyo waayo-aragnimada gabowga ee kala duwan oo laga wada hadlo sida bulshooyinku ula dagaallamaan fikradaha la aaminsan yahay… horumarinta fikirka dabacsan ee gabowga - iyo sida aan dhammaanteen uga faa'ideyno marka dadka waaweyni ay ku hawlan yihiin, madaxbannaan yihiin, oo lagu daro.\\" (acl.gov) Waa kuwan qaar ka mid ah talooyinka nafaqada si ay kaaga caawiyaan inaad madax-bannaanaato oo aad sii ahaato qayb firfircoon oo bulshadeena ah:1. Protein: Hayso cufnaanta muruqa. Markaan da'eyno, jirkeena wuxuu u baahan yahay qiyaastii 50% borotiin ka badan markii aan yaraa. Waxaan u baahanahay borotiinkan dheeraadka ah si aan u ilaalino tirada muruqa si loo yareeyo khatarta dhicis iyo lafaha jaban. Waxay noo ogolaataa inaan sii wadno sameynta waxyaabaha maalinlaha ah sida socodka, dukaameysiga, iyo inaan la joogno asxaabta iyo qoyska.• Cuntooyinka qaarkood ee aad ku dari karto cuntadaada oo ay ku badan yihiin borotiinku waa hilibka, digaaga, kalluunka, ukunta, digirta iyo lentil, caanaha (sida yogurt Greek, caano, iyo farmaajo), iyo miraha isku jira.• Qof kasta oo ka weyn da'da 65 waa inuu ku dadaalaa 0.45 ilaa 0.55 garaam oo borotiin ah halkii rodol ee miisaanka jidhka maalin kasta, ama qiyaastii 68 ilaa 83 garaam qof 150 rodol ah.2. Vitamin D: Lafo adag ilaali. Kadib da'da 50, jidhkeenu uma eka inuu ka soo saaro fitamiin D qorraxda iyo sidoo kale markii aan yaraa. Waxaa jira ilo cunto oo yar oo laga helo fitamiin D, sida kalluunka dufanka leh sida salmon, tuna, iyo sardines, ukunta, caano la xoojiyay, casiirka liinta, iyo caano fadhi.• Lafahayaga iyo muruqyadayadu way wada shaqeeyaan. Lafo adag iyo muruqyo adag, waxay u badan tahay inaan ku dhacno.• Caadi ahaan, waxaan helnaa qiyaastii 400 IU maalintii. Waxaa lagu talinayaa in aan helno 800 IU. Baadhitaan dhiig oo fudud, dhakhtarkaagu wuxuu sheegi karaa haddii aad ku yar tahay fitamiin D. Hadday sidaas tahay, dhakhtarkaagu wuxuu kugula talin karaa kaabis.3. Vitamin B12: Maskax ahaan u fiirso. Marka aan da'eyno, aad bay u adag tahay in laga nuugo fitamiin B12 cunnadayada, sidaas darteed waxaan u baahanahay xaddi badan oo ka mid ah. Nasiib wanaag, haddii aad ku nooshahay qaab nololeed caafimaad leh oo leh fitamiin B12 badan, jidhkaagu wuxuu awoodaa inuu kaydiyo qiyaastii 5 - 7 sano oo mudan in la isticmaalo. Faytamiin B12 yaraantu waxay sababi kartaa ceeryaamo maskaxda, jahawareer, iyo xusuusta oo lumis. Iyada oo qiyaasta saxda ah ee B12 ee cuntada, waxaa jiray daraasado muujinaya garashada korodhka. Nasiib darro, tani maaha xaalad kuwa laga helay nooc kasta oo waallida ah.• Cuntooyinka qaar ee uu ku badan yahay fitamiin B12 waa salmon, tuna, hilib lo'aad, caano, iyo caano fadhi.Mar labaad, waxaa jira ilo cunto oo kooban oo leh fiitamiin B12, markaa dhakhtarkaagu waxa laga yaabaa inuu kugula taliyo fitamiin B12.Guud ahaan, oo leh borotiin badan iyo heerarka saxda ah ee fitamiin D iyo B12, waxaan ku socon karnaa dariiqayada gabow caafimaad leh hadda iyo mustaqbalka."},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut:Kavinesh hendak memotong sekeping kad menjadi beberapa segi empat tepat. Diberi bilangan segi empat tepat, Z berubah secara songsang dengan panjang, p cm, dan lebar l cm bagi setiap segi empat tepat itu. Diberi Z = 2 apabila p = 9 dan l = 6.Cari bilangan segi empat tepat apabila panjang dan lebar masing-masing ialah 3 dan 2.A.) 18B.) 16.6C.) 4.5D.) 2","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah A.) 18Apabila p=9 dan l=6, keluasan segi empat=9*6=54Z=2, ini bermaskud keluasan kad pada asalnya =2*54=108Apabila p=3 dan l=2, keluasan segi empat=3*2=6Bilangan segi empat yang didapati = 108/6=18"},{"question":"नेपाल को सबै भन्दा होचो भूभाग कुन जील्ला मा पर्छ, यसको नाम र समुन्द्र सतह देखि कति मिटर ऊचाई मा छ?","answer":"नेपाल को सबै भन्दा होचो भूभाग झापा जील्लामा पर्छ र यसको नाम केचनाकलन हो । यो भूभाग ७० मिटर ऊचाई मा पर्छ।"},{"question":"Maloka sy mandrahona ny andro. Tokony itondra elo ve ny tenako?","answer":"Eny, tokony itondra elo ianao sao avy tampoka ny orana."},{"question":"Ajọ eleto idibo pariwo: Bi wọn ṣe n kọ lu awọn ileeṣẹ wa yii yoo ṣakoba feto idibo to n bọ o","answer":"“Laarin ọsẹ mẹta pere ọfiisi ileeṣẹ wa meje ni wọn kọ lu. Wọn dana sun marun-un, wọn si jalẹkun, wọn si ṣe ibẹ baṣubaṣu. Ipinlẹ Abia, Akwa Ibom, Enugu ati Ebonyi lawọn iṣẹlẹ naa ti waye. A o mọ ero ọkan awọn ti wọn wa nidii akọlu wọnyi to fi jẹ ileeṣẹ INEC ni wọn doju sọ lasiko yii. Ṣugbọn ohun to daju ni pe ti iwa basejẹ yii o ba duro, ko sọgbọn ko ma ṣakoba fun awọn eto idibo to n bọ lọna.”Ọjọgbọn Mahmood Yakubu, alaga ajọ INEC (Independent National Electoral Commission), iyẹn ajọ eleto idibo ilẹ wa ṣe sọ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee yii, niluu Abuja, nigba to n sọrọ nipa awọn akọlu to waye si awọn ọfiisi ajọ naa lawọn ipinlẹ kan nilẹ Ibo laipẹ yii.Eyi to kẹyin ninu akọlu naa ni ọfiisi INEC meji ti wọn lawọn ọbayejẹ ẹda kan dana sun lafẹmọju Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee yii, nipinlẹ Ebonyi. Ọfiisi INEC to wa nijọba ibilẹ Ariwa Ezza, ateyi to wa nijọba ibilẹ Izzi, niṣẹlẹ naa ti waye.Ṣaaju ni Alukoro ajọ INEC, Ọgbẹni Cornelius Alli, ti fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ fawọn oniroyin ni Abakaliki, o lawọn janduku to ṣakọlu naa dana sun awọn aga onipako ti wọn fi n dibo, awọn jẹnẹretọ, ati awọn iwe idibo atawọn dukia olowo iyebiye to wa lawọn ọfiisi ọhun.Alaga ajọ INEC ni awọn ti bẹrẹ si i fori kori pẹlu awọn agbofinro lati ṣeto aabo to gbopọn fun ajọ ọhun, ati lati wadii ohun to fa akọlu lemọlemọ ọhun.O ni yatọ sawọn dukia to ṣegbe, ọpọ awọn oṣiṣẹ ajọ naa ni wọn ti wa ninu ibẹru bayii, eyi si le nipa lori agbara wọn lati ṣe ojuṣe wọn lai si ifoya.O bẹnu atẹ lu iwa basejẹ naa, o si parọwa sawọn araalu lati fọwọ sowọ pọ pẹlu awọn agbofinro, pe ki wọn tete maa ta wọn lolobo ti wọn ba ti kẹẹfin awọn ọbayejẹ ti wọn fẹẹ ṣakọlu si nnkan ini ijọba."},{"question":"පරාස්ස යන්නෙහි තේරුම?","answer":"පරාස්ස ( ප්‍රරාක්ෂ - සංස්කෘත) ප්‍රබල රකුසා. වශයෙන් නිරුක්ති සහිත සිංහල ශබ්දකෝෂය දක්වයි."},{"question":"Unsa ang imong mga plano alang sa retirement?","answer":"Akong giplano ang pagpanguma ug pagtukod og negosyo human sa akong retirement aron nga mapadayon ang akong aktibong kinabuhi."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：人体的骨骼系统有多少个骨头组成？","answer":"答案：成年人的骨骼系统大约由206个骨头组成。"},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning till detta stycke - I oktober 2004 förhandlade al-Bashirs regering fram ett slut på det andra sudanesiska inbördeskriget, ett av de längsta och dödligaste krigen under 1900-talet, genom att ge begränsad autonomi till Sydsudan (vilket senare omvandlades till avskiljande som en ny suverän stat). Sedan dess blev dock hans regering kritiserad för dess roll i","answer":"Darfurkonflikten, där folkmord mot den icke-arabiska befolkningen har lett till dödstal på mellan 200 000 och 400 000. Hans styre ledde till våldsamma strider mellan Janjaweedmilisen och rebellgrupper som Sudanesiska folkets befrielsearmé (SPLA), Sudans befrielserörelse (SLA) och Justice and Equality Movement (JEM) i form av gerillakrig i Darfurregionen. Inbördeskriget ledde till att över 2,5 miljoner drivits på flykt, och de diplomatiska relationerna mellan Sudan och Tchad blev ansträngda."},{"question":"Qui à dit la phrase « Je fais un rêve » ?","answer":"« Je fais un rêve » (traduit en anglais par « I have a dream ») est le nom donné au discours prononcé le 28 août 1963 par le pasteur baptiste et militant américain Martin Luther King, devant le Lincoln Memorial, à Washington, D.C., durant la Marche sur Washington pour l'emploi et la liberté. Devant plus de 250 000 manifestants, King en appelle solennellement à la fin du racisme aux États-Unis et revendique l'égalité des droits civiques et économiques entre Blancs et Afro-Américains. Point d'orgue du Mouvement des droits civiques, le discours est considéré aux États-Unis comme l'un des plus importants du xxe siècle.Le discours débute par une référence à la Proclamation d'émancipation qui a libéré plusieurs millions d'esclaves en 1863. King déclare ensuite « qu’un siècle plus tard, le Nègre n'est toujours pas libre ». Poursuivant son discours, il s’écarte peu à peu de ses notes et improvise une anaphore, martelant l'expression « I have a dream » après que Mahalia Jackson lui a crié : « Parle-leur de ton rêve, Martin ! » Celui-ci décrit alors son rêve de liberté et d'égalité émergeant d'un monde marqué par l'esclavage et la haine. Selon le journaliste Jon Meacham, par cette seule phrase, Martin Luther King rejoint Jefferson et Lincoln parmi les hommes qui ont façonné les États-Unis modernes."},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Ña weddi ca ñoñ-téere ya ak way-bokkaale ya yéenewuñuleen, yiw wu bari ba bawoo ca seen Boroom, wàcc ci yéen, te Yàlla dana jagale yërmaandeem ku ko soob. Yàlla mooy boroom ngëneel yu màgg yi.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Ña weddi ca ñoñtéere ya ak waybokkaale ya yéenewu ñu léen, yiw wu bàri ba bawoo ca séen Boroom, wàcc ci yéen, te Yàlla da na jagale yërmandeem ku ko soob. Yàlla moo'y boroom ngëneel yu màgg yi."},{"question":"केहि उत्सव परम्पराहरूमा मास्क वा पोशाकको कुनै अर्थ के हुन्छ?","answer":"उत्सवमा प्रयोग गरिएका मास्क वा पोशाकहरू धेरैपटक आध्यात्मिक प्राणीहरू, ऐतिहासिक पात्रहरू, देवताहरू, वा पौराणिक अस्तित्वहरूलाई प्रतिनिधित्व गर्दछन्, सांस्कृतिक प्रतिष्ठा र कथाकलापलाई दर्शाउँदै।"},{"question":"大阪大学の初代総長をつとめた、原子模型の理論で知られる物理学者は誰でしょう？","answer":"長岡半太郎"},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة عتاب من بحر الكامل.","answer":"وَجَدَ القَريضُ إِلى العِتابِ سَبيلافَثَنى مَعاذِرَكَ الوُعورَ سُهولاما لي أُحَرِّكُ مِن وَفائِكَ ساكِناًوَأَهُزُّ مِنكَ إِلى الصَفاءِ كَليلاطالَ المِطالُ بِرَدِّ وِدٍّ لَم يَزَلعِندي مَصوناً فيكُمُ مَبذولافَإِلى مَتى يُنشي عِتابُكَ هَبوَةًوَتَشُنُّها قالاً عَلَيَّ وَقيلافي كُلِّ يَومٍ غارَةٌ ما تَنقَضيإِلّا وَتَثني سَيفَهُ مَفلولاإِنَّ الَّذي قَصَدَ المَدائِحَ غُلَّةًأَحرى بِأَن يَجِدَ الهِجاءَ غَليلاكَم مِن نِظامٍ قَد نَثَرنَ هَواجِسيحَتّى نَظَمتُ العُذرَ فيهِ فُضولاوَقَصائِدٍ سَدَّدتُهُنَّ أَسِنَّةًوَشَهَرتُهُنَّ قَواضِباً وَنُصولاجُعِلَت لِرَقراقِ السُرورِ جَداوِلاًنَحوَ القُلوبِ وَلِلهُمومِ سَبيلا"},{"question":"Phép tính x – 4 thực hiện được trong tập số tự nhiên khi:A. x > 4 B. x ≥ 4 C. x = 3D. x < 4 ","answer":"Lời giảiLý thuyết: Phép tính a – b  thực hiện được trong tập số tự nhiên khi a ≥ bDo đó: Phép tính x – 4 thực hiện được trong tập số tự nhiên khi x ≥ 4.Chọn đáp án B."},{"question":"Кыргыз тилинде метонимиялык  жол менен пайда болгон көп маанилүү сөздөрдү кандай түшүндуруп бере аласың? Ага карат мисал келтире кетчи.","answer":"Жарайт, анде эмесе кеттик! Кыргыз тилинде метонимияда нерселердин ортосундагы байланыш-катыш ар түрдүү мүнөздө болот: -Адам менен анын кийиминин ортосундагы байланыш: Ак жоолук жылмайып эшиктен кирип келди. - Идиш менен анын ичиндеги нерсенин ортосундагы байланыш: Бир аз күтүп турсан болмок, казан кайнап алды. -Ар кандай наамдагы зат менен нерсенин ортосундагы байланыш: Жусуптун калем акысына деп жыйырма пачка индийскийди айдап жүргөн автолавкасын колтуктай чыккан тура. - Сан менен нерсенин ортосундагы байланыш: Биринчи, сахнага чыгып коюнуз. - Орун менен адамдардын ортосундагы байланыш: Зал ичи кол чаап жиберди. - Иш орду же мекеме менен адамдардын ортосундагы байланыш: Бул продукт Тойбосско тиешелүү. - Автор менен анын чыгармаларынын ортосундагы байланыш: Шекспирди жана Айтматовду окуганымда жан дүйнөмө башкача сезимдер келди."},{"question":"ఒక బాలుడికి నెలక్రితం మశూచి వచ్చింది. ఇప్పుడు తగ్గింది. అతను మశూచి వచ్చిన పిల్లలతో కలసి ఉంటున్నాడు. అతనికి మశూచి మరలా వస్తుందా ! రాదా ! ఎందుకు ?","answer":"ఒక బాలుడికి నెలక్రితం మశూచి వచ్చింది. ఇప్పుడు తగ్గింది. అతను మశూచి వచ్చిన పిల్లలతో ‘కలిసి ఉన్నా అతనికి మశూచి మరలా రాదు. ఎందుకు అంటే మన శరీరంలో ఉన్న వ్యాధి నిరోధక శక్తి వ్యాధి జనక జీవితో మొదటగా ప్రవేశించినప్పుడు ప్రత్యేకంగా పోరాడే శక్తిని కలిగి ఉంటుంది.అది మొదటిగా వ్యాధి జనక క్రిములను గుర్తిస్తుంది. వాటిపై ప్రతిస్పందించి, జీవితాంతం వాటిని ప్రత్యేకంగా గుర్తు పెట్టుకుంటుంది. రెండవసారి అదే వ్యాధి జనక జీవి లేదా దానికి సంబంధించిన మరొక వ్యాధి జనక జీవి శరీరంలో ప్రవేశించినప్పుడు మన శరీరంలోని వ్యాధి నిరోధక శక్తి చాలా బలంగా పోరాడి మొదటిసారి కంటే తొందరగా వ్యాధి జనక జీవులను శరీరం నుంచి తొలగిస్తుంది."},{"question":"Maxaad awoodaa shaqada wax kabaxsan?","answer":"Aqriste: jawaabtu, Aniga waxaan jeclahay in aan qabto  wax walbo oo lagu horumarinaa kambaniga, hadee noqota fikir, xoog iyo maskax, marka aan tagaayo shaqada waxaan jeclahay in aan qabto howsha xafiiskeeda lagu horumarinaayo, sidoo kale waxaan aad u rabaa in aan ka bixiyo mishaarkeeda wax yaalaha yar yar oo lagu horumarinaa xafiiskeeyga , maxaa yeelay hadii aan horumariyo xafiiskeyga waa anigoo horumariyey kambaniga oo idil, hasa ahaatee, awooda xirfadeed ee aan rabo oona ka baxsan shaqada la i gulasoo heshiiyey waxaa ka mid ah:-1: Qof u baahan caawi maad, tusaale: shaqaala ayaa xanuunsaday, marka waxaa lagaa rabaa in aad buuxisa booskaas,2: Saacadihii lagula soo heshiiyey maalinta wey dhamaatay, balse, Xafiiskaada dad baa u baahan in aad u shaqeyso.3: In aad suubiso xayeysiin kambaniga aad u shaqeyso4: In aad keenta fikrada lagu horumarinaayo kambanigaada.5: In aan keeno xirfado lagu horumarinaayo shaqaalaha, Sidoo kale Dhib iyo dheef in aan u halgama kambanigeyga."},{"question":"Qual a resposta para a pergunta: Qual livro da série Jogos Vorazes é o mais longo?","answer":"A resposta correta é Em Chamas "},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe \\"alakarabo\\"?","answer":"Ny atao hoe \\"alakarabo\\" dia anarana ny laharana fahavalo amin' ny volana malagasy, ary zana-bintana ampofoin' ny Adimizana. Amin' ny lafin-drindrina andrefana, avy eo avaratry ny zorom-baravarambe no anjara-toerany. Ny anarany dia nalaina avy tamin' ny antokon-kintana izay ataon' ny Arabo hoe El-aqrab (Scorpion, maingoka)."},{"question":"Kokia treko dviratininkė 2009 bei 2010 m. tapo ir pasaulio čempione, ir pasaulio rekordininke, o 2009, 2010 ir 2016 m. buvo išrinkta Lietuvos metų sportininke?","answer":"Simona Krupeckaitė."},{"question":"रॉकेट प्रोपल्शन कसे कार्य करते?","answer":"रॉकेट प्रोपल्शन हे विज्ञान आणि तंत्रज्ञान आहे ज्यामध्ये रॉकेट अवकाशाच्या निर्वातातून किंवा पृथ्वीच्या वातावरणातून पुढे जाण्यासाठी जोर कसा निर्माण करतात. रॉकेट प्रणोदनामागील मूलभूत तत्त्व म्हणजे न्यूटनचा गतीचा तिसरा नियम: \\"प्रत्येक क्रियेसाठी समान आणि विरुद्ध प्रतिक्रिया असते.\\" रॉकेटीच्या संदर्भात, या कायद्याचा अर्थ असा आहे की जेव्हा रॉकेट वस्तुमान एका दिशेने (कृती) बाहेर काढते, तेव्हा त्याला विरुद्ध दिशेने एक शक्ती अनुभवते, जी त्यास पुढे (प्रतिक्रिया) चालवते.रॉकेट प्रोपल्शन कसे कार्य करते याचे मूलभूत स्पष्टीकरण येथे आहे:1. प्रोपेलंट: रॉकेटमध्ये दोन प्रकारचे प्रणोदक असतात: इंधन आणि ऑक्सिडायझर. हे वेगळ्या टाक्यांमध्ये साठवले जातात आणि हाय-स्पीड एक्झॉस्ट वायू तयार करण्यासाठी ज्वलन कक्षामध्ये एकत्र आणि प्रज्वलित केले जातात. सामान्य प्रणोदकामध्ये द्रव हायड्रोजन आणि द्रव ऑक्सिजन (स्पेस शटलच्या मुख्य इंजिनमध्ये वापरला जातो) आणि RP-1 (केरोसीनचा एक परिष्कृत प्रकार) आणि द्रव ऑक्सिजन (अपोलो मोहिमेला चंद्रावर नेणाऱ्या शनि व्ही रॉकेटच्या पहिल्या टप्प्यात वापरलेला) यांचा समावेश होतो. .2. दहन: ज्वलन कक्षामध्ये, इंधन आणि ऑक्सिडायझर मिसळले जातात आणि प्रज्वलित केले जातात. ही रासायनिक अभिक्रिया प्रचंड प्रमाणात उष्णता सोडते आणि उच्च-दाब वायू तयार करते. वायू वेगाने विस्तारतात आणि रॉकेट नोजलमधून उच्च वेगाने बाहेर पडतात.3. नोजल: रॉकेट नोजल हा काळजीपूर्वक डिझाइन केलेला घटक आहे जो ज्वलन कक्षातून बाहेर पडताना गरम वायूंचा वेग वाढवतो. ते उच्च-दबाव, उच्च-तापमान वायूंचे एक्झॉस्टच्या हाय-स्पीड जेटमध्ये रूपांतरित करते. थ्रस्ट आणि कार्यक्षमता ऑप्टिमाइझ करण्यासाठी नोजलचा आकार महत्त्वपूर्ण आहे.4. क्रिया आणि प्रतिक्रिया: रॉकेटच्या नोझलमधून हाय-स्पीड एक्झॉस्ट वायू बाहेर काढले जात असताना, ते न्यूटनच्या तिसऱ्या नियमानुसार विरुद्ध दिशेने एक बल निर्माण करतात. या शक्तीला जोर म्हणतात. रॉकेटला हा जोर एक धक्का देणारी शक्ती म्हणून अनुभवतो जो त्याला पुढे नेतो.5. सतत प्रक्रिया: रॉकेट प्रोपल्शन ही एक सतत प्रक्रिया आहे. जोपर्यंत प्रणोदकांचे ज्वलन टिकून राहते, तोपर्यंत एक्झॉस्ट वायू उच्च वेगाने बाहेर काढले जातात आणि रॉकेटला जोराचा अनुभव येत राहतो. हे रॉकेटला वेग वाढवण्यास आणि उच्च गतीपर्यंत पोहोचण्यास अनुमती देते.हे लक्षात घेणे महत्त्वाचे आहे की रॉकेट प्रोपल्शन केवळ अंतराळातच नाही तर पृथ्वीच्या वातावरणात देखील कार्य करते. अंतराळात, जेथे वातावरण नसते, रॉकेट केवळ जोर निर्माण करण्यासाठी वस्तुमान बाहेर काढण्यावर अवलंबून असतात. वातावरणात, रॉकेट वातावरणातील ऑक्सिजनचा वापर दहनासाठी करतात, म्हणूनच काही रॉकेट डिझाइन वेगवेगळ्या उंचीसाठी अनुकूल आहेत.रॉकेट इंजिनची रचना आणि जटिलता बदलू शकते, साध्या घन रॉकेट मोटर्सपासून ते अत्यंत जटिल द्रव-इंधन इंजिनपर्यंत. कार्यक्षमता, नियंत्रणक्षमता आणि विशिष्ट अनुप्रयोगांच्या बाबतीत प्रत्येक प्रकाराचे स्वतःचे फायदे आणि तोटे आहेत."},{"question":"Apakah terjun lelabah?","answer":"Terjun lelabah ialah satu aktiviti yang melibatkan penerjunan dari bangunan yang tinggi sementara pelompat disambungkan kepada tali elastik besar. Struktur ini biasanya objek yang tetap seperti sebuah bangunan, jambatan atau kren, tetapi lompatan juga boleh dibuat daripada objek yang bergerak seperti belon udara panas atau helikopter yang mempunyai keupayaan untuk berlegar di atas tanah. Rasa keterujaan sewaktu melakukan aktiviti ini datangnya daripada terjunan bebas serta lonjakan semula yang terhasil. Apabila orang yang diikut itu menerjun, tali menjadi tegang lalu si penerjun 'terbang' ke atas lagi akibat pengecutan tali dan terus berayun ke atas dan ke bawah sehingga kesemua tenaga kinetik yang tersimpan akhirnya hilang."},{"question":"اكتب سؤال في الجغرافيا وأجب عنه","answer":"كم عدد الدول في قارة أستراليا؟ 3"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਤੁਧੁ ਸਚੇ ਸੁਬਹਾਨੁ ਸਦਾ ਕਲਾਣਿਆ ॥ਤੂੰ ਸਚਾ ਦੀਬਾਣੁ ਹੋਰਿ ਆਵਣ ਜਾਣਿਆ ॥ਸਚੁ ਜਿ ਮੰਗਹਿ ਦਾਨੁ ਸਿ ਤੁਧੈ ਜੇਹਿਆ ॥ਸਚੁ ਤੇਰਾ ਫੁਰਮਾਨੁ ਸਬਦੇ ਸੋਹਿਆ ॥ਮੰਨਿਐ ਗਿਆਨੁ ਧਿਆਨੁ ਤੁਧੈ ਤੇ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਕਰਮਿ ਪਵੈ ਨੀਸਾਨੁ ਨ ਚਲੈ ਚਲਾਇਆ ॥ਤੂੰ ਸਚਾ ਦਾਤਾਰੁ ਨਿਤ ਦੇਵਹਿ ਚੜਹਿ ਸਵਾਇਆ ॥ਨਾਨਕੁ ਮੰਗੈ ਦਾਨੁ ਜੋ ਤੁਧੁ ਭਾਇਆ ॥੨੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 150 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅੰਗਦ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਸੱਚੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ! ਮੈਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ‘ਸੁਬਹਾਨੁ’ (ਆਖ ਆਖ ਕੇ) ਵਡਿਆਉਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ; ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹਾਕਮ ਹੈਂ, ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ ਜੰਮਦੇ ਮਰਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । (ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਜੋ ਬੰਦੇ ਤੇਰਾ ਸੱਚਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰੂਪ ਦਾਨ ਤੈਥੋਂ ਮੰਗਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹ ਤੇਰੇ ਵਰਗੇ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ; ਤੇਰਾ ਅੱਟਲ ਹੁਕਮ (ਗੁਰ-) ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਮਿੱਠਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ; ਤੇਰਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਮੰਨਣ ਨਾਲ ਅਸਲੀਅਤ ਦੀ ਸਮਝ ਤੇ ਉੱਚੀ ਟਿਕੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਤੇਰੇ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਾਸਲ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਤੇ ਇਹ ਸੋਹਣਾ) ਲੇਖ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਕਿਸੇ ਦਾ ਮਿਟਾਇਆ ਮਿਟਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ । ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ਾਂ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਨਿੱਤ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ਾਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ ਤੇ ਵਧੀਕ ਵਧੀਕ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ਾਂ ਕਰੀ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ । ਨਾਨਕ (ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਉਹੀ ਦਾਨ ਮੰਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਚੰਗਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਤੇਰੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਰਾਜ਼ੀ ਰਹਿਣ ਦਾ ਦਾਨ ਮੰਗਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੨੬।\\""},{"question":"句子1: 它位于昆<unk>溪和穆勒姆穆勒姆溪之间的山丘上. 句子二: 它位于穆勒姆溪和昆<unk>溪之间的山丘上. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"相同"},{"question":"Freagra a chur ar an gceist mhionsonraithe seo: Cé a rinne níos mó scannáin, Leslie Goodwins nó Kenneth Webb?","answer":"Rinne Leslie Goodwins é."},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase:  A Guerra de independência da Grécia foi primeiro uma guerra de libertação, uma luta contra a opressão otomana. Os movimentos principais efetuaram-se no Peloponeso e ao redor de Atenas. Houve também uns combates no Epiro (sobretudo por causa de Ali Paxá). A vitória final foi obtida graças ao apoio das grandes potências, a França, o Reino Unido e a Rússia, (que logo se fizeram chamar \\"Potências Protetoras\\" do novo reino grego) com, entre outras coisas, a","answer":"Batalha de Navarino e a expedição francesa de Peloponeso. Os gregos não se acharam em situação de obter todo o que queriam no momento das negociações que seguiram o fim do conflito. Com o fim de cuidar-se ainda do Império Otomano, a Conferência de Londres de 1830 fixou as fronteiras do novo Estado. A Grécia devia contentar-se com o Peloponeso, com uma parte da Rumélia (a fronteira ia de Arta a oeste a Vólos a leste) e de algumas ilhas próximas do continente como Egina ou Hidra e uma parte das Cíclades. de três milhões dos considerados como gregos reencontravam-se no novo Estado enquanto Constantinopla reagrupava gregos. Os grandes centros culturais, religiosos e econômicos estavam todos fora do reino, que não contava nenhuma grande cidade: as três primeiras capitais (Egina, Náuplia e mesmo Atenas) não ultrapassavam os 5000 habitantes. Desta forma, a decepção dos patriotas gregos dentro e fora do Estado foi grande."},{"question":"2023 ඔස්කාර් සම්මාන උළලේ හොඳම නිළියට හිමි සම්මානය දිනා ගත්තේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"Michelle Yeoh (Everything Everywhere All at Once)"},{"question":"Muhammad Ali","answer":"Muhammad Ali (orúko àbíso Cassius Marcellus Clay, Jr.; January 17, 1942 - June 3, 2016) jẹ́ ajẹ̀sẹ ará Amẹ́ríkà tó ti fẹ̀yị̀ntì àti onídárayá àkọ́kọ́ ágbáyé fún wúwotówúwo ní ẹ̀ẹ̀mẹta.A bi Ali si Louisville, Kentucky osi dagba si be pelu. O bẹrẹ ikẹkọ bi afẹṣẹja amateur ni ọjọ -ori 12. Ni ọdun 18, o ṣẹgun goolu kan ni pipin iwuwo iwuwo ina ni Awọn Olimpiiki Igba Irẹdanu Ewe 1960 ati pe o di alamọdaju nigbamii ni ọdun yẹn. O di Musulumi lẹyin ọdun 1961. O bori ni aṣaju iwuwo iwuwo agbaye lati ọdọ Sonny Liston ni ibinu nla ni ọjọ Kínní 25, 1964, ni ọjọ -ori 22. Ni Oṣu Kẹta ọjọ 6, 1964, o kede pe oun ko ni mọ mọ Cassius Clay ṣugbọn bi Muhammad Ali. Ni 1966, Ali kọ lati jẹ ki o wa sinu ologun, ni sisọ awọn igbagbọ ẹsin rẹ ati atako ihuwa si Ogun Vietnam. O jẹbi pe o yago fun kikọ silẹ nitorina o dojuko ọdun marun ninu tubu ati pe o gba awọn akọle Boxing rẹ. O duro kuro ninu tubu bi o ti bẹbẹ fun ipinnu si Ile -ẹjọ Adajọ, eyiti o yi idajọ rẹ pada ni ọdun 1971, ṣugbọn ko ti ja fun o fẹrẹ to ọdun mẹrin o padanu akoko iṣẹ ṣiṣe giga bi elere idaraya. Awọn iṣe Ali gẹgẹ bi alatako-ọkan si Ogun Vietnam jẹ ki o jẹ aami fun iran counterculture ti o tobi, ati pe o jẹ eeyan ti o ga pupọ ti igberaga ẹlẹyamẹya fun awọn ara Amẹrika Amẹrika lakoko gbigbe awọn ẹtọ ara ilu ati jakejado iṣẹ rẹ. Gẹgẹbi Musulumi, Ali ni ajọṣepọ lakoko pẹlu Elijah Muhammad's Nation of Islam (NOI). Nigbamii o kọwọ si NOI, ti o faramọ Islam Sunni, ati atilẹyin iṣọpọ ẹya bi onimọran iṣaaju rẹ Malcolm X. O kopa ninu ọpọlọpọ awọn ere -idije boxing ni pataki julọ awọn ija rẹ pẹlu Joe Frazier, pẹlu Ija ti Ọdun (iṣẹlẹ afẹṣẹja ti o tobi julọ titi di igba naa), Thrilla ni Manila, ati ija rẹ pẹlu George Foreman ti a mọ si The Rumble ninu Jungle, eyiti o jẹ wiwo nipasẹ igbasilẹ ti a fojusi awọn olugbohunsafefe tẹlifisiọnu ti awọn oluwo bilionu 1 ni kariaye, di igbohunsafefe tẹlifisiọnu laaye julọ julọ ni agbaye ni akoko yẹn. Ali ṣe rere ni iranran ni akoko kan nigbati ọpọlọpọ awọn onija jẹ ki awọn alakoso wọn sọrọ, ati pe o jẹ igbagbogbo ni imunibinu ati ajeji. O jẹ olokiki fun sisọ ọrọ idọti, ati igbagbogbo ni aṣa-ara pẹlu awọn eto orin ati ọrọ ewi ọrọ, ifojusọna awọn eroja ti hip hop. Ni ode oruka, Ali ti ṣaṣeyọri bi oṣere olorin ọrọ, nibiti o ti gba awọn yiyan Grammy meji. O tun ṣe ifihan bi oṣere ati onkọwe, dasile awọn itan -akọọlẹ ara ẹni meji. Ali ti fẹyìntì lati afẹṣẹja ni ọdun 1981 ati idojukọ lori ẹsin, alanu ati ijajagbara. Ni ọdun 1984, o ṣe agbekalẹ iwadii aisan ti Parkinson's syndrome, eyiti diẹ ninu awọn ijabọ ṣe ikawe si awọn ipalara ti o ni ibatan Boxing, botilẹjẹpe oun ati awọn dokita alamọja rẹ tako eyi. O jẹ eniyan ti n ṣiṣẹ lọwọ ni kariaye, ṣugbọn ni awọn ọdun igbẹhin rẹ ṣe awọn ifarahan gbangba diẹ bi ipo rẹ ti buru si, ati pe idile rẹ tọju rẹ. Ali ku ni Oṣu Karun ọjọ 3, ọdun 2016."},{"question":"Louis Pasteur ṣàwárí pé àwọn kòkòrò bakitéríà tó wà nínú ohun kan lè kú tí wọ́n bá mú kí ohun náà gbóná fún àkókò kúkúrú. Èwo nínú àwọn àṣà wọ̀nyí ló jàǹfààní jù lọ látinú ohun tí Pasteur ṣàwárí? Kí ló dé?  (a) fífi oúnjẹ pa mọ́ fún àkókò gígùn.(b) kíkọ́ àwọn ààrò àti àwọn ohun èèlò amúnáwá mìíràn.","answer":"(a) fífi oúnjẹ pa mọ́ fún àkókò gígùn."},{"question":"Naanị ","answer":"Olundi - Sọọsọ"},{"question":"హిల్సా చేపల మార్కెట్ విలువ సుమారు 18 వేల కోట్ల రూపాయలుకొన్ని మత్స్య జాతులు అంతరించిపోతుండగా, మరి కొన్ని తగ్గిపోతున్నాయని, బంగాళాఖాతంలో మత్స్య నిల్వల గురించి ప్రచురితమైన ఒక నివేదిక తెలిపింది.గల్ఫ్ అఫ్ థాయిలాండ్ వంటి కొన్ని సముద్ర తీరాల్లో చేపలు పూర్తిగా అంతరించిపోయాయని ఈ నివేదిక తయారు చేసిన వారిలో ఒకరైన సయేదుర్ రెహమాన్ చౌదరి ‘బీబీసీ బెంగాలీ’కి చెప్పారు.\\"మా బంగాళాఖాతం అలా మారడం మాకు ఇష్టం లేదు\\" అని ఆయన అన్నారు.కొన్ని వందల పెద్ద బోటులు వారు ఇక్కడ అధికంగా చేపలని వేటాడుతున్నారని కొంత మంది పర్యవేక్షకులు చెప్పారు.పెద్ద ట్రాలర్ల వాళ్ళు  సాధారణంగా తాము ఆధారపడే కొన్ని ప్రత్యేక రకాల మత్స్య జాతులను వేటాడటంతో కూడా ఈ సమస్య తలెత్తుతోందని, ప్రభుత్వం వీటిని పట్టించుకోవడం లేదని స్థానిక మత్స్యకారులు చెబుతున్నారు.ప్రపంచంలో అత్యధిక జనసాంద్రత కలిగిన దేశాల్లో బంగ్లాదేశ్ ఒకటి. ముఖ్యంగా నదులు బంగాళాఖాతంలో కలిసే ప్రాంతాల్లో ప్రజలు ఎక్కువగా జీవిస్తుంటారు.వీరిలో కనీసం 15 లక్షల జనాభా జీవనాధారం కోసం మత్స్య వేటపై ఆధారపడతారు. దేశ జనాభా తమ ఆహారంలో ప్రోటీన్ కోసం  చేపల మీద ఆధారపడుతుంది.అయితే ఈ ప్రాంతంలో ... Continue the article for another 4000 characters max:","answer":"పూర్తిగా టైగర్ రొయ్యలు, సాల్మన్ చేపల రకాలు అంతరించిపోయాయని మూడు సంవత్సరాలు పాటు అధ్యయనం చేసిన ప్రభుత్వ నివేదిక తెలిపింది.కొన్ని సంవత్సరాల క్రితం వరకు ఒక రెండు గంటలు వేటాడితే చేపలు పడేవని కానీ ఇప్పుడు 20 గంటలు సముద్రంలో ప్రయాణిస్తే గాని చేపలు పడటంలేదని, 35 సంవత్సరాలుగా చిట్టగాంగ్ రేవులో చేపలు పడుతున్న జాసిం అనే మత్స్యకారుడు చెప్పారు.\\"గతంలో చాలా రకాల చేపల్ని పట్టేవాళ్ళం. కానీ, ఇప్పుడు దొరకటం లేదు’’ అని జాసిం చెప్పారు. పెద్ద ట్రాలర్లు చేపల్ని వేటాడటమే ఈ పరిస్థితికి కారణమని జాసిం లాంటి మరి కొంత మంది చిన్న మత్స్యకారులు ఆరోపించారు.బంగాళాఖాతంలో అంతరించిపోతున్న మత్స్య జాతులునియంత్రణలో లేని ట్రాలర్లుబంగ్లాదేశ్ తీరంలో సుమారు 270  ట్రాలర్లు ఉన్నాయి. పెద్ద ట్రాలర్ ప్రతి సారి కనీసం 400 టన్నుల చేపలను వేటాడగలవు. ఇది సాధారణ బోట్ కన్నా 20  రెట్లు ఎక్కువ.“దీనిని నియంత్రించకపోతే భావి తరాలకి చేపలు దొరకవేమో” అని చౌదరి అన్నారు.ట్రాలర్ యజమానులు ప్రభుత్వానికి చెల్లించే లైసెన్స్ ఫీ వారి కంపెనీ లు సంపాదించే లాభాలలో అతి తక్కువ భాగం.చేపలు పట్టేందుకు కావల్సిన లైసెన్సులను ఈ కంపెనీలు చేపలు పట్టేవాళ్ళకి అమ్ముతాయి. ప్రభుత్వం ఆ అధికారాన్ని ఆ కంపెనీలకి కొన్ని సంవత్సరాల క్రితం ఇచ్చింది.దీంతో ఫిషరీస్ విభాగానికి సముద్రంలోకి వెళ్లే బోటులను నియంత్రించడం కష్టతరంగా మారింది.పాత లైసెన్సులని రద్దు చేసేందుకు ఫిషరీస్ విభాగానికి అధికారాలు ఇచ్చే కొత్త చట్టం పార్లమెంటులో ప్రవేశ పెట్టనున్నారు.అయితే, చాలా సార్లు బోట్ నిర్వాహకులు, వీటిని నియంత్రణలో పెట్టే ఎన్‌ఫోర్స్‌మెంట్ ఆఫీసర్లను కోర్టుల వరకు తీసుకుని వెళతారు. దీంతో, వ్యక్తిగతంగా కూడా అధికారులకి ముప్పు ఉంటుంది.సముద్ర ఉత్పత్తుల గురించి సరైన సమాచారం వచ్చే వరకు కొత్త ట్రాలర్లకి లైసెన్సులు ఇవ్వమని నావల్ ట్రేడ్ డిపార్ట్‌మెంట్ ఉన్నతాధికారి కెప్టెన్ మొహమ్మద్ గియాసుద్దీన్ అహ్మద్ చెప్పారు.“ఇలాగే జరిగితే చేపలు పట్టే ప్రాంతాల్లో ఇక చేపలు కనుమరుగవుతాయి” అని ఆయన అన్నారు.చేపల రకాలు తగ్గిపోవడంతో పెద్ద ట్రాలర్ల వాళ్ళు హిల్సా (గోదావరి డెల్టాలో దొరికే పులస రకం) చేపల వేటని లక్ష్యంగా పెట్టుకున్నారు. ఈ చేప బంగ్లాదేశ్ ఆహార భద్రతలో, సాంప్రదాయ మత్స్యకారుల జీవనాధారంలో చాలా ముఖ్యమైన పాత్ర పోషిస్తుంది.చిట్టగాంగ్ సముద్ర తీరంలో లంగరు వేసి ఉన్న సీ వ్యూ, సీ విండ్ ట్రాలర్లను బీబీసీ చూసింది"},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদ কোন গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ঘটনা সম্পর্কে ?প্রতুল ভট্টাচার্য বা প্রতুলচন্দ্র ভট্টাচার্য () (১৬ জানুয়ারি, ১৯০০ - ২৯ আগস্ট, ১৯৭৮) ছিলেন ভারতীয় উপমহাদেশের ব্রিটিশ বিরোধী স্বাধীনতা আন্দোলনের একজন অন্যতম ব্যক্তিত্ব এবং অগ্নিযুগের বিপ্লবী। ছাত্রাবস্থাতেই বিপ্লবী নেতা হেমেন্দ্রকিশোর আচার্য চৌধুরীর প্রভাবে যুগান্তর দলের সঙ্গে যুক্ত হন। ময়মনসিংহে শিক্ষা শেষ করে কলকাতায় আইন কলেজে পড়ার সময় বেঙ্গল ক্রিমিনাল ল অ্যাামেন্ডমেন্ট অ্যাক্টে আটক বন্দি হিসেবে জেলে থাকেন। ১৯২৮ সালে মুক্ত হন। ঐ বছরই কলকাতা কংগ্রেসে সুভাষচন্দ্র বসুর নেতৃত্বে পরিচালিত স্বেচ্ছাসেবক বাহিনীর সহ দলনেতার ভূমিকা গ্রহণ করেন। ঐ আধা-সামরিক বাহিনী গঠন করার উদ্দেশ্য ছিলো ভবিষ্যতে বিপ্লবী কর্মকাণ্ডের প্রস্তুতি। ১৯৩০ সালে তিন আইনে ধরা পড়ে ভারতের বিভিন্ন কারাগারে থাকেন। ১৯৩৮ সনে মুক্তি পাবার পর থেকে আমৃত্যু বাংলাদেশের কমিউনিস্ট পার্টির সদস্য ছিলেন। পূর্ব বাংলার মুক্তি আন্দোলনের সময় বহুভাবে এই আন্দোলনকে সাহায্য করেছেন। তিনি ব্রিটিশ রাজের জেলে মোট ১০ বছর বন্দি ছিলেন।","answer":"মুক্তি আন্দোলন |"},{"question":"Ti mo ba tun aye wa, Yinka ni ma a fẹ – Joe Odumakin","answer":"Iyawo Oloogbe Yinka Odumakin, Joe, ti sọ pe to ba ṣee ṣe fun oun lati tun aye wa, ọkunrin naa loun yoo tun pada fẹ gẹgẹ bii ọkọ.Lasiko tijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun n tẹwọ gba oku akọni yii ni Aṣejirẹ ni Joe sọrọ naa. O ni ọkọ rere, olufẹ awọn ọmọ rẹ lo jẹ.O ni ọkan pataki ninu ohun ti oun fi n jẹ eeyan lo ti lọ yii, ati pe oludamọran ati alaabarin oun ni Yinka jẹ.Joe fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe itunu toun ni nipa iku ọkọ oun ni pe o jẹ oniwa rere ati olorukọ rere, ki i ṣe fun ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre nikan, bi ko ṣe fun gbogbo orilẹ-ede yii.O waa dupẹ lọwọ ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun fun aduroti wọn latigba ti oloogbe naa ti jade laye."},{"question":"Ederede a ga-achịkọta: Mgbe anyị  jụrụ ụfọdụ ụmụnwaanyị ihe mere ha ji achọrịrị isi nri ụbọchị ahụ karịa ma inye ya onye ọzọ ka o siere ha maọbụ sie nri ahụ ụbọchị ọzọ tupu ụbọchị Ekeresimesi.Lee ihe ha sara anyị.Ọrịaku Sarah Medebem kwuru na ọ nọ n'usekwu site n'elekere iri na otu ruo elekere ise nke mgbede.O kwuru na o sipụtara osikapa, ofe na salad nye ndị be ya ma nyekwa ndị ọbịa.Oriakụ Stella Ezenwa kwuru na o ji elekere anọ na ọkara wee sie ofe ọha, sụọ akpu, ofe akwụ na osikapa.Oriakụ Nkem Ezike kwuru na o ji ụtụtụ bido siwe nri tupu ọ mara ihe na-emenụ, ọ kụọla elekere isii nke mgbede.Ọriakụ Sandra Harison kwuru na n'agbanyeghị na di ya agaala ala Igbo maka emume Ekeresimesi, o siri ọtụtụ nri.O kenyere ndị agbataobi ya nri o ji elekere atọ wee si.Mana Ugonna Okafor kwuru na dọkịta  ya gwara ya na ya abakwala usekwu n'oge mmemme a.O kwuru na ọ bụ makana ọ ka na-agbake n'ọrịa.Oriakụ Onyinye Ifionu kwuru na o ji elekere anọ  wee sie nri niile o siri ụbọchị Ekeresimesi.O kwuru na ihe mere ụmụnwaanyị jị anọte aka n'usekwu bụ makana ụbọchị ekeresimesi pụrụ iche .O kwuru na o nweghị ike inye onye ọzọ nri ka o siere ya ụbọchị ahụ makana ọ bụ ụbọchị ụmụnwaanyị kwesịrị iji leta ezinaụlọ ha ọfụma.Akụkọ ndị a ga-amasị gị:Nchịkọta nọ n'otu asụsụ dịka ederede:","answer":"Ọ ka ana-agbagwoju ọtụtụ mmadụ anya n'ala Igbo etu ụmụanwannyị sị anọte aka n'usekwu oge Ekeresimesi ọbụla."},{"question":"人工的に作られた最初の元素である、原子番号43、元素記号Ｔｃの元素は何でしょう？","answer":"テクネチウムです。"},{"question":"කෝස්ටික් සෝඩා නිපදවීමේ පටල කෝෂ ක්‍රමයෙහි ප්‍රධාන වාසි නම් කරන්න.","answer":"කෝස්ටික් සෝඩා නිපදවීමේ පටල කෝෂ ක්‍රමයෙහි ප්‍රධාන වාසි 3කි.නිපදවෙන NaOH ඉහළ සංශුද්ධතාවයකින් යුක්ත වීම.අඩු විදුලි ප්‍රමානයක් භාවිතා වීම.පාරිසරික බලපෑම අවම වීම."},{"question":"Ang bawat donut ay nagkakahalaga ng 1.20. Magkano ang halaga ng 6 na donut?","answer":"1.20 * 6 = 7.2Ang kabuuang halaga ng 6 na donut ay 7.2."},{"question":"कोणत्या देशाच्या चलनावर गणपतीचा फोटो आहे?","answer":"उत्तर: इंडोनेशिया देशाच्या चलनावर गणपतीचा फोटो आहे "},{"question":"Ułóż pytanie do tego tekstu: \\"Jest to obraz olejny malarza Williama Etty’ego. Po raz pierwszy został wystawiony w 1821 roku. Obecnie znajduje się w muzeum Lady Lever Art Gallery, w pobliżu Liverpoolu. \\"","answer":"Przykładowe pytanie: Jaka jest historia obrazu \\"Przybycie Kleopatry do Cylicji\\"?"},{"question":"1999年には「雑草魂」で流行語大賞を受賞したことがあり、2013年は日本人で初めてワールドシリーズの胴上げ投手となったのは誰？","answer":"上原浩治です。"},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:وجاء ذكْر «زِيج الشاه» هذا لدى الجغرافي ابن رُسْتَه الفارسي (ت 300هـ/912م) في كتابه ‘الأعلاق النفيسة‘، فقال إن المنجّمين وعلماء الفلك -حتى عصر","answer":"الخليفة المأمون العباسي (ت 218هـ/833م)- كانوا \\"لا يجدون الأحكام تصحّ إلا من «زِيج الشاه»، فقد أرّخوه بملك يَزْدَجِرد بن شَهْريار (ت 30هـ/651م) آخر مَن مَلكَ من ملوك العجم\\"، أي ملوك الفُرس الساسانيين. وقد أوضح كراتشكوفسكي ما أجمله ابن رُسْتَه هنا بقوله إن هذا الزيج \\"يبدأ حساب توقيته ببداية مُلْك يزدجرد [الثالث]، أي في اليوم السادس عشر من شهر يونيو عام 632\\" ميلادية الموافقة لسنة 12 هجرية."},{"question":"पॅराशुटची संकल्पना सर्वप्रथम कोणी मांडली ?","answer":"लिओनार्डो-दा- व्हीन्सी"},{"question":"Алгачкы электростанция качан, ким ойлоп тапкан?","answer":"1882-жылы Томас Эдисон куруп, Перл-Стрит шаарындагы 85 үйдү свет менен камсыздаган."},{"question":"निम्नलिखित कविताको अर्थ लेख्नुहोस्:कुन् हो जगत्को गहना बन्याको ?बिद्यै छ सब्को गहना बन्याको ।कुन् सत्य हो, सत्य कसोरी जान्नू ?जुन प्राणीको हित् छ उ सत्य मान्नू ।","answer":"भनिन्छ विधार्थीको गहना भनेको अनुशासन हो । हो, जब एक विधार्थीमा अनुशासन हुन्छ, यसले उसलाई आकर्षक ढङ्गले प्रस्तुत गराउँछ । त्यसैगरी जगतको गहनाको रुपमा विद्यालाई परिभाषित गराइएको छ । जुन मानिसले विद्या आर्जन गरेको छ, उसले नै विश्वलाई आफ्नो मुट्ठीमा राख्न सफल भएको छ । त्यसैले विद्यालाई जगतको विशेष गहना भनिएको हो ।एउटै प्रश्नको वरिपरि मानिसहरु झुम्मिरहेका छन् र सत्य भनेको के हो ? भनेर मान्छे भौतारिँदै छन् । जसले गर्दा यस संसारको प्राणीहरुको हित हुन्छ,  त्यो नै वास्तवकि सत्य हो । सत्यले नै मानिसको स्वरुप देखाउँछ ।"},{"question":"મકરંદ દવેની 'ભજન કરે તે જીતે' વાર્તા લખો","answer":"તુલસીદલથી તોલ કરોતો બને પવન પરપોટે,અને હિમાલય મુકો હેમનોતો મેરુથી મોટો.આ ભારે હળવા હરિવરનેમૂલવવો શી રીતે?રે મનવા, ભજન કરે તે જીતે.હે વજન કરે તે હારેમનવા, ભજન કરે તે જીતે.એક ઘડી તને માંડ મળી છેઆ જીવતરને ઘાટે,સાચ ખોટના ખાતાં પાડીએમાં તું નહીં ખાટે.સહેલીશ તું સાગર મોજે કેપડ્યો રહીશ પછી તે?રે મનવા, ભજન કરે તે જીતે.હે વજન કરે તે હારેમનવા, ભજન કરે તે જીતે.આવ હવે તારા ગજ મૂકીવજન મુકીને વરવાંનવલખ તારા નીચે બેઠોક્યાં ત્રાજવડે તરવા?ચૌદ ભુવનનો સ્વામી આવેચપટી ધૂળની પ્રીતે.રે મનવા, ભજન કરે તે જીતે.હે વજન કરે તે હારેમનવા, ભજન કરે તે જીતે."},{"question":"திருவிகவின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"பிறப்பில் தீண்டமை கருதுவது கொடுமை; வண்கண்; அநாகரிகம்."},{"question":"请问“独木不成林”这句谚语是什么意思？","answer":"这句谚语的直译是一棵树成不了森林，用来比喻个人力量有限,办不成大事。"},{"question":"सगरमाथाको उचाई ","answer":"८८४८ मिटर छ ।"},{"question":"Sheeg sanadkii la aasaasay Jabhaddii SPM iyo dalkii lagu aasaasay?","answer":"Waxaa la aasaasay sanadkii 1989kii, waxaana lagu aasaasay dalka Itoobiya."},{"question":" Inona no marika simika amin'ny \\"Fer\\"?","answer":"Ny marika simika ho an'ny \\"Fer\\" dia \\"Fe\\"."},{"question":"O que é a JBS?","answer":"A JBS é um empresa de processamento de carne, com operações em carnes bovina, suína, de frango e alimentos processados."},{"question":"ઓજ અને અગર કાવ્ય નું વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"ઓજ અને અગરઓજ અને અગર બંને સાથે ચાલે,જેમ સૂર્ય અને ચંદ્ર સાથે ચાલે.ઓજ વિના અગર નથી,અગર વિના ઓજ નથી.ઓજ એ છે જે આપણને મજબૂત બનાવે છે,અગર એ છે જે આપણને ઉત્સાહિત બનાવે છે.ઓજ એ છે જે આપણને આગળ વધવા માટે પ્રેરણા આપે છે,અગર એ છે જે આપણને સફળતાની શિખર સુધી પહોંચાડે છે.ઓજ એ વિજયની શરૂઆત છે,અગર એ વિજયનો અંત છે.ઓજ એ વિજયનો રસ્તો છે,અગર એ વિજયનો પરિણામ છે.આપણે બધામાં ઓજ અને અગર છે,પરંતુ આપણે તેને જાગૃત કરવાની જરૂર છે.આપણે ઓજ અને અગરને એકબીજા સાથે જોડીને,આપણે કોઈપણ પડકારનો સામનો કરી શકીએ છીએ,અને આપણે કોઈપણ સપનું સાકાર કરી શકીએ છીએ.કાવ્યની ભાષા સરળ અને સ્પષ્ટ છે, અને તે કાવ્યની ભાવનાને સચોટ રીતે પ્રતિબિંબિત કરે છે. કાવ્યમાં ઉપયોગમાં લેવામાં આવેલા શબ્દો અને છંદ કાવ્યને એક સુંદરતા અને ગતિ આપે છે જે ઓજ અને અગરના મહિમાને પ્રતિબિંબિત કરે છે"},{"question":"கோடிட்ட இடத்தைக் கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள வார்த்தைகளில் சரியான வார்தையைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்து நிரப்புக.வாக்கியம்: வலப்பக்க சுவரின் மேல் ____________ (பல்லி / பள்ளி ) இருக்கிறது.","answer":"வாக்கியம்: வலப்பக்க சுவரின் மேல் பல்லி இருக்கிறது. காரணம்: கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள வாக்கியத்தில் ஒரு உயிரினத்தை பொருத்தினால் மட்டுமே அது முழுமையான பொருளைத் தரும். எனவே சரியான வார்த்தை பல்லி என்பதே ஆகும். "},{"question":"ልዑል ራስ መኮንን የማን አባት ናቸው?","answer":"ንጉሠ ነገሥት ቀዳማዊ ኃይለ ሥላሴ"},{"question":"Waxan sual dhamestiran ma ahen ","answer":"Sual an fahmi karo maba ahen qofka so qoray maxa ka qaldna"},{"question":"கிராமப்புற இந்தியாவின் மையத்தில், பஞ்சாபின் பசுமையான வயல்களுக்கு மத்தியில், அமிர்தாபூர் என்ற ஒரு விசித்திரமான கிராமம் இருந்தது. கோடைக் காற்றில் கோதுமை வயல்கள் நடனமாடவும், பருவமழை தாகம் கொண்ட பூமிக்கு உயிரைக் கொடுத்ததாகவும் அமிர்தாபூர் வாழ்க்கை பருவங்களின் தாளங்களைச் சுற்றி சுழன்றது. கிராமத்தின் மையத்தில் ஒரு பழங்கால ஆலமரம் நின்றது, அதன் கிளைகள் எரியும் மதியங்களில் கிராம மக்களுக்கு நிழல் தரும்.அமிர்தாபூர் அதன் இறுக்கமான சமூகத்திற்காக அறியப்பட்டது, அங்கு அனைவரும் ஒருவருக்கொருவர் மகிழ்ச்சி மற்றும் துக்கங்களை அறிந்திருந்தனர். அதில் வசிப்பவர்களில் மீரா என்ற இளம் பெண்ணும் இருந்தாள், அவள் கண்கள் பிரபஞ்சத்தின் ரகசியங்களை வைத்திருந்தாள். கடவுள்கள், உத்வேகம் தரும் ஹீரோக்கள் மற்றும் நிழலில் பதுங்கியிருக்கும் மாய உயிரினங்கள் பற்றிய கதைகளை சொல்லும் திறமை அவளுக்கு இருந்தது. அவரது கதைகள் கிராமவாசிகளை ஒன்றிணைத்து, தலைமுறைகளைக் கடந்து, அவர்களின் கற்பனைகளைத் தூண்டின.கேள்வி: மேலே உள்ள பத்திகளின் உதவியுடன், குறைந்தபட்சம் மூன்று பத்திகளுடன் கதையை விரிவுபடுத்தி முடிக்கவும்.","answer":"பதில்:ஒரு மாலை நேரத்தில், சூரியன் அடிவானத்திற்குக் கீழே மூழ்கி, நட்சத்திரங்கள் பரந்த வானத்தில் மின்னத் தொடங்கியதும், மீரா பழங்கால ஆலமரத்தின் அடியில் கிராம மக்களைக் கூட்டிச் சென்றார். ஒளிரும் எண்ணெய் விளக்குகளின் மென்மையான பிரகாசத்துடன், அவள் காதல், தியாகம் மற்றும் விதியின் கதையைச் சுழற்றத் தொடங்கினாள். அமிர்தபூரின் வரலாற்றின் போக்கை என்றென்றும் மாற்றும் நிகழ்வுகளில் இந்தக் குறிப்பிட்ட கதை அமையும் என்பது அவளுக்குத் தெரியாது.மீராவின் வார்த்தைகள் காற்றை நிரப்பியபோது, ​​ஒரு மர்மமான அந்நியன் அமிர்தாபூருக்கு வந்தான். அவர் பிரபஞ்சத்தின் ரகசியங்களை வைத்திருப்பது போல் துளையிடும் நீல நிற கண்கள் கொண்ட ஒரு பயணி. அவரது வருகை கிராமத்தில் ஆர்வத்தின் அலைகளை அனுப்பியது, மேலும் அவரது நோக்கங்கள் மர்மமாகவே இருந்தன.விரியும் சூழ்ச்சிகளுக்கிடையில் மீராவின் கதை சொல்லல் எதிர்பாராத திருப்பத்தை பெற்றது. கிராமத்திற்குள் மறைந்திருக்கும் ஒரு கோவிலைப் பற்றி அவள் பேசினாள், நித்திய மகிழ்ச்சியைத் தரும் சக்தியைக் கொண்டிருப்பதாகக் கூறினார். கிராமவாசிகள் இந்த புதிரான கோவிலைத் தேடத் தொடங்கினர், ஒவ்வொன்றும் அவரவர் உந்துதல்கள் மற்றும் விருப்பங்களுடன். கிராமம் விரைவில் நம்பிக்கை மற்றும் ஆவேசத்தின் வலையில் சிக்கியது, அங்கு மீராவின் கதைகள் யதார்த்தத்திற்கும் கட்டுக்கதைக்கும் இடையிலான கோடுகளை மங்கலாக்கியது.மறைந்திருக்கும் கோவிலைத் தேடுவது அமிர்தபூரை உட்கொண்டதால், உறவுகள் சோதிக்கப்பட்டன, கூட்டணிகள் உருவாகி நொறுங்கின. மர்மமான அந்நியரும் கிராமத்தின் தேடலில் சிக்கினார், மீராவின் கதைசொல்லலுடன் ஒரு ஆச்சரியமான தொடர்பை வெளிப்படுத்தினார். ஒன்றாக, அவர்கள் கிராமத்தைச் சுற்றியுள்ள அடர்ந்த காடுகளுக்குள் நுழைந்தனர், அவர்களின் நம்பிக்கை, தைரியம் மற்றும் அவர்களின் பிணைப்பின் வலிமையை சோதிக்கும் சோதனைகளை எதிர்கொண்டனர். மீராவின் கதைகள் மற்றும் அந்நியரின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் மூலம், உண்மையான பொக்கிஷம் கோயிலின் பொருள் செல்வத்தில் இல்லை, மாறாக தங்கள் சமூகத்திற்குள் மீண்டும் புத்துயிர் பெற்ற ஒற்றுமை மற்றும் அன்பில் உள்ளது என்பதை கிராம மக்கள் உணரத் தொடங்கினர்."},{"question":"Kiní orúkọ àwọn owó tí wọ́n ń ná ní China?","answer":"yuan ni ò."},{"question":"අන්නාසි වගාවේ වල් පැල මර්දනය කරන්නේ කොහොමද?","answer":"අන්නාසි වගාවේ වල් පැල මර්දනය කරන්නේ සුළුපරිමාන වගාවන්හි අන්නාසි පත්‍රවලට හානි නොවන සේ උදලුගෑමෙන් වල් මර්දනය කළ හැක. වල් මර්දනයට රසායනික වල්නාශකද භාවිත කළ හැක. ඩියුරෝන් 80% තෙත්කළහැකි කුඩකි. එය ග්‍රෑම් 2ක් ජලය ලීටර 180- 200 ක මිශ්‍රකර සිටුවා මාසයක් පමණ වූ වගා වල වල්පැල මර්දනයට යෙදියහැක."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning till detta stycke - Efter Italiens landslags misslyckade EM-slutspel 2004 i Portugal","answer":", blev Lippi i juli 2004 ny förbundskapten för Italien. Under hans ledning vann Italien VM-guld 2006 i Tyskland, landets fjärde VM-guld totalt (första sedan 1982). Några dagar efter VM-segern meddelade Lippi sin avgång. Efter Italiens misslyckade EM-slutspel 2008 i Schweiz och Österrike återkom Lippi den 26 juni 2008 som förbundskapten för Italien. Efter ett totalt misslyckat VM 2010 i Sydafrika (1–1 mot både Paraguay och Nya Zeeland, förlust med 3–2 mot Slovakien och därmed sistaplats i gruppen) avgick Lippi och ersattes av Cesare Prandelli."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Landet hade planer att hoppa av","answer":"2010 på grund av dålig ekonomi men de bestämde sig att ändå vara med och tävla."},{"question":"ما هي السورة التي تبدأ بآية “وَلَوْ أَنَّ قُرْآنًا سُيِّرَتْ بِهِ الْجِبَالُ أَوْ قُطِّعَتْ بِهِ الْأَرْضُ أَوْ كُلِّمَ بِهِ الْمَوْتَى بَلْ لِلَّهِ الْأَمْرُ جَمِيعًا”؟\\t","answer":"سورة الرعد"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa goorma ayaa la waajib yeelay Soonka?","answer":"Waxa soonka la waajib yeelay Sanadkii labaad (2-Aad) ee Hijriyada"},{"question":"Trả lời các câu hỏi sau:a) Đọc số: – 54.b) Viết số: âm chín mươi.","answer":"a) Số – 54 được đọc là: \\"âm năm mươi tư\\" hoặc đọc là \\"trừ năm mươi tư\\".b) Số \\"âm chín mươi\\" được viết là – 90."},{"question":"ඔන්චිල්ලා වාරම් කවියක් කියන්න ","answer":"පී නා එන කල තිසරුන් ගො ල්ලාබා නා වැල ගෙඩි මෙන් සුවි පු ල්ලාඕ නෑ රඟවට සැරසී ග ල්ලානෑනා වරුනේ තෑගි දිය ල්ලා"},{"question":"इस इमोजी का प्रतिक्रिया क्या हो सकता है? 😍","answer":"😍 प्यार भरा चेहरा: यह इमोजी प्यार, आकर्षण और उत्कृष्टता की भावना को दर्शाता है। जब आप किसी विशेष व्यक्ति, वस्त्र या स्थिति से प्यार करते हैं, तो यह इमोजी आपके अद्भुत भावनाओं को प्रकट करता है।"},{"question":"અહીં એક ગુજરાતી ગરબા ની શરૂઆત ની પંક્તિઓ નીચે આપેલી છે: \\"કેસરીયો રંગ તને લાગ્યો ઓલ્યા ગરબા,કેસરીયો રંગ તને લાગ્યો રે લોલ..\\"આ કવિતા ની આગળની પંક્તિઓ લખો.","answer":"કેસરીયો રંગ તને લાગ્યો ઓલ્યા ગરબા,કેસરીયો રંગ તને લાગ્યો રે લોલ..ઝીણી ઝીણી જાળીયું મેલાવો ઓલ્યા ગરબા,ઝીણી ઝીણી જાળીયું મેલાવો રે લોલ..કોના કોના માથે ઘૂમ્યો ઓલ્યા ગરબા,કોના કોના માથે ઘૂમ્યો રે લોલ..અંબાજીના માથે ઘૂમ્યો ઓલ્યા ગરબા,અંબાજીના માથે ઘૂમ્યો રે લોલ..કિયા કિયા ગામે પધરાવ્યો ઓલ્યા ગરબા,કિયા કિયા ગામે પધરાવ્યો રે લોલ..અબાંજી ગામે પધરાવ્યો ઓલ્યા ગરબા,અબાંજી ગામે પધરાવ્યો રે લોલ.."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : “వేదమనగా ఉత్కృష్టమైన (ఉన్నతమైన) జ్ఞానము” వ్యాఖ్యానించుము.","answer":"సంస్కృత భాషలో వేదమనగా ఉన్నతమైన జ్ఞానం ఆత్మజ్ఞానమే వేధము.వేదాలను శృతులు అని కూడా అంటారు.పండితులైన వారు కనుగొన్న పరమ సత్యాలే వేదాలు.భారతీయ యోగాకు వేదాలే ఆధారాలు.వేదాలలో లోతైన ఆధ్యాత్మిక మరియు శాస్త్రీయ విజ్ఞాన కలదు.వేదకాలపు సాంప్రదాయాలు ఇప్పటికీ అవిచ్చినముగా కొనసాగుతున్నవి.ఆధునిక కాలంలో స్వామి దయానంద సరస్వతి ‘వేద కాలానికే మరలా వెళ్ళాలి’ అని పిలుపునిచ్చారు.వేదాల మీద భారతీయ మరియు ఇతర దేశాల విశ్వవిద్యాలయాలలో పరిశోధనలు కొనసాగుతున్నాయి.వేద సాహిత్యములో నాలుగు ప్రముఖ వేదాలు కలవు. ఋగ్వేదము, యజుర్వేదము, సామవేదము, ఆధర్వణ వేదము"},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Kroasia?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Kroasia dia Zagreb."},{"question":"请问“不知天高地厚”这句谚语是什么意思？","answer":"这句谚语直译为不知道天有多高,地有多深，也形容骄狂无知。"},{"question":"Kapı önüne park eden araç nereye şikayet edilir?","answer":"Zabıta Amirliklerine ihbarda bulunmak için Alo Zabıta Hattını (153) arayabilirsiniz."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నకి ఆలోచించి ఐదేసి వాక్యాల్లో సమాధానాలు రాయండి.చదువుకున్నవాళ్ళంతా తమ కష్టఫలాన్ని తింటూ పట్నాలలో సౌఖ్యాలు అనుభవిస్తున్నారన్న రచయిత అభిప్రాయంతో మీరు ఏకీభవిస్తారా? ఎందుకు?సూచన : రచయిత అభిప్రాయంతో కీభవించవచ్చు. వికీభవించక పోవచ్చును. అందుచేత రెండు అభిప్రాయాలు ఇవ్వబడ్డాయి. మీకు నచ్చిన ఒక అభిప్రాయాన్నే గ్రహించండి.","answer":"i) రచయిత అభిప్రాయంతో ఏకీభవిస్తాను. ఎందుకంటే విద్యార్థులు కళాశాలలో, పాఠశాలలో, ఉన్నత విద్యలోనూ అనేక సదుపాయాలు పొందుతున్నారు. ఆ విద్యార్థులకు ఆ సదుపాయాలన్నీ ప్రభుత్వం కల్పిస్తోంది. దానికి ఖర్చయ్యేది ప్రభుత్వ ధనం. అంటే పన్నుల రూపంలో ప్రజలు కట్టిన డబ్బు కదా ! మరి, పేద ప్రజల డబ్బుతో సదుపాయాలు పొంది, చదువుకొన్నవాళ్ళు పట్నాలకు వెడుతున్నారు. అక్కడ హాయిగా సుఖపడుతున్నారు. పల్లెటూర్ల వైపు కన్నెత్తి చూడరు. తమ అభివృద్ధికి కారకులైన సామాన్యులను పట్టించుకోరు. ధన సంపాదనలో మునిగిపోతారు.ఉదాహరణకు ఒక డాక్టరు తయారవ్వాలంటే కనీసం 50 లక్షల రూపాయలు ఖర్చవుతుంది. ఆ డబ్బంతా ప్రజాధనమే. కాని, చదువు పూర్తయ్యాక పల్లెటూర్లో ఉండడానికి ఎవ్వరూ అంగీకరించరు. వైద్యశాలల్లో డాక్టర్లు లేక, మందులు లేక పల్లెటూరి రోగులు అనేక బాధలు పడుతున్నారు కదా ! చాలా వృత్తులు ఇలాగే ఉన్నాయి. అందుచేత రచయిత అభిప్రాయం నూటికి నూరుపాళ్ళూ సమర్థించతగినది.ii) “చదువుకొన్న వాళ్ళంతా తమ కష్టఫలాన్ని తింటూ, పట్నాలలో సౌఖ్యాలు అనుభవిస్తున్నారు” అన్న రచయిత అభిప్రాయంతో ఏకీభవించను. ఎందుకంటే చదువుకొన్న వాళ్ళు కూడా వ్యవసాయ కుటుంబాల నుంచి వచ్చిన వాళ్ళు ఉన్నారు. పేదలు ఉంటారు. దళితులు ఉంటారు. కూలిపని చేసుకొనే వారి కుటుంబాల నుండి వచ్చిన వారుంటారు. లేఖా రచయిత కూడా పేద దళిత వ్యవసాయ కుటుంబానికి చెందినవాడు. చదువుకొన్నవాడు.అన్ని ఉద్యోగాలూ పట్నాలలోనే లేవు. ఉపాధ్యాయులు, రెవెన్యూ, పోలీసు మొదలైన ఉద్యోగాలు పల్లెటూళ్ళలోనివే. పోలీసు వంటి ఉద్యోగం ప్రాణాలతో చెలగాటం కూడా. నిరంతరం ప్రమాదపుటంచున వారి జీవితాలు ఉంటాయి. అందర్నీ రక్షిస్తారు. కాని, వారికి రక్షణ లేదు.చదువుకొన్న వాళ్ళందరికీ ఉద్యోగాలు లేవు. ఉద్యోగులు అందరూ పట్నాలలోనే లేరు. పల్లెటూళ్ళలోనూ ఉన్నారు. భయంకరమైన అడవులలో, కొండలలో కూడా ఉద్యోగులు ఉన్నారు. కనుక రచయిత అభిప్రాయంతో నేను ఎట్టి పరిస్థితులలోనూ ఏకీభవించను."},{"question":"Inona no singa simika betsaka indrindra ao amin'ny vatan'olombelona?","answer":" Ny singa simika betsaka indrindra ao amin'ny vatan'olombelona dia oksizenina."},{"question":"క్రింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండి: భారతదేశంలో అతి ఎత్తై రోడ్డు మార్గం?","answer":"మనాలి - లేహ్"},{"question":"Awọn agbaagba Yoruba fẹẹ ṣeranti Ogun Kiriji n’Ibadan","answer":"Ilu Ibadan yoo gba alejo nla ni Ọjoruu, Wẹside, ọsẹ yii nigba ti awọn agbaagba Yoruba ati awọn ẹgbẹ loriṣiriiṣi ba kora jọ pẹlu awọn ọba alaye lati sami ayẹyẹ ọdun kẹrinlelaadoje (134) ti ẹya Yoruba parapọ lati jẹ ọkanṣoṣo lẹyin Ogun Kiriji.Ọjọ kẹtalelogun oṣu kẹsan-an ọdun 1886 ni ogun Kiriji wa sopin lẹyin ti gbogbo ilẹ Yoruba pata ti fi ọdun mẹrindinlogun doju ija kọra wọn. Ogun Kiriji yii naa ni wọn tun n pe ni ogun Ekiti parapọ. Lasiko ogun naa, iha meji lawọn ọmọ ogun ọhun pin si, awọn kan fara mọ awọn ọmọ ogun Ekiti, nigba ti iha keji fara mọ awọn ọmọ ogun Ibadan, bẹẹ logun ọhun gbona janjan.Alakooso ipade naa, Ọjọgbọn Banji Akintoye, ẹni to tun jẹ Aarẹ gbogbo-gboo fun ẹgbẹ awọn ọmọ Yoruba lagbaye sọ pe o ṣe pataki ki ipade ọhun waye lati fi sami ayajọ ọjọ naa, ati pe lati isiniyi lọ, gbogbo ọjọ kẹtalelogun oṣu kẹsan-an ọdun ni awọn ọmọ Yoruba yoo maa kora jọ lati sami ọjọ iṣọkan wọn.O ni, lọjọ naa, awọn Ọba alaye, awọn mọlẹbi awọn jagunjagun ti orukọ wọn wa ninu itan ni wọn yoo peju-pesẹ, bẹẹ gẹgẹ lawọn ọmọ Yoruba yoo lọ si awọn aaye ti ogun naa ti gbona gidi bii ilu Igbajọ, Imẹsi Ile ati ni Oke Imẹsi nipinlẹ Ekiti lati lọọ ṣe ifilọlẹ ami ti yoo duro fun iṣọkan ati alaafia ilẹ Yoruba.Lara awọn aṣaaju ỌmỌ Oduduwa to maa wa nibẹ ni Olori ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre, Oloye Ayọ Adebanjọ, Ojiṣẹ Ọlọrun Ayọ Ladigbolu ti ẹgbẹ Yoruba Unity Forum, Adajọ-agba Ademọla Bakare, ti ẹgbẹ igbimọ agba Yoruba ati Ọjọgbọn Adetoun Ogunṣẹyẹ, ẹni ti i ṣe aṣaaju awọn obinrin nilẹ Yoruba pẹlu awọn agbaagba mi-in atawọn ọba alaye.Ọjọgbọn Banji Akintoye sọ pe pataki ipade ọlọjọ meji yii ni lati fi wa idagbasoke ati iṣọkan si ilẹ Yoruba. Bakan naa lo rọ gbogbo ọmọ Yoruba pata lati peju sibi ipade ọhun, ki wọn si kun eto naa lọwọ fun aṣeyọri gidi."},{"question":"Көкүрөк күчүк","answer":"Эң кенжеси, эң кичүү баласы.Ата кургур кантсин, көкүрөк күчүгү Шарипаны жакшы көрчү. (Сыдыгалиев)"},{"question":"কোষঝিল্লির ১০টি কাজ বর্ণনা করো।","answer":"কোষঝিল্লির ১০টি কাজ নিন্মরূপ:১. এটি কোষীয় সব বস্তুকে ঘিরে রাখে।২. বাইরের প্রতিকূল অবস্থা হতে অভ্যন্তরীণ বস্তুকে রক্ষা করে।৩. কোষঝিল্লির মধ্যদিয়ে বস্তুর স্থানান্তর, ব্যাপন নিয়ন্ত্রণ ও সমন্বয় হয়।৪. ঝিল্লিটি একটি কাঠামো হিসেবে কাজ করে যাতে বিশেষ এনজাইম এতে বিন্যস্ত থাকতে পারে।৫. ভেতর থেকে বাইরে এবং বাইরে থেকে ভেতরে বস্তু স্থানান্তর করে।৬. বিভিন্ন বৃহদাণু সংশ্লেষ করতে পারে।৭. বিভিন্ন রকম তথ্যের ভিত্তি হিসেবে কাজ করে।৮. পারস্পরিক বন্ধন, বৃদ্ধি ও চলন ইত্যাদি কাজেও এর ভূমিকা আছে।৯. ফ্যাগোসাইটোসিস প্রক্রিয়ায় কঠিন ও পিনোসাইটোসিস প্রক্রিয়ায় তরল বস্তু গ্রহণ করে।১০. এনজাইম ও অ্যান্টিজেন ক্ষরণ করে।"},{"question":"કચ્છનું રણ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"કચ્છનું રણ  અનેક ક્ષારીય કળણો ધરાવતું વિશાળ ક્ષેત્ર છે. તેનો મોટોભાગ ગુજરાતના કચ્છ જિલ્લામાં આવેલો છે અને અમુક ભાગ પાકિસ્તાનના સિંધની દક્ષિણ છેડે આવેલો છે. તેને બે મુખ્ય ભાગમાં વહેંચી શકાય છે; કચ્છનું મોટું રણ અને કચ્છનું નાનું રણ.કચ્છનું રણ થરના રણનો એક ભાગ છે, જે ગુજરાતના કચ્છ અને પાકિસ્તાનના સિંધમાં ફેલાયેલું એક જૈવિક ભૂક્ષેત્ર છે. અહીં રણનો અર્થ \\"ક્ષારીય કળણ\\" સંપ્રત છે. આ ક્ષેત્રમાં મોસમી કળણ નિર્માણ થાય છે અને તેની વચ્ચે વચ્ચે આવેલા થોડી ઉંચાઈ ધરાવતા ''મેડક'' તરીકે ઓળખાતા ક્ષેત્રોમાં લીલોતરી ઊગી નીકળે છે.આ કળણ કચ્છનો અખાત અને દક્ષિણ પાકિસ્તાનમાં સિંધુના મુખની વચ્ચે આવેલું છે અને 10,000  જેટલું વિશાળ ક્ષેત્ર ધરાવે છે. તેના ઈશાન ખૂણે રાજસ્થાનમાંથી નીકળતી લુણી નદી વહે છે."},{"question":"வினா : கீழ்க்கண்டவற்றுள் பெருமுத்தரையர்கள் பற்றிய குறிப்புகள் அமைந்துள்ள நூல் எது?(1) இன்னா நாற்பது                                  (2) நான்மணிக்கடிகை(3) நாலடியார்                                            (4) சிறுபஞ்சமூலம்","answer":"விடை: பெருமுத்தரையர்கள் பற்றிய குறிப்புகள் அமைந்துள்ள நூல் நாலடியார்.        நாலடியார் பதினெண் கீழ்க்கணக்கு நூல் தொகுப்பைச் சேர்ந்த ஒரு தமிழ் நீதிநூல் ஆகும் .  இது நான்கு அடிகளைக் கொண்ட வெண்பாக்களால் ஆனது. இது சமண முனிவர்களால் இயற்றப்பட்ட நானூறு தனிப்பாடல்களின் தொகுப்பாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது. இதனால் இது நாலடி நானூறு எனவும் பெயர் பெறும். 'வேளாண் வேதம்' என்ற பெயரும் உண்டு. பல நேரங்களில் இது புகழ் பெற்ற தமிழ் நீதி நூலான திருக்குறளுக்கு இணையாகப் பேசப்படும் சிறப்பைப் பெற்றுள்ளது.    'ஆலும் வேலும் பல்லுக்குறுதி; நாலும் இரண்டும் சொல்லுக்குறுதி' என்னும் பழமொழியில் நாலு என்பது நாலடியாரையும், இரண்டு என்பது திருக்குறளையும் குறிக்கும்.     'சொல்லாய்ந்த நாலடி நானூறும் நன்கு இனிது', 'பழகுதமிழ் சொல்லருமை நாலிரண்டில்' என்கிற கூற்றுகள் இதன் பெருமையைத் திருக்குறளுக்கு இணையாக எடுத்தியம்புவன.நாலடியார் பாடல்களின் எண்ணிக்கை கடவுள் வாழ்த்து : 1 அறத்துப்பால் : 130 பாடல்கள் (13 அதிகாரங்கள்) பொருட்பால் : 240 பாடல்கள் (24 அதிகாரங்கள்) காமத்துப்பால் : 30 பாடல்கள் (3 அதிகாரம்) மொத்தம் : 400 பாடல்கள் (40 அதிகாரங்கள்)      பதினெண்கீழ்க்கணக்கு நூல்களில் உள்ள ஒரே தொகை நூல் நாலடியார் ஆகும்.வாழ்க்கையின் எளிமையான பொருட்களை உவமைகளாகக் கையாண்டு நீதி புகட்டுவதில் நாலடியார் தனித்துவம் பெற்று விளங்குகிறது. இந்நூலினை ஆங்கிலத்தில் ஜி.யூ.போப் மொழி பெயர்த்துள்ளார்."},{"question":"Leven er wolven in Nederland?","answer":"Ja, in 2023 leven er zo'n 9 wolvenroedels in Nederland. "},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Hiệu quả từ Đề án \\"Xã biên giới sạch về ma túy\\" | VTV.VN","answer":"Quế Phong là một trong những huyện biên giới trọng điểm, phức tạp về ma túy tại Nghệ An. Sau khi triển khai Đề án \\"Xã biên giới sạch về ma túy\\", lực lượng Công an Quế Phong đã tấn công đồng loạt vào 12 tụ điểm ma túy phức tạp tại các xã Tri Lễ, Mường Nọc, Châu Kim… Các chuyên án đã đập tan các ổ nhóm, đường dây ma túy phức tạp mà trước đây rất khó để xử lý. Đại úy Nguyễn Hồng Quân - Trưởng Công an xã Tri Lễ, huyện Quế Phong, Nghệ An - cho biết: \\"Trước đây các đối tượng xâm nhập vào địa bàn nhiều nhưng khi thực hiện đề án các đối tượng đã cắt giảm do cấp trên tăng cường đấu tranh, trấn áp\\". Còn tại xã biên giới Ngọc Lâm, huyện Thanh Chương, sau 3 tháng triển khai đề án, Công an xã đã phối hợp với chính quyền địa phương đưa 23 người đi cai nghiện, triệt xóa 02 tụ điểm buôn bán ma túy. Đồng thời phối hợp tuyên truyền nâng cao nhận thức cho người dân về tác hại của ma túy. Đề án \\"Xã biên giới sạch về ma túy\\" được chia thành 3 giai đoạn với quyết tâm xây dựng 27 xã biên giới không còn ma tuý ngay trong năm 2022. Quyết tâm giữ vững, nâng cao hiệu quả hơn nữa trong những năm tiếp theo, đồng thời nghiên cứu, nhân rộng mô hình ở các địa bàn khác trên toàn tỉnh. Để thực hiện đề án này, Công an tỉnh Nghệ An đã điều động 132 cán bộ tăng cường về cho Công an 27 xã biên giới. Nghệ An có đường biên giới dài 468 km, tiếp giáp 3 tỉnh nước bạn Lào; vị trí địa lý lại nằm gần khu vực \\"Tam giác vàng\\" - địa điểm tình trạng mua bán, vận chuyển ma túy diễn ra phức tạp. Việc thực hiện thành công Đề án \\"Xã biên giới sạch ma túy\\" sẽ góp phần giữ vững an ninh trật tự trên tuyến biên giới Việt-Lào.  * Mời quý độc giả theo dõi các chương trình đã phát sóng của Đài Truyền hình Việt Nam trên TV Online và VTVGo! Từ khóa:"},{"question":"前を通過する被写体に合わせて撮影する、競馬や競輪の着順判定に用いられるカメラは何でしょう？","answer":"スリットカメラ"},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira de Papua-Nova Guiné.","answer":"A bandeira de Papua-Nova Guiné possui duas faixas diagonais de igual tamanho que se cruzam, formando quatro triângulos. Os triângulos superiores são pretos, e os triângulos inferiores são vermelhos. No cantão superior esquerdo, há um círculo amarelo com um pássaro do paraíso vermelho."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk daging masak lada hitam? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Daging masak lada hitam ialah hidangan popular dalam masakan Asia, terutamanya di Malaysia dan Singapura. Seperti namanya, hidangan ini terdiri daripada kepingan daging yang dimasak dalam sos berasaskan lada hitam. Hidangan ini biasanya dihidangkan panas dan pedas kerana sedikit lada hitam, dan ia sering dihidangkan dengan nasi putih.Bahan: ½ kg daging lembu batang pinang, 4 ulas bawang putih, ½ inci halia, 1 sudu besar sos tiram, 2 sudu besar kicap manis, 1 sudu kecil lada hitam, 1 biji lada benggala (capsicum), 1 biji bawang besar, 2 sudu kecil tepung jagung, Garam, Minyak masakCara penyediaan:1. Kisar bawang putih dan halia. Tumbuk kasar lada hitam.2. Potong daging nipis-nipis melintang urat supaya cepat empuk.3. Gaulkan daging dengan bahan kisar, lada hitam, sos tiram, kicap dan gula. Perap selama satu jam atau lebih.4. Belah lapan bawang besar dan potong capsicum.Cara memasak:1. Panaskan minyak dalam kuali. Masukkan daging yang telah diperap. Tambah air hingga tenggelam daging dan dan renehkan sehingga daging lembut. Tambah air jika air kering sebelum daging empuk.2. Setelah daging lembut dan air kering, besarkan api dan goreng daging secara stir fry sehingga garing.Tahap kegaringan mengikut citarasa anda.3. Masukkan garam, hirisan bawang besar dan capsicum. Kacau rata.4. Akhir sekali masukkan bancuhan tepung jagung dan kacau.5. Bila kuah pekat, padamkan api, angkat dan hidangkan panas-panas."},{"question":"පිල්ලෑව යන වචනයේ තේරුම කුමක්ද?","answer":"කුඹුරත් ගොඩ ඉඩමත් අතර පිහිටි ජලාශ්‍රිත පහත් බිම, කුඹුරක කමත පිහිටි ගොඩ ඉඩම් කැබැල්ල, කුඹුරක වගා නොකළ කොටස (ප්‍රාෙයා්ගික සිංහල ශබ්දකෝෂය: අධිනීතිඥ හරිශ්චන්ද්‍ර විජයතුංග: පිටුව1078)"},{"question":"ከ1841 እስከ 1846 የታላቋ ብሪታንያ ጠቅላይ ሚኒስትር ማን ነበሩ?","answer":"ሮበርት ፔል"},{"question":"Inona no teny firarian-tsoa lazaina rehefa mamangy marary?","answer":"Ny teny firarian-tsoa lazaina rehefa mamangy marary dia 'mirary fahasalamana'"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'buka tembelang'? Berikan satu contoh ayat untuk simpulan bahasa ini.","answer":"Ia bermaksud mendedahkan keburukan orang lain. Contoh ayat: Si Hamid telah membuka tembelang dengan mengatakan Si Guna yang mencuri kambing Kurupaya."},{"question":"Mitovy hevitra sa mifanipa-kevitra sa tsy misy ifandraisany ireto fehezanteny roa ireto?Fehezanteny A: Tsy manambola aho amin'izao fa fotoana no misy.Fehezanteny B: Mahantra aho.","answer":"Tsy misy ifandraisany ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kais pagi makan pagi, kais petang makan petang'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud pendapatan yang hanya cukup untuk hidup sahaja (kalau tidak bekerja tidak makan)."},{"question":"கம்பரை ஆதரித்த வள்ளல்?","answer":"விடை: சடையப்ப வள்ளல்"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Eamon Kelly. ","answer":"Drámadóir agus aisteoir Éireannach ab ea Eamon Kelly (30 Márta 1914 - 24 Meán Fómhair 2001). Rugadh i nGníomh go Leith, Sliabh Luachra, Contae Chiarraí é. "},{"question":"O ma waa ga o! Wọn tun ji agbẹ mi-in gbe n’Igangan","answer":"Lẹyin ọjọ mẹta ti wọn ji gbajumọ oniṣowo epo rọbi gbe niluu Idere nitosi Igboọra ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ ki wọn too pada yinbọn pa a, wọn tun ti ji ọkunrin agbẹ kan, Nosiru Aderoju, gbe niluu Igangan ni ipinlẹ yìí kan naa.Ta o ba gbagbe, lọsẹ to lọ lọhun-un ni wọn ji agbẹ kan tó n jẹ Oluwọle  Agboọla gbe ninu oko ẹ lọna Ibadan siluu Ọyọ.Ni nnkan bíi aago mẹjọ aabọ alẹ lawọn ajinigbe ọhun lọọ ka Alhaji Aderoju mọ itosí ile ẹ ti wọn sì gbé e bi igba ti aṣa ba gbe ọmọ adiẹ.Gẹgẹ b’ALAROYE ṣe gbọ, lasiko ti ọkunrin agbẹ náà n dari lọ sile lẹyin to kí irun aago mẹjọ alẹ tan lawọn amookunṣika ẹda naa lọọ da a lọna ti wọn si ji i gbe nitosi ilé ẹ lOke agbẹdẹ niluu Igangan.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, alaga ẹgbẹ idagbasoke ilu Igangan, Ọgbẹni Ọladokun Ọladiran sọ pe o jọ pé awọn obayejẹ ẹda naa ti n ṣọ Ọgbẹni Aderoju tipẹ, ti wọn sì n tẹle e kiri tẹlẹ ki wọn too papa ri i mu.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “awọn eeyan ṣakiyesi awọn àjèjì kan bíi Fulani ni mọṣalaṣi to (Alhaji Aderoju) ti kirun lalẹ ana yẹn ṣugbọn wọn ko fura pe iṣẹ ibi ni won waa ṣe. O ṣe é ṣe kó jẹ pe awọn èèyàn yẹn ni wọn ṣọ ọ dé mọsalaṣi ki wọn tóo tun ti ibẹ tẹle e de ọna ile ẹ ti wọn ti jí i gbe.Agbẹnusọ fún ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ SP Olugbenga Fadeyi fidi iṣẹlẹ yìí mulẹ, o ni awọn agbofinro ti bẹrẹ iṣẹ lati yọ ọkunrin agbẹ naa kuro nigbekun awọn ajinigbe ọhun ki wọn sì mú awọn afurasi ọdaran naa."},{"question":"Quais são as modalidades esportivas praticadas por um triatleta?","answer":"Resposta: natação, ciclismo e corrida."},{"question":"Những câu thơ sau nằm trong bài thơ nào của Tản Đà?Non cao những ngóng cùng trôngSuối tuôn dòng lệ chờ mong tháng ngàyXương mai một nắm hao gầyTóc mây một mái đã đầy tuyết sương.","answer":"Những câu thơ này nằm trong bài thơ 'Thề non nước' của Tản Đà.Bài thơ ban đầu có 12 câu lục bát, làm vào đầu năm 1920, là kết quả chuyến đi đầu tiên của nhà thơ theo chiều dài đất nước. Hai năm sau, ông sửa lại và viết thêm 10 câu để đưa vào một truyện ngắn cùng tên, làm một tình tiết truyện. Về sau, khi công bố bài thơ như một tác phẩm độc lập, Tản Đà lấy lại hầu như nguyên vẹn bài thơ trong truyện."},{"question":"ਆਖਰ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਚਰਚਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਰਿਤੇਸ਼ ਅਤੇ ਜੇਨੇਲੀਆ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ। ਚਿੱਟੇ ਲਹਿੰਗੇ ‘ਚ ਸਜੀ ਜੇਨੇਲੀਆ ਤੇ ਨੀਲੇ ਰੰਗ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੇਰਵਾਨੀ ‘ਚ ਸਜੇ ਰਿਤੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਸਮਾਰੋਹ ਨੇ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ‘ਚ ਧੁੰਮਾਂ ਪਾਈਆਂ। ਵਿਆਹ ਵਾਲੇ ਦਿਨ ਜੇਨੇਲੀਆ ਨੇ ਮਹਾਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀਅਨ ਦੁਲਹਨ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ‘ਚ ਲਾਲ-ਸੁਨਹਿਰੀ ਡਿਜ਼ਾਇਨਰ ਸਾੜੀ ਪਾਈ ਤੇ ਰਿਤੇਸ਼ ਨੇ ਕਰੀਮ ਸ਼ੇਰਵਾਨੀ ਪਾਈ। ਰਿਤੇਸ਼ (32 ਸਾਲ) ਤੇ ਜੇਨੇਲੀਆ (24 ਸਾਲ) ਨੂੰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਤੁਝੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਕਸਮ’ ਦੌਰਾਨ 2003 ‘ਚ ਇੱਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਦੇਰ ਤਕ ਛੁਪਾ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਿਆ। ਵਿਆਹ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ‘ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਲਵ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ’ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਆ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਮੋਸ਼ਨ ਵੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ 24 ਫਰਵਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਸਮਾਗਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੌਬੀ ਦਿਓਲ, ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ, ਅਭਿਸ਼ੇਕ ਬੱਚਨ, ਸੋਹਾ ਅਲੀ ਖਾਨ, ਸੁਨੀਲ ਸ਼ੈਟੀ, ਮਲਾਇਕਾ ਅਰੋੜਾ ਖ਼ਾਨ, ਮਿਲਨ ਲੂਥਰੀਆ, ਅਰਬਾਜ਼ ਖ਼ਾਨ, ਨੀਤੂ ਸਿੰਘ, ਰਿਸ਼ੀ ਕਪੂਰ, ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਬੇਂਦਰੇ, ਟੀਨਾ ਅੰਬਾਨੀ, ਸ਼ਾਹਰੁਖ, ਕਾਜੋਲ-ਅਜੈ, ਸਾਜਿਦ ਖ਼ਾਨ, ਅਕਸ਼ੈ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਈ ਹਸਤੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਸ਼ਿਰਕਤ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਵਿਲਾਸ ਰਾਓ ਦੇਸ਼ਮੁਖ ਦੇ ਰਾਜਨੀਤਕ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਰਾਜ ਠਾਕਰੇ, ਪ੍ਰਿਥਵੀਰਾਜ ਚੌਹਾਨ, ਅਦਿੱਤਿਆ ਠਾਕਰੇ ਵੀ ਹਾਜ਼ਰ ਹੋਏ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਰਿਤੇਸ਼ ਦੇਸ਼ਮੁਖ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਨਾਮ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ  ਰਿਤੇਸ਼ ਦੇਸ਼ਮੁਖ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਵਿਲਾਸ ਰਾਓ ਦੇਸ਼ਮੁਖ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"Ẹ ni suuru diẹ fun ijọba Buhari, Lai Mohammed bẹ gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria","answer":"Minisita feto iroyin ati aṣa, Lai Mohammed, ti bẹ gbogbo ọmọ orilẹede Naijiria lati ni suuru diẹ fun ijọba Muhammadu Buhari bo ti ṣe n tiraka lati mu ayipada rere to ṣeleri lọdun 2015 ba orileede yii.Nibi ipade kan to waye niluu Ilọrin lopin ọsẹ to kọja ni Minisita ọhun ti sọrọ naa.O rọ awọn ti ko ba ti i ri ipa tijọba to wa lori aleefa n ko tabi ti wọn ro pe ijọba ko ti i ṣe nnkan to, lati fun wọn lasiko diẹ si i.Mohammed ni, “Ta a ba ti i ṣe to tabi kopa gidi ninu igbe aye gbogbo eeyan, a bẹ yin, ẹ ba wa fara da a fun igba diẹ.“Lakọọkọ naa, owo ta a n pa wọle kere si ida ọgọta ohun tawọn ijọba to ṣaaju wa ri. Gbogbo wa la mọ pe ajalu Covid-19 de ba wa, bi a tun ṣe n kuro lori iyẹn ni rogbodiyan mi-in tun bẹ silẹ. A rọ gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria lati ni suuru fun ijọba”.O nijọba gbe biliọnu marundinlọgọrin naira #75b kalẹ labẹ eto idokoowo fawọn ọdọ (National Youth Investment Fund). Eyi ni yoo fun wọn lanfaani lati ri owo gba fi ṣiṣẹ ati ṣowo.Lara awọn to wa nibi ipade naa ni Gomina Abdulrazaq Abdulrahman, Olori ile aṣofin Kwara, Ọnarebu Yakubu Danladi, Emir Ilọrin, awọn ori ade mi-in, aṣoju awọn ọdọ, awọn iyalọja atawọn mi-in bẹẹ lọ."},{"question":"Китеп окуунун пайдалуу жактары жөнүндө айтып бере аласыңбы?   ","answer":"Креативдүү ойлордун жаралышына түрткү берет:Идеяга бай адамдар көп ойлорду китептен алышат. Мисалы, атактуу «Apple» компаниясынын негиздөөчүсү Стив Жобс бош убактысынын көбүн көркөм чыгарма окууга арначу экен. Балким, китеп көп окусаңыз, сиз дагы дүйнөгө жаңы ийгилик жаратарсыз..."},{"question":"Waa maxay shirkiga weyni?","answer":"Waa in wax ka mid ah cibaadada loo leexiyo cid aan Alle ahayn, sida ducada, salaadda, sujuudda, gawraca qurbaanka, rajaynta wixii Ilaahay kelidii karo, ka cabsashada jinka, shayaadiinta, maytida iwm."},{"question":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Мунайдын баасы - Сауд Арабия жана Венесуэлада сууга караганда арзан."},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Nangeen gëm li Ma wàcce, te muy dëggal li ngeen yore; buleen doon ñi ko jëkk a weddi. Buleen jaay samay laaya ak njëg gu néew. Te nangeen ma ragal Man doŋ.","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Na ngéen gëm li Ma wàcce, te mu'y dëggal li ngéen yore; buléen doon ñi ko jëkk a weddi. Buléen jaay sama'y laaya ak njëg gu néew. Te na ngéen ma ragal Màn doŋŋ."},{"question":"An bhfuil cártaí bronntanais go maith mar bhronntanais Nollag?","answer":"Tá cártaí bronntanas foirfe le haghaidh bronntanais a thabhairt! Tá mo chuid is fearr liom ar mo liosta mianta pearsanta, ach is féidir leat cárta Amazon, Walmart, Target, nó Apple Store a bheith agat freisin le haghaidh brón uathúil agus pearsanta. Is féidir leat iad a cheannach do siopaí grósaera, chomh maith le siopaí éadaí, siopaí leictreonacha agus mar sin de."},{"question":"கைவினைத் தொழிலாளர்களால் முதன் முதலில் செய்யப்பட்ட பொருள் எது?","answer":"விடை :  செங்கல்"},{"question":"Inona no fomban-drazana fanao rehefa ririnina?","answer":"Ny famadihana sy famorana no fomban-drazana atao rehefa ririnina."},{"question":"ग्लोबल वार्मिंग के कारण सभी महासागरों/जल निकायों में मूंगा कम होता जा रहा है। लक्षद्वीप द्वीप के लोग लोगों/पर्यटकों को कुछ टुकड़े छीनने की अनुमति न देकर अपने मूंगों की रक्षा करते हैं।(ए) मूंगा के संघ का नाम बताइए।(बी) मूंगा किससे बना होता है?(सी) लक्षद्वीप द्वीप में लोगों के कौन से मूल्य परिलक्षित होते हैं?","answer":"(ए) मूंगा का संघ सीलेन्टरेटा है।(बी) मूंगा कैल्शियम कार्बोनेट से बना होता है।(सी) लक्षद्वीप द्वीप के लोग पर्यावरण और प्रकृति का सम्मान करने वाले जिम्मेदार नागरिक होने के मूल्य को दर्शाते हैं।"},{"question":"Kabuzange buvume ukufika ubuthongo kuXolani. Wayethi uzama ukucimeza kuvelekugqame isithombe sikaMahlengi nje engqondweni yakhe. Wayeze azethuke esequmamanje, ngenhliziyo ebalisa ngokuthi uyaqala ukusanganiswa ngumuntu kanje.'Kawulele ngani, ucabangani kangaka?' kubuza umkakhe ngokunganaki nje.'Eyi, yindaba yomsebenzi, ingqondo kayikutholi ukuphumula,' enkwankwazaezinxaphisa ubala.'Uthi kusewumsebenzi wodwa nje lona okuqwashisile?' ebuza sakubhuqa.'Uchaza ukuthini?' ebuza ngolakana oluxube ukwethuka.'Hhayi, bengizibuzela nje mntanomuntu,' kuphendula umkakhe, edonsa umoya,ephenduka emfulathela.Wakuziba ukukhononda okwakuzwakala ekuphawuleni komkakhe. Wazama ukulala.Nakho-ke esezithela kuMahlengi. Bahlangana olwandle seliyozilahla kunina, kuhelezaumoya opholile, amagagasi alokhu eduma laphaya ezansi sengathi abashayelaihlombe njengoba bebingelelana bevule izingalo bebambana.'Mahlengi, Mahlengi ...' kubingelela uXolani ngenjabulo embamba ngesandlauMahlengi emdonsa ngengalo, bexhakana, becothoza kancane ezihlabathinizolwandle ezithofozelayo, bephenduka begqolozelana ngamehlo alanguka uthando.'Mahlengi, Mahle ...' Embambisisa, enamathela esifubeni sakhe esincanyana,esithaphuka amakha awunqambothi, esihlotshiswe ngamabele amancanyana,esifudumele, okulenga kuso umgexo obenyezeliswa yimisebe yelanga seliyoshona.1. Yimuphi umoya otholakala kulesi siqeshana? Bhekisa impendulo yakhokumlingiswa onguLungile bese usekela impendulo yakho.","answer":"Umoya wentukuthelo/ wokukhathazeka. ULungile uthukutheliswa/ukhathazwa nguXolani olokhu equma esola nokuthi umqambela amanga/uvika ngokuthi ukhathazwa ngumsebenzi. Uphinde athukutheliswe /akhathazwe nguXolani ophupha aze abize igama likaMahlengi athi nomaembuza ngoMahlengi amphuphayo impendulo kaXolani ingamgculisi uzeumbheka kabi."},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Sudã lu ëpp benn miliyoŋ u xale toxal na'ñ léen; Darfuur a nga jëm guddi gu bët setagul.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Sudã lu ëpp benn miliyoŋ u xale toxal na'ñ léen; Darfuur a nga jëm guddi gu bët setagul.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Sudã: PROPNlu: PRONëpp: ADJbenn: NUMmiliyoŋ: NUMu: ADPxale: NOUNtoxal: VERBna: AUX'ñ: PRONléen: PRON;: PUNCTDarfuur: PROPNa: AUXnga: AUXjëm: VERBguddi: NOUNgu: PRONbët: NOUNsetagul: ADJ.: PUNCT"},{"question":"كمل الفقرة:وأكد الأمين العام للمعرض الدولي للبستنة إكسبو الدوحة 2023 محمد علي الخوري، أن اللجنة المنظمة عملت على جذب جميع التقنيات العالمية التي تسهم في","answer":"تطوير قطاع البستنة والزراعة. وأضاف الخوري أن المعرض سيكون منصة رائعة لتبادل الخبرات والمعرفة في مجال البستنة، حيث سيشهد مشاركة متخصصين وخبراء من مختلف دول العالم. كما أشار إلى أهمية التحولات التكنولوجية في هذا القطاع وكيف يمكن أن يسهم المعرض في تعزيز هذه التقنيات وتبادلها بين الدول المشاركة."},{"question":"Maak de volgende zin af: De Academy Award voor beste documentaire (Engels: Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature, ook bekend als de Oscar voor beste documentaire) is sinds","answer":"1943 een jaarlijkse prijs van de Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences voor documentaires."},{"question":"Welke soorten vis bevatten de laagste niveaus van kwik?","answer":"De volgende soorten vis bevatten lage niveaus van kwik: zalm, schol, Atlantische makreel, ansjovis, koolvis, meerval en schelpdieren (bijv. mosselen en coquilles)."},{"question":"ક્રિકેટર મહેન્દ્ર સિંઘ ધોની વિષે જણાવો","answer":"મહેન્દ્ર સિંઘ ધોની મુખ્યત્વે એમ. એસ. ધોની ના નામે જાણીતા ભારતીય ક્રિકેટર બેટ્સમેન અને વિકેટકીપર છે અને હાલની ભારતીય રાષ્ટ્રીય ક્રિકેટ ટીમ તેમજ ચેન્નાઇ સુપરકિંગ્સના કપ્તાન છે. તેમણે ડિસેમ્બર ૨૦૦૪ માં બાંગ્લાદેશ વિરુધ્ધ એક દિવસીય ક્રિકેટમાં તેમજ આ જ સમયગાળામાં તેમણે શ્રીલંકા વિરુદ્ધ ટેસ્ટમાં પદાર્પણ કર્યુ હતું.તેઓ ક્રિકેટના ત્રણેય ફોર્મેટમાં ભારતીય ક્રિકેટ ટીમના સુકાની છે. તેમણે ૨૦૦૭માં રાહુલ દ્રવિડ પાસેથી વન-ડે શ્રેણીનું સુકાનીપદ સંભાળ્યું અને તેમના નેતૃત્વ હેઠળ શ્રીલંકા અને ન્યુઝિલેન્ડ દ્વિપક્ષીય વન-ડે શ્રેણીમાં તેની પ્રથમ જીત થઇ."},{"question":"What does the mapview() function do with the spatial data?","answer":"The mapview() function is used in programming environments like R, particularly in the context of spatial data analysis and visualization. It is a part of the mapview package, which is a powerful tool for interactive viewing and manipulation of spatial data in R. Here's what mapview() generally does with spatial data:Interactive Mapping: The primary function of mapview() is to create interactive maps that allow users to explore spatial data visually. These maps are typically web-based and can be viewed in a web browser.Handling Different Spatial Formats: The function supports various spatial data formats, including sf (simple features), sp (spatial), and raster objects, making it versatile for different types of spatial data analysis.Layered Visualization: Users can add different layers to the maps, including points, lines, polygons, and raster images. This is useful for overlaying various types of spatial information to gain comprehensive insights.Customization Options: mapview() offers various customization options, such as setting the zoom level, centering the map at a specific location, adjusting the basemap (like satellite or terrain), and modifying the appearance of the spatial features (like colors and symbols).Attribute Visualization: It allows for the exploration of attribute data associated with spatial features. Clicking on a feature in the map can display additional information, such as the feature's metadata.Integration with Leaflet: The mapview package integrates well with the leaflet package in R, which is a leading library for interactive maps. This integration extends the functionality and customization possibilities.Export Options: Maps created with mapview() can be exported for use in reports, presentations, or for sharing with others. This can include static representations or interactive web applications.Overall, the mapview() function is a user-friendly way to visualize and interact with spatial data, making it a valuable tool for geospatial analysts, researchers, and anyone working with geographical information systems (GIS) in R. It helps in making spatial data more accessible and easier to interpret, enhancing the understanding of spatial relationships and patterns."},{"question":"आंतरराष्ट्रीय कसोटी क्रिकेट मध्ये २०२३ या वर्षात कोण सर्वधिक शतके करणारा फलंदाज ठरला आहे?(A)  विराट कोहली(B)  केन विल्यमसन(C)  जो रुट(D)  रोहित शर्मा","answer":"(B) केन विल्यमसन"},{"question":"Tuuti","answer":"small\\t"},{"question":"Rasao ity fehezanteny manaraka ity : \\"Milalao karatra ny tanora.\\"","answer":"Mi lalao karatra ny tanora."},{"question":"கேள்வி :\\"காண்பிப்பார்\\" என்பதன் பகுபத உறுப்பிலக்கணம் கூறுக.","answer":"பதில் காண்பிப்பார் = காண்பி + ப் + ப் + ஆர்காண்பி – பகுதிப் – சந்திப் – எதிர்கால இடைநிலைஆர் – படர்க்கை பலர்பால் வினைமுற்று விகுதி"},{"question":"வினா: பல்யானை செங்குட்டுவன் தந்தை?","answer":"விடை: உதயஞ்சேரலாதன்"},{"question":"سورة من القرآن تخلو تمامًا من حرف الراء، وتنتهي كافة آياتها بحرف الدال، فأي سورةٍ تكون؟\\t","answer":"سورة الاخلاص"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਪਾਤਾਲ ਕੇ ਵਾਸੀ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਨਰਕ ਸੁਰਗ ਨਿਵਾਸੀ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਜਨਮਹਿ ਜੀਵਹਿ ਮਰਹਿ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਬਹੁ ਜੋਨੀ ਫਿਰਹਿ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਬੈਠਤ ਹੀ ਖਾਹਿ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਘਾਲਹਿ ਥਕਿ ਪਾਹਿ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਕੀਏ ਧਨਵੰਤ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਮਾਇਆ ਮਹਿ ਚਿੰਤ ॥ਜਹ ਜਹ ਭਾਣਾ ਤਹ ਤਹ ਰਾਖੇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸਭੁ ਕਿਛੁ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕੈ ਹਾਥੇ ॥੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 276 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਜੀਵ ਪਾਤਾਲ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਨ । ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਹੀ ਨਰਕਾਂ ਤੇ ਸੁਰਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸਦੇ ਹਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਦੁਖੀ ਤੇ ਸੁਖੀ ਹਨ);ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਜੀਵ ਜੰਮਦੇ ਤੇ ਮਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਜੀਵ ਕਈ ਜੂਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਭਟਕ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ; ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਜੀਵ ਬੈਠੇ ਹੀ ਖਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਕਰੋੜਾਂ (ਐਸੇ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਰੋਟੀ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ) ਮੇਹਨਤ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਥੱਕ ਟੁੱਟ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ;ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਜੀਵ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ) ਧਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਣਾਏ ਹਨ । ਕਰੋੜਾਂ (ਐਸੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਲੱਗਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ । ਜਿਥੇ ਜਿਥੇ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਓਥੇ ਓਥੇ ਹੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਹਰੇਕ ਗੱਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਹੱਥ ਵਿਚ ਹੈ ।੫।\\""},{"question":"සැන් ෆ්රැන්සිස්කෝ හි නොමිලේ සවස් වරුවේ මා කුමක් කළ යුතුද?","answer":"ඔබට පියර් 39 හෝ ගෝල්ඩන් ගේට් පාලම වැනි සැන් ෆ්රැන්සිස්කෝ හි බිම් සලකුණු වෙත ගොස් ඡායාරූප ගත හැකිය. ඔබ එළිමහනේ ඇවිදීමට කැමති නම්, නගරයේ විශාල උද්යාන කිහිපයක් තිබේ. ඔබට ගෝල්ඩන් ගේට් උද්‍යානය සහ උද්‍යානයේ පිහිටා ඇති විවිධ ආකර්ෂණීය ස්ථාන සහ කෞතුකාගාර නැරඹිය හැකිය. ප්‍රෙසිඩියෝ යනු ජනප්‍රිය උද්‍යානයක් වන අතර ඔබට ගෝල්ඩන් ගේට් පාලමේ හොඳම දර්ශන කිහිපයක් ලබා ගත හැකිය."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي الآيات التي إذا حفظها المسلم عصمته من الدجال؟      ","answer":"  الجواب: عشر آياتٍ من سورة الكهف."},{"question":"“రెండు కరణీయ సంఖ్యల మొత్తం ఎల్లప్పుడు కరణీయ సంఖ్య కాకపోవచ్చును” ఒక ఉదాహరణతో సమర్థించండి.","answer":"2 + √3 మరియు 5 – √3 లు కరణీయ సంఖ్యలు. వీని మొత్తం (2 + √3) + (5 – √3) = 7 ఒక అకరణీయ సంఖ్య."},{"question":"ما الفرق بين سندس وإستبرق؟","answer":"السندس: رقيق الديباج أو الحرير.. الإستبرق: الغليظ من الديباج أو الحرير."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai api makan dalam dedak\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya ialah perbuatan jahat ataupun cinta yang disembunyikan"},{"question":"நுண்ணோக்கியை முதன் முதலில் பயன்படுத்தியவர்?","answer":"விஞ்ஞான நோக்கத்திற்காக நுண்ணோக்கியை தயாரித்து பயன்படுத்திய முதல் நபர் ஆண்டனி வான் லீவென்ஹோக் ஆவார்."},{"question":"السؤال: واش ممكن يتصلحوا الشقات اللي كاينين فالمباني بسهوله  ؟","answer":"نعم ممكن"},{"question":"Qual metal foi descoberto por Hans Christian Oersted em 1825?","answer":"O metal descoberto por Hans Christian Oersted em 1825 foi o alumínio. "},{"question":"DAREENNADA KA BAXSAN KUWA AYNNU NAQAANNO.Qoraa: Buuga: ","answer":"Inta badan; waynnu ka hadalnaa dareennada iyo dhandoonyinka aynnu la nool nahay ee inagu -gedaaman, laakiin way inagu adag tahay in aynnu u faahfaahinno si la fahmi karo. Xaqüqooyinka dareen waxa loo yaqaanaa cilmiga ka baxsan dareenwa dayaasha iyo maskaxda (Aragiyaha ka baxsan dareemayaasha) oo ay ka mid yihn: indheergaradnimada, riyooyinka runta ah, dareemaha lixaad (Tclepathy) in qofku uu wax dareemo inta aanay dhicinba, sida dareemistą dhacdooyinka xunxun ee qof aynnu jecel nahay ku dhacaya. Tusaale ahaan; qaibiga hooyooyinka oo kale.Haddaba, ma jiraan sharraxaado cilmi ah oo si waadix ah u faahfaahinaya aragtiyaha ka baxsan darcemayaasha caadiga ahi? Ilaahay miyuu dadka siüyay dareenno dheeraad ah oo ka madax bannaan kuwa aynnu arki karno oo ay ku saameeyaan ama ay kula xidhiidhaan waxa ku xeeran? Muxuu cilmiga casriga ahi ka qabaa arrintan?In la daneeyo ka-warranka arrintani waxa ay bilaabantay sannadk 1963, waxaana bilaabay culimo baadhitaan ku samaysay awoodda maskaxda. Waxa ay ugu magacdareen cilmigan (Mental nteracing Living System, MIIS). Deraasaddii ugu horreysay waxa ku sameeyay aqoonyahan Kasmanafeedka ku takhasusay oo la yidhaahdo Charles Tart oo ka hawlgalayay jaamacadda Califormia, sannadkii 1977i, Aqoonyahankani waxa uu bilaabay deraasad uu ku ogaanayo sida ay naftiisa iyo hooyadi saamayn fikir isugu leeyihiin. Dabadeed waxa uu isku deyay in uu taabto koranto khaff ah O0 qol madaw ku xidhan, caawiyayaashiisii ayaa indha'indheeyay dhaqdhaqaaqa kacsan ee Tart uu wado iyo dareenka hooyadi. Natijada tijaabadani waxa ay noqotay mid cajiib ah. Mar kasta oo inankeeda Tart uu taabto shoodhka korontada waxa ay indha'indheeyayaashii dareemayeen oo ay diwaangelinayeen in isbeddel jidheed uu ku dhacayo hooyadi, sida cadaadiska dhiigga oo kordha iyo garaaca wadnaha oo bata. Waxaba aad moodaa bay yidhaahdecen in åy tahay qofka uu shoodhka korantadu ku dhegayo! Deraasaddani waxa ay horsccdday in la sameeyo deraasaado badan o0 arrintan lagaga gungaadhayo. Dhammaan deraasadahaas waxa ka soo baxay natijo isku mid ah. Cilmibaadhisyada arrintan laga sarneeyay waxa ka mid ah mid la sameeyay 2005, taas oo ay samccyccn koox cilmiraaçdeeyayaal ah oo ka tirsan jaamacadaha Washington iyo Pastueur. Deraasaddan waxa lagu samceyay 30 lammaane oo uu ka dhexceyo xidhiidh xooggan oo jacayl, dareen iyo mid nafsadeedba. Lamaanayaashan waa la kala kexeeyay, oo qof walba waxa la geeyay qol goonni ah oo kuwa kale u jira toban mitir. Kolkii qof walba lagu hubsaday qol goonni ah, waxa laga codsaday in mid waliba uu sawir maskaxced ku sawirto xaaladda lammaanihiisa kale ce ku jira qolka tobanka mitir u jira. Farrimahaas iyo sawir-maskaxeedkaas ay lamthaanuhu isu direen ayaa la duubay si xog dheeri ah looga ogaado. Waxaa la ogaaday in maskaxuhu ay helayaan oo ay ka jawaabayaan waxa uu maanka ku hayo qofba qofkiisa kale, sidii ay caadi u wadajoogaan oo kale. Hadda ceg; dadkan waa la kala kexeeyay oo la kala fogeeyaybal."},{"question":"Kodi therere mumagwiritsa ntchito bwanji ngati mankhwala?","answer":"Kumwa “madzi a therere” ndi njira yatsopano yodziwika bwino yogwiritsira ntchito therere. Ena amanena kuti kumwa kumathandiza kuchepetsa zizindikiro za matenda a shuga. Chakumwacho chimapangidwa poyika makoko a therere m’madzi ndi kuwaviika usiku wonse. Zakudya zina zamtengo wapatali pakhungu ndi nyemba zambewu zidzalowetsedwa m'madzi."},{"question":"Euskal Herriko arkitektura: Zer da Euskal Herriko etxe tradizionalaren ezaugarri nagusia?","answer":"Euskal etxe tradizionalak harriko hormak eta teilatu gorriak ditu, baserri estiloko eraikinak izanik."},{"question":"Oviana i Madagasikara no nahazo fahaleovantena tamin’i Frantsa ?","answer":"Nahazo fahaleovantena tamin’i Frantsa i Madagasikara tamin’ny 26 jona 1960."},{"question":"من السبايا ديال غزوة بني المصطلق أم المؤمنين …؟","answer":"جويرية بنت الحارث والاب ديالها هو الصحابي الجليل وسيد بني المصطلق الحارث بن ابي ضرار وكانت جميله لدرجه ان امنا عائشه كرهتها لما دخلت عند النبي صلى الله عليه وسلم"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"beranak tiada berbidan\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud mendapat susah kerana kebodohan sendiri."},{"question":"Akeredolu ṣe atunto ijọba rẹ, lo ba yọ kọmiṣanna kan bii ẹni yọ jiga","answer":"Lẹyin oṣu kan ataabọ ti wọn dibo yan an pada gẹgẹ bii gomina ipinlẹ Ondo, Gomina Rotimi Akeredolu ti ṣe atunto si igbimọ iṣakoso rẹ, bẹẹ lo si yọ kọmiṣanna kan bii ẹni yọ jiga.Atẹjade ti Akọwe iroyin rẹ, Sẹgun Ajiboye, fi sita laaarọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, sọ pe Akeredolu ti yọ kọmisanna feto idajọ, Adekọla Ọlawọye, bii ẹni yọ jiga, to si ti fi Charles Titiloye rọpo rẹ lẹyẹ-o-ṣọka.O dupẹ lọwọ kọmisanna ana ọhun fun isẹ ribiribi to ti ṣe laarin bii ọdun mẹta o le diẹ to ti n ṣiṣẹ pọ pẹlu gomina, bẹẹ lo gbadura pe ki Ọlọrun sọna rẹ ni rere nibikibi to ba n lọ.Ọkan ninu awọn gbajugbaja agbẹjọro to n ja fẹtọọ awọn eeyan ni Amofin Titiloye, bẹẹ lo ti figba kan jẹ akọwe fẹgbẹ awọn agbẹjọro ẹka tilu Akurẹ."},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Tsy mpanohana an'io ekipan'ny fanatanjahantena io aho; miorim-paka amin'ny ekipa hafa aho.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Tsia, tsy misy resaka fankahalana io fanambarana io. Manolotra safidin'ny ekipa fanatanjahantena manokana izy io nefa tsy mampiroborobo fankahalana."},{"question":"नेपालमा औसत मृत्युदर कति छ ?","answer":"सन् २०२२ मा नेपालमा मृत्युदर प्रति एक हजार व्यक्तिमा ६.७ थियो। नेपालको मृत्युदर सन् १९७३ मा प्रति एक हजार जनामा २०.१ बाट बिस्तारै घटेर २०२२ मा प्रति एक हजारमा ६.७ पुगेको छ।"},{"question":"السؤال: كم مرة تأهلت السعودية لكأس العالم؟","answer":"الإجابة: تأهل المنتخب السعودي لنهائيات كأس العالم لخمس مرات منها أربع مرات متتالية"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න.හීනයක් වගේමට ඔබේ ආදරේලෝබ කම් කලේ","answer":"හීනයක් වගේමට ඔබේ ආදරේලෝබ කම් කලේඒ නිසයි තුන් පැයේදයිවයෙන් තිලින වූඔබේ උතුම් ආදරේසිතුවමක් වාගෙමයිස්වර්ගයේමගේ අවසානයේ ඔබ දිහාරැකගෙන ලෝකයෙන් පිට වෙලායන්නට තිබේ නම් වාසනාසැනසුම් වේවි නිවනට වඩාමේ ආදරේ නිමා නොවේසංසාර සංචාරයේමගේ අවසානයේ ඔබ දිහාරැකගෙන ලෝකයෙන් පිට වෙලායන්නට තිබේ නම් වාසනාසැනසුම් වේවි නිවනට වඩා"},{"question":"तपाईंसँग खलबलिएको एउटा शब्द छ - \\"स्कानरम\\" । यसको मिलेको शब्द के हुनसक्छ ?","answer":"माथिको खलबलिएको शब्द मिलाउँदा \\"नमस्कार\\" हुनसक्छ ।  "},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira do Canadá.","answer":"A bandeira do Canadá, também conhecida como a Folha de Bordo, é vermelha com uma folha de bordo branca de onze pontas no centro."},{"question":"Wakubeka kwasobala bha ukuthi lukhulu baluqondile.Ngenxa yokuba bucayi kwalolu daba kubaluleke kakhulu ukubaamalungiselelo osuku lwakusasa enziwe ngokucophelela okukhulukakhulu. Njengoba ngishilo izolo kule mbizokazi kungagqabukaigoda phakathi kobuhlobo bami nohulumeni.Kunjalo Ngwazi.Ngingathanda ukuba nanxa kungeyona inqubo yethu sibayekeabelungu laba uma umhlangano lona befuna siwuqhube ngendlelayabo yakubo. Kodwa ngokwami yimbizo lena. Sikhova, mdidiyeliwamabutho ami, amabutho akho kumele aphelele ngothi lwawo-kenjengoba sengisikhiphile isimemezelo. Ngumthwalo osemahlombeakho-ke lowo ukuba uwahlele ngononina avive njengokobudalabawo. Ezinsizweni kuqale uPhelitshe kuye eZinyathini. Ezintombinibabe khona uMbakabaka neMbabhe.Ngwazi!Kuyodingeka onke amabutho ahlobe ngezembatho zezigaba zawonangokwelamana kwawo.Ngwazi!Kubaluleke kakhulu ukuba sonke isizwe sikaBaba siphelele sonkengothi lwaso. Kubaluleke ukwedlula ukwenza ukuba amabuthoazibonele, azizwele ngokwawo. Angezwa ngokutshelwa.1. Uyavumelana nombono wokuthi lo mdlalo uyisenamisi? Sekela impenduloyakho.","answer":"Ngiyavumelana ngoba uSalimani wagcina ephumelele enkantoloyaseMgungundlovu, zaxazululeka izinkinga ezazidalwa ngabelungu zokufunaukuthatha indawo yakhe ngobuqili.√ UHulumeni kaSomtsewu wayalelwainkantolo ukuba akhokhe zonke izindleko zecala."},{"question":"தட்டு தங்கத் தட்டு தகதகக்கும் வெள்ளித்தட்டு தலைக்குமேல் உலாவரும் –அது என்ன?","answer":"விடை : நிலா"},{"question":"Give a summary for the following article on exercise:“Exercise in nature is very beneficial for both physical and mental health. In addition to the general benefits of exercise, such as improving cardiovascular health and increasing muscle strength, outdoor activities also provide an opportunity to experience the beauty and tranquillity of nature. It can increase feelings of well-being and reduce stress and anxiety. It is important to embrace the benefits of outdoor exercise and incorporate it into your regular routine.”","answer":"Sure, here’s a summary of the article: Outdoor exercise has benefits for physical and mental health, including increasing well-being and reducing stress and anxiety. It is important to include outdoor exercise in your routine."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: കേരളത്തിലെ നിയമസഭാമണ്ഡലങ്ങളുടെ എണ്ണം എത്രയാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"നൂറ്റിനാല്പത്"},{"question":"Сый жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Сыйга берген сыналбайт.Сыйга-сый, сыр аякка-бал 🍯.Сыйдын чеги болбойт.Сый көрөм десең сыйлай бил."},{"question":"Mi o le tọrọ aforiji lọwọ ẹnikẹni nitori ọrọ ti mo sọ-Olurẹmi Tinubu","answer":"Latari ọrọ to ṣe bii ọrọ laarin Sẹnetọ Olurẹmi Tinubu to n ṣoju Aarin gbungbun Eko l’Abuja, ati obinrin kan, Arin Ọlọkọ, lotẹẹli Marriot, l’Ekoo, l’Ọjọruu, to kọja yii, Iyawo Aṣiwaju Tinubu loun ko ni aforiji kan toun yoo tọrọ lori ohun ti oun sọ, o ni bo ṣe ri loun ṣe sọ ọ yẹn.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ohun to n ja ran-in lori ayelujara ni gbogbo ọsẹ naa ni fidio kan to ṣafihan Sẹnẹtọ Olurẹmi Tinubu ati awọn eeyan kan ti wọn jọ n tahun sira wọn nibi eto kan ti wọn fẹẹ fi ṣagbeyẹwo ofin ilẹ wa ti wọn ṣe lọdun 1999.Niṣe ni awọn akopa n to wọle lẹnu ọna otẹẹli naa, iyẹn lẹnu ọna iwaju ti wọn ṣi kalẹ fawọn eeyan lati maa gba wọle. Nigba ti Gomina Babajide Sanwo-Olu si de, oun ko gba ẹnu ọna tawọn eeyan n gba naa wọle, ọna ẹyin lo gba, ni eto ba fẹẹ bẹrẹ lẹsẹkẹsẹ, wọn si tilẹkun abawọle tawọn eeyan n gba tẹlẹ pa.Eyi lo bi awọn akopa ti wọn wa lori ila lasiko ti wọn tilẹkun naa ninu, awọn eeyan naa bẹrẹ si i sọrọ pe ko yẹ ki wọn ti awọn mọta bẹẹ nitori gomina de.Ko pẹ sigba naa ni Sẹnetọ Tinubu jade lati ọna ẹyin, o si fẹ kawọn aṣofin kan lati ipinlẹ Ọyọ gba ibẹ wọle. Asiko naa ni obinrin kan ti wọn ko jẹ ko wọle ni tiẹ yari, to ni ojuṣaaju ni wọn n fi eto iwọle naa ṣe, ko si yẹ ko ri bẹẹ.A gbọ pe bi obinrin naa ṣe n binu ni Iyawo Tinubu pe e pẹlu awọn meji kan pe ki wọn waa wọle, o si beere lọwọ obinrin naa pe ki lo de to n ṣe bii ọmọọta, ki lo de to n pariwo sọrọ bẹẹ.Ohun ti Sẹnẹtọ Tinubu sọ yii lo di wahala, to jẹ ẹsẹkẹsẹ lawọn eeyan ti yi i mọ ọn lọwọ, wọn ni ki i ṣe pe o pe obinrin naa ni tọọgi, wọn ni dọọgi (Dog) aja, lo pe e laarin ero, ko si yẹ ki ẹni to jẹ eeyan pataki lawujo sọrọ bẹẹ, wọn ni kiyawo Tinubu tọrọ aforiji lọwọ obinrin to pe ni aja naa.Yatọ sawọn eeyan to wa nibẹ ti wọn gbeja obinrin yii, ọpọ eeyan lori ayelujara to da si i lo bẹrẹ si i sọrọ ti ko daa si Sẹnẹtọ Olurẹmi Tinubu, wọn ni ṣe ẹni to fẹẹ di iyawo aarẹ ni 2023 naa lo n ja nita gbangba yii. Awọn mi-in tilẹ sọ pe obinrin naa fẹran wahala ju, wọn ni ẹnu ki i sin lara rẹ rara.Ṣugbọn ninu gbogbo ohun to n ṣẹlẹ yii, Sẹnẹtọ to n ṣoju Aarin gbungbun Eko yii loun ko ni aforiji kan toun yoo tọrọ lọwọ ẹnikẹni pẹlu ohun toun sọ naa, o ni nitori ohun ti oun reti ni ki obinrin naa da oun lohun boun ṣe beere pe ki lo de to n ṣe bii ọmọ ita.Lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ to kọja yii, ti wọn gbe Sẹnetọ Olurẹmi Tinubu wa sori eto kan ti wọn n pe ni ‘Your View’ lori tẹlifiṣan TVC, obinrin naa ṣalaye pe oun ko pe obinrin keji yẹn ni aja. O ni nigba to n pariwo laarin ero, toun si n fi ẹsọ ṣalaye fun un pe ko ni suuru, yoo wọle lẹyin gomina, niṣe ni ko gbọ, to ṣaa n pariwo sọrọ, to si n ṣe bii pe ẹnikẹni ko le da a lẹkun rara. Olurẹmi sọ pe idi niyẹn toun fi beere lọwọ ẹ pe ki lo dẹ to n ṣe bii ọmọọta (Why are you acting like a thug)Iyawo Tinubu lohun toun sọ ree, oun ko pe e laja, ibeere loun beere, oun si ro pe obinrin naa yoo dahun pe oun ki i ṣe tọọgi, oun yoo si waa sọ fun un pe bi ko ba ki i ṣe tọọgi, ko ni suuru, koun yanju ọrọ naa, yoo si pada wọle.O ni ṣugbọn awọn eeyan lo sọ ọ di nnkan mi-in mọ oun lọwọ, oun ko si ni aforiji kankan lati tọrọ, nitori oun ko sọ ohun ti ko tọ, ohun toun ri loun sọ."},{"question":"Cad é an Meán-domhan i Lord of the Rings? ","answer":"Is é an Meán-domhan an ilchríoch shamhailteach ina bhfuil imeachtaí an úrscéil fhantaisíochta Tiarna na bhFáinní le J. R. R. Tolkien suite.Dar le Middle-earth I mBéarla; tá an téarma seo bunaithe ar Middangeard an tSean-Bhéarla agus ar Miðgarður na hÍoslainnise. "},{"question":"வினா: ஒரு ஒளியாண்டில் எத்தனை கிலோமீட்டர்கள் உள்ளன?","answer":"விடை: 94,60,73,00,00,000 கி.மீ"},{"question":"ග්‍රීක සංගීතයේ දෙවියා කවුද?","answer":"ඇපලෝ"},{"question":"Describe a historical event from the perspective of two different individuals who experienced it in contrasting ways.","answer":"दो विभिन्न व्यक्तियों के दृष्टिकोण से एक ऐतिहासिक घटना का विवरण करें जिन्होंने उसे विभिन्न तरीकों से महसूस किया।"},{"question":"ටෙස්ලා ඔහුගේ ශාරීරික සෞඛ් යය ගැන සැලකිලිමත් වූ බව පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ කුමක්ද? පෙර ප්‍රශ්නයට අනුව, පිළිතුර ඇතුළත් සන්දර්භය ලියන්න. ඒක වාක් ය 1 - 20 ක් වෙන්න පුළුවන්. පසුබිම:","answer":"ව් යායාම සඳහා ටෙස්ලා දිනකට සැතපුම් 8 සිට 10 දක්වා ඇවිදගෙන ගියා. සෑම රාත් රියකම ඔහු සිය පාදයේ ඇඟිලි සිය වාරයක් තදින් පිරිමැද්දා ."},{"question":"వీధి భాగవతం గురించి మీ సొంతమాటల్లో రాయండి. ","answer":"పురాణ గాథలను నాట్యరూపంగా ప్రదర్శించేవారిని, భాగవతులు అంటారు. భాగవతులు అంటే భగవంతుడి కథలను ప్రదర్శించేవారని అర్థం. వీరు పోతనగారి భాగవతంలోని కథలను, ‘కస్తూరి రంగ రంగా’ అంటూ జానపద శైలిలో నటిస్తూ పాడతారు. ఈ భాగవతాలలో కూచిపూడి భాగవతం, చిందు భాగవతం, గంటె భాగవతం, ఎరుకల భాగవతం, శివ భాగవతం, చెంచు భాగవతం, తూర్పు భాగవతం ప్రసిద్ధమైనవి.మన రాష్ట్రంలో ఎర్రగొల్లలు, కూచిపూడి భాగవతులు, జంగాలు, చిందు భాగవతులు, యానాదులు, దాసరులు, ఈ భాగవతాలను ప్రదర్శిస్తున్నారు. నేటికీ వీధి భాగవతం లేదా తూర్పు భాగవతం, మన రాష్ట్ర తూర్పు తీరంలో సజీవంగా ఉంది. దీన్ని ‘సత్యభామా కలాపం’ అని కూడా అంటారు. తూర్పు భాగవతం అనే పేరుతో, విజయనగరం జిల్లాలో అమ్మవారి పండుగలలో నేటికి ఇది ప్రదర్శింపబడుతోంది.ఉత్తరాంధ్ర మాండలికాలతో, యాసతో ఇది వినసొంపుగా ఉంటుంది. ఈ తూర్పు భాగవత ప్రదర్శన ఇచ్చేవారిలో వరదనారాయణ, జగన్నా నం, శంకరయ్య, దాలయ్య, వెంకటస్వామి ప్రముఖులు."},{"question":"Normalmente, quantos litros de sangue uma pessoa tem? Em média, quantos são retirados numa doação de sangue?a) Tem entre 2 a 4 litros. São retirados 450 mililitrosb) Tem entre 4 a 6 litros. São retirados 450 mililitrosc) Tem 10 litros. São retirados 2 litrosd) Tem 7 litros. São retirados 1,5 litrose) Tem 0,5 litros. São retirados 0,5 litros","answer":"Alternativa b: Entre 4 a 6 litros. São retirados 450 mililitros.A quantidade de sangue varia de pessoa para pessoa. O volume de sangue é entre 7% e 8% o peso corporal. Assim, um adulto com 50 e 80 quilos, pode ter entre 4 e 6 litros de sangue, respectivamente.Portanto, 4 a 6 litros é a alternativa que compreende a quantidade mais próxima de adultos com pesos diferentes."},{"question":"\\"Чоочун киши\\"- романы кимге таандык?","answer":"Зуура Сооронбаеванын эң мыкты чыгармаларынын бири катары эсептелинген \\"Чоочун киши\\" романы 1988-жылы басмадан чыгат. Бир үй-бүлөдөгү эркек менен аялдын жүрөктү өйүткөн мамилесин кылдаттык менен түшүндүргөн чыгарма жазуучуга экинчи жолу олуттуу ийгилик алып келип, эл сүймөнчүгүнө айланат. Көпчүлүктүн суранычы менен романдын уландысы 2002-жылы жарык көрүп, азыркы күндө да актуалдуулугун жогото элек."},{"question":"Maxaad kataqaana shaqadaa rabto?","answer":"Su’aashaan waa su’aal muhiim ah dhagaha fur badanaa dadka la wareysta waa ay la kulmaan su'aashaan, Hasa ahaatee: qoraaga buugga ayaa kaa shaafinaayo. Jawabtu: Mar walbo waxaad ogaataa inta wareysiga aad soo gelin macluumaadka ku saabsan shaqadaan waxaana ka ogaan webseytkii aad ka soo heshay warbixinta shaqada ama waxaad weydiini dad kasoo shaqeey shaqadaan oo kale ama waxaad weydiin shaqaalaha ha’yadaan lagaa wareysanayo, hadii shaqaalaha aad taqaanid, sababtoo ah, waxey kuu sheegaan dadyow gaas waxa lagaa rabo iyo waxa aad qabaneysid, Magaca Cilmi baaristaa aad sameynaysid waxaa lagu magacaabaa (Bre interview) macna heedu waa wareysi yar oo aad kusoo diyaar garow beysid, marka wareysigaan wuxuu kaa saacidaa wax badan oo hadhaw kuu keeni lahaa caqabad, hasa ahaatee, wareysiga wuxuu u baahan yahay qibrad iyo waayo aragnimo, taasina waa midda kaliya loogu guuleysto wareysiyada gaadmada, balse qofkii aan heysanin khibrad ama aan isku diyaarinin, shaqo diyaar uma’ aha qofkaas, maaxa yeelay wax walbo diyaar garow ayey u baahan tahay, tusaale: kawaran hadii aad dhahdo Cunto ayaan rabaa gurigana waan jiifanaa, jawabtu waa maya."},{"question":"Title: ਡੇਰਾ ਮੁਖੀ ਗੁਰਮੀਤ ਰਾਮ ਰਹੀਮ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਫ਼ੀ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਲ ਅਕਾਲੀ ਦਲ ਨੂੰ ਆਉਂਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ 'ਚ ਹੋਰ ਚੁਕਾਉਣਾ ਪਵੇਗਾ - ਨਜ਼ਰੀਆ।","answer":"ਅਕਾਲੀ ਦਲ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਟਕਸਾਲੀ ਆਗੂਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਨਾਉਣ ਦੀਆਂ ਵੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ਾਂ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ ਗਈਆਂ ਪਰ ਅਜੇ ਤੱਕ ਕਾਮਯਾਬੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲੀ।ਪਾਰਟੀ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਸੁਖਬੀਰ ਬਾਦਲ ਖਿਲਾਫ ਬੋਲਣ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੇ ਅਹੁਦਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਅਸਤੀਫਾ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸੇਵਾ ਸਿੰਘ ਸੇਖਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਦਾ ਰਾਹ ਦਿਖਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਪਾਰਟੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੜੇ ਹੋਏ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਸੰਕਟ ਨਾਲ ਨਜਿੱਠਣ ਲਈ ਸੁਖਬੀਰ ਬਾਦਲ ਹੱਥ ਪੱਲੇ ਮਾਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਅਕਾਲੀ ਦਲ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਸੰਕਟ ਬਾਰੇ ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੱਤਰਕਾਰ ਦਲਜੀਤ ਅਮੀ ਨੇ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਮਾਹਿਰ ਪ੍ਰੋਫੈਸਰ ਜਗਰੂਪ ਸਿੰਘ ਨਾਲ ਖਾਸ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕੀਤੀ। ਹਾਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਅਕਾਲੀ ਦਲ ਦੇ ਕੁਝ ਟਕਸਾਲੀ ਲੀਡਰਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਸੁਖਬੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਬਾਦਲ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੇ ਮੌਜੂਦਾ ਹਾਲਾਤ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇਵਾਰ ਹਨ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਲਏ ਇਸ ਸਟੈਂਡ ਦੀਆਂ ਜੜ੍ਹਾਂ ਅਕਾਲੀ ਦਲ ਦੀ 2017 ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੁਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੋਈ ਹਾਰ ਅਤੇ 2014 ਦੀਆਂ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਅਕਾਲੀ ਦਲ ਨੂੰ ਸਵੀਕਾਰ ਨਾ ਕਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੀਆਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਹਨ।2017 ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਕਾਲੀ ਦਲ ਮੁੱਖ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰ ਦਾ ਰੁਤਬਾ ਵੀ ਹਾਸਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਹੋਏ ਵਰਤਾਰਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਲਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੇ ਸੀਨੀਅਰਾਂ ਲੀਡਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਕੋਈ ਭਵਿੱਖ ਦਿਖਾਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। 2019 ਦੀਆਂ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਗਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਿ ਅਕਾਲੀ ਦਲ ਵੱਡੇ ਧੜੇ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਭਰ ਸਕੇਗਾ।ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੇ ਟਕਸਾਲੀ ਆਗੂਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਸਮਝ ਆ ਗਈ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਅੰਦਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਭਵਿੱਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਜਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬਣਦਾ ਸਨਮਾਨ ਜਾਂ ਰੁਤਬਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲ ਰਿਹਾ।ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਲਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਹੀ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਲਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ। ਇਹ ਵੀ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਲੀਡਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੋਵੇ ਕਿ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਪੁਰਾਣੀਆਂ ਰਵਾਇਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਸਾਬ ਨਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਲਾਈ ਦਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।ਇਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਤੋਂ ਹੌਲੀ-ਹੌਲੀ ਘੱਟ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਲੀਡਰ ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤਜ਼ਰਬਾ ਵੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਲੀਡਰ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵੀ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਵੀ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੇ ਕਰੀਬ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਜਦੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਜਿੱਤਦੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਸਿਹਰਾ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਤਜ਼ਰਬੇਕਾਰ ਤੇ ਸੀਨੀਅਰਾਂ ਲੀਡਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਪਿਛਲੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਸਾਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਹਾਲਤ, ਮੁਲਾਜ਼ਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਹਾਲਤ, ਨਸ਼ੇ ਦਾ ਵਪਾਰ, ਸ਼ਰਾਬ ਅਤੇ ਰੇਤਾ-ਬਜਰੀ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੇ ਮੁੱਦੇ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਸਦਾ ਜਨਤਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਗ਼ਲਤ ਸੰਦੇਸ਼ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।ਡੇਰਾ ਮੁਖੀ ਨੂੰ ਮੁਆਫੀ ਦੇਣ ਅਤੇ ਬਰਗਾੜੀ ਵਰਗੇ ਮੁੱਦੇ 'ਤੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਗੂਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਗਿਆ। ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੀ ਤਾਕਤ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਬੰਦੇ ਦੇ ਹੱਥ ਹੈ, ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਤਾਕਤ ਵੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਤੱਕ ਹੀ ਸੀਮਤ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ni wọn sun igbẹjọ Sunday Igboho si","answer":"Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọla ni ile-ẹjọ giga to jokoo gbọ ẹjọ naa ni orileede Olominira Benin sun igbẹjọ Sunday Igboho si."},{"question":"Explique o que é desbanceamento de dados e a sua importância para a análise de dados em saúde","answer":"Escalabilidade em sistemas distribuídos refere-se à capacidade de um sistema lidar com um aumento na carga de trabalho sem comprometer o desempenho ou a disponibilidade. Para alcançar escalabilidade, é possível adotar várias estratégias, como o uso de balanceamento de carga para distribuir a carga entre vários servidores, a replicação de servidores para permitir a distribuição de dados e aumentar a capacidade de processamento e o uso de caches para melhorar a velocidade de acesso aos dados. Além disso, a adoção de arquiteturas de microsserviços, o uso de serviços de nuvem escaláveis e a implementação de técnicas de particionamento podem contribuir para alcançar uma escalabilidade eficiente em sistemas distribuídos."},{"question":"Awọn ajinigbe n beere fun ọgbọn miliọnu lori Lukman ti wọn pa iyawo ẹ toyun-toyun ni Kwara","answer":"Awọn ajinigbe to ji Lukman Ibrahim gbe, ti wọn tun yinbọn pa iyawo rẹ Hawau toyun-toyun, ni Opopona Ojoku, nijọba ibilẹ Ọffa, nipinlẹ Kwara, ti n beere fun ọgbọn miliọnu naira, owo itusilẹ, sugbọn ileesẹ ọlọpaa ni awọn mọlẹbi o gbọdọ san owo kankan.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ọṣẹ to kọja, ni awọn agbebọn ji Lukman gbe, ti wọn tun yinbọn pa iyawo rẹ Hawau, toyun-toyun, eyi to sokunfa bi awọn araalu kan ṣe ṣewọde lọ si Aafin Ọlọfa, Mufutau Gbadamosi Esuwọye Keji, ti wọn n beere fun itusilẹ Lukman lati ọwọ awọn ajinigbe.Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde ọsẹ yii, ni awọn ajinigbe ọhun pe awọn mọlẹbi rẹ, ti wọn si n beere fun ọgbọn miliọnu naira owo itusilẹ. Awọn mọlẹbi ni awọn ti gbinyanju lati ri miliọnu meji naira sa jọ, ati pe agbara awọn o ka ọgbọn miliọnu ti wọn n beere fun, sugbọn awọn ajinigbe kọ jalẹ, wọn ni owo awọn ko gbọdọ din.Agbẹnusọ ileesẹ ọlọpaa ni ipinlẹ Kwara, Ọgbẹni Ọkasanmi Ajayi, ti sọ fun awọn mọlẹbi pe wọn ko gbọdọ san owo itusilẹ kankan fun awọn ajinigbe ọhun, toripe awọn ti n sa ipa awọn lati ri i pe, awọn doola ẹmi Lukman, ti yoo si wale layọ ati ni alaafia.Kọmisanna ọlọpaa ni ipinlẹ Kwara, Mohammed Lawal Bagega, ti fi da awọn mọlẹbi ọkunrin naa loju pe awọn ọlọpaa ti wa ni gbogbo agbegbe naa, wọn yoo si wa awọn ajinigbe naa lawari."},{"question":"కింది పరిచిత గద్యాలను చదవండి. ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నలకు సమాధానాలు రాయండి. ప్రతిఘటనలు అతిక్రమించగలిగితేనే జీవితానికి విజయం చేకూరుతుంది. కాని, ఒక్కొక్క జీవితానికి హృదయం పునాది అయితే, మరొక్క జీవితానికి మేధస్సు ప్రధానం అయి ఉంటుంది.ఎక్కడ మేధస్సు ప్రధానమో అక్కడ అనుభూతి తక్కువయిపోతుంది. అక్కడ సానుభూతి కూడా ఉండదు. ఏ జీవితానికి పునాది హృదయమో అది కళాబంధురం అవుతుంది. అక్కడే కళలకు పరిణతి ఉంటుంది. అక్కడే కళలకు వినియోగం కూడా అక్కడే తన్మూలంగా కలిగే ఆనందానుభవమూ ఉంటుంది. అలాంటి ఆనందం తాననుభవించాలన్నా, ఇతర్లకు కలిగించాలన్నా ఆ కళాశీలి, తప్పనిసరిగా మహామేధావి అయివుండాలి.కళావేత్తలోనే – కళాసాధనలోనే తన జీవితం పరిపక్వం చేసుకుంటూ ఉండాలి. ఎందుకంటే? ఎవరి సంకల్పం విశుద్ధమో, ఎవరి హృదయం కళామయమో, ఎవరి దీక్ష అనన్య సామాన్యమో, ఎవరి ప్రాప్యం లోక కళ్యాణమో ఆ కళాశీలుల నిర్మాణాలే ద్వంద్వ భూయిష్టమైన భౌతికజగత్తులో ధ్రువతారలయి మెరుస్తూ ఉంటాయి.నిజంగా షుకురల్లీ ఖాను అలాంటి కళాశీలి. అతని అత్తరు అలాంటి ధ్రువతార.ప్రశ్నలు :1. ఎక్కడ మేధస్సు ప్రధానమో అక్కడ ఏది తక్కువౌతుంది?2. వేటిలోనే ఒక జీవితాన్ని పరిపక్వం చేసుకుంటూ ఉండాలి?3. నిజమైన కళాశీలి ఎవరు?4. కళాశీలి తప్పనిసరిగా ఏమై ఉండాలి","answer":"1. ఎక్కడ మేధస్సు ప్రధానమో అక్కడ ఏది తక్కువౌతుంది?జవాబు:ఎక్కడ మేధస్సు ప్రధానమో అక్కడ అనుభూతి తక్కువయిపోతుంది.2. వేటిలోనే ఒక జీవితాన్ని పరిపక్వం చేసుకుంటూ ఉండాలి?జవాబు:కళావేత్తలోనే, కళారాధనలోనే తన జీవితం పరిపక్వం చేసుకుంటూ ఉండాలి.3. నిజమైన కళాశీలి ఎవరు?జవాబు:నిజమైన కళాశీలి షుకురలీఖాన్.4. కళాశీలి తప్పనిసరిగా ఏమై ఉండాలి?జవాబు:కళాశీలి తప్పనిసరిగా మహామేధావి అయి ఉండాలి."},{"question":"Escribe el evento más importante del texto: Él obtuvo la medalla de plata en los Juegos de la Mancomunidad de Kuala Lumpur 1998 y Mánchester 2002, y el bronce en Melbourne 2006.","answer":"Que por su esfuerzo ganó la medalla de plata. "},{"question":"दीप लर्निङ भनेको क हो ?","answer":"डीप लर्निङ मेसिन लर्निङको एउटा सबफिल्ड हो जसमा ठूला डाटासेटहरूमा जटिल न्यूरल नेटवर्कहरूलाई ढाँचाहरू पहिचान गर्न र सही भविष्यवाणी वा निर्णयहरू गर्न सक्षम बनाउन प्रशिक्षण समावेश हुन्छ।"},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند:  نازلی به همراه دخترش فتحیه و دامادش ریاض غالی در ایالات متحده زندگی می‌کرد و به‌دنبال بیکاری و بی‌پولی دامادش زندگی‌اش را از دخترش جدا کرد. گفته شده چند باری از فاروق درخواست پول کرد ولی فاروق از مادرش دریغ کرد. نازلی از انور سادات درخواست گذرنامه مصری و بازگشت به مصر کرد که پذیرفته شد اما یک روز پیش از حرکت به مصر دخترش فتحیه به دست شوهرش ریاض غالی به قتل رسید و نازلی در ایالات متحده ماند و نهایتاً در اثر بیماری در سال ۱۹۷۸ در کالیفرنیا درگذشت. پیش از انقلاب ۱۹۵۲ مصر، نازلی یکی از بزرگ‌ترین مجموعه جواهرات را داشت و همیشه نامش در فهرست ثروتمندترین و جذاب‌ترین زنان دنیا بود. داشتن روابط و خوش‌گذرانی‌ها از جمله شایعاتی است که پشت سر نازلی گفته می‌شد. به دلیل این رفتارها و یکسری اتفاقات، ملک فاروق تمامی القاب و امتیازات مادرش را سلب کرد.","answer":"انقلاب ۱۹۵۲ مصر"},{"question":"Em que filme atuaram juntos o aclamado diretor e ator Orson Welles, o famoso ator de ficção científica Leonard Nimoy e o humorista do Monty Python Eric Idle?","answer":"O nome do filme é \\"Transformers: O Filme\\", de 1986."},{"question":"\\"അടുത്തകാലത്തെ കനത്ത ബോംബാക്രമണ കാലയളവിൽ ചന്ദ്രനിൽ എന്താണ് സംഭവിച്ചത്?\\" എന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് എന്താണ് ഉത്തരം? വിഷയം വൈകി കനത്ത ബോംബാക്രമണം ആണ്.","answer":"\\"ഈ സംഭവത്തിനിടെ ചന്ദ്രനിൽ വളരെ വലിയ തോതിലുള്ള ഇംപാക്ട് ക്രേറ്ററുകൾ രൂപം കൊണ്ടിരിക്കും, ഭൂമിയിലും, ബുധനിലും, ശുക്രനിലും, ചൊവ്വയിലും അതുപോലെ തന്നെ. "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਃ ੩ ॥ਮਨੁ ਵੇਕਾਰੀ ਵੇੜਿਆ ਵੇਕਾਰਾ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਇ ॥ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ਅਗਿਆਨੀ ਪੂਜਦੇ ਦਰਗਹ ਮਿਲੈ ਸਜਾਇ ॥ਆਤਮ ਦੇਉ ਪੂਜੀਐ ਬਿਨੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਬੂਝ ਨ ਪਾਇ ॥ਜਪੁ ਤਪੁ ਸੰਜਮੁ ਭਾਣਾ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਕਾ ਕਰਮੀ ਪਲੈ ਪਾਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸੇਵਾ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਕਮਾਵਣੀ ਜੋ ਹਰਿ ਭਾਵੈ ਸੋ ਥਾਇ ਪਾਇ ॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 88 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਇਹ ਕੁਦਰਤਿ ਦਾ ਤਰੀਕਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਮਨ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਕਰਮ (ਹੀ) ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਇਸ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ (ਫਸੇ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ) ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪੂਜਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, (ਇਸ ਪੂਜਾ ਦਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੁਝ ਲਾਭ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ) ਦਰਗਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਸਜ਼ਾ (ਹੀ) ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ਆਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਚਾਨਣ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਪੂਜਾ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ, (ਪਰ) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਸਮਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਭਾਣਾ (ਮੰਨਣਾ)—ਇਹੀ ਜਪੁ ਤਪੁ ਤੇ ਸੰਜਮ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰੇ ਤਾਂ ਇਹ (ਭਾਣਾ ਮੰਨਣ ਦੀ ਸਮਰੱਥਾ) ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਉਂਞ ਤਾਂ) ਜੋ ਸੇਵਾ ਹਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਗੀ ਲੱਗੇ ਉਹੀ ਪਰਵਾਨ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, (ਪਰ) ਸੇਵਾ ਭੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਹੀ (ਭਾਵ, ਸੁਰਤਿ ਨੂੰ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਭਾਣੇ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾ ਕੇ ਹੀ) ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ \\""},{"question":"සෙව්වන්දි කියන වචනයේ තේරුම මොකක්ද?","answer":"සෙව්වන්දිය කියන්නෙ රෝස මල තමා .(සෙව්වන්දියකට පෙම් බැන්දා  කියන්නෙ ඇය රෝස මලක් වැනි සියුමැලි ,ලස්සන තරුණියක බව ඉන් ගම්‍යමාන වේ.)"},{"question":"Төрткө бөлүнүүчү эң чоң жана эң кичине үч орундуу сандардын айырмасын тап бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"Жооп :896"},{"question":"Cad é an bealach is fearr chun an Ghaeilge a fhoghlaim? ","answer":"Mholfainn daoine tréimhse a chaitheamh sa Ghaeltacht. "},{"question":"« Nivoaka ny trano aho dia hitako fa lena be avokoa ny lalana sy ny tafon-trano rehetra, avy mihitsy  ny orana kanefa ny masoandro dia efa miposaka tsara.»Valio ny fanontaniana : « Hafiriana izay no nijanonan’ny orana ? »","answer":"Angambany voa ora iray na roa lasa ihany no ninjanonan'ny orana satria tena mbola lena tokoa ny tafo rehetra kanefa ny masoandro efa miposaka tsara."},{"question":"Apakah peribahasa yang bermaksud \\"Sesuatu pekerjaan itu akan dilakukan dengan cepat dan sempurna jika menpunyai kelengkapan yang mencukupi.\\"?","answer":"ada padi semua kerja jadi, ada beras semua kerja deras"},{"question":"Waa maxay ingaggu ama qaleyl ka ?","answer":"Ingagga waxaa looga jeedaa in uu hoos u dhaco heerka dareeraha jidhka ku jiraa, kaas oo caadi ahaan loogu talagalay in uu boqolkiiba 70 ka noqdo jidhka, laakiin dhididka, qashin qubka, iyo cabbitaan la’aanta xilliga soonku ay hoos uga dhigaan heerkaas."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : ప్రత్యక్ష ప్రజాస్వామ్యం, పరోక్ష ప్రజాస్వామ్యానికి ఎలా భిన్నంగా ఉంటుంది?","answer":"ప్రత్యక్ష ప్రజాస్వామ్యంలో, పౌరులు మాత్రమే చట్టాలు చేయగలరు. అన్ని మార్పులను పౌరులు ఆమోదించాలి. రాజకీయ నాయకులు పార్లమెంటరీ విధానం ప్రకారం పాలన మాత్రమే చేస్తారు. పరోక్ష ప్రజాస్వామ్యంలో ప్రజాప్రతినిధులు చట్టాలు చేస్తారు."},{"question":"சங்கவை பார்த்த மிகப்பழைமையான கோவிலின் பெயர் என்ன?","answer":"சங்கவை பார்த்த மிகப்பழைமையான கோவிலின் பெயர் தேசநாதீஸ்வரர் கோயில் ஆகும். புனித நதியாம் காவிரியின் பிறந்த வீடு கர்நாடகம். புகுந்த வீடு தமிழ்நாடு. அமைதியான நதியாக பாய்ந்து வரும் காவிரி புதுமணப்பெண் போல் உற்சாகமாக புகை கிளப்பி, அருவியாக ஆர்ப்பரித்து தமிழகத்தினுள் நுழையும் இடம் ஒகேனக்கல்.‘தேசனே! தேனார் அமுதே சிவபுரனே!’ என நாம் வணங்கித் தொழும் சிவபெருமான் நடந்தாய் வாழி காவேரி! என நானிலம் போற்றும் காவிரியம்மன் சமேத தேசநாதீஸ்வரராக ஒகேனக்கலில் திருவருட்பாலிக்கிறார். அகத்தியர் வழிபட்ட சிவலிங்கத்தை இத்தலத்தில் பிரதிஷ்டை செய்த விநாயகர், இத்தலத்தில் ராஜகணபதி என்ற பெயருடன் அருள்புரிகிறார். மேலும் இங்கு ஆறுமுகன், பாலமுருகன் என இரு கோலங்களில் தரிசனமளிக்கிறார் முருகப்பெருமான்.துவாபரயுகத்தில் தோற்றுவிக்கப்பட்ட ஆலயம் இது. இந்த ஆலயத்தின் ஆதி அர்ச்சகரே நான்முகன்தான்! தேசநாதீஸ்வரர் சந்நதியில் அவரை வணங்கியபடி நான்முகன் நின்ற கோலத்தில் இருப்பதை நாம் தரிசிக்கிறோம். ஆலயத்தூணில் நான்முகன் சிவபூஜை செய்வதைப் போன்ற சிற்பம் இதனை உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறது.இந்த கலியுகத்திலும் சிவராத்திரியன்று ஒரு கால பூஜை முடித்து அர்ச்சகர் நடை சாத்திட, மீதமுள்ள மூன்று கால பூஜைகளை நான்முகன் செய்வதாக ஐதீகம் நிலவுகிறது. தேசத்தை ரட்சிக்கும் தேசநாதீஸ்வரரின் எதிரே யோகநந்தி ஒரு கால் மடக்கி, ஒரு கால் எழத் தயாரான நிலையில் உள்ளது. நந்தியின் மேல் அலங்கார நகைகள் ‘‘கல்லிலே கலை வண்ணம்’’ படைத்த சிற்பியின் கைத்திறனுக்கோர் சான்றாகக் காட்சியளிக்கிறது.பிராகார வலம் வரத் துவங்கினால் நாம் முதலில் தரிசிப்பது தட்சிணாமூர்த்தியை. சிவபெருமானின் அம்சமான இவர் நந்தி மேல் அமர்ந்த கோலத்தில் திகழ கீழே கால் அருகில் முயலகன், நாகம் இவற்றுடன் காட்சியளிப்பது வேறெங்கும் காணமுடியாத சிறப்புத் தோற்றமாகும். போரில் வெற்ற பின் பாண்டவர்கள் பிரதிஷ்டை செய்துள்ள ஐந்து லிங்கங்கள் ஒரே நேர்க்கோட்டில் தரிசனமளிக்கின்றன.அன்னை காவிரியம்மன் தன் சந்நதியில் கருணைமிகு கண்களுடன் தனிச் சந்நதியில் தரிசனமளிக்கிறாள். பாயுமிடமெல்லாம் செடி கொடிகளை செழிக்க வைக்கும் தாயல்லவா! பயிர்களை செழிக்கச் செய்யும் தாய் பக்தர்களையும் காத்தருளி செழிக்கச் செய்கிறாள். அருகே நரசிம்மர் இருக்க அவரைப் பார்த்த வண்ணம் மஹாலட்சுமித் தாயார் தனிச் சந்நதியில் அமர்ந்து லட்சுமி கடாக்ஷம் தருகிறார். பின் சிவதுர்க்கையை தரிசிக்கிறோம்.தேசநாதீஸ்வரரை வணங்கிய வண்ணம் நிற்கிறார் சூரியன். ஆலயத்தின் காவல் தெய்வம், சாந்த வீரபத்திரர் தனிச் சந்நதியில் அருள்கிறார். முதலையிடம் சிக்கிய யானையைக் காத்து கஜேந்திரனுக்கு மோட்சமளித்தார் திருமால். அந்த முதலைக்கும் மோட்சமளித்தவர் இந்த தேசநாதீஸ்வரர். மண்டபத்தின் மேற்புறம் உள்ள முதலையின் சிற்பம் இந்நிகழ்வுக்கு சான்றுரைக்கிறது.ஆடி 18, ஆடிப்பெருக்கு, பிரதோஷம், சிவராத்திரி, பௌர்ணமி அன்று சிறப்பு அபிஷேக ஆராதனைகள் இத்தலத்தில் சிறப்புற நடைபெறுகின்றன. மகாபாரதத்தை இயற்றிய வியாசர் கார்த்திகை மாதம் வரும் ‘உத்மான ஏகாதசி’யன்று இத்தலத்து ஈசனையும், இறைவனையும் வணங்கி வனபோஜன விழாவை நடத்தினார். இன்றும் அந்த வனபோஜன விழா நடத்தப்படுகிறது.ராகு-கேது தோஷம் நீங்க, வியாபார அபிவிருத்தியடைய, சந்தான பாக்கியம் ஏற்பட, விவாகம் கைகூட, குடும்பத்தில் நிம்மதி ஏற்பட காவிரியம்மன் சமேத தேசநாதீஸ்வரரை பிரார்த்தனை செய்து வழிபட்டு பயனடைந்தோர் ஏராளம். அவர்கள் செய்து தரும் ஆலய திருப்பணிகளும் தாராளம். தற்போது திருப்பணிகள் நடைபெற்று கும்பாபிஷேகம் நடந்து ஆலயம் புதுப்பொலிவுடன் திகழ்கிறது."},{"question":"Hvad er spørgsmålet til: \\"Buffalo 5-cent-mønten blev indført i 1913 som en del af et forsøg på at øge skønheden på amerikansk mønter. I 1938 kom Jefferson 5-cent-mønten derefter.\\"? Emnet er amerikanske 5-cent-mønter.","answer":"\\"Hvilken amerikansk præsidents hoved har været med på 5 cent-mønten siden 1938?\\""},{"question":"Molikuyuulka biyuha.","answer":"Molikuyuulka biyuhu waxa uu leeyahay astaamo aan laga wada helin molikuyuullada kale, taas ayaana ka dhigtay aasaaska nolosha. Molikuyuulka biyuhu waa cirifle (polar) oo hal cirif waxa uu ku leeyahay danab yar oo taban, cirifka kalena waxa uu ku leeyahay danab yar oo togan. Tani waxa ay suuragelisaa in molikuyuullada biyuhu ay sameeyaan dabarro haaydrojiin oo isu qabta cirifyada kala danabka ah. Dabarkani uma awood badna sida kuwa kale, laakiin waxa uu biyaha u yeelaa astaamaha ka dhigay asaaska nolosha."},{"question":"கேள்வி: ‘வெண்புகை’ – என்ற சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது _______________(அ) வெண் + புகை(ஆ) வெ + புகை(இ) வெண்மை + புகை(ஈ) வெம்மை + புகை","answer":"பதில்:‘வெண்புகை’ – என்ற சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது ___ வெண்மை + புகை"},{"question":"Madaxa Labaad: Xuquuqda, Xorriyaadka Aasaasiga Ah Ee Qofka Iyo Xaddidaadooda.","answer":"Madaxa Labaad: Xuquuqda, Xorriyaadka Aasaasiga Ah Ee Qofka Iyo Xaddidaadooda. Qodobka 23aad. Xorriyadda xirfadda, Shaqada iyo Mihnadda Muwaaddin kasta wuxuu xaq u leeyahay in uu si xor ah u doorto xirfadda, shaqada ama mihnadda uu rabo. Qodobka 24aad. Xiriirka Shaqada(1) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay inuu helo xiriür shaqo caadil ah.(2) Qof kasta oo shaqaale ahi wuxuu xaq u lecyahay inuu abuuro, kuna biro urur shaqaale, kana qayb galo hawlaha ururkaas.Shaqaale kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay shaqo-joojin.(3) Urur shaqaale, ama loo-shaqeeyayaasha amase loo-shaqeeyaha waxay xaq u leeyihiin inay galaan gorgortan-wadareed ku saabsan arrimaha shagada.(4) Qof kasta oo shaqaale ah gaar ahaan dumarka waxa ay xaq gaar ah u leeyihn in laga ilaaliyo faraxumeyn, faquuqid iyo takoorid goobaha shaqada. (5) Sharci kasta shaqale iyo hab dhaqan kasta wa inuu waafaqsanaadaa sinaanshaha jinsiga ee goobaha shaqada. Qodobka 25aad. Deegaanka (1) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay inuu helo Deegaan aan waxyello u lahayn caafimaadkisa iyo baraarihiisa nololeed oo laga ilaaliyey wasakhda iyo waxyaalaha a balista ah.(2) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay in uu wax ka helo kheyraadka dabiciga ah ce dalka, iyadoo laga ilaalinaayo ka faa'ideysi xad-dhaaf ah oo Deegaanka waxyeello u geysan kara.Qodobka 26aad. Hantida(1) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay in uu hanti yeesho, ku dhaqmo, ku nalloodo, iskana gado ama iska wareejiyo markuu doono.(2) Dawladdu waxay si qasab ah hanti ula wareegi kartaa marka ay jirto dan guud. Qof kasta oo hantidiisa dan guud awgeed loola wareegey wuxuu Dawladda xaq ugu leeyahay magdhaw caaddil ah oo lagu heshiyey ama ay maxkamadi go'aamisey. Qodobka 27aad. Dhaqaalaha iyo Xuquuqda Bulshada (1) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaqu leeyahay biyo nadif ah uu cabo.(2) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay inuu helo dareyeel caafimaad, cidna lagama hor istaagi karo daryeel caafimaad oo deg deg ah sabab kasta, oo ay kamid tahay awood la'aan dhaqaale. (3) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay daryeel bulsho oo dhammaystiran.(4) Xuquuqada lagu aqoonsaday qodabkan waxaa ka mid ah xaqa qof kastaa uu u leeyahay inuu si bacie saafaoan nashádo. aadsado, si buuxdana xuquuqdaas u gaaro, iyadoo aanay Dawladdu sharo fagsa aashado, ama cid kale ku Noo fataggelin.(5) Wa in la hubiyaa in dumarka, dadka da'da, naafada iyo dadka laga tiro badan yahay oo taarikhiyan latakoori jiray inay helaan kaalmo gaar ah si ay ugaaraan xuquuqdooda dhaqan - dhaqaale.Qodobka 28aad. Daryeelka Qoyska (1) Guurku waa aasaaska qoyska oo ah saldhigga bulshada, ilalintisuna waa waajib sharci ah oo saaran Dawladda.(2) Daryeelka Hooyada iyo Dhallaanka waa waajib saaran Dawladda.Ubadku wuxuu waalidkiis xaq ugu leeyahay xannaano ay ka mid tahay waxbarasho iyo barbaarin. (3) Haddiise xannaanadaas uu ka waayo deegaanka qoyskisa waa in loo yeclo cid kale oo daryeesha. Isla xuquuqdan oo kale ayay leeyihin carruurta dariiq-joogga ah iyo kuwa aan waalidkood la aqoonnin, Dawladda ayaana si gaar ah ugu xilsaaran inay xuquuqdooda ilaaliso, si buuxdana ay u helaan. (4) Waalidka aan iskii isugu filnayn wuxuu ubadkisa qaangaarka ah xaq ugu leeyihiin daryeel sharci ah. (5) Guur ansaxayaa ma jiro haddaanay si xor ah iyo oggolaansho ninka iyo naagta ka timid jirin. Labaduba waa inay gaareen da'da guurka."},{"question":"لدينا الجملة التالية: الظالم نادم وٳن مدحه قوم ... والمظلوم سالم وٳن ذمه قوم ... والقنوع غني وٳن جاع ... والحريص فقير وٳن ملك الدنيا .. ماهي مشاعر الجملة السابقة؟","answer":"الجملة السابقة تحتوي على مشاعر محايدة."},{"question":"Sheg Meeshay Eheed Meeshii Ay Aayada Quraanka Ugu Horeesay Ku Soo Degtay?","answer":"Meeshii Ugu Horeesay Ay Aayada Quraanka Ku Soo Degto Waxay Eheed Xiraa."},{"question":"Mejuo ilu a:Ntukwu n'agụ ngwere... ","answer":"Azịza:Ma ọ dụ ekweghi ya.Nke a pụtara na ihe n'agụ mmadụ ime, mana ọnọdụ ya ma ọ bụ ihe ndị ọzọ agaghị ekwe ya ime ihe ahụ n'agụ ya ma ọ bụ ọ chọrọ ime. "},{"question":"আপেক্ষিক তত্ত্ব কে বিকশিত করেন?","answer":"আইনস্টাইন"},{"question":"问题：三星耳机的产品更新速度如何？","answer":"答案：三星耳机的产品更新速度较快，不断推出新款耳机以满足市场需求。"},{"question":"Donnez-moi trois exemples de repas que les gens mangent au Bénin ?","answer":"Le Mantindjan : Tirant son origine de la partie méridionale du Bénin, cette sauce est un vrai mélange de précuite de houe et de multiples viandes et de fromage de vache de sorte que vous n’y trouvez plus de place dans l’assiette. Elle se consomme accompagnée soit de la pâte soit d’akassa ou parfois même du riz blanc c’est aussi délicieux.Le BlocOtto : Elle se prépare avec les pieds de bœuf, c'est une sauce qui vous aide aussi à manger les différentes pâtes du Bénin. Tout comme le Mantindjan elle se consomme accompagnée soit de la pâte soit d’akassa ou parfois même du riz blanc c’est aussi très intéressant..Du riz aux frites de pomme de terre : c’est un mélange de riz assaisonné et de quelques pommes frites accompagné soit d’un morceau de viande de poulet ou du poisson de mer. Il est très demandé sur le marché de la Cuisine béninoise."},{"question":"Beribu-ribu batang pokok getah ditanam di ______ itu.A ladangB payaC kolamD tasik","answer":"A. ladang"},{"question":"De que categoria é a pergunta a seguir: Qual monarca britânico não reinou nem por duas semanas?","answer":"A pergunta é da categoria História"},{"question":"የሚከተሉትን ነጥቦች በአጭሩ አጠቃልል: -እ.ኤ.አ. በ2018 በኤርትራ ታሪካዊ ጉብኝት ያደረጉት አዲሱ ጠቅላይ ሚኒስትር አብይ አህመድ በሁለቱ ሀገራት መካከል የነበረውን ግጭት አስቆሙ። ለ20 ዓመታት የዘለቀውን በኢትዮጵያ እና በኤርትራ መካከል የተካሄደውን ጦርነት ለማቆም ላደረጉት ጥረት አብይ አህመድ በ2019 የሰላም የኖቤል ሽልማት ተሸለሙ። እ.ኤ.አ. በኤፕሪል 2018 ስልጣን ከያዙ በኋላ፣ የ46 አመቱ አብይ የፖለቲካ እስረኞችን አስፈትቷል፣ ለ2019 ፍትሃዊ ምርጫ እንደሚደረግ ቃል ገብቷል እና አጠቃላይ የኢኮኖሚ ማሻሻያዎችን አስታውቋል። ከጁን 6 2019 ጀምሮ ሁሉም ቀደም ሲል ሳንሱር የተደረገባቸው ድረገጾች እንደገና ተደራሽ እንዲሆኑ ተደርገዋል፣ ከ13,000 በላይ የፖለቲካ እስረኞች ተለቀቁ እና በመቶዎች የሚቆጠሩ የአስተዳደር ሰራተኞች እንደ ማሻሻያው አካል ተባረዋል።","answer":"አዲሱ ጠቅላይ ሚኒስትር አብይ አህመድ በ2018 ኤርትራን የጎበኙ ሲሆን በ2019 የኖቤል የሰላም ሽልማት ተሸላሚ ሆነዋል። የፖለቲካ እስረኞችን አሰናብቷል፣ ፍትሃዊ ምርጫ እንደሚደረግ ቃል ገብቷል፣ እንዲሁም የሳንሱር ድረ-ገፆች ዳግም መከፈታቸውንና የአስተዳደር ሰራተኞችን ማባረርን ጨምሮ ኢኮኖሚያዊ ተሃድሶ እንደሚካሄድ አስታውቋል።"},{"question":"ما هي عملة البحرين؟","answer":"عملة البحرين هي الدينار البحريني."},{"question":"Quelle sonts trois raisons du colonialisme ?","answer":"- des raisons économiques : années 1870, un sentiment de crise émerge en Europe. Un enjeu important apparait : la recherche de nouveaux marchés ; la colonisation part d'une volonté de trouver de nouveau débouché. La concurrence et féroce : la plupart du temps on occupe un territoire pour éviter qu'une autre s'en empare.- des raisons politiques : au XIXe siècle, l'Europe ne connait pas de grande guerre, mais est parcourue de nombreuses tensions bilatérales, des révolutions et des conflits. Ces rivalités sont permanentes. Mais progressivement, il apparait qu'une guerre sera inévitable, dans cette optiques les Empires doivent s'assurer des bases-arrières.- des raisons idéologiques : les Européens ont la conviction de représenter la civilisation, à cela s'ajoute un dimension missionnaire et chrétienne."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"adat periuk berkerak, adat lesung berdedak\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah sekiranya ands mahu hidup senang, ands perlu sanggup bersusah-payah"},{"question":"以下の段落に関連する内容を記入しなさい： 兵庫県の加古川市は去年11月、誰でも弾いていいピアノを加古川駅に置きました。みんなに音楽を楽しんでもらうためです。","answer":"しかし、ルールを守らないで、大きな声で歌いながら弾く人や、弾いてもいい時間のあとも弾く人などがいたため、迷惑だという意見がありました。市はルールを守るように言いましたが、よくなりませんでした。このため、市はこのピアノを4月30日までで終わりにして、片づけることにしました。 30日は、たくさんの人がピアノを弾いて、駅に来た人たちが楽しんでいました。大阪から来た人は「残念ですが、違う場所でまたピアノを弾くことができるようにしてほしいです」と話しました。 市は、ピアノを置く場所を変えたり、期間を決めて置いたりすることを考えています。"},{"question":"Akẹkọọ to ni arun Korona kọ idanwo nibudo iyasọta ni Kwara","answer":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Kwara ti ṣeto bi akẹkọọ-binrin ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlogun kan to ni arun Korona yoo ṣe maa kọ idanwo aṣekagba, WAEC, to bẹrẹ lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, nibudo iyasọtọ to ti n gbatọju.Akọwe iroyin gomina to tun jẹ alukoro igbimọ amuṣẹya to n mojuto ọrọ Covid-19, Rafiu Ajakaye, lo kede ọrọ naa ninu atẹjade kan l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii.Akẹkọọ ọhun ti wọn forukọ bo laṣiiri lo jokoo kọ idanwo ẹkọ nipa Ọgbin (Agricultural Science), labẹ idari oṣiṣẹ ajọ to n ṣedanwo naa.Adari ikọ to n gbogun ti arun Korona ni Kwara, Dokita Kudirat Ọladeji-Lambẹ ṣalaye pe bo tilẹ jẹ pe akẹkọọ naa ni arun ọhun lara, sibẹ, o ṣi le ṣe idanwo naa lai si idiwọ kankan.O ni ọsẹ meji ni yoo lo nibudo naa tawọn yoo fi yẹ ẹ wo daadaa lati ri i pe kinni ọhun ko gbodi lara rẹ.Lambẹ ni ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, ni awọn gbe e wa sibudo iyasọtọ naa. O ni ko lanfaani lati kọ idanwo ọjọ naa, ṣugbọn awọn ti ba ajọ WAEC sọ ọ bi wọn ṣe maa ṣe e."},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: Ostiriya tana da iyaka kuma tana iyaka da kasashe takwas. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"Andininy voalohany: Nilaza i Lisa fa mpihinana zava-maniry izy.Andininy faharoa: Nanafatra steak tao amin'ny trano fisakafoanana i Lisa.Mifanaraka ve ireo fehezanteny roa ireo?","answer":"Tsia, mifanohitra izy ireo."},{"question":"Terjemahno pecahan crito Bahasa Inggris ing ngisor iki dadi teks Basa Jawa.I see a grey and brown mouse hiding in a pink house.Terjemahane ing Basa Jawa yaiku:","answer":"Aku weruh ana tikus klawu-coklat lagi ndhelik ing omah werna jambon."},{"question":"این سوال به چه معناست: \\"در مبحث زمین شناسی، این مفهوم به یکی یا همه بخش های اصلی اقیانوس جهانی سیاره اشاره دارد. آنها به ترتیب عمق عبارتند از: اقیانوس آرام، اقیانوس اطلس، هند، جنوب (آنتارکتیک) و اقیانوس های قطب شمال\\"؟ موضوعش در مورد اقيانوس هست","answer":"این سوال میخواهد بداند که واژه تخصصی ای که به اقیانوس های متصل در زمین اشاره میکند چیست."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"adat balai\\"?","answer":"Maksud \\"adat balai\\" ialah adat dalam istana raja."},{"question":"Mo mọ Tinubu daadaa, oun lo le ṣe aarẹ lọdun 2023- Alagba Faṣọranti","answer":"Olori ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre to ṣẹṣẹ gbe kinni ọhun silẹ fun Oloye Ayọ Adebanjọ, Alagba Reuben Faṣọranti, ti sọ pe oun fara mọ ọn daadaa pe ki Aṣiwaju Bọla Tinubu, di aarẹ Naijiria lọdun 2023, nitori ẹni toun mọ daadaa ti yoo si ṣe ohun ti araalu n fẹ ni bo ba de ipo naa.Ikọ to n polongo ibo fun Tinubu, eyi ti wọn n pe ni ‘South West Agenda For Asiwaju Bola Ahmed Tinubu’(SWAGA 23) lo ṣabẹwo sile Alagba Faṣọranti niluu Akurẹ, ti wọn waa beere fun atilẹyin baba naa.Ninu ọrọ ti baba ẹni ọdun marundinlọgọrun-un(95) naa sọ fun wọn lo ti fi atilẹyin rẹ han fun Tinubu, baba naa sọ pe,’’Tinubu kunju oṣuwọn lati ṣakoso Naijiria, nitori oriṣiiriṣii nnkan lo ti gbe ṣe lorilẹ-ede yii. Mo fọwọ si i, mo si tun gba a ladura pe ki Ọlọrun jẹ ko ṣee ṣe fun un. Nitori to ba depo naa tan, gbogbo ohun ti a fẹ ni yoo ṣe. Tinubu ko ni i ja awọn ọmọ Naijiria kulẹ, mo mọ ọn daadaa’’Baba fi kun un pe ọna kan ṣoṣo ti ipo aarẹ ko fi ni i bọ mọ Yoruba lọwọ lọdun 2023 ni ki gbogbo eeyan gbaruku ti Tinubu, o ni didun lọsan yoo so bi gbogbo ilu ba ṣatilẹyin fun un.Ṣugbọn latigba ti baba ti sọrọ yii lawọn eeyan ti n bu ẹnu atẹ lu olori ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre tẹlẹ naa, oriṣiiriṣii ọrọ lo si n ja ran-in lori ayelujara bayii si baba naa, ti wọn n sọ pe ojo ogbo ti n da ọkunrin yii laamu, wọn ni ko daju pe o mọ ohun to n sọ.Ọpọ eeyan lo n sọ pe ṣe baba ti gbagbe iku ọmọ rẹ tawọn Fulani pa lọdun 2019, Funkẹ Ọlakunrin, ni. Wọn ni ṣe ko ranti ọrọ ti Tinubu sọ nigba to lọọ ki baba naa nile lori iku Funkẹ, to ni ki i ṣe Fulani lo pa obinrin naa, abi maaluu wo lawọn to n sọ bẹẹ ri lọwọ awọn to pa Funkẹ.Awọn mi-in tilẹ sọ pe afẹnifẹbi ni baba, o ti kuro ninu ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre. Bẹẹ lawọn mi-in sọ pe owo ti wọn gbe wa fun baba arugbo naa lo n ṣiṣẹ rẹ. Wọn ni nigba tawọn SWAGA 23 ko ti i wa sile rẹ, njẹ o polongo atilẹyin fun Tinubu bi, wọn ni owo ti wọn waa fi di Baba Faṣọranti lẹnu lo jẹ ko maa sọ ohun ti ko tọ sẹnu ẹni ti ọjọ ti dalẹ fun bii eyi.Yatọ si Baba Faṣọranti, awọn ọba meji to tun fi atilẹyin wọn han fun Bọla Tinubu l’Ondo ni, Ọsẹmawe, Ọba Victor Kiladejọ, ati Abodi Ikalẹ, Ọba George Faduyile. Wọn ni ki gbogbo ọmọ Yoruba ti Jagaban lẹyin, nitori oun ni ipo aṣiwaju Naijiria tọ si."},{"question":"Ułóż pytanie do podanej odpowiedzi: Stolicą Australii jest Canberra.","answer":"Oto pytanie do powyższej odpowiedzi: Jakie miasto jest stolicą Australii?"},{"question":"“పల్లెటూరి జీవితం ఎంతో మనోహరమైంది.” దీనిపై మీ అభిప్రాయాలు తెల్పండి.","answer":"పల్లెటూరి జీవితం చాలా బాగుంటుంది. పక్షుల కిలకిలలతో మెలుకువ వస్తుంది. ఎటుచూసినా పచ్చని చెట్లు, వరి పొలాలు కన్పిస్తాయి. పిల్ల కాలువలలో చేపల మిలమిలలూ, ఉదయకాలపు లేత ఎండలో నీటి తళతళలూ, లేగదూడల గంతులు, పొలాలకు వెళ్ళే వారి హడావుడి, పిల్లల అల్లరి, నీటి బిందెలతో స్త్రీలు, చక్కటి వాతావరణం. కలుషితం కాని వాతావరణం. కల్మషం తెలియని మనుషుల పలకరింపులతో పల్లెటూరి జీవితం చక్కగా ఉంటుంది. ఎవరిని పలకరించినా నవ్వుతూ మాట్లాడతారు. చక్కటి కథలు చెబుతారు."},{"question":"Jelaskan maksud peribahasa, \\"Bagai buluh ditarik songsang\\"?","answer":"Menunjukkan kesukaran mempengaruhi seseorang atau sesuatu kumpulan mengikut seperti yang dikehendaki."},{"question":"ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ਤ ਲਹਿਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਨੋਟ ਲਿਖੋ ।","answer":"ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ਤ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਯੁੱਧ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਮੁਸਲਮਾਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਬ੍ਰਿਟਿਸ਼ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਚਲਾਇਆ। ਯੁੱਧ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੁਰਕੀ ਦੀ ਹਾਰ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਜੇਤੂ ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਨੇ ਤੁਰਕੀ ਸਾਮਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਤੋੜ-ਭੰਨ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਮੁਸਲਿਮ ਜਨਤਾ ਭੜਕ ਉੱਠੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਤੁਰਕੀ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਭਾਵਨਾਵਾਂ ਜੁੜੀਆਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਸਨ । ਇਸੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਮੁਸਲਮਾਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ਤ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਪਰ ਇਹ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਵਾਦੀ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਦਾ ਇਕ ਅੰਗ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿਚ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੇ ਵੀ ਕਈ ਨੇਤਾ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਏ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿਚ ਫੈਲਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ।"},{"question":"મેડાગાસ્કરમાં વિશાળ મેદાનોથી માંડીને કઠોર પર્વતો સુધી ઘણાં વિવિધ લેન્ડસ્કેપ્સ છે. મેડાગાસ્કરના પ્રખ્યાત રાષ્ટ્રીય ઉદ્યાનનું નામ શું છે, જે તેની અનન્ય ખડકોની રચના અને બાઓબાબ વૃક્ષોના રસ્તાઓ માટે જાણીતું છે?","answer":"પાર્ક નેશનલ ડી ઇસાલો એ મેડાગાસ્કરનું રાષ્ટ્રીય ઉદ્યાન છે જે તેની અનોખી ખડક રચનાઓ અને બાઓબાબ વૃક્ષોના રસ્તાઓ માટે જાણીતું છે."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Under VM i Falun 2015 var Kallas första distans skiathlon där hon bildade en tätgrupp med Therese Johaug och Astrid Jacobsen som drog ifrån resten av fältet. När de tre åkte upp för mördarbacken för sista gången gjorde Therese Johaug guldrycket och Charlotte Kalla slutade på tredjeplats. På 10 km fristil under VM i Falun 2015 vann Kalla guldet överlägset med 41 sekunder före tvåan Jessie Diggins. Kalla tog också under mästerskapet silver på stafetten där hon gjorde en mycket bra andrasträcka för Sverige och körde i kapp Norge. Hon fick köra andrasträckan på grund av att de klassiska banorna var jobbigare än skatebanorna och att Norge hade sitt starkaste kort där genom Therese Johaug. Kalla avslutade VM i Falun 2015","answer":"med att ta ett brons på 30 km klassisk stil där hon såg ut att tappa kampen om medaljerna men kom tillbaka och tog brons efter Therese Johaug och Marit Björgen. Charlotte Kalla kammade totalt hem fyra medaljer från hemma-VM."},{"question":"Ndi dziko liti lomwe limadziwika ndi kabichi?","answer":"Pafupifupi theka la matani oposa 71 miliyoni omwe amalima padziko lonse lapansi amakololedwa ku China, kenako India, Russia, South Korea ndi Ukraine. Indonesia, Japan, Poland, Uzbekistan ndi United States of America amamaliza 10 apamwamba. Makabichi onse amabzalidwa m'maiko opitilira 150 padziko lonse lapansi."},{"question":" Стив Джобс жөнүндө жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Стив ДжобсДагы бир жогорку билими жок, компьютер дүйнөсүнүн генийи — Стив Джобс. Apple’дин негиздөөчүсү Америкадагы эң кымбат жана беделдүү окуу жайлардын бири Портленддеги Рид-колледжге тапшырган. Бирок сабакка келгендин ордуна чыгыш руханий дүйнөсүн изилдеп, өзүнүн комьютердик компаниясы жөнүндө кыялданууну жакшы көрчү. 4 жылдан соң Стив өз кыялдарын ишке ашырат."},{"question":"கோடிட்ட இடத்தை நிரப்புக.                                                                                                                                                 எங்கள் தமிழ் மொழி _________ போன்ற மொழியாகும். ","answer":"விடை : தேன்"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండి:లోహక్షయం అంటే ఏమిటి? ఒక ఉదాహరణ ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"లోహక్షయం :ఒక లోహం, దాని చుట్టూ ఉన్న పరిసరాలతో చర్య జరపడం వల్ల తుప్పు పట్టడం, కాంతి విహీనం కావడం (వెండి వస్తువులు), రాగి వంటి వాటిపై పచ్చని పొర ఏర్పడటం వంటి మార్పులకు లోను కావడాన్ని లోహక్షయం అంటారు.ఉదా : ఐరన్, తన ఆక్సైడ్ (Fe2O3-హెమటైట్) రూపంలోకి, కాపర్, తన కార్బనేట్ (మోలకైట్) రూపంలోకి మరియు సిల్వర్, తన సల్ఫైట్ (AgS సిల్వర్ గ్లాన్స్) రూపంలోకి మారిపోవడానికి ప్రయత్నిస్తాయి.ఎనోడ్ వద్ద లోహం విద్రవణం చెందడాన్ని విద్యుత్ రసాయన లోహక్షయం అంటారు."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਸਫਲ ਹੈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਪਾਵੈ ਥਾਇ ॥ਜਿਸੁ ਹਰਿ ਭਾਵੈ ਤਿਸੁ ਗੁਰੁ ਮਿਲੈ ਸੋ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਹਰਿ ਪਾਈਐ ਹਰਿ ਪਾਰਿ ਲਘਾਇ ॥ਮਨਹਠਿ ਕਿਨੈ ਨ ਪਾਇਓ ਪੁਛਹੁ ਵੇਦਾ ਜਾਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਸੋ ਕਰੇ ਜਿਸੁ ਲਏ ਹਰਿ ਲਾਇ ॥੧੦॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 86 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਬੰਦਗੀ (ਉਂਞ ਤਾਂ ਹਰ ਇਕ ਲਈ ਹੀ) ਸਫਲ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਨੂੰ ਸਫਲਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਹੈ, ਪਰ) ਕਬੂਲ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਹੰੁਦੀ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਪੂਰਨ ਸਫਲਤਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੰੁਦੀ ਹੈ) ਜੋ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ (ਹੀ) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤਰੁੱਠਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹੋ ਹੀ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ(ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਾਗਰ ਤੋਂ ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਹੈ ਵੇਦ (ਆਦਿਕ ਧਾਰਮਕ ਪੁਸਤਕਾਂ) ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਪੁੱਛ ਵੇਖੋ (ਭਾਵ, ਪੁਰਾਤਨ ਧਰਮ-ਪੁਸਤਕ ਭੀ ਇਹੀ ਗੱਲ ਦੱਸਦੇ ਹਨ) ਕਿ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਹਠ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੇ ਰੱਬ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭਾ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ)ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਹਰੀ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਉਹੀ ਜੀਵ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ (ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਾ ਕੇ) ਹਰੀ ਆਪਿ ਸੇਵਾ ਵਿਚ ਲਾਏ ।੧੦।\\""},{"question":"Ndiani akanyora Nyika Itsva Yakashinga (zita rizere)?","answer":"Bhuku rinokurudzira kufunga \\"Nyika Itsva Yakashinga\\" rakanyorwa naAldous Huxley. Kuongorora kwake kwemadingindira edystopian uye kutsoropodza kwemagariro kwakanzwika nevaverengi kwezvizvarwa."},{"question":"Mẹ tôi là giáo viên tiểu học, năm nay 56 tuổi và đến hết tháng 9 này sẽ về hưu. Nay, mẹ tôi muốn tham gia một hợp đồng bảo hiểm nhân thọ, với hai mục đích là được chi trả khi ốm đau đi khám, nằm viện và có khoản gọi là để lại thêm cho con cái sau này.Mẹ cũng từng tham gia hợp đồng bảo hiểm nhân thọ cho tôi từ khi còn bé, cách đây ba năm vừa nhận lại toàn bộ tiền khi hết hợp đồng.Anh em tôi thực ra không nghĩ đến chuyện tiền nong đền bù sau nay, nhưng thấy mẹ muốn mua trong khi lại chưa hiểu rõ về bảo hiểm nhân thọ. Mẹ cứ nghĩ mua bảo hiểm nhân thọ là sẽ được chi trả tiền khi đi khám, không may qua đời thì sẽ nhận được tiền đền bù.Nhưng tuổi mẹ tôi cũng nhiều, hiện tại lại có bệnh tiểu đường loại 2, thoái hoá đốt sống cổ, đau dạ dày. Nhờ anh/chị tư vấn với tuổi tác và các bệnh nền như vậy, liệu mẹ tôi có nên tham gia bảo hiểm nữa không? Nếu có thì nên tham gia loại bảo hiểm nào cho phù hợp?","answer":"Ở độ tuổi nào chúng ta cũng nên tham gia bảo hiểm nhân thọ, bởi mục đích của bảo hiểm nhân thọ là để bảo vệ tài chính và mang lại sự an tâm trước biến cố khó lường về sức khỏe và sinh mạng. Tuy nhiên, hãng bảo hiểm thường khuyến khích khách hàng tham gia bảo hiểm càng sớm càng tốt, vì mua bảo hiểm khi còn trẻ có mức phí thấp hơn, bảo vệ được nhiều rủi ro bệnh tật hơn, chủ động tài chính lâu dài...Với trường hợp của mẹ bạn (đã có một số bệnh nền), công ty bảo hiểm sẽ thẩm định dựa vào tiền sử bệnh, quá trình điều trị và tình trạng sức khỏe để đưa ra các quyết định bảo hiểm. Bạn cần nắm rõ nguyên tắc bảo hiểm để bảo vệ tài chính trước những rủi ro không lường trước được và những rủi ro có sẵn sẽ được các công ty bảo hiểm thẩm định kỹ lưỡng.Nếu chấp nhận bảo hiểm, hãng sẽ loại trừ không chi trả bảo hiểm cho các bệnh có sẵn và chỉ bảo vệ trước những bệnh chưa phát sinh. Công ty bảo hiểm sẽ thu phí bảo hiểm phụ trội cho các bệnh nền có sẵn, do đó phí đóng bảo hiểm có thể cao hơn so với những hợp đồng bảo hiểm cho người có sức khỏe đạt chuẩn ở cùng độ tuổi. Tuỳ vào từng đơn vị và sức khoẻ thực tế của mẹ bạn, hãng bảo hiểm có thể từ chối hồ sơ yêu cầu tham gia bảo hiểm nếu các rủi ro nằm ngoài phạm vi có thể chấp nhận của họ. Nguyên tắc này áp dụng cho cả bảo hiểm nhân thọ và phi nhân thọ.Với trường hợp của mẹ bạn, nếu chỉ có nhu cầu có các gói bảo hiểm giúp trang trải chi phí khi ốm đau bệnh tật, có thể lựa chọn những dòng sản phẩm bảo hiểm sức khỏe và chi phí y tế (phi nhân thọ). Còn nếu mẹ bạn muốn nhận được quyền lợi bảo vệ tài chính trước rủi ro và tích luỹ, gia tăng tài sản, có thể tham gia các gói bảo hiểm liên kết đầu tư (Bảo hiểm liên kết chung, Bảo hiểm liên kết đơn vị), cộng thêm các sản phẩm bảo hiểm bổ trợ sức khỏe.Tôi có hai lời khuyên dành cho mẹ bạn khi tham gia bảo hiểm:Thứ nhất, bạn nên tìm đến các công ty bảo hiểm uy tín, và trao đổi chính xác nhu cầu, khả năng tài chính với tư vấn viên để được tư vấn giải pháp phù hợp. Dù lựa chọn tham gia sản phẩm bảo hiểm nào, bạn cũng cần tư vấn viên tư vấn rõ ràng các điều kiện và điều khoản trong hợp đồng, hiểu rõ quyền lợi và nghĩa vụ của mình để đảm bảo tối ưu quyền lợi của mình.Thứ hai, rất quan trọng và luôn luôn cần lưu ý, là mẹ bạn cần phải kê khai thông tin sức khỏe chính xác và trung thực. Đây chính là cơ sở để doanh nghiệp bảo hiểm thẩm định khách hàng có đủ điều kiện tham gia bảo hiểm nhân thọ hay không. Không nên chỉ vì muốn nhanh chóng có hợp đồng bảo hiểm mà bỏ qua các thông tin kê khai cần thiết, các điều khoản loại trừ bảo hiểm... để tránh các rắc rối không mong muốn khi làm thủ tục yêu cầu chi trả quyền lợi bảo hiểm sau này."},{"question":"Ratidza emoji inomiririra zororo remugungwa rinopisa.","answer":"🏖️🌴🌊"},{"question":" Sheeg Ninkii sheegtey nabi nimada xiligii khilaafada abuubakar","answer":" Waxa La Oran Jiray Musaylamatul Kadaab."},{"question":"问题：地球上最高的瀑布是哪个","answer":"答案：安赫尔瀑布（Angel Falls）"},{"question":"Awọn eeyan ya bo ibi tijọba apapọ ko ounjẹ pamọ si ni Irọjo, n’Ileṣa","answer":"Gbogbo ounjẹ gbigbẹ tijọba apapọ ko pamọ si agbegbe Ọṣun Ankara, ni Irojo, niluu Ileṣa, lawọn araalu tinu n bi ti ko tan bayii.Silo yii ni wọn kọ lasiko iṣejọba Aarẹ Goodluck Jonathan. O wa kaakiri orileede yii. Ṣe nijọba apapọ maa n ko ounjẹ  sibẹ lasiko ojo, to ba ti di asiko ẹẹrun ni wọn maa n ta a.Nigba to di pe awọn eeyan agbegbe Ẹdẹ ri ounjẹ Corvid 19 tijọba ko pamọ siluu wọn lonikaluku naa bẹrẹ si i wa gbogbo ibi ti ounjẹ ijọba le wa niluu tiwọn naa.Abẹnugan ile-igbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ Ọṣun, Honarebu Timothy Owoẹyẹ, to wa lati agbegbe naa fidi iṣẹlẹ ọhun mulẹ."},{"question":"د اسلام شپږ ارکان کوم دي؟","answer":"مسلمانان شپږ بنسټيزه ارکانونو باندې عقيده لري:1. د الله(ج) په وحدانيت باندې ايمان راوړل او يواځی الله(ج) ته عبادت او اطاعت کول او د هغه نه مرسته غوښتل توحيد.2. د الله(ج) په پيغمبرانو باندې ايمان راوړل (انبيا‌ء) چې ټول پېغمبران (رسول) د الله(ج) له خوا رالېږل شوي. (د اسلام پېغمبران وگورۍ.)3. په اسماني کتابونو عقيده(کتب):په ابراهيمي صحيفو (ابراهيم(ع) باندې نازل شوې صحيفې)په تورات باندې ايمان راوړل چې همدا کتاب پر موسی(ع) باندې نازل شوی.په زبور باندې ايمان راوړل چې همدا کتاب پر داود(ع) باندې نازل شوی.په انجيل باندې ايمان راوړل چې همدا کتاب پر عيسی(ع) باندې نازل شوی.په قرآن باندې ايمان راوړل چې همدا کتاب پر محمد(ص) باندې نازل شوی.4. د الله(ج) په پرښتو باندې.(ملايکه).5. په قيامت او وروسته د مرگ نه د بيا ژوندي کېدلو عقيده (قيامة) (په جنت او دوزخ عقيده). (يادونه: کله ناکله دغه وروستۍ موضوع باندې ځانگړی بحث کېږی, او په همدې توگه د عقيدې ارکان اوو ته رسېږي.)6. په قسمت عقيده(تقدير)."},{"question":"Kodi ku Malawi kuli mafuko angati?","answer":"Mitundu ikuluikulu khumi imagwirizanitsidwa ndi dziko la Malawi lamakono—A Chewa, Nyanja, Lomwe, Yao, Tumbuka, Sena, Tonga, Ngoni, Ngonde, ndi Lambya/Nyiha. Zilankhulo zonse za mu Afirika ndi zilankhulo za Bantu. Kuchokera mu 1968 mpaka 1994, Chichewa chinali chinenero chokha cha dziko; tsopano ndi chimodzi mwa zilankhulo zambiri zomwe zimagwiritsidwa ntchito posindikiza ndi kuulutsa zoulutsira mawu ndipo zimalankhulidwa ndi anthu ambiri. Mu 1996 ndondomeko ya boma inasonyeza kuti maphunziro a m’giredi 1–4 adzaperekedwa m’chinenero cha makolo kapena chinenero cha kwawo; kuyambira giredi 5, njira yophunzitsira ingakhale Chingelezi, chomwe, ngakhale chinkamveka ndi anthu ochepera pa gawo limodzi mwa magawo asanu a anthu omwe adalandira ufulu wodzilamulira mu 1964, akupitilizabe kugwiritsidwa ntchito kwambiri m'mabizinesi, utsogoleri ndi milandu, maphunziro apamwamba, ndi kwina kulikonse. Zinenero zina zazikulu ndi Chilomwe, Chiyao, ndi Chitumbuka."},{"question":"هل يمكنك اخباري عن تاريخ منظمة الصحة العالمية؟","answer":"بالتأكيد. من المسائل التي ناقشها الدبلوماسيون، عندما اجتمعوا لتشكيل الأمم المتحدة في عام 1945، إنشاء منظمة صحية عالمية.ودخل دستور المنظمة حيّز النفاذ في 7 نيسان/أبريل 1948- وهو التاريخ الذي أصبح يُعرف بيوم الصحة العالمي ويُحتفل به كل عام."},{"question":"كم خلية دم حمراء يستطيع أنتاجها الجسم في اليوم الواحد ؟","answer":"200 مليون خلية"},{"question":"次の段落を完成させなさい： 耳に障害がある人たちのスポーツの世界大会「デフリンピック」が、東京都で2025年にあります。印刷の会社などは、話したことばを自動で字にして、画面に出す技術を作りました。耳に障害がある人たちの空手の大会で、この技術を使ってみる実験がありました。","answer":"会場の受付に画面とタブレットが置いてあります。話したことばは字になって見えて、耳に障害がある人に伝えることができました。 利用した男性は「手話ができない人とも会話ができてよかったです。顔を見ながら会話ができて、気持ちもわかりました。通訳の人がいない場所などに置いてほしいです」と話していました。 東京都は、この技術をデフリンピックで使うことができるようにしたいと考えています。"},{"question":"செந்தமிழ் இச்சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது ………………………1)செம்மை + தமிழ்2)செந் + தமிழ்3)செ + தமிழ்4)செம் + தமிழ்","answer":"விடை : செந்தமிழ் இச்சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது …………செம்மை + தமிழ்"},{"question":"गौतम बुद्धांनी दिलेल्या वचनांचा संग्रह कोणत्या ग्रंथात आहे?","answer":"गौतम बुद्धांनी दिलेल्या वचनांचा संग्रह धम्मपद ग्रंथात आहे."},{"question":"جمله 1: \`\` Almost a Memory Now'یوه سندره ده چې د وان سټیفنسن ، ډیو روبینز ، او ډیل اولیور لخوا لیکل شوې ، د امریکایی هیواد میوزیک بینډ بلیک هوک لخوا ثبت شوې. دوهمه جمله: \`\` Almost a Memory Now'د امریکا د هیواد د موسیقۍ ډلې بلیک هاک لخوا ثبت شوی د وان سټیفنسن ، ډیو روبینز او ډیل اولیور لخوا سندره ده. پوښتنه: ایا لومړۍ او دویمه جمله یو شان معنی لري؟ هو یا نه؟","answer":"هو"},{"question":"வினா : ஐஸ்கிரீம் உருகுதல் எத்தகைய மாற்றத்திற்கு உதாரணம் ","answer":"விடை : இயற்பியல் மாற்றம்"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Saya tebal atau nipis, bercorak atau tidak, panjang atau pendek terpulang pada kehendak anda, siapakah saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah kain. Kain mempunyai pelbagai corak dan saiz."},{"question":"靴の上から痒い所を掻く、という意味の、歯がゆさやもどかしさをたとえた四字熟語は何でしょう？","answer":"隔靴掻痒（かっかそうよう）です。"},{"question":"為什麼胃不會消化自己？　　","answer":"胃能夠分泌胃酸和胃蛋白酶，消化肉類食物中的蛋白質，把它變成人體的營養物質。而胃本身也是由蛋白質組成的，為什麼胃本身不被消化呢？　　科學家們發現：胃還能分泌一種黏稠的、膠凍狀的黏液物質，覆蓋在胃的內表面， 防止胃酸和胃蛋白酶的腐蝕。此外，胃內表面黏膜的上皮細胞，是一層緊密排列的特殊結構， 從而形成了一道生理屏障。 這種屏障可以阻止胃酸侵入。 只要黏液膜和胃黏膜生理屏障這兩道“防線”健全，就能抵禦胃自身的分解。"},{"question":"السّؤال: من هو أول صحابيٍّ غزا في سبيل الله تعالى؟","answer":"الجواب: حمزة بن عبد المطلب رضي الله عنه."},{"question":"Oyetọla bura fawọn adajọ kootu ibilẹ ko-tẹ-mi-lọrun meji l’Ọṣun","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ọṣun, Alhaji Gboyega Oyetọla, ti sọ pe ijọba oun ko ni i dawọ duro ninu gbogbo igbesẹ lati fi iṣẹ rọ awọn adajọ lọrun, ki wọn le maa ṣedajọ lai ṣegbe si ẹyin ẹnikankan.Lasiko to n ṣebura fun awọn oadajọ tuntun meji fun kootu ibilẹ ko-tẹ-mi-lọrun (Customary Court of Appeal), niluu Oṣogbo ni gomina sọrọ ọhun. O ni oun nigbagbọ ninu idajọ ododo ti ko ni eru ninu, ti ko si mu ẹru kankan lọwọ rara.Awọn mejeeji ọhun ni Adajọ Ayọade Aderẹmi Adeṣina ati Adajọ Ojo Ọlayinka Muibat. Bi wọn ṣe bura fun wọn tan ni gomina fi kọkọrọ ọkọ tuntun ti wọn yoo maa lo le wọn lọwọ.Oyetọla ṣapejuwe ẹka eto idajọ gẹgẹ bii ireti awọn araalu, bẹẹ lo ni ile-ẹjọ ko-tẹ-mi-lọrun yoo jẹ ibi isadi fun ẹnikẹni ti ko ba ri idajọ ododo gba lati kootu agbegbe ibilẹ kọọkan.Gomina waa ke si awọn adajọ mejeeji naa lati fi otitọ inu ṣiṣẹ, ki wọn ma ṣe ja awọn araalu ni tan-an-mọ, ki wọn si di opo iwa ọmọluabi ti gbogbo eeyan mọ ẹka eto idajọ ipinlẹ Ọṣun mọ.O ni wọn gbọdọ maa ranti atubọtan ninu gbogbo idajọ ti wọn ba n ṣe, ki wọn si lo aaye tuntun ti wọn bọ si naa fun idagbasoke ọmọniyan ati tipinlẹ Ọṣun.Bakan naa lo ṣeleri pe gbogbo atilẹyin to yẹ nijọba yoo fun awọn adajọ naa lati le ṣiṣẹ wọn lai foya rara.Ninu ọrọ idupẹ rẹ, Onidaajọ Ayọade Aderẹmi Adeṣina dupẹ fun anfaani ti gomina fun wọn lati sin ipinlẹ Ọṣun. O ṣeleri pe awọn yoo di opo idajọ ododo mu, bẹẹ ni awọn ko ni i bẹru ẹnikẹni lati huwa ti ko tọ."},{"question":"Vraag: Welke politicus volgde Boris Johnson op 6 september 2022 op als partijleider en premier? A. Sadiq Khan B. Liz Truss C. Rishi Sunak D. Jo Cox","answer":"Antwoord: B. Liz Truss"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa Asxaabigii Uu Rasuulka (NNKH) Ku Magacaabay Amiinka Umadaan?","answer":"Jawaab: Wuxu Ku Magacaabay Abii Cubeyda Caamir Bin Jaraax (RC)."},{"question":"சரியான விடையைத் தெரிவு செய்வோமா?ஏற்றம் என்ற சொல்லின் பொருள் ___________________சோர்வுதாழ்வுஉயர்வுஇறக்கம்","answer":"விடை : உயர்வு"},{"question":"હેરી પોટર જ્યાં ભણે છે તે શાળાનું નામ શું છે?","answer":"હોગવર્ટ્સ સ્કૂલ ઓફ વિચક્રાફ્ટ એન્ડ વિઝાર્ડરી"},{"question":"Nguwena wedwaOngaqhekeza ubutshe bedwala;Nguwena wedwaOngathuntubeza izinciji zameva;Wena wedwa – wena wedwa!Thumela uzamcolo, Baba,Amadwala amatiswe amanzisweUbulukhuni bukhunyuzwe;Kuqhekeke nezimfa ukuzeIzwele imvula yempilo;Aphile amatshe namadwala,Alimemeze igama longabonwayo!1. Phawula ngokuphumelela kwembongi ekusebenziseni isizura/isikhawu ","answer":"Imbongi iphumelele ukusebenzisa isizura/isikhawu ukukhombisa ukuzithoba/ukunxusa uNkulunkulu onguMenzi wezimangaliso njengoba kunguyeokwaziyo ukuguqula izinhliziyo ezilukhuni"},{"question":"Kodi anthu ambiri ku Malawi amakhala m'nyumba zotani?","answer":"Dziko la Malawi lili ndi nyumba zokwana 4.8 miliyoni pomwe 58.9% mwa nyumbazi ndi zachitukuko. Nyumbazi zimakhala ndi makoma a matope komanso madenga ofoleredwa ndi udzu ndipo mabanja a m’nyumbazi amakhala opanda chiyembekezo choti adzapeza nyumba yabwino."},{"question":"Ọpẹ o, wọn ti ri awọn agbẹ mẹrin ti wọn ji gbe ni Ikosu-Ekiti","answer":"Awọn ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ekiti ni Satide, ọjọ Abamẹta, ti kede pe awọn ti ṣe awari awọn agbẹ mẹrin ti awọn ajinigbe ji gbe ninu oko wọn niluu Ikosu-Ekiti, ijọba ibilẹ Mọna, nipinlẹ Ekiti.Bi ẹ ko ba gbagbe, ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ to kọja yii, ni awọn ajinigbe yii ti wọn dihamọra ṣadeede wọ inu oko awọn agbẹ wọnyi, ti wọn si ji wọn gbe lọ.Lẹyin ọjọ keji ti wọn ji awọn agbẹ wọnyi gbe ni wọn beere aadọta miliọnu lọwọ awọn mọlẹbi wọn, awọn agbẹ wọnyi, ti meji lara wọn jẹ dẹrẹba to n wa ọkọ katakata ti wọn fi n kọ ebe ti wọn n pe ni Agiriiki.Ọkan lara awọn mọlẹbi awọn agbẹ wọnyi to ba ALAROYE sọrọ ti ko fẹ ka darukọ oun ṣalaye pe mọlẹbi awọn agbẹ naa san miliọnu meji aabọnaira, ki wọn too tu wọn silẹ.O fi kun un pe ọkan lara awọn agbẹ naa ti eto ilera rẹ ko dan mọran lo jẹ ki wọn tete tu awọn agbẹ naa silẹ ati lati jẹ ki wọn gba iye owo to wa lọwọ wọn lẹyin idunaa-dura to waye laarin ọjọ marun-un gbako ti wọn ti ko awọn agbẹ wọnyi.O ṣalaye pe nirọlẹ ọjọ Satide ni awọn agbẹ naa ṣadeede fi ẹsẹ wọn rin waa ba awọn mọlẹbi wọn niluu Ikosun, nibi ti wọn ti n ṣe ipade lori bi wọn yoo ṣe ri owo ti wọn ti fun awon ajinigbe naa.Nigba ti ALAROYE beere bi wọn ṣe ri owo naa, ọkunrin yii sọ pe gbogbo awọn araalu ati awọn agbẹ lo da owo ti wọn lọọ fun awọn ajinigbe naa.Ṣugbọn ninu iwe kan ti Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinle Ekiti, Ọgbẹni Sunday Abutu, fi ṣọwọ si awọn oniroyin niluu Ado-Ekiti, o sọ pe gbogbo awọn agbẹ naa lo gba iyọnda lẹẹkan naa, ti wọn si ti darapọ mọ awọn mọlẹbi wọn.Abutu ṣalaye pe awọn ọlọpaa ati awọn Amọtẹkun pẹlu awọn ọdẹ ibilẹ to wa ni agbegbe naa ko ni isinmi latọjọ ti wọn ti ko awọn agbẹ wọnyi lọ.Alukoro ọlọpaa yii ni awọn agbofinro ti tun bẹrẹ igbesẹ to nipọn lagbegbe naa lati foju awọn ajinigbe to n da agbegbe naa laamu han, ati pe awọn ọlọpaa ṣe eleyii lati fopin si iṣẹlẹ ajinigbe to n waye lemọlemọ ni agbegbe naa lati nnkan bii oṣu meji sẹyin."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన మొదటి పేరా మరియు చివరి పేరా అనుసరించు మధ్య పేరా రాయండి:మొదటి పేరా:వేషాలు వేసేటప్పుడు ఎవరూ చూడకుండా జాగ్రత్తపడేవారు. తెరముందు ఆడేటప్పుడు మాత్రమే అందరూ చూడాలి అనుకునేవారు. అందుకోసం మాదిగ ఇండ్లల్లో వేషం ధరించేవారు. అలా కుదరనప్పుడు పందిరికి కొంత దూరంలోనో, అలాకూడా కుదరనప్పుడు చుట్టూ దుప్పటి కట్టుకోని రంగులు వేసుకునే వారు. రంగులు వేసుకున్నాక దుప్పటి కప్పుకొని భాగోతం ప్రదర్శించే పందిరి లోపలికి వచ్చేవారు. కళాకారులు ఎవరి వేషం (మేకప్) వాల్లే వేసుకునే వారు. ఎవరి అద్దం వాల్లదగ్గరే ఉండేది. మొకంకు రేవిడిని, లేకుంటే పసుపు పచ్చ పౌడరును వేసుకునే వారు. తెల్ల వెంట్రుకలు కావాలంటే మెంచు, లేదా అర్దూలం (జింక్ ఆక్సైడ్) వాడేవారు. ఆ అర్దూలం చెమటకు వెంటనే కరిగిపోయేది. చూసేవారు కంటికి ధారలుపడేటట్టు ఏడుస్తున్నారు అనుకునే వాళ్ళు. పాత రోజుల్లో ఏడుపు రావాలంటే కంట్లో వేలు పెట్టుకునే వారు లేదా నూనె చుక్కలు వేసుకునేవారు.చివరి పేరా:ప్రదర్శనకు వాడే వస్తువుల తయారీ : భుజకీర్తులు, కిరీటాలు మొదలైన ఆభరణాలను కళాకారులే తయారు చేసుకునేవారు. కొంత మంది మగవారికి మాత్రమే వాటిని తయారు చేయడం తెలుసు. “పొనికి కట్టెతో వీటిని తయారు చేస్తారు. దాన్ని బూరుగు కట్టె అనికూడా అంటారు. అగ్గిపుల్లలను కూడా ఈ కర్రతోనే తయారు చేస్తారు. కలిపెల్లిగుట్టలో ఈకర్ర చాలా లభించేది. పూర్వం పెద్దపెద్ద గుట్టలు, అడవులు ఉండేవి. దొనకంటి, కథారుపల్లె వైపు ఈ కలప లభించేది. అడవులను నరికిన కారణంగా ఇప్పుడు లభించడం లేదు.","answer":"కాని ఎల్లమ్మకు దుఃఖం పాట పాడగానే ఏడుపు వచ్చేది. భాగోతం చూసేవారు కూడా వెక్కివెక్కి ఏడ్చేవారు. వారు ఏడిస్తే చీరకొంగులు తడిసిపోయేవి. అంత కష్టపడి భాగోతాన్ని రసవంతంగా ప్రదర్శించేవారు. సత్యహరిశ్చంద్ర భాగోతం ఆడితే చూసేవారు కూడా ఏడ్చేవారు. అలా ప్రదర్శిస్తున్నప్పుడు ఒక్కోసారి ఆఊరి దొరలు “మేం ఇట్లనే కొంగులు పెట్టుకొని ఏడుద్దుమా? బంజేస్తరా? ఓ గంగారం!, ఓ ఎల్లవ్వా! ఇదేం ఏడుసుడు. ఏం కథ, దేవుడా… జర బందు జేయుండ్రి గదా!” అని చెప్పేవారు. అంత లీనమై ఆ ప్రదర్శనను చూసేలా ఆడేవారు. అంత కష్టపడి ప్రదర్శిస్తేనే ఆ కళకు అంతర్జాతీయ స్థాయిలో గుర్తింపు వచ్చింది."},{"question":" முகலாயப் பேரரசர் இரண்டாம் பகதூர் சாவின் சபையில் கங்காதர் நேரு காவல்துறைத் தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார். 1857 ஆம்","answer":"ஆண்டு இந்தியக் கிளர்ச்சியின் விளைவாக இந்தப் பதவி ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டதால், அந்த பதவியை வகித்த கடைசி நபர் இவர்தான். பின்னர் பிரிட்டிசு துருப்புக்கள் நகருக்குள் நுழையத் தொடங்கியபோது, இவர் தனது மனைவி ஜெயராணி மற்றும் தங்களது நான்கு குழந்தைகளுடன் (பன்சிதார் மற்றும் நந்தலால் என்ற மகன்களும் மற்றும் பத்ராணி மற்றும் மகாராணி என்ற இரு மகள்கள்) ஆகியோருடன் ஆக்ராவுக்கு தப்பி ஓடினார். இவரது கடைசி மகன் மோதிலால் இவரது மரணத்திற்கு மூன்று மாதங்களுக்குப் பிறகு பிறந்தார்."},{"question":"නව ගිලන් 60ක්","answer":"ලෝක බැංකු ණය ආධාර යටතේ ක්‍රියාත්මක වන, මෙරට කොවිඩ්-19 හදිසි ප්‍රතිචාර සහ සෞඛ්‍ය පද්ධති වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමේ ව්‍යාපෘතිය මඟින් සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය වෙත ලබාදුන් නව ගිලන් රථ 60ක් සෞඛ්‍ය ආයතන වෙත ලබාදී ඇත.මෙරට සෞඛ්‍ය පද්ධතියේ භෞතික සම්පත් ඉහළ නැංවීමේ අරමුණින් ලබාදුන් මෙම එක් ගිලන් රථයක වටිනාකම රුපියල් මිලියන 24.4ක් වන අතර, මුළු ගිලන් රථවල වටිනාකම රුපියල් මිලියන 1464 කි.ඒ අනුව රාගම පුනරුත්ථාපන හා තැලසීමියා ඒකකය, මහරගම අපේක්ෂා රෝහල, මුල්ලේරියාව රෝහල, රාගම ශික්ෂණ රෝහල, කළුබෝවිල රෝහල, ද සොයිසා කාන්තා රෝහල, මහනුවර ජාතික රෝහල, කොළඹ, කෑගල්ල, මහනුවර සහ රත්නපුර ප්‍රාදේශීය සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා අධ්‍යක්ෂ කාර්යාල වෙත ගිලන් රථ ලබාදීම සිදුව තිබේ.සබැඳි"},{"question":"Tsanangura kuti tsumo inotevera inorevei?Mbavariro inoda vane nharo.","answer":"Kuti ugone chinhu zvinoda shungu uye ruzivo."},{"question":"Täydennä seuraava kappale:  Lontoon olympialaisissa 2012 Donato sijoittui kolmanneksi tuloksella 17,48 m. Hän on karsiutunut olympialaisten loppukilpailusta Sydneyssä 2000, Ateenassa 2004, Pekingissä 2008 ja Rio de Janeirossa 2016. Daegun MM-kilpailuissa 2011 hän oli kymmenes. Hän on karsiutunut ulkoratojen MM-kilpailuissa","answer":"myös Osakassa 2007 ja Moskovassa 2013. Sisäratojen MM-kilpailuissa Donato on saavuttanut neljännen sijan Istanbulissa 2012. Euroopan mestaruuskilpailuissa hän on ollut lähellä mitalisijoja useita kertoja, mutta mitali on jäänyt haaveeksi. Urallaan Donato on tunnettu vahvana kilpailijana, mutta myös epätasaisuudestaan, mikä on näkynyt erityisesti suurissa arvokilpailuissa. "},{"question":"Mitä ovat mykobakteerit?","answer":"Mykobakteerilajeja tunnetaan noin 200 ja uusia lajeja löydetään jatkuvasti. Tärkein mykobakteerien aiheuttama infektiotauti on tuberkuloosi, jonka aiheuttaa M. tuberculosis -bakteeri lähisukulaisineen. Muiden mykobakteerien taudinaiheuttamiskyky vaihtelee. Ympäristön mykobakteereista tavallisimpia ovat M. avium, M. intracellulare, M. fortuitum ja M. lentiflavum, jotka ovat ehdollisia eli opportunisteja taudinaiheuttajia . Se tarkoittaa, että bakteerin taudinaiheuttamiskyky riippuu potilaan vastustuskyvystä.Tavallinen on myös M. gordonae, joka on yleinen ympäristömykobakteeri, mutta tuskin koskaan taudinaiheuttaja. M. leprae aiheuttaa lepran, jota voidaan todeta maahanmuuttajilla tai pitkään tropiikin maissa oleskelleilla.Mykobakterioosilla tarkoitetaan ympäristön mykobakteerien aiheuttamaa infektiota."},{"question":"Ọwọ tẹ awọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ mẹrinlelọgbọn l’Ọwọ, oriṣiiriṣii ọkọ ni wọn ba lọwọ wọn","answer":"Awọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ bii mẹrinlelọgbọn lọwọ ajọ to n gbogun ti iwa ibajẹ lorilẹ-ede yii, EFCC, tẹ niluu Ọwọ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ to pari yii.Ọgbẹni Wilson Uwujaren to jẹ Alukoro ajọ naa fidi rẹ mulẹ fawọn oniroyin pe awọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ ọhun ni wọn wa ninu ẹgbẹ onijibiti kan ti wọn n pe ni Erinlẹ.Orukọ awọn to ni awọn ṣi ri mu ninu awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ naa ni, Adesuyan Ayọọla, Oyesanmi Ṣọla, Adegbole Victor, Osagie Ekiende, Akinayọmide James, Okunade Jamilu,Ọmọtọṣọ Oluwaṣeyi, David Oluwatobi, Ahmed Rilwan, Saheed Ọdunayọ, Ọlrọrunfẹmi Emmanuel ati Obakpolor Tommy.Bakan naa ni awọn bii, Emmanuel Ibe, Temiloluwa Joshua, Victor Benjamin, Akinwale Oluwaṣeun, Ogunboye Dọtun, Adeniyi Fẹmi, Ọbademi Samson, Ọladunjoye Tẹniọla, Eze Raphael, Samson Fadugbagbe pẹlu Oguntimẹhin Bamidele.Awọn yooku ni, Moshood Kazeem, Oniye Damilare, Balogun Mayọwa, Ọbadapọ Wale, Ese Stephen, Atakili Pẹlumi, Adesumọ Fatai, Ọlalekan, Demi Temidayọ, Ọṣọrun Joseph ati Oluwafẹmi Damilọla Michael.Awọn ẹru bii ọpọlọpọ kọmputa agbeletan, ọkọ olowo nla, foonu loriṣiiriṣii, kaadi idanimọ atawọn nnkan mi-in to lodi sofin lo ni awọn ka mọ wọn lọwọ.O ni gbogbo wọn lawọn ti fi ṣọwọ si olu ileesẹ awọn to wa niluu Benin, nipinlẹ Edo, nibi ti wọn ti n fọrọ wa wọn lẹnu wo lọwọ."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: ബഹിരാകാശത്ത് ഒരു റോക്കറ്റിനെ മുന്നോട്ട് നയിക്കുന്ന ശക്തി എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ബഹിരാകാശത്ത് റോക്കറ്റിനെ മുന്നോട്ട് നയിക്കുന്ന ശക്തിയാണ് ന്യൂട്ടന്റെ മൂന്നാം ചലന നിയമം എന്നറിയപ്പെടുന്ന പ്രവർത്തനത്തിന്റെയും പ്രതികരണത്തിന്റെയും തത്വം. അതിവേഗ എക്‌സ്‌ഹോസ്റ്റ് വാതകങ്ങളെ ഒരു ദിശയിലേക്ക് പുറന്തള്ളുന്നതിലൂടെ, റോക്കറ്റിന് തുല്യവും വിപരീതവുമായ ശക്തി അനുഭവപ്പെടുന്നു, അത് മുന്നോട്ട് നയിക്കുന്നു. ഒരു റോക്കറ്റ് അതിന്റെ പ്രൊപ്പൽഷന്റെ വിപരീത ദിശയിൽ ഉയർന്ന ഊർജ്ജവും ആവേഗവും ഉള്ള വാതകങ്ങളെ പുറന്തള്ളിക്കൊണ്ട് മുന്നോട്ട് നീങ്ങുന്നു"},{"question":"Trong truyện \\"Thánh Gióng\\", Thánh Gióng bộc lộ những phẩm chất nào? Tên truyện Thánh Gióng gợi cho bạn suy nghĩ gì về thái độ của người kể đối với nhân vật Gióng?","answer":"- Trong truyện, Thánh Gióng bộc lộ những phẩm chất của một người anh hùng kiên cường, bất khuất chống giặc ngoại xâm.+ Nói với sứ giả những yêu cầu về tư trang để được đi đánh giặc của Thánh Gióng → Sẵn sàng chiến đấu dẹp giặc, hi sinh vì đất nước.+ Đến nơi có giặc để chặn đánh → Phẩm chất anh hùng chủ động trong tình thế, sức mạnh hơn người.+ Nhổ những cụm tre để thay thế roi sắt bị gãy → Khẳng định sức mạnh phi phàm của nhân vật, thể hiện sự thông minh, nhanh nhạy của anh hùng trong chiến đấu.+ Đánh giặc xong cưỡi ngựa bay lên trời → Phẩm chất trong sạch, khẳng định hành động chính nghĩa mà anh hùng vừa thực hiện.- Tên truyện Thánh Gióng gợi cho em suy nghĩ về thái độ của người kể đối với nhân vật Gióng: Sự ca ngợi, tôn vinh dành cho Thánh Gióng. Một trong “Tứ bất tử” (tên gọi chung của bốn vị thánh bất tử trong tín ngưỡng Việt Nam), tượng trưng cho tinh thần chống ngoại xâm và sức mạnh tuổi trẻ."},{"question":"Yaushe Pakistan ta sami 'yancin kai?","answer":"A ranar 14 Agusta na 1947."},{"question":"உலக போதை மருந்து எதிர்ப்பு நாள் எப்போது அனுசரிக்கப்படுகிறது?","answer":"உலக போதை மருந்து எதிர்ப்பு நாள் ஜூன் 26  அன்று  அனுசரிக்கப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"_________ tarian tradisional menarik perhatian para penonton.","answer":"Pertunjukan"},{"question":"Qual a resposta para a piada a seguir: O que os matemáticos disseram à pessoa que criou o zero?","answer":"Obrigado por nada."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Keputusan setiap pelajar ditunjukkan dalam kertas ini. Apa dia?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah kad laporan."},{"question":"“蜀犬吠日”的意思是？","answer":"少見多怪"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕੁ ॥ਕਾਮ ਕ੍ਰੋਧ ਅਰੁ ਲੋਭ ਮੋਹ ਬਿਨਸਿ ਜਾਇ ਅਹੰਮੇਵ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਸਰਣਾਗਤੀ ਕਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦੁ ਗੁਰਦੇਵ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 269 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਮੇਰਾ) ਕਾਮ, ਕੋ੍ਰਧ, ਲੋਭ, ਮੋਹ ਅਤੇ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਏ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰ ਤੇ ਆਖ)—ਹੇ ਗੁਰਦੇਵ! ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੈਂ ਸਰਣ ਆਇਆ ਹਾਂ, (ਮੇਰੇ ਉਤੇ) ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ।\\""},{"question":"ජනප්‍රවාදයේ සඳහන්වන අන්දමට , නමුණුකුල කන්දට අධිපති දෙවියන් කවුද ?","answer":"ජනප්‍රවාදයේ සඳහන්වන අන්දමට , නමුණුකුල කන්දට අධිපති දෙවියන් වන්නෙ ඉන්දක දෙවියන් ය."},{"question":"'सज्जन' या शब्दातील संधीप्रकार ओळखा.स्वरसंधीविसर्गसंधीजोडसंधीव्यंजनसंधी","answer":"व्यंजनसंधीशब्द- सज्जनसंधीविग्रह- सत् + जन = सज्जन (त् + ज = सज्जन )व्याख्या- संधी:जोडशब्द तयार करतांना पहिल्या शब्दातील शेवटचा वर्ण व दुसऱ्या शब्दातील पहिला वर्ण हे एकमेकांमध्ये मिसळतात व त्या दोन्हीबद्दल एक वर्ण तयार होतो. वर्णाच्या अशा एकत्र होण्याच्या प्रकाराला ‘संधी' असे म्हणतात.व्यंजनसंधी- जवळ जवळ येणाऱ्या या दोन वर्णांपैकी दोन्ही वर्ण व्यंजने असतील किंवा पहिला वर्ण व्यंजन व दुसरा वर्ण स्वर असेल तर त्याला व्यंजनसंधी असे म्हणतात.उदा. सत् + चित = सच्चित( त् + च = सच्चित )प्रस्तुत संधी मध्ये जवळ येणाऱ्या या दोन वर्णांपैकी दोन्ही वर्ण व्यंजने आहेत म्हणून या शब्दाचा संधी प्रकार ‘व्यंजन संधी’ हा आहे.स्वरसंधी- एकमेकांच्या शेजारी येणारे वर्ण हे जर स्वरांनी जोडले असतील तर त्यांना स्वरसंधी असे म्हणतात.स्वर + स्वर असे त्याचे स्वरूप असते.उदा. कवि = ईश्वर = कवीश्वर (इ + ई = ई)विसर्गसंधी- एकत्र येणाऱ्या वर्णातील पहिला विसर्ग व दुसरा वर्ण व्यंजन किंवा स्वर असेल तर तेव्हा त्यास विसर्ग संधी असे म्हणतात. विसर्ग + व्यंजन किंवा विसर्ग + स्वर असे त्याचे स्वरूप असते. उदा. तपः + धन = तपोधन"},{"question":"Бул абзацты улантып 2 сүйлөм кошуп жазып бер !\\"Ланкастер үйүнүн салттуу эмблемасы - Ланкастердин кызыл розасы, Йорк үйүнүн ак розасына окшош. Аттар Ланкастер жана Йорк королдук герцогдуктарынын \\"15-кылымдагы эмблемаларынан алынган. Бул Розалар согушу учурунда тактыга талашып-тартышып, жарандык согушка айланган.\\"","answer":"Сиз суранган абзацтын уландысы мындайча болушу мүмкүн:\\"...15-кылымдагы эмблемаларынан алынган. Бул Розалар согушу учурунда тактыга талашып-тартышып, жарандык согушка айланган.\\""},{"question":"manao  ahoana Ireo karazana gidro/varika misy eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Tsy mitsahatra mitombo ny karazan’ireo gidro/varika fantatra fa misy eto Madagasikara  hatramin’izay nisian’ny fikarohana momba azy ireny. Tamin’ny fanisana farany dia fantatra fa misy 5 ny fianakaviam-be ny varika eto Madagasikara ka mitsinjara ho 15 ny “genre” , 99 karazany ary  110 taxa.Betsaka ihany koa anefa ireo karazana gidro/varika lehibe izay mahatratra hatrany amin’ny 200 kg ny halehibeny no fantatra fa lany tamingana noho ny fahasimban’ny tontolo iainan’izy ireo."},{"question":"Taoreed Lágbájá ","answer":"Ọ̀gágun Major General Taoreed Abíọ́dún Lágbájá (ni wọ́n bí lọ́jọ́ kejìdínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù Èrèlé, ọdún 1968) jẹ́ Ọ̀gágun-àgbà tí ó gboyè Major General nínú iṣẹ́ ológun orílẹ̀ - èdè Nigeria. Òun ni Ọ̀gágun-àgbà yányán àwọn ológun Nigeria, Chief of Army Staff.Wọ́n bí Lágbájá ní ìlú Ìlobù ní ìjọba Ìbílẹ̀ Ìrẹ́pọ̀dùn ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ọ̀sun lọ́jọ́ kejìdínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kejì ọdún 1968. Ó lo ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ pẹ̀pẹ̀ ayé rẹ̀ ní ìlú Òṣogbo, níbi tí ó ti kàwé àkọ́bẹ̀rẹ̀ ní ilé-ìwé St Charles Grammar School àti Local Authority Teachers College.Wọ́n gbà á sí ilé-ìwé àwọn ológun Nigerian Defence Academy ọdún 1987. Wọ́n fún un lóye ológun (Second Lieutenant) lọ́jọ́ kọkàndínlógún oṣù kẹsàn-án ọdún 1992 ẹgbẹ́ ológun Nigerian Infantry Corps."},{"question":"అంకగణిత ప్రాథమిక సిద్ధాంతమును రాయండి.","answer":"అంకగణిత ప్రాథమిక సిద్ధాంతము: ప్రతి సంయుక్త సంఖ్యను ప్రధాన కారణాంకాల లబ్దంగా రాయవచ్చును మరియు ప్రధాన కారణాంకాల క్రమం ఏదైనప్పటికి ఈ కారణాంకాల లబ్దము ఏకైకము."},{"question":"Inona no areti-mifindra nisy manerana an'izao tontolo izao nanomboka tamin'ny taona 2019?","answer":"Ny areti-mifindra COVID-19 dia nisy fiantraikany teo amin'izao tontolo izao nanomboka ny taona 2019."},{"question":"請用簡潔的語言回答以下問題：人類學如何研究不同文化的數位化與科技變遷？","answer":"人類學透過研究不同文化對數位化科技的接受與應用、科技變遷對社會的影響等面向來了解其數位化與科技變遷的文化適應與社會後果。"},{"question":" Maisheegi kartaa  Eey-Gii Galay Janada ?","answer":" Wuxuu Ahaa Eey-Gii La-Socday Reer Asxaabu Kahfi"},{"question":" Os Jogos Olímpicos de Inverno são sediados de quanto em quanto tempo?","answer":"Handebol. Também está correto se respondeu polo aquático."},{"question":"De quem é a famosa frase “Penso, logo existo”?a) Platãob) Galileu Galileic) Descartesd) Sócratese) Francis Bacon","answer":"Alternativa c: Descartes.“Je pense, donc je suis” é a frase original, escrita em francês, do filósofo René Descartes (1596-1650). Ela resume o pensamento e o método de Descartes, para quem tudo tem início na dúvida."},{"question":"මාත්තු කිරීම්‌ සහ රසායනික ප්‍රතික්‍රියා සඳහා භාවිතා වන සැහැල්ලු ලෝහය කුමක්ද?","answer":"මාත්තු කිරීම්‌ සහ රසායනික ප්‍රතික්‍රියා සඳහා භාවිතා වන සැහැල්ලු ලෝහය බෙරලියම්‌ ලෝහයයි."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air jernih, ikannya jinak\\"?","answer":"Peribahasa ini bermaksud negeri yang maju dan aman, rakyatnya berbudi bahasa"},{"question":"आपल्या स्वराज्याचा कारभार पाहण्यासाठी शिवाजी महाराजांनी कशाची निर्मिती केली ?","answer":"आपल्या स्वराज्याचा कारभार पाहण्यासाठी शिवाजी महाराजांनी अष्टप्रधान मंडळची निर्मिती केली."},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara ny folo (10) Marsa fito amby sivifolo sy sivinjato sy arivo (1997)?","answer":"Tamin' ny folo (10) Marsa fito amby sivifolo sy sivinjato sy arivo (1997) dia nihaona ny filoha Didier Ratsiraka sy ny filoha frantsay \\"Jacques Chirac\\"."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bala lalu dibawa singgah\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud mencari kesusahan dan lain-lain dengan sengaja."},{"question":"ಸಾರು ಎಂದರೇನು?","answer":"ಸಾರು, ದಕ್ಷಿಣ ಭಾರತದ ಒಂದು ಅಡುಗೆ ಪದಾರ್ಥ. ಅದನ್ನು ಹುಣಿಸೆ ರಸ ಅಥವಾ ಟೊಮೇಟೊ, ಮೆಣಸಿನಕಾಯಿ ಮತ್ತು ಇತರ ಸಂಬಾರ ಪದಾರ್ಥಗಳನ್ನು ಬಳಸಿ ತಯಾರಿಸಲಾಗುತ್ತದೆ. ಕೆಲವರು ತೊಗರಿ ಬೇಳೆಯನ್ನು ತರಕಾರಿಗಳೊಂದಿಗೆ ಸೇರಿಸುತ್ತಾರೆ."},{"question":"Mô tả sự kiện quan trọng được nói tới trong văn bản này - Nhằm hướng tới việc kết thúc chiến tranh Lạnh, cả hai siêu cường đã bắt đầu phát triển tên lửa liên lục địa (ICBM) chạy bằng đường sắt gắn trên đoàn tàu bọc thép. Liên Xô triển khai các tên lửa SS-24 vào năm 1987, nhưng chi phí ngân sách và tình hình quốc tế thay đổi dẫn đến việc hủy bỏ chương trình này, với tất cả các tên lửa chạy bằng đường sắt cuối cùng đã bị ngừng hoạt động vào năm 2005. Một đoàn tàu bọc thép còn lại vẫn được sử dụng thường xuyên là của Kim Nhật Thành và Kim Jong-il, cái đầu tiên trước đây là do Liên Xô tặng và sau này được sử dụng nhiều cho các chuyến thăm chính thức Trung Quốc và Nga vì lãnh đạo Bắc Triều Tiên ngại đi máy bay.","answer":"Sự kiện quan trọng được nói tới trong văn bản này việc  hủy bỏ chương trình phát triển tên lửa liên lục địa (ICBM) của Liên Xô do chi phí ngân sách và tình hình quốc tế thay đổi."},{"question":"\\" ચતુરાઈની પરીક્ષા \\" વાર્તા લખો.","answer":"લક્ષ્મણ પટેલને અરજણ અને ભગવાન નામે બે દીકરા હતા. બેઉ કહ્યાગરા અને મહેનતુ હતા. એક દિવસ એમણે દીકરાઓને પાસે બોલાવી, દરેકના હાથમાં દશ-દશ રૂપિયા આપતાં કહ્યું, ‘જાઓ, દશ રૂપિયામાં ઘર ભરાય એવી ચીજ લઈ આવો તો ચતુર છો એમ જાણું.’બેઉ ભાઈ દશ-દશ રૂપિયા લઈ ગામમાં ખરીદી માટે નીકળી પડ્યા. મોટો ભાઈ અરજણ પહેલાં કુંભારવાડે ગયો ને દશ રૂપિયાનાં કોડિયાં માગ્યાં. કુંભારે એને કોડિયાંની એક થપ્પી આપી. અરજણ કહે : ‘આટલાં જ કેમ ?’કુંભાર કહે : ‘જોઈએ તો દશ વધારે લો.’અરજણ કહે : ‘મારે તો ઘર ભરાય એટલાં જોઈએ.’કુંભારે એને રૂપિયા પાછા આપ્યા. ત્યાંથી અરજણ મોદીની દુકાને ગયો ને કહ્યું : ‘લો દશ રૂપિયામાં ઘર ભરાય એટલી દીવાસળીની પેટીઓ આપો.’મોદીએ એને દીવાસળીની થોડી પેટીઓ આપી. એ પાછી આપતાં અરજણ કહે, ‘મારે તો ઘર ભરાય એટલી દીવાસળી જોઈએ. આટલી ઓછી ન ચાલે.’ ત્યાંથી પણ રૂપિયા પાછા લઈને એ ચાલતો થયો. પછી એ એક પીંજારાને ત્યાં ગયો. રૂપિયા લઈ પીંજારાએ એને રૂનું એક પડીકું બાંધી આપ્યું. અરજણ કહે, ‘બસ, આટલું જ કે ? મારે તો ઘર ભરાય એટલું રૂ જોઈએ.’ પડીકું પાછું આપી, રૂપિયા લઈ, એ આગળ ચાલ્યો અને એક ઘાંચીને ઘેર ગયો. ઘાંચીના હાથમાં રૂપિયા મૂકી એ બોલ્યો : ‘ફકીરકાકા ! લ્યો આ રૂપિયા અને ઘર ભરાય એટલું તેલ મને આપો.’ ફકીર ઘાંચી હસી પડ્યો ને બોલ્યો, ‘ગાંડા ! આટલા રૂપિયામાં માંડ લોટી ભરાય એટલું તેલ આવે. લે, આ તારા રૂપિયા પાછા.’એમ ગામમાં ફરી ફરીને અરજણ થાક્યો. દશ રૂપિયામાં ઘર ભરાય એવી કોઈ ચીજ એની નજરે ના પડી. અરજણની પાછળ જ એનો નાનો ભાઈ ભગવાન આ બધું જોતો જોતો ચાલ્યો આવતો હતો. એણે પોતાની પાસેના રૂપિયામાંથી થોડાં કોડિયાં લીધાં. થોડુંક રૂ લીધું, એક દીવાસળીની પેટી લીધી અને બાકી વધ્યા તેટલા પૈસાનું તેલ લીધું. પછી એ ઘર તરફ વળ્યો. બેઉ ભાઈને આવેલા જોઈ લક્ષ્મણ પટેલ જરા હસ્યા ને બોલ્યા, ‘અરજણ ! તું દશ રૂપિયામાં શું શું લાવ્યો છે ?’અરજણ કહે, ‘બાપા ! હું કાંઈ કાચો નથી. દશ રૂપિયામાં ઘર ભરાય એવી કોઈ ચીજ આપણા ગામમાં મળતી નથી. લો, આ તમે આપેલા રૂપિયા પાછા.’ એમ કહી એણે રૂપિયા બાપાના હાથમાં મૂક્યા..હવે લક્ષ્મણ પટેલે નાના દીકરા ભગવાન તરફ નજર કરી તો એ રૂની દિવેટો તૈયાર કરી રહ્યો હતો. પછી એણે કોડિયામાં તેલ પૂર્યું ને અંદર વાટ મૂકી. કોડિયાં ઘરના ખંડે ખંડે મૂકી દીધાં. બહાર ટોડલા પર પણ મૂક્યાં, ને દીવાસળી વડે દીવા સળગાવ્યા. તરત આખા ઘરમાં ઝાકઝમાળ થઈ ગયું. આખું ઘર પ્રકાશથી ભરાઈ ગયું. પટેલ કહે : ‘વાહ બેટા ! ધન્ય છે તારી ચતુરાઈને. તેં દીવા કરીને ઘરને અજવાળ્યું છે તેમ સારાં સારાં કામ વડે તું આપણા કુળને પણ અજવાળજે.’ અને અરજણ તરફ ફરીને બોલ્યો, ‘બેટા ! તારો નાનો ભાઈ વધારે ચતુર છે. નાનો ગણી એને પુછાય નહીં એવું ના રાખતો. બેઉ ભાઈ હળીમળીને રહેજો ને દીવા બનીને આપણા કુળને ઉજાળજો.’તરત જ અરજણ નાના ભાઈ ભગવાનને ભેટી પડ્યો. પછી બેઉ ભાઈ બાપાને પગે પડ્યા અને અને એમના આશીર્વાદ મેળવ્યા."},{"question":"What does the project feasibility document typically include?","answer":"The project feasibility document includes a statement of work, business objectives, project budget, project milestones, analysis of stakeholders, project risks, possible alternatives, and an evaluation of the project and alternatives."},{"question":"नेपाल को सबै भन्दा होचो भूभाग कुन जील्ला मा पर्छ, यसको नाम र समुन्द्र सतह देखि कति मिटर ऊचाई मा छ?","answer":"झापा जील्लामा पर्छ यसको नाम केचनाकलन हो र यो ७० मिटर ऊचाई मा पर्छ।"},{"question":"Waa maxay xisaab?","answer":"1. Xisaabtu waa sayniska iyo daraasadda tayada, qaab-dhismeedka, booska, iyo isbeddelka.2. Barashada sida ratibaadyo iyo xiriiro loo bandhigo la isuna gaarsiiyo. 3. Barashada tirooyinka, shaxannada iyo qaybo kale oo lojik ahaan loo adeegsado. Waxaa loo qaybiyaa xisaab saafid iyo dabaqaad. Inkastoo qaybintu aan ahayn mid go'an misna labada qaybood waa ay isku xiranyihiin."},{"question":"Who were the most important people in the French Revolution?","answer":"Prominent figures included Maximilien Robespierre, Jean-Paul Marat, Georges Danton, and leaders of the Girondins and Jacobins who played pivotal roles in shaping the revolution."},{"question":"Kaamatan diraikan di negeri mana? Pilih jawapan yang betul dari pilihan berikut. A. TerengganuB. KelantanC. SabahD. Sarawak","answer":"Jawapan yang betul adalah C. Sabah.Kaamatan adalah pesta sempena meraikan tamatnya musim menuai padi yang disambut oleh suku kaum Kadazan-Dusun di Sabah. Pesta ini bermula pada 1 Mei dan berakhir pada 31 Mei."},{"question":"Odidi mọlẹbi kan jẹ majele mọ ounjẹ, ni mẹwaa ba ku ninu wọn ni Kwara","answer":"Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, ni awọn mọlẹbi kan jẹ majele mọ ounjẹ alẹ niluu Biogberu, lagbegbe Gwanara, nipinlẹ Kwara, ti eeyan mẹwaa si dagbere faye.ALAROYE gbọ pe ni nnkan bii aago mẹwaa alẹ ọjọ Aje ni wọn jẹ ounjẹ alẹ ọhun, eyi ti majele ti wa ninu rẹ ni ile olori awọn Fulani to wa ni agbegbe Biogberu ti wọn si gbabẹ lọ sọrun alakeji.Ohun tawọn tọrọ naa ṣoju wọn sọ ni pe olori awọn Fulani ọhun lọ sọdọ oniṣegun rẹ, Musa, pe ohun nilo oogun agbele-pọta, baba oloogun si gbe oogun naa fun un pe ki wọn da a sinu ounjẹ, ki wọn jẹ ẹ mọ ounjẹ. Ṣugbọn wọn ṣi oogun naa lo, ọtọ ni bi Musa to jẹ baba oloogun ṣe ni ki wọn lo o, ọtọ ni bi wọn ṣe lo o. Ni inu ba bẹrẹ si i run gbogbo wọn pẹlu oniruuru inira.Awọn mẹfa ni ko ku lalẹ ọjọ Aje tiṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣẹlẹ, ti wọn si gbe wọn lọ sọsibitu Bukari Kawo Memorial, to wa ni Gwanara, sugbọn awọn naa pada ku ni owurọ kutu ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee ọṣẹ yii.Wọnyii ni orukọ awọn to ba iṣẹlẹ naa lọ : Ibou oun ni baba, Bake ni iya, orukọ awọn ọmọ ni, Juli, Sidiq, Banna, Yon, Zenab, Denbo ati Junbo.Agọ ọlọpaa to wa ni ilu Gwanara ti tẹwọ gba iṣẹlẹ naa, wọn si ni awọn yoo ṣe ẹkunrẹrẹ iwadii lori iṣẹlẹ ọhun.Bakan naa ni Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Kwara, Ọgbẹni Ọkasanmi Ajayi, fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, o ni awọn yoo gbe igbesẹ to ba tọ lori iṣẹlẹ naa."},{"question":"Como os Cientistas determinam a Idade dos Fósseis?","answer":"A Idade dos Fósseis é calculada, com base em métodos de datação, utilizando-se isótopos (átomos de um mesmo elemento químico) de elementos, como, por exemplo, o carbono. Cada elemento químico possui uma idade, o carbono é usado para os fósseis, que ainda possuem esse elemento, nos ossos, geralmente provenientes de períodos geológicos mais recentes, como os hominídeos. Quando não é possível avaliar a idade do fóssil, procura-se fazer a datação da rocha em que ele foi encontrado. Como cada camada de rocha sedimentar é característica de um período geológico específico, é possível determinar uma cronologia através do estudo de uma determinada quantidade de camadas."},{"question":"*كم دولة عربية عملتها الدينار في أفريقيا ؟","answer":"4 دول"},{"question":"Lima mooy gëblag man réew ?","answer":"Lima mooy gëblag réewum Pérou."},{"question":"Sheeg Rasuulka (Nnkh) Markii Uu Geeriyooday Ilmihiisa Imisa Ayaa Ka Noolaa?","answer":"Waxa Ka Nooleed Faaduma Bintu Rasuulullaah."},{"question":"O canadense Connor McDavid é uma estrela em ascensão em que esporte?","answer":"Hockey no gelo"},{"question":"શીત યુદ્ધનો ઇતિહાસ શું છે?","answer":"શીત યુદ્ધ એ યુનાઇટેડ સ્ટેટ્સ અને સોવિયત યુનિયન અને તેમના સંબંધિત સાથીઓ વચ્ચે 1945 અને 1991 ની વચ્ચે ભૌગોલિક રાજકીય તણાવનો સમયગાળો હતો.શીત યુદ્ધ શબ્દનો ઉપયોગ કરવામાં આવે છે કારણ કે બંને મહાસત્તાઓ વચ્ચે સીધા મોટા પાયે લડત નહોતી, પરંતુ તેઓએ પ્રોક્સી યુદ્ધો તરીકે ઓળખાતા મોટા પ્રાદેશિક તકરારમાં વિરોધી પક્ષોને ટેકો આપ્યો હતો.આ સંઘર્ષ આ બંને મહાસત્તાઓ દ્વારા વૈશ્વિક પ્રભાવ માટેના વૈચારિક અને ભૌગોલિક રાજકીય સંઘર્ષ પર આધારિત હતો, બીજા વિશ્વ યુદ્ધના સાથી તરીકેની ભૂમિકાને પગલે 1945 માં નાઝી જર્મની અને શાહી જાપાન સામે વિજય થયો હતો. પરમાણુ શસ્ત્રોની જાતિ અને પરંપરાગત સૈન્ય સિવાય.જમાવટ, વર્ચસ્વ માટેનો સંઘર્ષ પરોક્ષ માધ્યમ દ્વારા વ્યક્ત કરવામાં આવ્યો હતો, જેમ કે મનોવૈજ્ .ાનિક યુદ્ધ, પ્રચાર અભિયાન, જાસૂસી, દૂરના પ્રતિબંધ, રમતગમતની મુત્સદ્દીગીરી અને સ્પેસ રેસ જેવી તકનીકી સ્પર્ધાઓ.શીત યુદ્ધ બીજા વિશ્વયુદ્ધના અંત પછી તરત જ શરૂ થયું, 1961 માં સોવિયત અને પીપલ્સ રિપબ્લિક ઓફ ચાઇના વચ્ચે ચીન-સોવિયત વિભાજન સાથે ધીમે ધીમે પવન શરૂ થયો, અને 1991 માં સોવિયત યુનિયનના પતન સાથે સમાપ્ત થયો.\\""},{"question":"Sheeg kumuu ahaa nebigii ugu danbeeyey Ee Reer Banii Israa’iil?","answer":"Wuxu ahaa nebi Ciise CS."},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Nangeen fonk julli, di joxe asaka, te di rukkoo ànd ak way-rukkoo ya. [Jullig mbooloo, di julli ci biir jàkka yi].","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Na ngéen fonk julli, di joxe àsaka, te di rukoo ànd ak wayrukoo ya. [Jullig mbooloo, di julli ci biir jàkka yi]."},{"question":"Tóm tắt văn bản sau: Lâu nay, ông Sunak vẫn tự nhận rằng nước Anh đi tiên phong trong công cuộc chống biến đổi khí hậu trên thế giới. Với những thay đổi chính sách mới, ông Sunak làm cho nước Anh trở thành quốc gia đi tiên phong trong việc lùi lại trên lĩnh vực này.Những đảo ngược của ông Sunak không động chạm gì đến bản chất của các mục tiêu hay biện pháp chính sách đã cam kết thực hiện mà là trì hoãn thời gian đạt được mục tiêu và thực hiện hoàn toàn những biện pháp chính sách đã cam kết, đa phần lùi thời hạn 15 năm, từ dự định ban đầu là năm 2035 nay lùi đến năm 2050.Trong số các thay đổi có những mục tiêu và cam kết của hai người tiền nhiệm mà ông Sunak đã buộc phải tiếp nhận khi lên cầm quyền. Đảo ngược chúng bây giờ tuy không hay ho và lẽ ra không nên nhưng dù sao cũng vẫn có thể biện luận được đối với ông Sunak. Nhưng đảo ngược những cam kết của chính mình thì mới là chuyện lớn. Ông Sunak ý thức được vậy nhưng vẫn quyết định cài số lùi bởi nguy cơ phe đảng Bảo thủ của ông có thể bị thất bại trong cuộc bầu cử quốc hội dự kiến diễn ra trong năm tới. Tình trạng tăng trưởng kinh tế hiện tại và tâm trạng không hài lòng của bộ phận cử tri truyền thống của phe Bảo thủ buộc ông Sunak phải chấp nhận thất hứa về chống biến đổi khí hậu để đổi lấy sự hậu thuẫn của bộ phận cử tri này và tập trung nguồn lực hiện có cho tăng trưởng kinh tế. Cách tiếp cận và tư duy rất thực tế bởi không đắc cử thì đến muốn lùi còn chẳng được chứ nói gì tiến. ","answer":"Thủ tướng Anh Rishi Sunak đã thay đổi căn bản định hướng chính sách về chống biến đổi khí hậu. Cái đặc biệt nhất, nổi bật nhất và cũng đáng được chú ý nhất ở sự thay đổi này là đảo ngược nhiều mục tiêu đã đề ra và nhiều cam kết quốc tế đã được long trọng tuyên cáo trước đấy."},{"question":"Giải bài toán sau:Gieo ngẫu nhiên xúc xắc một lần. Tính xác suất xảy ra biến cố “Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có số chấm là hợp số”.","answer":"Tập hợp gồm các kết quả có thể xảy ra đối với mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc là:A = {mặt 1 chấm; mặt 2 chấm; mặt 3 chấm; mặt 4 chấm; mặt 5 chấm; mặt 6 chấm}.Số phần tử của tập hợp A là 6.Từ 1 đến 6 có các hợp số là 4; 6.Do đó có 2 kết quả thuận lợi cho biến cố “Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có số chấm là hợp số”.Khi đó xác suất của biến cố “Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có số chấm là hợp số” là 2/6 = 1/3"},{"question":"భారతీయ రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు పాత్రను వివరించండి.","answer":"రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు ఆఫ్ ఇండియా మన దేశానికి కేంద్ర బ్యాంకు. దేశంలోని ద్రవ్య, కోశ విధానాలను రూపొందించడం లోను, అమలు పరచడంలో ముఖ్యపాత్ర వహిస్తుంది. ఇది దేశంలోని బ్యాంకింగ్ వ్యవస్థ అభివృద్ధికి నాయకత్వం వహిస్తూ దేశ అవసరాలకు తగినట్లుగా బ్యాంకింగ్ కార్యకలాపాలను క్రమబద్దీకరిస్తుంది.రాయల్ కమీషన్ ఆఫ్ ఇండియన్ కరెన్సీ అండ్ ఫైనాన్స్ సూచన మేరకు 1935 ఏప్రిల్లో 5 కోట్ల వాటా మూలధనంతో రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు నెలకొల్పబడినది. మొదట ఇది ప్రైవేటు వాటాదారు యాజమాన్యం క్రింద ఏర్పడింది. దీనిని 1949లో భారత ప్రభుత్వం జాతీయం చేసింది. 1934 భారతీయ రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు చట్టం ప్రకారం అన్ని ముఖ్యమైన కేంద్ర బ్యాంకు విధులను ఇది నిర్వహిస్తుంది.దీని ప్రధాన కార్యాలయం ముంబాయిలో ఉంది. ఢిల్లీ, కోలకత్తా, చెన్నై, ముంబాయి మొదలైన నగరాలలో ప్రాంతీయ కార్యాలయాలు పనిచేస్తాయి. 20 మంది డైరెక్టర్లతో కూడిన కేంద్ర డైరెక్టర్ల బోర్డు నియంత్రణ క్రింద ఇది పనిచేస్తుంది. ఇందులో ఒక గవర్నరు, నలుగురికి మించకుండా డిప్యూటీ గవర్నర్లు, రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు నాలుగు స్థానిక డైరెక్టర్ల బోర్డుల నుంచి ఒక్కొక్కరు కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వంచే నియమించబడే పదిమంది డైరెక్టర్లు, ఒక ప్రభుత్వ అధికారి, మొత్తం 20 మంది ఉంటారు. వీరందరినీ కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వం నియమిస్తుంది.భారతీయ రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు విధులు:1) కరెన్సీ నోట్ల జారీ: మనదేశంలోని కరెన్సీ నోట్ల జారీపై గుత్తాధిపత్య అధికారం రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు కలిగి ఉంది. రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు 1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 రూపాయల కరెన్సీ నోట్లను జారీ చేస్తుంది. ఈ నోట్లపై భారతీయ రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు గవర్నర్ సంతకం ముద్రించబడతాయి. 2006 ఆగష్టు నాటికి దేశంలో చలామణిలో ఉన్న కరెన్సీ విలువ 23,936 కోట్లు.2) ప్రభుత్వ బ్యాంకరు రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వానికీ, రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వానికి బ్యాంకరుగా, ప్రతినిధిగా, ఆర్థిక సలహాదారుగా వ్యవహరిస్తుంది. ప్రభుత్వ బ్యాంకరుగా వివిధ ప్రభుత్వ విభాగాల అకౌంట్లను నిర్వహిస్తుంది. ప్రభుత్వం తరుపున ద్రవ్యాన్ని స్వీకరిస్తుంది, చెల్లింపులు చేస్తుంది. ప్రభుత్వాలకు తాత్కాలిక ఋణాలు అందిస్తుంది. అన్ని ఆర్థిక వ్యవహారాలలో ప్రభుత్వాలకు సలహాదారుగా కూడా పనిచేస్తుంది.3) బ్యాంకుల బ్యాంకరు: దేశంలోని బ్యాంకులకు రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు బ్యాంకరుగా పనిచేస్తుంది. కొన్ని రకాల బిల్లులను రీడిస్కౌంట్ చేసుకునే సదుపాయం వాణిజ్య బ్యాంకులకు కలుగజేస్తుంది. వివిధ బ్యాంకుల మధ్య బ్యాంకింగ్ లావాదేవీలను పరిష్కరించడానికి క్లియరింగ్ హౌస్ గా పనిచేస్తుంది. అలాగే బ్యాంకుల కార్యకలాపాలు తీర్చిదిద్ది వాటికి నాయకత్వం వహిస్తుంది.4) అంతిమ ఋణదాత: మార్కెట్లోని అన్నిరకాల పరపతి సౌకర్యాలు ఉపయోగించుకున్న తర్వాత ఇంకా ద్రవ్యత్వ ఇబ్బందులున్నప్పుడు రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు వాణిజ్య బ్యాంకులకు, డిస్కౌంటు గృహాలకు, ఇతర పరపతి సంస్థలకు కొన్ని షరతులకు లోబడి వాటి వినిమయ బిల్లులను రీడిస్కౌంట్ చేయడం ద్వారా పరపతి అందిస్తూ అంతిమ ఋణదాతగా పనిచేస్తుంది.5) క్లియరింగ్ హౌస్ల నిర్వహణ: వ్యాపార అవసరాల నిమిత్తం బ్యాంకు ఖాతాదార్లు చెక్కుల ద్వారా చెల్లింపులు చేస్తుంటాయి. వేరువేరు ఖాతాదార్లు వేరువేరు బ్యాంకులలో తమ ఖాతాలు కలిగి ఉండటం వల్ల వివిధ బ్యాంకుల మీద ఈ చెక్కులు జారీ అవుతూ ఉంటాయి. వివిధ బ్యాంకుల మధ్య ఖాతాదార్ల చెక్కులకు సంబంధించిన సొమ్ము వారి వారి ఖాతాలలో జమచేయడానికి రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు తమవద్ద ఉన్న వివిధ బ్యాంకుల ఖాతాలను సర్దుబాటు చేస్తూ వసూళ్ళ చెల్లింపులు సులభతరం చేయడానికి వివిధ నగరాలలో క్లియరింగ్ హౌస్లు నిర్వహిస్తుంది.6) విదేశీ మారక ద్రవ్యం పరిరక్షణ: రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు విదేశీ మారక ద్రవ్యంను పరిరక్షిస్తుంది. విదేశీ మారక ద్రవ్యం మారకం రేటులను స్థిరంగా ఉంచవలసిన బాధ్యత రిజర్వు బ్యాంకుది. విదేశీ మారక నిల్వలను నిర్వహిస్తూ వాటి వినియోగాన్ని నియంత్రణ చేస్తుంది.7) పరపతి నియంత్రణ: ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థలోని పరపతి పరిమాణాన్ని తగిన ద్రవ్య విధానం ద్వారా కేంద్ర బ్యాంకు నియత్రిస్తుంది. ద్రవ్యోల్బణం సమయంలో పరపతి తగ్గిస్తుంది. ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థ తిరోగమన పరిస్థితి ఎదుర్కొంటున్న సమయంలో పరపతి సప్లయ్ పంచుతుంది.రిజర్వు బ్యాంకు ఆశయాలు:కరెన్సీ నోట్ల జారీని క్రమబద్ధం చేయటం.దేశంలో ద్రవ్య స్థిరత్వాన్ని సాధించటం.వాణిజ్య బ్యాంకులకు మార్గదర్శకత్వం వహించటం.దేశంలో పరపతి వ్యవస్థను నియంత్రించటందేశవ్యాప్తంగా ఒకే పరపతి విధానాన్ని రూపొందించి అమలు చేయడం."},{"question":"العالم الذي أخترع التلفون هو…؟","answer":"-الكسندر غراهام بيل"},{"question":"I wonder బాలెమర్రు గ్రామ పిన్ కోడ్ ఏంటి?.Help me answer this question with \\"Yes\\" or \\"No\\" or \\"None\\" if none of the first two answers apply.Here's what I found on the internet:Topic: బాలెమర్రుArticle: బాలెమర్రు, గుంటూరు జిల్లా, క్రోసూరు మండలానికి చెందిన గ్రామము. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన క్రోసూరు నుండి 10 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన సత్తెనపల్లి నుండి 27 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 284 ఇళ్లతో, 1228 జనాభాతో 359 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 601, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 627. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 595 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 15. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 589933[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 522410గ్రామ చరిత్రఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ రాజధాని ప్రాంత అభివృద్ధి ప్రాధికార సంస్థ (సీఆర్‌డీఏ) పరిధిలోకి వస్తున్న మండలాలు, గ్రామాలను ప్రభుత్వం విడిగా గుర్తిస్తూ ఉత్తర్వులు జారీచేసింది. ప్రస్తుతం గుర్తించిన వాటిలోని చాలా గ్రామాలు వీజీటీఎం పరిధిలో ఉన్నాయి. గతంలో వీజీటీఎం పరిధిలో ఉన్న వాటితోపాటుగా ఇప్పుడు మరిన్ని కొన్ని గ్రామాలు చేరాయి. సీఆర్‌డీఏ పరిధిలోకి వచ్చే గుంటూరు, కృష్ణా జిల్లాల్లోని మండలాలు, గ్రామాలను గుర్తిస్తూ పురపాలక శాఖ ముఖ్య కార్యదర్శి  ద్వారా ఉత్తర్వులు జారీ అయ్యాయి.[2]గణాంకాలు2001 వ.సంవత్సరం జనాభా లెక్కల ప్రకారం గ్రామ జనాభా 1,356.[3]  ఇందులో పురుషుల సంఖ్య 684,  స్త్రీల సంఖ్య 672, గ్రామంలో నివాస గృహాలు 309 ఉన్నాయి. గ్రామ విస్తీర్ణము 359 హెక్టారులు.జనాభా (2011) - మొత్తం \\t1,228 -  పురుషుల సంఖ్య \\t601 -  స్త్రీల సంఖ్య \\t627 - గృహాల సంఖ్య \\t284విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుగ్రామంలో ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాలలు రెండు ఉన్నాయి.సమీప బాలబడి, మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల‌లు క్రోసూరు లోను,  ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల అందుకూరు లోనూ ఉన్నాయి.సమీప జూనియర్ కళాశాల క్రోసూరులోను, ప్రభుత్వ ఆర్ట్స్, సైన్స్, డిగ్రీ కళాశాల సత్తెనపల్లిలోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వైద్య కళాశాల గుంటూరులోను, పాలీటెక్నిక్‌ క్రోసూరులోను, మేనేజిమెంటు కళాశాల కంటెపూడిలోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వృత్తి విద్యా శిక్షణ పాఠశాల సత్తెనపల్లిలోను, అనియత విద్యా కేంద్రం క్రోసూరు లోను, దివ్యాంగుల ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాల గుంటూరు లోనూ ఉన్నాయి.వైద్య సౌకర్యంప్రభుత్వ వైద్య సౌకర్యంబలేమర్రులో ఉన్న ఒక ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య ఉప కేంద్రంలో డాక్టర్లు లేరు. ఒకరు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బంది ఉన్నారు.ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉంది. ప్రత్యామ్నాయ ఔషధ ఆసుపత్రి, పశు వైద్యశాల, సంచార వైద్య శాల గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. సమీప సామాజిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, మాతా శిశు సంరక్షణ కేంద్రం,...","answer":"పిన్ కోడ్ 522410 "},{"question":"Đề bài:Hai đội bóng đá thi đấu giao hữu chào mừng năm mới 2023. Trước khi thi đấu, tất cả cầu thủ chính thức và dự bị của cả hai đội bắt tay nhau, mỗi cầu thủ bắt tay với mọi cầu thủ khác của cả hai đội đúng một lần.Biết rằng trong tổng số 903 cái bắt tay của các cầu thủ (không tính các cái bắt tay với tổ trọng tài) có 441 cái bắt tay giữa các cầu thủ ở trong cùng một đội. Hỏi mỗi đội có bao nhiêu cầu thủ dự bị (biết mỗi đội có 11 cầu thủ chính thức)?","answer":"Gọi số cầu thủ của hai đội bóng là a và b thì tổng số cầu thủ là a + b.Do cầu thủ A bắt tay cầu thủ B cũng giống như B bắt tay A nên tổng số cái bắt tay của các cầu thủ là (a + b) (a + b – 1) / 2 = 903,hay (a + b) (a + b – 1) = 1806 = 43 x 42. Từ đó suy ra a + b = 43.Số cái bắt tay giữa các cầu thủ ở khác đội là ab = 903 – 441= 462.Từ a + b = 43 và ab= 462 suy ra a = 21, b = 22 hoặc a = 22, b = 21Như thế số cầu thủ dự bị của hai đội bóng là 11 và 10."},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-carriage return","answer":"நகர்த்தி திரும்புகை"},{"question":"¿Qué es una supernova?","answer":"Una supernova es una explosión estelar extremadamente poderosa que ocurre al final de la vida de una estrella masiva. Durante una supernova, la estrella libera una cantidad enorme de energía y esparce elementos pesados en el espacio."},{"question":"Inona no fihetseham-pon'ity fanambarana manaraka ity?\\"Nankalaza ny faha-50 taonan'ny mariazy izahay tamin'ity herinandro ity. Feno fitiavana sy fifamatorana ny dianay. Tena feno fifaliana aho manana fifandraisana toy izany amin'ny vadiko.\\"","answer":"Ny fahatsapana dia tsara, noho ny hafaliana noho ny fifandraisana mafy orina amin' ny fanambadiana."},{"question":"Ergonomic  යන්නට ගැලපෙන සිංහල වචනය මොකක්ද?","answer":"මිනිස් කාර්ය පරිසර සම්බන්ධතා  විද්‍යාව Erganomics කියන්නෙ භෞතික විද්‍යාව ඇසුරින් මිනිසාගේ ශරීරයට උපරිම පහසුතාව, කාර්යක්ෂ්මතාව හා මිනිස් පේශී පද්ධතියට ආරක්ෂාව ගෙන දෙන මෙවලම් සැලසුම් කිරීම ආදී විෂයයක්."},{"question":"เติมข้อความต่อจากข้อความนี้ให้สมบูรณ์:  ตะวันเริ่มเล่นฟุตบอลอาชีพให้กับ สโมสรราชวิถี และมาโด่งดังกับสโมสรธนาคารกรุงเทพพาณิชยการ จนก้าวขึ้นไปติดทีมชาติในยุคที่มี ชัชชัย พหลแพทย์ เป็นกุนซือ โดยติดทีมชาติไทยเป็นครั้งแรก เมื่อเดือนกุมภาพันธ์ พ.ศ. 2536 ในรายการปรีเวิลด์คัพ 1994 และได้ลงเล่นนัดแรกในนามทีมชาติ ในนัดที่แข่งกับทีมชาติบังคลาเทศ ที่ เมืองโกเบ ประเทศญี่ปุ่น ตะวันเติบโตมาในวงการฟุตบอลกับชุดดรีมทีม นำโดย ธวัชชัย สัจจกุล และ วิรัช ชาญพานิชย์ และมีผลงานที่สำคัญคือการนำทีมชาติชุด บี คว้าแชมป์ คิงส์คัพ ประจำปี พ.ศ. 2537 และมาคว้าแชมป์รายการอินดิเพนเดนท์ แชมเปียนชิพ ปี พ.ศ. 2537, ได้ 4 เหรียญทอง จากการแข่งขันฟุตบอล","answer":"ซีเกมส์ ครั้งที่ 17 ที่ประเทศสิงคโปร์, ซีเกมส์ ครั้งที่ 18 ที่จังหวัดเชียงใหม่, ซีเกมส์ ครั้งที่ 19 ที่ประเทศอินโดนีเซียและ ซีเกมส์ ครั้งที่ 20 ที่ประเทศบรูไน, รวมทั้งแชมป์ ไทเกอร์คัพ อีก 3 สมัย และอันดับที่ 4 การแข่งขันฟุตบอลใน เอเชี่ยนเกมส์ ครั้งที่ 13 ที่กรุงเทพมหานคร"},{"question":"What are databases in the field of Computer Science?","answer":"A database is an organized collection of structured information, or data, typically stored electronically in a computer system. A database is usually controlled by a database management system (DBMS). There are nearly a dozen types of databases. Some of the more commonly used categories of databases include: Relational Databases: These databases commonly use Structured Query Language (SQL) for operations like creating, reading, updating, and deleting (CRUD) data. These databases stores data in discrete tables, which can be joined together by fields known as foreign keys. MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, and Oracle are examples.Non-Relational Databases: commonly referred to as NoSQL databases. It is a database that does not use the tabular scheme of rows and columns found in most traditional database systems. Instead, non-relational databases use a storage model that is optimized for the specific requirements of the type of data being stored. E.g. MongoDB, Apache Cassandra, Redis, and Apache HBase ."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe ONG (Organisation Non-Government)?","answer":"Ny ONG dia fikambanana mahaleo tena, tsy mitady tombontsoa natokana ho an'ny tanjona ara-tsosialy, maha-olona na tontolo iainana."},{"question":"भारतीयों ने साइमन कमीशन का विरोध क्यों किया?","answer":"भारतीयों ने साइमन कमीशन का विरोध इसलिए किया क्योंकि उसमे कोई भारतीय सदस्य नहीं था। "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai aur ditarik songsang\\"?","answer":"Pekerjaan yang sukar dijalankan kerana sudah salah cara penggunaannya"},{"question":" \\"МАК\\" - кыскартылган сөзүнүн түшүндүрмөсү кандай  ?","answer":"МАК— Мамлекеттик аттестация комиссиясы;"},{"question":"පැහැදිලි දිනයක අහසේ වර්ණය කුමක්ද?","answer":"පැහැදිලි දිනයක අහසේ වර්ණය සාමාන්‍යයෙන් නිල් පැහති වේ."},{"question":"Em 2017, qual era o nome da artista feminina que tinha mais streams no Spotify?","answer":"Rihanna"},{"question":"Ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ya bo ileewe girama l’Ọrẹ, ni wọn ba tu awọn akẹkọọ ka nibi ti wọn ti n ṣe idanwo lọwọ","answer":"Kayeefi lo ṣi n jẹ fawọn eeyan Ọrẹ, nijọba ibilẹ Odigbo, pẹlu bawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun kan ṣe ya bo ileewe girama Muslim to wa niluu ọhun laaarọ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, ti wọn si tu awọn akẹkọọ ka nibi ti wọn ti n ṣe idanwo ijọba to n lọ lọwọ.ALAROYE gbọ pe lara awọn akẹkọọ ileewe ọhun ti wọn jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ni wọn waa ṣe akọlu si olukọ atawọn ẹgbẹ wọn ki wọn le dawọ idanwo ti wọn n ṣe naa duro.Awọn soja to wa lagbegbe Ọrẹ ni wọn pada waa tu awọn janduku akẹkọọ ọhun ka, ti wọn ko fi ri ẹnikẹni ṣe leṣe, ti wọn si tun ri ọkan ninu awọn tọọgi ọhun mu lọ.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, adele olukọ agba ileewe girama ọhun, Abilekọ Ẹniọla Moradekẹ, rọ ijọba ipinlẹ Ondo lati ṣeto awọn ẹsọ alaabo ti yoo maa ṣọ wọn laarin asiko ti wọn ba wa nileewe.O ni eyi nikan lo le fawọn akẹkọọ ati olukọ lọkan balẹ lati gbaju mọ isẹ wọn.Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, lawọn akẹkọọ kilaasi kejì agba (SS2) kaakiri ipinlẹ Ondo bẹrẹ idanwo tijọba n ṣe fun wọn ki wọn too kọja si ipele aṣekagba (SS3).Idi tawọn akẹkọọ kan nileewe Muslim ko ṣe fẹẹ kopa ninu idanwo gbogbogboo naa ṣi n ya awọn eeyan lẹnu."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai keluang bebar petang\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud \\"berkerumun (berhimpun) beramai-ramai.\\""},{"question":"ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਆਲੀਆ ਭੱਟ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹੋ?","answer":"ਆਲਿਆ ਭੱਟ (ਜਨਮ 15 ਮਾਰਚ 1993) ਭਾਰਤੀ ਮੂਲ ਦੀ ਬ੍ਰਿਟਿਸ਼ ਨਾਗਰਿਕਤਾ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਅਤੇ ਗਾਇਕਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਆਲਿਆ ਭੱਟ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਮਹੇਸ਼ ਭੱਟ ਅਤੇ ਸੋਨੀ ਰਾਜ਼ਦਾਨ ਦੀ ਪੁੱਤਰੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਛੋਟੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ 1999 ਵਿੱਚ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਫਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਬੱਚੀ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। ਬਾਲਗ ਹੋਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਸਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਐਕਟਿੰਗ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕਰਣ ਜੌਹਰ ਦੀ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਫਿਲਮ ਸਟੂਡੈਂਟ ਆਫ਼ ਦੀ ਈਅਰ (2012) ਤੋਂ ਕੀਤੀ। ਭੱਟ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਤਨਖਾਹ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਹੈ। ਉਹ 2014 ਤੋਂ ਫੋਰਬਸ ਇੰਡੀਆ ਦੀ ਸੇਲਿਬ੍ਰਿਟੀ 100 ਸੂਚੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਗਟ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਅਤੇ 2017 ਦੀ ਫੋਰਬਜ਼ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਦੀ 30 ਅੰਡਰ 30 ਦੀ ਸੂਚੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ।ਭੱਟ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਈ, ਉਹ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਮਹੇਸ਼ ਭੱਟ ਅਤੇ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਸੋਨੀ ਰਜ਼ਦਾਨ ਦੀ ਧੀ ਹੈ।== ਮੁੱਢਲਾ ਜੀਵਨ ==ਆਲਿਆ ਭੱਟ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 15 ਮਾਰਚ 1993 ਨੂੰ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਵਿਖੇ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਮਹੇਸ਼ ਭੱਟ ਅਤੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਸੋਨੀ ਰਾਜ਼ਦਾਨ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਹੋਇਆ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਗੁਜਰਾਤੀ ਮੂਲ ਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਕਸ਼ਮੀਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਜਰਮਨ ਮੂਲ ਦੀ ਹੈ। ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਨਾਨਾਭਾਈ ਭੱਟ ਉਸਦਾ ਦਾਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡੀ ਭੈਣ, ਸ਼ਹੀਨ (ਜਨਮ 1988) ਅਤੇ ਦੋ ਸੌਤੇਲੇ- ਭੈਣ ਭਰਾ, ਪੂਜਾ ਭੱਟ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਭੱਟ ਹਨ। ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਹਾਸ਼ਮੀ ਅਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਮੋਹਿਤ ਸੂਰੀ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਮੇਰੇ ਭਰਾ ਹਨ, ਜਦਕਿ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਮੁਕੇਸ਼ ਭੱਟ ਉਸਦਾ ਚਾਚਾ ਹੈ। ਭੱਟ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਦੇ ਜਮਨਾਬੀ ਨਰਸੀ ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਕੋਲ ਬ੍ਰਿਟਿਸ਼ ਨਾਗਰਿਕਤਾ ਹੈ। ਆਲਿਆ ਭੱਟ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ (1999) ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਬਾਲ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੀ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਕਸ਼ੈ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਪ੍ਰੀਤੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਟਾ ਨੇ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਸਨੇ ਜਿੰਟਾ ਦੇ ਚਰਿੱਤਰ ਦਾ ਬਚਪਨ ਦਾ ਰੋੋੋਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ।== ਹੋਰ ਕੰਮ ਅਤੇ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਚਿੱਤਰ ==ਭੱਟ ਨੇ ਹਾਈਵੇਅ (2014) ਦੇ ਗੀਤ \\"ਸੋਹ ਸਾਹਾ\\" ਲਈ ਪਲੇਬੈਕ ਗਾਇਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਫਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਸੰਗੀਤਕਾਰ ਏ.ਆਰ. ਰਹਿਮਾਨ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਖਲਾਈ ਲੈਣ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੁਲਾਇਆ। 2014 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸਨੇ ‘ਹੰਪਟੀ ਸ਼ਰਮਾ ਕੀ ਦੁਲਹਨੀਆ’ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੰਗੀਤਕਾਰ ਸ਼ਾਰੀਬ-ਤੋਸ਼ੀ ਲਈ ਗੀਤ \\"ਸਮਝਵਾਂ\\" ਦਾ ਅਨਪਲੱਗਡ ਸੰਸਕਰਣ ਗਾਇਆ। 2016 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਹਿ-ਸਟਾਰ ਦੋਸਾਂਝ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ, \\"ਉੜਤਾ ਪੰਜਾਬ\\" ਦੇ ਸਾਉਂਡਟ੍ਰੈਕ ਲਈ ਗੀਤ \\"ਇਕ ਕੁੜੀ\\" ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਕਲਪਿਕ ਸੰਸਕਰਣ ਗਾਇਆ।ਭੱਟ ਨੇ ਫਿਲਮਫੇਅਰ, ਸਕ੍ਰੀਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਟਾਰਡਸਟ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਸਮਾਰੋਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਟੇਜ 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ਅਤੇ ਵਰੁਣ ਧਵਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਿਧਾਰਥ ਮਲਹੋਤਰਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਹਾਂਗਕਾਂਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਸਟੇਜ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ। 2013 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸਨੇ ਉੱਤਰਾਖੰਡ ਦੇ ਹੜ੍ਹ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਿਤ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਲਈ ਫੰਡ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਧਵਨ, ਮਲਹੋਤਰਾ, ਆਦਿਤਿਆ ਰਾਏ ਕਪੂਰ, ਸ਼ਰਧਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਤੇ ਹੁਮਾ ਕੁਰੈਸ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਚੈਰਿਟੀ ਸਮਾਗਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤਾ। ਅਗਸਤ 2016 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸਨੇ ਜੌਹਰ, ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ ਧਵਨ, ਮਲਹੋਤਰਾ, ਰਾਏ ਕਪੂਰ, ਕੈਟਰੀਨਾ ਕੈਫ, ਪਰਿਣੀਤੀ ਚੋਪੜਾ, ਅਤੇ ਗਾਇਕ ਬਾਦਸ਼ਾਹ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ \\"ਡ੍ਰੀਮ ਟੀਮ 2016\\" ਦੌਰੇ ਲਈ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਦੇ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਸ਼ਹਿਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤਾ।2013 ਵਿੱਚ, ਭੱਟ ਨੇ ਬੇਘਰੇ ਜਾਨਵਰਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਗਰੂਕਤਾ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਪੇਟਾ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਮੁਹਿੰਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਲਿਆ। 2017 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸਨੇ ਗਲੀ ਜਾਨਵਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਭਲਾਈ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਗਰੂਕਤਾ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ CoExist ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਵਾਤਾਵਰਣਕ ਪਹਿਲਕਦਮੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤੀ। ਅਗਲੇ ਸਾਲ, ਉਸਨੇ ਵਾਤਾਵਰਣਵਾਦ ਦੀ ਮੁਹਿੰਮ ਲਈ, ਫਾਈਡ ਯੂਅਰ ਗ੍ਰੀਨ ਨਾਮਕ ਇੱਕ ਮੁਹਿੰਮ ਲਈ ਫੇਸਬੁੱਕ ਲਾਈਵ ਨਾਲ ਸਹਿਯੋਗ ਕੀਤਾ। ਭੱਟ ਨੇ ਔਨਲਾਈਨ ਫੈਸ਼ਨ ਪੋਰਟਲ Jabong.com ਲਈ 2014 ਵਿੱਚ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਲਈ ਆਪਣਾ ਕਪੜੇ ਦਾ ਬ੍ਰਾਂਡ ਡਿਜ਼ਾਈਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ 2018 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸਨੇ VIP ਉਦਯੋਗਾਂ ਲਈ ਹੈਂਡਬੈਗਾਂ ਦੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਲਾਈਨ ਲਾਂਚ ਕੀਤੀ।2017 ਵਿੱਚ, ਭੱਟ ਨੂੰ ਫੋਰਬਸ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਦੁਆਰਾ 30 ਅੰਡਰ 30 ਦੀ ਸੂਚੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਉਹ 2014 ਤੋਂ ਫੋਰਬਸ ਇੰਡੀਆ ਦੀ ਸੇਲਿਬ੍ਰਿਟੀ 100 ਸੂਚੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਗਟ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ, 2019 ਵਿੱਚ ਅੱਠਵੇਂ ਸਥਾਨ 'ਤੇ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਸਾਲ, ਮੈਗਜ਼ੀਨ ਨੇ ਉਸਦੀ ਸਾਲਾਨਾ ਆਮਦਨ ₹592.1 ਮਿਲੀਅਨ (US7.9 ਮਿਲੀਅਨ) ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਅਨੁਮਾਨ ਲਗਾਇਆ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਕਮਾਈ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਸੂਚੀਬੱਧ ਕੀਤਾ। 2018 ਅਤੇ 2019 ਵਿੱਚ, GQ ਦੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਐਡੀਸ਼ਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ 50 ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਨੌਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਨੂੰ \\"ਵੱਡੇ-ਬਜਟ, ਆਲ-ਸਟਾਰ ਬਲੌਆਉਟਸ ਅਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਸਕ੍ਰਿਪਟ-ਅਧਾਰਿਤ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੰਤੁਲਨ ਬਣਾਉਣ\\" ਦਾ ਸਿਹਰਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਭੱਟ ਨੂੰ ਦ ਟਾਈਮਜ਼ ਆਫ਼ ਇੰਡੀਆ ਦੀ 2018 ਦੀ \\"50 ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਮਨਭਾਉਂਦੀਆਂ ਔਰਤਾਂ\\" ਸੂਚੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਸਥਾਨ 'ਤੇ ਸੂਚੀਬੱਧ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।ਭੱਟ ਕੋਕਾ-ਕੋਲਾ, ਗਾਰਨੀਅਰ ਅਤੇ ਮੇਬੇਲਾਈਨ ਸਮੇਤ ਕਈ ਬ੍ਰਾਂਡਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਾਂ ਲਈ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਹਸਤੀ ਸਮਰਥਕ ਵੀ ਹਨ। ਡੱਫ ਐਂਡ ਫੇਲਪਸ ਨੇ 2018 ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸਦੀ ਬ੍ਰਾਂਡ ਮੁੱਲ US36.5 ਮਿਲੀਅਨ ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਅਨੁਮਾਨ ਲਗਾਇਆ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਹਸਤੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਅੱਠਵੇਂ ਸਥਾਨ 'ਤੇ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Suaal: Qiimaha π (pi) waa sidee?","answer":"Jawaab: Qiimaha π (pi) waa 3.14159."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：以下哪位是美國著名數學家？(a) 約翰·福勒 (b) 卡爾·弗里德里希·高斯 (c) 埃莉諾·羅斯福 (d) 安德魯·懷爾斯","answer":"答案：(d) 安德魯·懷爾斯"},{"question":"Ọdún wo ni wọ́n bẹ̀rẹ̀ síí ṣe fíìmù \\"The Simpsons\\"?","answer":"Ọdún 1987 ni."},{"question":"வினா:அரளிக்கொட்டையில் உள்ள நச்சுப்பொருள் எது? ","answer":"விடை: அரளிக்கொட்டையில் உள்ள நச்சுப்பொருள் ஒலியாண்டர். அரளி அல்லது அலரி நச்சுத் தன்மை வாய்ந்த தாவரம். நீளமான இலைகளுடன் காட்சியளிக்கும் அரளி தாவரத்தில் செவ்வரளி, வெள்ளரளி ஆகிய வகைகள் உள்ளன. இதன் மலர்மாலைகளைக் கோயில்களில் தெய்வ உருவங்களுக்குச் சார்த்துவர். "},{"question":"Naglakad ang isang lalaki sa ulan na walang kahit anong payong o kapote na suot, ngunit hindi nabasa ang kanyang buhok sa ulo. Paano kaya ito nangyari?","answer":"Maaring kalbo ang lalaki. Hindi mababasa ang kanyang buhok dahil wala naman talaga siyang buhok sa ulo."},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 中国から日本に入った人　30日から新型コロナの検査をする","answer":"中国で新型コロナウイルスが広がっています。このため、日本の政府は12月30日から中国から日本に入るときのチェックを厳しくします。中国から日本に入った人と、7日以内に中国に行ったことがある人に、空港で新型コロナウイルスの検査をします。新型コロナウイルスがうつっていることがわかった場合、熱などがある人は7日の間、熱などがない人は5日の間、外に出ることができません。しっかり検査をするために、中国からの飛行機が着くのは、成田空港、羽田空港、関西空港、中部空港の4つの空港だけにします。政府は、中国の新型コロナウイルスの広がり方を考えて、検査などをいつまで続けるか決めます。"},{"question":"Inona no tena mahatonga ny fiakaran'ny maripanan'ny tany, izay mahatonga ny fivondronan'ny entona mampidi-doza ao amin'ny atmosfera?a) orana asidrab) fandripahana alad) hetsika ataon'ny olombelona","answer":"d) Ny hetsika ataon'ny olombelona no tena mahatonga ny fiakaran'ny maripanan'ny tany, izay mahatonga ny fivondronan'ny entona mampidi-doza ao amin'ny atmosfera"},{"question":"Classify the historical eruptions of \\"Mount Agung\\" in Indonesia based on their impact.","answer":"The historical eruptions of Mount Agung in Indonesia can be classified based on their impact as follows:1843 Eruption: This eruption was relatively minor, characterized by the emission of ash, sand, and stones. There was no significant impact reported, except for the initial signs of volcanic activity like earthquake shocks​​.1963-64 Eruption: This was one of Indonesia's largest and most devastating eruptions. It involved loud explosions, lava flows, and massive pyroclastic flows, resulting in the death of an estimated 1,100–1,500 people. Additional 200 people were killed by cold lahars caused by heavy rainfall after the eruption. A second eruption in May caused further fatalities and minor eruptions continued for almost a year. The eruption also had global effects on temperatures and displaced the US transport ship USAT Liberty​​.2017-2019 Eruptions: This period was marked by significant seismic activity and eruptions, leading to the evacuation of about 122,500 people. The eruptions included phreatic and magmatic activities, with ash clouds reaching up to 9,144 meters altitude and affecting air traffic. The eruptions led to many people being housed as temporary refugees, the closure of Ngurah Rai International Airport, and the disruption of international flights. The activity in 2018 and 2019 also interrupted air traffic and affected nearby communities"},{"question":"A ko le fagi le SARS, ṣugbọn atunṣe yoo ba iṣẹ wọn-Buhari","answer":"Bi awọn ọmọ Naijiria ṣe n pariwo, ti wọn n ṣe iwọde kiri loriṣiiriiṣi lati fẹhonu wọn han, Aarẹ Muhammed Buhari ti sọ pe awọn ko ni i fagi le ẹka ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to n gbogun ti idigunjale ati iwa ọdaran, SARS, gẹgẹ bi awọn kan ṣe fẹ, atunto ni yoo ba ẹka ileeṣẹ agbofinronaa.Ninu ọrọ ẹ lori ikanni abẹyẹfo (twitter) lo ti sọ pe, “Emi ati ọga ọlọpaa patapata ti ṣepade, ohun ti a si jọ fẹnu ko le lori ni pe a oo ṣatunṣe sọrọ awọn ọlọpaa SARS. Gbogbo ohun to n ṣẹlẹ pata, paapaa awọn iwa itiniloju tawọn ẹṣọ agbofinro hu, ni a n gbọ gbogbo bo ṣe n Iọ, bẹẹ ni mo fẹẹ fi da yin loju pe ọrẹ araalu ni ọlọpaa gbọdọ jẹ, wọn si ni lati mojuto araalu daadaa.”Aarẹ Buhari  tun fi kun un pe oun ti paṣẹ fun ọga ọlọpaa lati wa gbogbo awọn to n huwa ti ko bojumu jade ninu iṣẹ ọlọpaa, ki wọn si foju winna ofin gẹgẹ bo ti yẹ‘Mo fẹ ki awọn eeyan orilẹ-ede yii ni suuru, gbogbo ohun ti wọn n beere fun la oo gbe igbesẹ lori ẹ gẹgẹ bi wọn ti ṣe lẹtọọ lati fẹhonu wọn han lori ohun ti wọn ko ba fẹ.’ Buhari lo sọ bẹẹ.O ni ohun toun mọ daju ni pe ojulowo ẹṣọ agbofinro lọkunrin ati lobinrin ni Naijiria ni, bẹẹ ni wọn ki i fiṣẹ wọn ṣere lori eto abo, ati pe ijọba yoo tubọ maa kun wọn lọwọ daadaa.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, lati nnkan bii ọjọ meloo kan sẹyin ni iwọde ti n waye kaakiri orilẹ-ede yii, ninu ẹ naa lẹmi araalu ti bọ, ti ọlọpaa paapaa naa ku, nigba ti awọn eeyan n sọ pe dandan ni ki ijọba ko awọn ẹṣọ SARS kuro nilẹ patapata."},{"question":"\\"Pasauliu netikiu, o Pasaka tikiu\\". Koks lietuvių poetas vieną savo eilėraščių baigė šiais žodžiais? Reikalingas tik vardas, pavardė nebūtina.","answer":"Henrikas"},{"question":"दूर शिक्षाका चुनौतीहरू र फाइदाहरू अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":": दूरी शिक्षाले लचिलोपन प्रदान गर्दछ तर सीमित सामाजिक अन्तरक्रिया जस्ता चुनौतीहरूको सामना गर्न सक्छ। लाभहरूमा पहुँच र सुविधा समावेश छ, जबकि चुनौतीहरूमा विद्यार्थी संलग्नता र प्रभावकारी सञ्चार कायम राख्नु समावेश छ।"},{"question":"ما هي الفئة التي تفرض الزكاة؟","answer":"\\tعلى الأغنياء"},{"question":"لدينا النص التالي: رغم الأحوال الاقتصادية التي تعيشها مصر في ظل أزمة انتشار فيروس كورونا، إلا أن الحكومة نجحت في شراء كمية إجمالية بلغت 3مليون و 520 ألف طن قمح من المزارعين، بزيادة قدرها 300 ألف طن عن موسم العام الماضي لاستخدامها في إنتاج الخبز البلدي المدعم. وكشفت خطة وزارة التموين والتجارة الداخلية تشكيل لجان دائمة لاستلام الأقماح المحلية بكافة أماكن التوريد قبل بداية الموسم، واستمر لمدة ثلاثة أشهر اعتبارا من 15 إبريل حتى 15 يوليو، وعلى مدار الثلاثة أشهر كانت كافة مواقع ولجان الاستلام تعمل دون توقف وعلي أكثر من وردية في عدد 450 نقطة استلام وتوريد. وتمكنت الوزارة في الحصول على القمح بعد الإعلان عن سعر عادل قبل بداية الموسم، حيث يتم استلام القمح بسعر 700 جنيه للأردب درجة نظافة 23.5 قيراط، و685 جنيها للأردب درجة نظافة 23 قيراطا، و670 جنيها، لأردب درجة نظافة 22.5 قيراط مما أدى الى تشجيع المزارعين على توريد الأقماح المحلى المخصصة لإنتاج الخبز البلدى المدعم. وقال الدكتور على المصيلحي، وزير التموين والتجارة الداخلية، أن الموسم الحالي يعد واحدا من أنجح مواسم التوريد للقمح المحلى نتيجة عدة عوامل أولها دعم رئيس الوزراء ووزير المالية من خلال توفير المبالغ المالية اللازمة أسبوعيا، وكذلك تكاتف كافة الأجهزة المعنية والعمل كفريق واحد. وأضاف وزير التموين، أن تحسن الظروف المناخية ساهم في زيادة ووفرة المحصول وبالتالي زيادة معدلات التوريد، فضلا عن زيادة السعات التخزينية ودخول 3 صوامع جديدة الخدمة، وسرعة سداد مستحقات المزارعين مما ساهم في زيادة معدلات التوريد، لافتا إلى أن معدل التوريد وصل إلى 3.5 مليون طن وبهذا يكون قد تم تحقيق المستهدف ويعد هذا الرقم أعلى معدل توريد منذ سنوات. وكشفت الوزارة أنه تم تسويق ما يقرب من مليون وستمائة وواحد وخمسين ألف طن ويعد ذلك من أعلى معدلات التسويق مقارنة بالسنوات السابقة وتم تخزين هذه الكميات بالكامل داخل صوامع الشركة المصرية القابضة للصوامع والتخزين، ويرجع ذلك إلي دخول ٣ صوامع جديدة الخدمة خلال موسم ٢٠٢٠ وهي صومعة عرب العليقات بالقليوبية، وصومعة الحمام بمطروح، وصومعة صان الحجر بالشرقية. ورغم جائحة كورونا إلا أنه تم اعداد جداول منظمة لعمليات استلام الأقماح لمنع التزاحم والتكدس أمام أماكن التوزيع بجانب تعقيم وتطهير السيارات المحملة للأقماح قبل دخولها الصوامع وأماكن التوريد الأمر الذى الى زيادة معدلات الاقبال على توريد الأقماح لصالح هيئة السلع التموينية . وكشفت منظمة الأمم المتحدة للأغذية والزراعة «فاو»، إن واردات مصر من القمح ارتفعت إلى 12 مليون طن سنويا لتصبح أكبر مستوردى هذه السلعة الاستراتيجية فى العالم، فيما سترتفع هذه الكميات إلى 15 مليون طن فى عام 2028.. قم بإنشاء عنوان مناسب.","answer":"رغم جائحة كورونا.. مصر تنجح في فى شراء 3.5 مليون طن قمح محلى لإنتاج الخبز البلدي."},{"question":"Kami ketawa terbahak-bahak apabila melihat adik menangis kerana takut melihat ________ di Zoo Negara.","answer":"gajah"},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Musi waChikunguru 21, 1919, hondo yakachinjwa zita kuti Crimean Rifle Division iyo mumazuva matanhatu yakaparadzwa ndokushandurwa zvakare kuva 58th Rifle Division. Sentence 2: Musi waJuly 21, 1919, uto rakaparadzwa ndokuchinjwa kuva Crimean Rifle Division, iyo yakatumidzwa zita rokuti 58th Rifle Division mumazuva matanhatu. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hungu kana kuti Aiwa?","answer":"Aiwa"},{"question":"জীববিজ্ঞান ক্লাসে শিক্ষক ভাস্কুলার বান্ডল পড়াতে গিয়ে প্রথমে জাইলেম ও পরে ফ্লোয়েম টিস্যু নিয়ে আলোচনা করেন। আলোচিত টিস্যুগুলো উদ্ভিদের পরিবহন প্রক্রিয়া সম্পন্ন করে— মন্তব্যটি বিশ্লেষণ করো।","answer":"উদ্দীপকে আলোচিত টিস্যুগুলো হলো জাইলেম ও ফ্লোয়েম। এরা একত্রে পরিবহন টিস্যুতন্ত্র গঠন করে পরিবহন প্রক্রিয়া সম্পন্ন করে।জাইলেম টিস্যু ট্রাকিড, ভেসেল, জাইলেম প্যারেনকাইমা ও জাইলেম ফাইবারের সমন্বয়ে গঠিত। ফ্লোয়েম টিস্যু সিভনল, সঙ্গীকোষ, ফ্লোয়েম ফাইবার ও ফ্লোয়েম প্যারেনকাইমা নিয়ে গঠিত। জাইলেম টিস্যুর ভেসেল উদ্ভিদের মূল হতে পানি ও পানিতে দ্রবীভূত খনিজ লবণ গাছের পাতা ও অন্যান্য সবুজ অংশে পরিবহন করে এবং সালোকসংশ্লেষণসহ অন্যান্য শারীরবৃত্তীয় কাজে বিশেষ ভূমিকা রাখে। ট্রাকিড কোষরসের পরিবহন ও অঙ্গকে দৃঢ়তা প্রদান করে। তবে কখনও খাদ্য সঞ্চয়ের কাজও এ টিস্যু করে থাকে। জাইলেম প্যারেনকাইমা খাদ্য সঞ্চয় ও পানি পরিবহন করে। জাইলেম ফাইবার উদ্ভিদে যান্ত্রিক শক্তি যোগায়। জাইলেম টিস্যু যেমন খাদ্যের কাঁচামাল পানি সরবরাহ করে তেমনি ফ্লোয়েম টিস্যু পাতায় প্রস্তুত খাদ্য উদ্ভিদ দেহের বিভিন্ন স্থানে পরিবহন করে। ফ্লোয়েম টিস্যুর সিভকোষ পাতায় প্রস্তুত খাদ্য উদ্ভিদ দেহের বিভিন্ন অংশ পরিবহন করে। ফ্লোয়েম প্যারেনকাইমা খাদ্য সঞ্চয় ও খাদ্য পরিবহনে সহায়তা করে। ফ্লোয়েম ফাইবার পাতায় উৎপাদিত শর্করা ও মূলে সঞ্চিত খাদ্য একই সাথে উদ্ভিদ দেহের উপরে ও নিচে পরিবহন করে।অতএব, বলা যায় যে, উদ্দীপকের আলোচিত টিস্যুগুলো অর্থাৎ জাইলেম ও ফ্লোয়েম উদ্ভিদের পরিবহন প্রক্রিয়া সম্পন্ন করে।"},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：什么是物联网？","answer":"答案：物联网是指通过互联网连接和交互的各种物理设备和对象，使它们能够收集和交换数据。"},{"question":"వ్యాధికి సంబంధించి సత్వర కారకాలు, దోహదపడే కారకాలు అంటే ఏమిటో వివరించండి.","answer":"ఏదైనా వ్యాధిని ఒక సూక్ష్మజీవి కలుగచేయును. అది ఆ వ్యాధి కలుగజేయుటకు కారణం కాబట్టి దానిని సత్వర కారకం అంటారు. ఆ సూక్ష్మజీవి ఆ వ్యక్తి శరీరంలో వ్యాధి పెంచుటకు కొన్ని కారకాలు అనగా అతనికి ఉన్న ఇతర శారీరక సమస్యలు కారణం అవుతాయి. వీటిని వ్యాధి దోహద కారకాలు అంటారు.ఉదా : ఒక వ్యక్తికి శరీరంలో వ్యాధి జనక జీవుల వలన అతనికి పుండ్లు వచ్చినాయి. కానీ అతనికి చక్కెర వ్యాధి ఉంది. అప్పుడు పుండ్లు ఇంకా ఎక్కువగా పెరుగుతాయి. పుండ్లు రావడానికి కారణమైన వ్యాధి జనకజీవులు సత్వర కారకాలు అయితే, చక్కెర వ్యాధి పుండ్లు పెరుగుటకు దోహద కారకాలు."},{"question":"Owo epo bẹntiroolu yoo tun lọ soke lẹẹkan si i o","answer":"Ijọba apapọ ti sọ pe iye tawọn araalu n ra epo bẹntiroolu yoo tun lọ soke lẹẹkan si i.Ọgbẹni Timipre Sylva, ẹni ti ṣe minisita kekere fun ọrọ epo bẹntiroolu ti sọ pe ki awọn eeyan orilẹ-ede yii maa mura silẹ fun afikun iye ti wọn n ra epo bẹntiroolu, bi iye ti wọn n ra agba epo rọbi ṣe gbowo lori bayii lọja agbaye.Minisita yii sọ pe epo rọbi ti di ọgọta dọla (60) agba kan lagbaaye, ati pe ti ọrọ ba ti ri bayii, a jẹ pe iye ti awọn ọmọ Naijiria n ra jala epo bẹntiroolu yoo kuro ni iye ti wọn ra a, yoo tun wọn si i.Ni bayii, iye ti wọn n ra jala kan wa laarin ọgọjọ naira (N160) si naira marun-un-din-laaadọsan-an (N165). Nigba ti epo rọbi wa ni dọla mẹtalelogoji (43) ni nnkan bii oṣu mẹrin sẹyin ni wọn ṣe agbekalẹ ọhun.Nibi ipade apero kan ti wọn ṣe niluu Abuja ni Sylva ti ta awọn ọmọ Naijriia lolobo pe iye ti wọn n ra jala epo bẹntiroolu yoo tun lọ soke lẹẹkan si i.O ni idi ti owo ọhun yoo fi kuro ni iye tawọn eeyan n ra a bayii ni pe ijọba Buhari ko ni in lọkan, bẹẹ ni ko tun si ninu eto iṣuna ọdun 2021 yii, lati seto iranwọ lori iye ti wọn yoo maa ta epo. O ni bo tilẹ jẹ pe owo gọbọi ti wọn n ta epo rọbi yoo tun pawo wọle fun ijọba, sibẹ yoo ṣoro ki ijọba tun maa na ere ẹ yii sori eto iranwọ lori iye tawọn eeyan yoo maa ra jala epo bẹntiroolu.Timipre Sylva sọ pe ohun idunnu ni pe orilẹ-ede yii yoo tun pawo repẹtẹ lori epo rọbi ẹ, ṣugbọn awọn eeyan orilẹ-ede yii naa gbọdọ gbaradi lati ra jala epo ju eyi ti wọn n ra a bayii.Ṣa o, Aarẹ ọkan ninu ẹgbẹ awọn oṣiṣẹ ni Naijiria, Trade Union Congress, Quadri Ọlalẹyẹ, ti bu ẹnu atẹ lu ohun ti minisita yii sọ, bẹẹ lo sọ pe ko si ọrọ apọnle kankan ninu ohun to sọ kalẹ naa pe epo yoo tun wọn si i ni Naijiria.O ni, tidunnu tidunnu ni ijọba Naijiria fi maa n sare kede awọn eto to le mu aye nira fawọn eeyan orilẹ-ede yii, ṣugbọn ti wọn ki i kọbi ara si ohun to le mu idẹrun ba wọn. Bakan naa lo fi kun un pe ijọba kan ti ko laaanu ni ijọba Buhari, ati pe o foju han daadaa pe awọn to n ṣejọba lasiko yii ko bikita bi nnkan ṣe nira fawọn ọmọ Naijiria bayii."},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut:Ikhwan mempunyai polisi insurans perubatan dengan peruntukan deduktibel sebanyak RM1 000dan penyertaan peratusan ko-insurans 85/15 dalam polisinya. Baru-baru ini, dia menjalanipembedahan hati dan bil perubatannya ialah RM120 000. Berapakah kos bayaran yang ditangungoleh syarikat insurans?A.) RM 17 850B.) RM 18 000C.) RM 101 150D.) RM 102 000","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C.) RM 101 150Jumlah kos perubatan =RM120 000Kos perubatan selepas deduktibel= RM120 000-RM1000=RM119 000Kos yang ditanggung oleh syarikat insurans= RM119000*(85/100)=RM 101 150"},{"question":"Miten ilmanpainetta mitataan merellä?","answer":"Monet rahti- ja muut laivat on varustettu automaattisilla sääasemilla, jotka välitettävät tietonsa kansallisiin meteorologisiin keskuksiin. Sääsanomissa on mukana laivan sijaintitieto, joten niiden avulla saadaan selville pistekohtaiset tiedot ilmanpaineesta."},{"question":"අදේවවාදය ආගමක්ද?","answer":"අදේවවාදය වැනි ඕනෑම විශ්වාස පද්ධතියක් ආගමක් ලෙස වර්ග කිරීමට අප උත්සාහ කිරීමට පෙර ආගම නිර්වචනය කිරීම ප්‍රයෝජනවත් වනු ඇත. ආගම පිළිබඳ ශබ්දකෝෂ නිර්වචනයකට පහත සඳහන් දේ ඇතුළත් වේ:1. විශ්වයේ හේතුව, ස්වභාවය සහ අරමුණ පිළිබඳ විශ්වාස එකතුවකි, විශේෂයෙන් විශ්වය අධිමානුෂික නියෝජිතයෙකු හෝ නියෝජිතයෙකුගේ නිර්මාණයක් ලෙස දකින විට. බොහෝ විට මානව කටයුතු සහ චාරිත්‍ර හෝ භක්ති චාරිත්‍ර සඳහා සදාචාරාත්මක ආචාර ධර්ම පද්ධතියක් ඇතුළත් වේ.2. පුද්ගලයන් හෝ නිකායන් ගණනාවක් විසින් එකඟ වූ විශ්වාසයන් සහ පිළිවෙත්වල නිශ්චිත මූලික එකතුවකි.3. යම් විශ්වාසයන් හෝ පිළිවෙත් එකතුවකට අනුගත වන පුද්ගල කණ්ඩායම.4. ඇදහිල්ල හෝ ආගමික විශ්වාසයන් පිළිපැදීම චාරිත්‍රානුකූලව පිළිපැදීම.5. පුද්ගලයෙකු විශ්වාස කරන සහ කැපවීමෙන් අනුගමනය කරන දෙයක්; හෘදය සාක්ෂිය හෝ ආචාර ධර්ම පිළිබඳ කාරණයක්.මෙම නිර්වචනවලට අනුව අදේවවාදය සැබවින්ම ආගමක් ලෙස සැලකිය හැකිය."},{"question":"Na mitologia egípcia quem é Nut?","answer":"Filha dos irmãos Shu e Tefnut, Nut é a deusa dos céus."},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Keji)","answer":"Awọn onileejọsin gbogbo yoo bẹrẹ ijọsin wọn pada lati ọjọ Jimọ ọsẹ yii. Awọn onimọṣalaaṣi yoo lọ si mọṣalaasi, awọn oniṣọọṣi naa yoo si lọ. Nigba iṣoro bayii, ko si ohun to dara ju bii ki eeyan ke pe Ọlorun. Iṣọro to ba de ti eeyan ko raaye ke pe Ọlọrun, tabi ṣe akojọpọ lati sin Ọlọrun, iṣoro nla gbaa ni o. Iru ẹ si ni ti Korona yii. Ni ọpọ igba ni awọn ẹlẹsin Kristẹni ati awọn ti Musulumi ti ba ijọba ja loriṣiiriṣii, awọn mi-in si sọ pe bi awọn ba lọ si ile ijọsin, ti Korona ba mu awọn nibẹ, ti awọn ku, o da awọn loju pe ọrun rere lawọn n lọ. Wọn ni ki ijọba fi awọn silẹ ki Korona pa awọn, ki wọn ṣaa ti jẹ ki awọn ṣejọsin fun Ọlọrun awọn. Ki i ṣe pe ijọba Naijiria nikan ni, ohun to n ṣẹlẹ kari aye nigba naa ni, ati oku to n ku, ti gbogbo eeyan n gbọroyin rẹ, ko si ijọba gidi kan ti yoo laju silẹ ti yoo fẹ ki awọn eeyan ku rẹpẹtẹ bi a ti gbọ ti wọn n ku ni Amẹrika, ku ni Brazil ati awọn orilẹ-ede mi-in bẹẹ yii, nitori bi kinni naa ba bẹrẹ, o le re kọja ibi ti awọn eeyan foju si patapata. Ṣugbọn nnkan naa n lọ silẹ diẹdiẹ bayii, o si da bii pe eyin ajakalẹ arun naa ti kan, paapaa ni awọn orilẹ-ede bii ti ọdọ wa nibi. Ajẹsara ati bi oju ọjọ ti ṣe maa n ri lọdọ tiwa yii ti jẹ ko han pe kinni naa ko ni i lagbara rẹpẹtẹ kan lọdọ tiwa yii, paapaa bi a ba le tẹle awọn ofin keekeeke tijọba ṣe. Aṣẹ ti ijọba Eko pa yii, pe ki awọn eeyan bẹrẹ ijọsin wọn dara gan-an ni, yoo jẹ ki ọkan onikaluku fuyẹ, nigba to jẹ pupọ ninu wa lo nigbagbọ ninu agbara adura ati ikepe-Ọlọrun ẹni. Kaluku yoo ribi gbadura bayii, yoo si le fi ẹnu ara rẹ tọrọ ohun to ba n fẹ. Nidii eyi, ijọba ti ṣe tiwọn o, wọn si ti ṣe bo ṣe yẹ ki wọn ṣe loootọ. Eyi to ku ku sọwọ araalu o. Ka ma ro pe ko si arun yii loootọ, Korona yii wa, o wa daadaa paapaa. Ṣugbọn awọn miiran ninu wa ti jẹ oriṣiiriṣii ewe ati egbo, bẹẹ la ni okun-ara to lagbara, to le pa arunkarun to ba wọ agọ ara wa. Ṣugbọn ki i ṣe gbogbo wa lo ri bẹẹ fun, awọn mi-in wa laarin wa to jẹ hẹgẹhẹgẹ lara wọn. Wọn ko ni ajẹsara to to, ara wọn ko si ni okun to le koju iru arun bẹẹ. Eyi lo ṣe jẹ to ba kọlu wọn, ọrun lẹrọ ni. Ṣugbọn a le dena ẹ, a le kapa ẹ, nigba ti a ba ti tẹle ofin ti wọn fun wa. Ka bo imu wa, ka si jinna si ara wa daadaa nibi ti a ba ti n ṣe ijọsin wa. Korona ko ni i mu wa, bẹẹ ni a ko ni i ba wọn ku iku ajọku, ṣugbọn ki awa naa ṣọra wa o.Ni Ọjọruu to kọja lọ, ile-ẹjo ko-tẹ-mi-lọrun to jokoo si ilu Ilọrin dajọ pe ẹgbẹ APC ko ni oludije fun ipo ile-igbimọ aṣofin lati agbegbe Ilọrin South, ninu ibo ti wọn di ninu oṣu kẹta, ọdun to kọja, nitori bẹẹ, ki wọn ṣebura fun ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP to wọle ibo naa, iyẹn Rahem Agboọla, ki wọn si le Azeez Elewu ti ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC ti fi tipatipa gbe sori ijokoo naa kuro nile-igbimọ kia. Iyẹn nikan kọ, gbogbo owo-oṣu ti ọkunrin APC yii ti gba ni wọn ni ko da pada, ko da a pada, nitori owo ti ko tọ si i lo n gba lati ọjọ yii, ko si kinni kan to kan an lati jokoo sile-igbimọ aṣofin Kwara. Ọrọ yii ko ba ti da bayii, bo ba jẹ alaga ile-igbimọ aṣofin naa, Yakubu Danladi, tẹle ofin ile-ẹjọ, to si tẹle ofin Naijiria. Ṣugbọn ọkunrin naa nigbagbọ pe nigba to ti jẹ APC lo n ṣejọba, to si jẹ awọn ti awọn wa ninu APC lawọn n tẹ oju ofin mọle yii, ko si ohun ti ẹnikan le ṣe fawọn. Ṣugbọn ọrọ ko ri bẹẹ, eto ijọba awa-ara-wa ko si ri bẹẹ rara. Lori ofin ati ilana ẹtọ onikaluku ni ijọba alagbada da le, o yatọ si ijọba ologun, nibi ti olori ologun kan le maa ṣe ohun to ba fẹ. Ile-ejọ akọkọ ti da ẹjọ yii tipẹ, lati inu oṣu kọkanla, ni 2019, ṣugbọn awọn Danladi ko gba, wọn bẹrẹ si i pọn irọ lewe, wọn ni awọn ti gbe ẹjọ naa lọ sile-ẹjọ ko-tẹ-mi-lọrun, wọn ni ki Azeez Elewu ti ki i ṣe oun lo wọle ibo jokoo sileegbimọ nibẹ, ko maa gbowo iṣẹ tẹnikan ko ran an. Awọn eeyan bii Danladi yii ko dara ni ipo nla, wọn ko dara ni ipo ti o ba jẹ tilu, nitori wọn yoo huwa ti yoo ba ibẹ jẹ ni. Gẹgẹ bi ile-ẹjọ ko-tẹ-mi-lọrun ti waa wi yii, olori ile-igbimọ aṣofin kan ko lẹtọọ lati ma ṣe ibura fun ọmọ ile-igbimọ yoowu ti ile-ẹjọ ba ti fi aṣẹ si pe ki wọn ṣe ibura fun. Ohun to n dun Danladi ni pe Agboọla nikan ni yoo jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP nile-igbimọ naa. Ṣugbọn ki lo kan wọn ninu iyẹn, ile-igbimọ aṣofin ko yẹ ko jẹ fun ti ẹgbẹ oṣelu kan, fun ti gbogbo Kwara lo yẹ ko jẹ, ilọsiwaju ati idagbasoke ipinlẹ Kwara lo yẹ ki wọn maa wa, ki i ṣe ti ẹgbẹ oṣelu tiwọn. Ẹgbẹ oṣelu kan yoo de, yoo ṣejọba, yoo lọ, ẹgbẹ oṣelu mi-in yoo si tun de. Ṣugbọn ipinlẹ ati awọn eeyan Kwara yoo wa nibẹ titi lae ni. Ki waa ni alaga ile-igbimọ kan yoo tori oṣelu fẹẹ fa idagbasoke awọn eeyan ibẹ sẹyin, nitori kin ni! Ẹ wo o, ẹ bara yin sọhun-un wayi ṣaa, kẹ ẹ ṣebura fẹni to wọle ibo, ko le maa ṣe ojuṣe rẹ lọ. Abi ta lo sọ pe ọkunrin naa ko le pada waa dọmọ APC! Abi awọn oloṣelu asiko yii kọ! Ṣiọ!Ko pọ ninu awọn gomina ti wọn n gba ijọba ti awọn pẹlu awọn ti wọn fi ipo naa silẹ maa tun n ṣe ọrẹ ara wọn. Ṣugbọn ti Rotimi Akeredolu ati Oluṣẹgun Mimiko yatọ, nitori lati ọjọ ti Mimiko ti lọ, ko sẹni kan to gbọ ọrọ odi nipa rẹ, tabi nipa ijọba rẹ, lati ẹnu Akeredolu ati ijọba tuntun to n ṣe. Eleyii yatọ si awọn ohun kan to n ṣẹlẹ ni ipinlẹ mi-in gan-an, nibi to ti jẹ bii ọdun kan akọkọ, ẹjọ ni wọn yoo maa fi ṣe, wa-loni-in, wa-lọla, ni kootu ko si ni i jẹ ki ẹni to wọle naa tete raaye ṣejọba. Ṣugbọn ohun gbogbo lọ wọọrọ l’Ondo ni ti pe Akeredolu ko tu idi ọrẹ rẹ wo.  Bo ba jẹ o tu idi rẹ wo ni, ko si oloṣelu ti wọn yoo yẹdi ẹ wo ti wọn ko ni i ba nnkan kan, kinni ọhun yoo si maa run ni. Wọn ti wa lẹnu iyẹn lati bii ọdun kẹrin sẹyin bayii, afi bi ibo ṣe de ti awọn kan ni Akeredolu loun yoo fi ẹjọ Mimiko sun EFCC. Dajudaju, irọ leleyii, nitori bi Akeredolu ba fẹẹ ṣe iyẹn ni, ki i ṣe lẹyin to ti lo ọdun mẹrin nile ijọba ni yoo maa wa ọna lati fi ẹjọ Mimiko sun, iba ti ṣe bẹẹ tipẹ, Mimiko iba si ti maa lọ maa bọ lọdọ awọn EFCC Abuja. Mimiko naa yoo mọ iyẹn ṣaa, yoo mọ pe eyi tawọn eeyan n sọ yii ko le ri bẹẹ, bi ọrọ kan ba si ru u loju, ko lọ sọdọ Akeredolu funra ẹ, ko si wadii ododo. Awọn kan ni wọn n lo orukọ rẹ, wọn si fẹẹ ko kọyin si Akeredolu lasiko ibo to n bo yii ni. Bawọn oloṣelu ṣe ri niyẹn, ko si ohun ti wọn ko le ṣe lati ba nnkan jẹ, to ba ti di ọrọ idibo bayii. Eyi fi han pe iṣẹ nla ṣi wa lọwọ Akeredolu funra ẹ, o ti lọ si Eko lọdọ Tinubu, ṣugbọn iṣẹ wa nilẹ l’Ondo, ti yoo ṣe, bi bẹẹ kọ, to ba pẹ diẹ bayii, wọn yoo yi i lagbo da sina ni. N lo ba tan!Ọrọ apara ni, ko jẹ jẹ bẹẹ. Ṣugbọn to ba waa lọọ jẹ bẹẹ, a jẹ pe Agboọla Ajayi, Igbakeji Gomina ipinlẹ Ondo, ko mọ eyi to kan rara. Ariwo to gba gbogbo ipinlẹ naa kan lọsẹ to kọja ni pe Agboọla n lọ sinu ẹgbẹ oṣelu ZLP lọsẹ yii, wọn lo ni nibẹ loun yoo ti du ipo gomina oun. Ko too digba yii, nigba ti ọkunrin naa ba wọn du ipo yii ninu ẹgbẹ PDP ti ko wọle, ohun to sọ ni pe ko si ibi ti oun fẹẹ  lọ, oun yoo wa ninu ẹgbẹ naa lati le jọ gbajọba lọwọ Akeredolu ni. Ohun to ba fi waa mu Agboọla gbagbe ileri to ṣe yii, to waa gba ẹgbẹ oṣelu mi-in lọ, to ni oun fẹẹ du ipo gomina, a jẹ pe oun gan-an ko lojuti kan bayii, awọn ara ipinlẹ Ondo yoo si fi ọwọ ara wọn ṣe ara wọn lasan ni ti wọn ba dibo wọn fun un.To ba ṣe eleyii, yoo fi han pe ki i ṣe pe Akeredolu ni ko dara, oun gan-an ni ko daa, oun ni wọn fi jọba to tun n wẹ ọṣẹ awure, oun ni ipo to wa ko tẹ lọrun, to jẹ ipo ti ọga rẹ wa gan-an lo fẹ. Iwa bẹẹ ko daa, iwa ole ati ojukokoro ni. Ẹnikẹni to ba si ni iwa ole, ojukokoro ati iwọra bayii, bi iru wọn ba de ipo gomina, ilu naa yoo fọ mọ wọn lori ni. Nigba to jẹ ki i ṣe ifẹ awọn araalu lo gbe wọn debẹ, to jẹ nitori ole ti awọn fẹẹ ja ni. Tabi kin ni Agboọla yoo tun sọ pe oun n wa kiri. Ọran ni wọn fi n ṣe gomina ni. Bo ṣe rọrun to, oun naa lo sa lọ sinu PDP ti wọn ko le fa a kalẹ ko du ipo gomina lorukọ wọn, ti wọn ko tun le fi i ṣe igbakeji yẹn, bẹẹ lo n sọ pe oun ni baba oloṣelu ipinlẹ Ondo, oun naa yoo ti ri i bayii. Bẹ ẹ ba moju ẹ, ẹ jẹ yaa sọ fun un ko jokoo ẹ jẹẹ. Bi bẹẹ kọ, abuku oniyọrọ ni yoo kan nibi to n lọ yii, yẹyẹ ti wọn yoo si fi i ṣe, yoo ju ti baba to ba iyawo ọmọ rẹ sun lọ.Bi ọmọde ba ṣe bii ọmọde, agba a si maa ṣe iṣe agba. Igba mi-in, ki i ṣe ọjọ ori ni wọn fi maa n ni eeyan n ṣe bii ọmọde, ihuwasi a maa fa a nigba mi-in, koda, ki ọjọ ori eeyan pọ rẹpẹtẹ. Igbakeji Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Alaaji Rauf Ọlaniyan, lo fi iwa agba yii han lọsẹ to kọja yii. Awọn oniroyin tọwọ bọ ọ lẹnu, wọn fẹ ko sọ kinni kan lori ohun to ṣẹlẹ si i nile awọn Ajimọbi lẹẹmejeeji to lọ sibẹ. Ṣugbọn kaka ki Ọlaniyan sọrọ ti yoo tun da nnkan ru, tabi ti yoo fọ ọrọ loju debi ti awọn oloṣelu ati awọn oniroyin to n wa ohun ti wọn yoo jẹ ni tiwọn yoo fi maa sọrọ sijọba wọn, o ni awọn ti mọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ ti iyawo Ajimọbi fi binu bẹẹ. Njẹ ki lo de to fi binu bẹẹ, o ni iku ọkọ rẹ lo ka a lara, eeyan ko le sọ iru nnkan to to bẹẹ yẹn nu ko ma bara jẹ, bi ọkọ ẹni ba ku, adanu nla ni. Pẹlu iru ọrọ yii, o daju pe ohun yoowu ti obinrin naa ibaa ṣe fun Ọlaniyan, o ti gbe oju fo o, o si ti mọ pe ko si ohun ti ẹni ti ọfọ ba ṣẹ ko le ṣe. O daju pe oju iyawo Ajimọbi naa yoo ti walẹ bayii, oun naa yoo si ti ri awọn aṣiṣe rẹ, yoo ti ri i pe ọrọ oṣelu nibi to de duro, ati awọn abanida a ti yoo maa tiiyan gbọn-ọn gbọn-ọn nitori ki awọn le ri ibi ba wọnu ọrọ fun imọtara wọn nikan ko ni i ba ni debẹ mọ bi ọrọ naa ba burẹkẹ. Ajimọbi ti lọ, iwa rere to ba hu silẹ lawọn ẹbi ati awọn ọmọ rẹ yoo jẹ. Ṣugbọn kekere niyẹn, iwa rere ti awọn to ba fi silẹ ba n hu bayii ni yoo jẹ ki ounjẹ naa pẹ lẹnu wọn. Ki iyawo Ajimọbi naa mọ eyi, ọwọ diẹdiẹ lara n fẹ o."},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన సినిమా పాటలోని ఒక భాగం యొక్క సాహిత్యంపై విశ్లేషణ చెయ్యండిశుభగాత్రి గిరిరాజపుత్రి.. అభినేత్రి శర్వార్ధగాత్రిసర్వార్ధ సంధాత్రి జగదేక జనయిత్రి చంద్రప్రభా ధవళకీర్తిచతుర్బాహు సంరక్షిత శిక్షిత చతుర్బశాంతర భువనపాలినికుంకుమరాగశోభిని కుసుమ బాణ సంశోభినిమౌనసుహాసిని… గానవినోదిని.. భగవతి.. పార్వతి… దేవీ","answer":"శుభగాత్రి = మంగళకరమైన మోము కలది; చల్లని చూపులతో తన పిల్లలను అనుగ్రహించెడిది. గిరిరాజ పుత్రి = పర్వత రాజు  ఐన హిమవంతుని కుమార్తె.  అభినేత్రి  = ఎటువంటి కార్యాన్నయినా తన చూపులద్వారా సిద్ధింప చేయగలది.  శర్వార్ధగాత్రి = శర్వుడు అంటే శివుడు కదా ఆయనలో సగమైనది అంటే అర్ధనారీశ్వర తత్వంలో విరాజిల్లునది.(శర్వ + అర్ధ + గాత్రి – శర్వార్ధగాత్రి) సర్వార్ధ = అన్ని భావములను సంధాత్రి = భరించునది అన్ని భావములను తన మోములో పలికించునది అని అర్ధం. జగదేక = ప్రపంచానికి అంతటికి ఒకే ఒక  జనయిత్రి = తల్లి – ఈ విశ్వం లోని సకల జీవ రాశులకు జన్మనిచ్చిన తల్లి. చంద్రప్రభా = చంద్రుని కళలంతటి  ధవళకీర్తి = తెల్లని అనగా ఎటువంటి కల్మషమైన పాప పంకిలములు లేనటువంటి కీర్తితో విలసిల్లేది. చతుర్బాహు = నాలుగు చేతులతో సంరక్షిత = సంరక్షించేది అనగా కాపాడునది  శిక్షిత = శిక్షించునది  చతుర్బశాంతర = నాలుగు భుజముల మధ్యన ఉన్న  భువనపాలిని = ప్రపంచమును పాలించునది. అంటే తన నాలుగు చేతులతో దుష్టులను శిక్షిస్తూ శిష్టులను రక్షిస్తూ తన నాఱుగు భుజములు అనగా నాలుగు దిక్కులు మధ్యనున్న ఈ విశ్వముని పాలించెడిది. కుంకుమరాగశోభిని = ఎర్రని కుంకుమ వర్ణముతో భాసిల్లే సర్వమంగళ మూర్తి, కుసుమ బాణ సంశోభిని = కుసుమ పుష్పముల బాణములతో శోభిల్లునది.  కుసుమ అనేది ఒక ప్రత్యేకమైన పుష్పం. దీని మొదటి ఆవాస ప్రాంతం ఐయా మత్తు ఆఫ్రికా, అలాగే మధ్యభారతం నుండి తూర్పుమధ్యధరాప్రాంతపుదాటి యుథోపియా వరకు వ్యాప్తిచెందినది.  ఇది చాలా కొమ్మలు కలిగిన ఏకవార్షిక గుల్మం. దీని ఆకులు వాడిగా ఉన్న ముండ్లు కలిగిఉంటాయి. ఈ మొక్కలు 30 నుండి 36 అంగుళాలఎత్తు వరకూ పెరుగుతాయి. కుసుమ పూలు గుండ్రని ఆకారము కలిగి పచ్చటి పసుపు, నారింజ, ఎరుపు లేక తెలుపు రంగులలో ఉంటాయి. ఇవి ఒక్కో కొమ్మకు ఒకటి నుండి ఐదు చొప్పున వస్తాయి. ఒక్కో పువ్వులో 15-20 గింజలు ఉంటాయి. ఈ మొక్క యొక్క తల్లి వేరు దృఢంగా ఉండడం వలన కుసుమ ఎటువంటి వాతావరణాన్నైనా తట్టుకో గలదు.  ఇప్పుడు అర్ధాన్ని గమనిస్తే ఎటువంటి పరిస్ధితులనైనా తన కుసుమ బాణములతో ఛేదించి మంగళకరమైన శుభ సంపదలను ఇవ్వగలిగిన తల్లి.  మౌనసుహాసిని… గానవినోదిని.. భగవతి.. పార్వతి.  యోగ ముద్రలో అనవసరమైన వాటిని దూరం చేసి మౌనముగా మంగళప్రదమైన నవ్వుతో, సంగీతానికి పరవశించే భగవత్ స్వరూపముగా ప్రకాశించే తల్లి.  "},{"question":"Trả lời câu hỏi sau bằng cách chọn câu trả lời phù hợp trong các câu dưới đây.Câu hỏi: Hồ Ba Bể có tên địa phương là gì?A. Slam PéB. Pé LùC. Pé Lèng","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng: A. Slam PéGiải thích: Tên gọi hồ Ba Bể theo tiếng địa phương là \\"Slam Pé\\" (ba hồ). Đây là tên gọi chung của ba hồ thông nhau gồm Pé Lầm, Pé Lù và Pé Lèng. Hồ Ba Bể được hình thành cách đây hơn 200 triệu năm, do cuộc kiến tạo lục địa Đông Nam Á cuối kỷ Camri đã đưa một khối nước khổng lồ với bề mặt xấp xỉ 5 triệu m2 và chiều dày hơn 30 m lên lưng chừng vùng núi đá vôi, tạo ra hồ Ba Bể.Toàn bộ diện tích của Hồ Ba Bể nằm trong địa giới xã Nam Mẫu, huyện Ba Bể, tỉnh Bắc Kạn. Hồ cách thành phố Bắc Kạn 70 km về phía Tây Bắc, nằm trong Vườn quốc gia Ba Bể, ở độ cao khoảng 145 m so với mực nước biển, được bao bọc bởi những dãy núi đá vôi có nhiều hang động và những suối ngầm. Độ sâu trung bình của hồ là 20-25 m vào mùa mưa nhưng có thể xuống xấp xỉ 10 m vào mùa khô. Hồ được cấp nước bởi hai con sông nhỏ là sông Chợ Lèng và sông Nam Cường rồi đổ ra sông Năng. Có hai đảo nhỏ nổi lên giữa hồ là đảo An Mã và đảo Bà Góa."},{"question":"बर्सेनि राष्ट्रपति परिवर्तन हुने देश कुन हो ?","answer":"बर्सेनि राष्ट्रपति परिवर्तन हुने देश स्विजरल्यान्ड हो । स्विस कन्फेडेरेसनका अध्यक्ष, जसलाई कन्फेडेरेसनको अध्यक्ष, संघीय अध्यक्ष वा स्विट्जरल्याण्डको अध्यक्षको रूपमा पनि चिनिन्छ, स्विट्जरल्याण्डको सात सदस्यीय संघीय परिषद्को प्रमुख, देशको कार्यकारी शाखा हो। संघीय सभाले एक वर्षको लागि निर्वाचित गरेको पदाधिकारीले संघीय परिषद्को बैठकको अध्यक्षता गर्ने र विशेष प्रतिनिधित्वको जिम्मेवारी लिन्छ।"},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada teka-teki yang susah ini: Dalam banyak-banyak ikan, ikan apa yang maknyah?","answer":"Jawapan: Ikan patin bakar. (I don't get it.)"},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:نجلاء المرزوقيتقول نجلاء المرزوقي (34 عامًا)، وهي رائدة أعمال حاصلة على درجة الماجستير في إدارة المخاطر، وتعيش في","answer":"نيس- إن \\"الناس ينظرون إلينا بغرابة؛ عندما تتحدث وسائل الإعلام عن (الانفصالية) فإنها تخلق صورة مخادعة، ويمكنني رؤية ذلك في عيون الناس. صحيح أننا نرتدي الحجاب، ولكن لدينا عقل تحت هذا الحجاب، إنه العقل الذي يسمح لي بالتواصل والتحدث وإبداء مشاعر الحب؛ نحن بشر بالحجاب أو من دونه\\"."},{"question":"60 को 0.4 द्वारा विभाजित नतिजा पत्ता लगाउनुहोस्।","answer":"60 भाग 0.4 बराबर 150 हो।"},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο: Πρώτος του δάσκαλος ήταν ιερεύς ονόματι Πέτρος από τη Μύκονο, εφημέριος του ναού των Λουτρών, Αγ.Πέτρου. Κατά τις ημέρες της σφαγής της Χίου","answer":"το 1822, αιχμαλωτίστηκε από τους Τούρκους και πουλήθηκε πρώτα στο σκλαβοπάζαρο της Κωνσταντινούπολης, έπειτα του Αϊδινίου και τέλος της Αλεξανδρείας, όπου το 1828 τον αγόρασε έμπορος αποικιακών από την Τεργέστη, που εκτίμησε τα πνευματικά του χαρίσματα και τον είχε σαν παιδί του."},{"question":"چند مکان از ایران را نام ببرید؟","answer":"تخت سلیمان، کاخ گلستان تهران، میدان نقش جهان،  کاخ سعد آباد، غار نمکدان قشم، ماسوله، باغ ارم شیراز"},{"question":"\\"තමාගේ යහපත පමණක් සලකන\\"  යන්නට වඩාත්ම ගැලපෙන කෙටි පදය කුමක්ද? (ඔබට භාවිතා  කල හැක්කේ එක වචනයක් පමණි)","answer":"\\"ආත්මාරතකාමී\\" වඩාතම ගැලපෙන තනි පදයයි."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Quan hệ Việt - Mỹ được bình thường hóa từ tháng 7/1995 và nâng cấp lên Đối tác toàn diện tháng 7/2013, với nhiều chuyến thăm cấp cao của lãnh đạo hai nước đã diễn ra. Hai bên hợp tác trên mọi lĩnh vực, từ chính trị - ngoại giao, ","answer":"kinh tế, giáo dục, đến khoa học - công nghệ, quốc phòng - an ninh.Thương mại Việt - Mỹ đạt hơn 123,86 tỷ USD năm 2022, tăng 11% so với năm 2021, và đạt hơn 51,2 tỷ USD trong 6 tháng đầu năm 2023. Mỹ là thị trường xuất khẩu lớn nhất và đối tác thương mại lớn thứ hai của Việt Nam, trong khi Việt Nam là đối tác thương mại lớn thứ 8 của Mỹ trên thế giới, lớn nhất trong ASEAN."},{"question":"Tại sao mỗi khi khóc xong mắt chúng ta lại sưng","answer":"Mỗi khi khóc xong mắt chúng ta lại sưng do 4 nguyên nhân chính: 1. Nước mắt bốc hơi hoặc hấp thụ trực tiếp xuống mũi: Khi tình trạng trên xảy ra trong một thời gian dài, mắt bạn sẽ dần sưng lên nếu nước mắt tràn xuống và chảy ra từ mũi.2. Dụi mắt khi khóc: Đây cũng là một trong những nguyên nhân khiến mắt sưng đỏ. Nước mắt chính là môi trường có nồng độ chất tan so với môi trường nội bào bé hơn. Do đó, để cân bằng được nồng độ chất từ cả hai bên, nước mắt buộc phải di chuyển từ màn kết đi vào các mô xung quanh để cân bằng nồng độ chất. Do đó, tình trạng bị sưng vùng da quanh mắt xuất hiện.3. Sự giãn nở của mạch máu: Vùng mắt và xung quanh mắt chứa rất nhiều mạch máu và khi khóc quá nhiều sẽ gây hiện tượng giãn nở. Nước mắt tiết ra quá nhiều sẽ buộc lượng máu bơm đến vùng mắt nhiều hơn, các mạch máu giãn nở gây hiện tượng sưng mắt.4. Mắt yếu cũng gây ra sưng"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الذي أمره الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم أن يتخلف بعده بمكة ريثما يؤدي الأمانات إلى أصحابها؟","answer":"الإجابة: علي بن أبي طالب"},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Aostralia?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Aostralia dia Canberra . Ao amin'ny Faritanin'i Renivohitr'i Aostralia no misy azy io."},{"question":"Firy ny isan'ny fatorana atao amin'ny maty?","answer":"Tsy misy isa voafaritra ny isan'ny fatotra atao amin'ny maty fa matetika dia na 5 na 7 no fataon'ny olona."},{"question":"Martina Ohadugha","answer":"Martina Ohadugha jẹ agbabọọlu lobinrin órilẹ ede naigiria ti a bini 5, óṣu May ni ọdun 1991. Arabinrin naa ṣere gẹgẹbi midfielder fun River Angels.Martina kopa ninu ere idije awọn obinrin ilẹ afirica ni ọdun 2012 ati 2014. Arabinrin naa kopa ninu Cup FIFA awọn obinrin agbaye ni ọdun 2015."},{"question":"මගධ රාජ්‍යයේ බලය ලබාගැනීම සඳහා , මෞර්‍ය චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත රජුට උදව්-උපකාර කල බ්‍රාහ්මණ පඬිවරයා කවුද ?","answer":"චානක්‍ය හෙවත් කෞටිල්‍ය ."},{"question":"در برج کبوترخانه میبد چند لانه کبوتر وجود دارد؟","answer":"کبوتر‌خانه میبد برجی استوانه‌ای است که داخل آن چهار‌هزار لانه کبوتر وجود دارد و نوار سفید رنگی برای جذب کبوتران دورتادور برج کشیده شده است. این برج در برابر خطر حمله دیگر حیوانات به کبوترها بسیار ایمن بوده است."},{"question":"Apakah soalan untuk ayat berikut: \\"Tanah Lapang Aluvial Sungai Mississippi ialah tanah lapang aluvial yang dicipta oleh Sungai Mississippi terletak bahagian tujuh negeri A.S., dari selatan Louisiana ke selatan Illinois.\\"? Subjecknya ialah Tanah Lapang Aluvial Sungai Mississippi.","answer":"\\"Di manakah dataran Tanah Lapang Aluvial Sungai Mississippi yang terkenal?\\""},{"question":"சு. தியோடர் பாஸ்கரன் அவர்களின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"மனிதர்கள் உணவுக்காக மட்டுமே வேட்டையாடிய போது தீமை ஏதும் ஏற்படவில்லை. அவர்களும் ஒரு இரைக் கொல்லியாக, காட்டுப்பூனை, புலி போன்று இயங்கினார்கள்."},{"question":"Answer the following question with \\"Yes\\" or \\"No\\" or \\"None\\" if none of the first two answers apply.Question: కిర్గిజిస్తాన్ దేశానికి స్వాతంత్య్రం ఎప్పుడు వచ్చింది?Topic: సిరియాArticle: సిరియా  ఒక పశ్చిమాసియా దేశము. 2013 లో జరిగిన రసాయన దాడిలో ఈ దేశం ఒక్కసారిగా వార్తలలోకి వచ్చింది.నైసర్గిక స్వరూపముపూర్వ నామం:సిరియన్ అరబ్ రిపబ్లిక్ (అల్ జుమురియా అల్ అరబియ అస్ సుర్రియా)ఖండం: ఆసియాదేశస్తులు:సిరియన్లువైశాల్యం: 1,85,180 చదరపు కిలోమీటర్లుజనాభా: 2,20,87,048 (తాజా అంచనాలు 2004 ప్రకారం)రాజధాని: డమాస్కస్ప్రభుత్వం: యూనిటరీ సింగిల్ పార్టీ సెమీ ప్రెసిడెన్షియల్ రిపబ్లిక్కరెన్సీ: సిరియన్ పౌండ్అధికారిక భాష: అరబిక్మతం: 90 శాతం ముస్లిములు, 8 శాతం క్రైస్తవులు,1 శాతం మిగిలిన ఇతర మతాలు .వాతావరణం: జనవరిలో 0 నుండి 12 డిగ్రీలు, ఆగస్టులో 18 నుండి 37 డిగ్రీలు ఉంటుంది.పంటలు: పత్తి, పళ్ళు, బంగాళదుంపలు, చెరకు, గోధుమలు, బార్లీ, కూరగాయలు.పరిశ్రమలు: చమురు సహజవాయువులు, దుస్తుల పరిశ్రమలు, పళ్ళు, కూరగాయల ప్రాసెసింగ్, బార్లీ, ఊలు, సిమెంటు, తోలు వస్తువులు, గ్లాస్, మెటల్ పరిశ్రమలు.సరిహద్దులు: ఇరాక్, జోర్డాన్, ఇజ్రాయెల్, లెబనాన్, టర్కీ, మధ్యధరా సముద్రం.స్వాతంత్య్ర దినోత్సవం: 1944 ఏప్రిల్ 17చరిత్రక్రీ.పూ. 2500 సంవత్సరాల నుండి ఇక్కడ ప్రజల ఉన్న దాఖలాలు ఉన్నాయి. రాజధాని డమాస్కస్ నగరంలో ఆనాటి ఆనవాళ్ళు ఇప్పటికీ కనబడుతున్నాయి. అయితే ఇజ్రాయెల్, లెబనాన్ దేశాలతో నిత్యమూ పోరాటాలు, చిన్నపాటి యుద్ధాలు నేడు చోటు చేసుకుంటున్నాయి. క్రీస్తుపూర్వం 4వ శతాబ్దం నుండి 9వ శతాబ్దం వరకు ఫోనీషియన్లు ఈ ప్రాంతాన్ని పరిపాలించారు. దేశంలో ఎక్కువగా పర్వత ప్రాంతాలు, ఎడారి ఆక్రమించి ఉన్నాయి. ప్రజలు ఎక్కువగా రాజధాని డమాస్కస్ ప్రాంతంలో నివసిస్తుంటారు. ఒకప్పుడు సిరియా దేశం వివిధ దేశాల రాజులకు యుద్ధభూమిగా ఉండేది. 'సిరియన్లు '’ ఎక్కువగా వ్యాపారరంగంలో ఉన్నాయి. సమీప దేశాలతో వీరి వ్యాపార బంధాలుగా చైనా, భారతదేశం, అరబ్బు దేశాలలో ఉన్నాయి. దేశాన్ని ఫోనేషియన్ల తర్వాత గ్రీకులు, రోమన్లు, బైజాంటైన్ రాజుల పరిపాలించారు. క్రీస్తుశకం 632లో ముస్లిం మత నమ్మకం కలిగిన ప్రాఫెట్ మహమ్మద్, ఇతర అరబ్బీ సైనికులు ఆ దేశాన్ని తమ అధీనంలోకి తీసుకున్నారు. ఆ విధంగా సిరియాదేశం ముస్లిం మత దేశంగా మారిపోయింది. కొన్ని వందల సంవత్సరాలపాటు కలీఫాలు పరిపాలించారు. క్రీ.శ. 1095లో యూరోపు నుండి క్రైస్తవులు క్రమంగా వచ్చి ఈ దేశాన్ని తమ అధీనంలోకి తీసుకున్నారు. క్రీ.శ. 1114లో సుల్తాన్ నూరుద్ధీన్ అనే రాజు క్రమంగా సిరియాదేశాన్ని ఆక్రమించి క్రిస్టియన్లను తరిమివేశాడు. ","answer":"None"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana : « Nitsiky tokoa izy vao hitany niditra ilay namany. »","answer":"Maneho hafaliana izany satria mitsiky izy."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన మొదటి పేరా మరియు చివరి పేరా అనుసరించు మధ్య పేరా రాయండి:మొదటి పేరా:ఫొటోలు తీస్తే వాళ్ళ కంఠమాధుర్యం పోతుందని వారి భావన. వారికి నచ్చచెప్పి డబ్బులిచ్చి గాయక భిక్షుకుల ఫొటోలు తీసుకున్నారు. తాళపత్రాలకోసం ఒక వేసవిలో కరీంనగరం జిల్లా ఎల్లారెడ్డి పేటకు నడచిపోయి ఎండ తీవ్రతకు తట్టుకోలేక సొమ్మసిల్లి ఊరి బయట కొట్టం వద్ద, మూర్చపోయారు. కొట్టం యజమాని బలిజాయన మంచినీళ్ళు, పాలు ఇచ్చాడు. రెండు రూపాయలిస్తే బండి కట్టాడు. ఆ బండిలో నారాయణపురం పోయి మురళీధరశర్మ అనే ఆయన దగ్గర బస్తా (సంచి) నిండా తాళపత్ర గ్రంథాలు తీసుకున్నాడు. తిరుగు ప్రయాణంలో వీరమ్మ – శివరాజం అనే ఆ బలిజ దంపతులే నీళ్ళచారు అన్నం పెట్టి బస్సెక్కించారు.చివరి పేరా:గంభీరావుపేటలో వై. రామేశ్వర శర్మ, కటకం వెంకటేశ్వర్ల ఇంట్లో వంద తాళపత్ర గ్రంథాలు తీసుకొని ఇద్దరు మనుషులను తీసుకొని చెరువు కట్ట దగ్గరున్న శాసనాన్ని తవ్వించారు. దానిని భూమిలోపల కనపడకుండా పూడ్చి పెట్టించారు. హైదరాబాదు వెళ్ళి ఆర్షశాఖ డైరెక్టరుకు ఈ విషయం చెప్తే శాసనలిపులు నేర్చి శాసనాలు తీసి ప్రకటించటం ఇష్టం లేకనో ఏమోగాని, ఆయన పాఠాలు చెప్పటం మానేశారు. అప్రియమైన సత్యాన్ని పలుకకూడదు. (నబ్రూయాత్ సత్యమప్రియం).","answer":"శాసనాల సేకరణలో అనుభవాలు : అప్పటి ఆర్షశాఖ (ఇప్పటి దేవాదాయ శాఖ వంటిది) డైరెక్టర్ గొప్ప చారిత్రక పరిశోధకులు. వారివద్ద శాసన లిపులు చదివే తొలిపాఠాలు నేర్చుకున్నారు. తాళపత్రాల కోసం పోతూ ముస్తాబాదులో 29-10-1954 బస్సెక్కి మానేరు వద్ద దిగి ఆ ప్రాజెక్ట్ చూచి కాలినడకన గంభీరావుపేటకు పోతుంటే గంభీరావుపేట చెరువు కట్టకు ఏటవాలులో ఒక శిలాశాసనం కనబడింది. కొడవండ్లు, గొడ్డండ్లు నూరటం చేత శాసనం కొంత భాగం అరిగిపోయింది. వరాహ లాంఛనం (పంది గుర్తు) ఉండటం వల్ల అది కాకతీయుల కాలపు శాసనమని గుర్తించారు."},{"question":"Ẹ wo Isiwat, nitori ẹgbẹrun marun-un naira lo ṣe ṣa ọmọ ọdun mejila ladaa l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Abẹrẹ sọnu, wọn lọọ bu Ṣango, lowe to ba iyaale ile kan,  Isiwat Taofeek, mu. Obinrin ẹni ogoji ọdun naa ni awọn ọlọpaa mu laaarọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, lagbegbe Isọka, Kugba, l’Abẹokuta. Wọn lo yọ ada si ọmọ odun mejila to n gbe lọdọ ẹ, bẹẹ lo fi ọbẹ gbigbona jo o lara kaakiri nitori ẹgbẹrun marun-un naira to ni oun tọju pamọ, ọmọ naa lo si ko o.Ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ aabọ aarọ ni awọn ọlọpaa teṣan Adatan lọọ mu Isiwa nile, lẹyin ti obinrin kan to jẹ ayalegbe pẹlu ẹ mu ọmọ ti apa oriṣiiriṣii wa lara rẹ naa wa si teṣan yii, to si sọ fun wọn pe obinrin naa lo ṣe ọmọ ọdun mejila ọhun yankan yankan bẹẹ.Nibi to ti n fẹjọ sun lọwọ lọmọdekunrin naa ti ṣubu lulẹ, lo ba daku lọ gbari. Ileewosan ni wọn sare gbe e lọ lati teṣan naa fun itọju.Kia ni DPO Samuel Aladegoroye ti ran awọn ikọ rẹ lati lọọ mu  Isiwa ti wọn fẹsun kan wa, nigba to de lo ni ọmọ aburo ọkọ oun lọmọ yii, o ti ṣe diẹ to ti n gbe pẹlu oun.O loun tọju ẹgbẹrun marun-un naira sinu ile, oun ko si ri owo naa mọ, oun si gbagbọ pe ọmọ yii lo ji i, ohun to jẹ koun da sẹria fun un niyẹn pẹlu fifi ọbẹ sina, toun jẹ ko gbona daadaa koun too fi jo o ni gbogbo ara. Ko sọ nipa ti ada ti araale rẹ ni o fi ṣa a.DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi sọ pe ọga awọn, CP Edward Ajogun, ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn gbe Isiwa lọ sẹka to n ri si ifiyajẹ ọmọde, nibi ti wọn yoo ti wadii rẹ daadaa fun iwa to hu naa."},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity : \\"Ny aina Ramangatahiana , _\\"","answer":"\\"Ny aina Ramangatahiana , ny vola Ramangatadiavina\\""},{"question":"كم يبلغ عدد دول الاتحدا الأوروبي؟","answer":"يضم الاتحاد الأوروبي 27 دولة. وتاسس بماستريش بهولندا في نوفمبر 1993 ومؤسسوا الاتحاد الاوروبي هم المانيا و فرنسا و ايطاليا و هولندا و بلجيكا واللوكسمبورغ."},{"question":"Kirjoita seuraava teksti omin sanoin: Ohjaa hänet yksityishuoneeseen.","answer":"Vie hänet yksityishuoneeseen."},{"question":"Aanadii Nageeye Qeybtii:92-aad?","answer":"Aanadii Nageeye Qeybtii:92-aadSheekadu waxa ay inoo maraysay,“Gurigayaga ma waxay moodayaan mawlac qofka meel kale waayaa u soo nolol doonto marka uu cokanaadana ka carraabo?” ayuu Negeeye ku dooday.“Denbiga oo dhan adiga ayaa leh, naago yar yar oo casarka soo xareediya cawayskana carrabka ceshan kari waaya wax badan baad aragtaye maxaad ugu oggolaatay in ay soo baxaan?” ayuu Diiriye saaxiibkii ku hiifay.“Balaayo ku dhacdaygu goor ay soo baxeenba ma anigaa ogaa.”Dad badan oo deriska ah ayaa meeshii ku soo xoomay. Negeeye iyo Diiriye waxay isku dayeen dhawrkii qof ee ugu soo horreeyay in ay ka la diraan.“Naga taga! Naga ag dareera! Guryihiinna miyaanu idiinku nimid? Naga qaada shoobbaraha.”Laakiin marka ay dadku soo bataanba xanaaquna wuu sii badanayay. Diiriye wuxuu isku dayay arrinta in uu qaboojiyo, oo xataa markii dambe wuxuu oggolaaday haddii ay habluhu diideen in ay guriga ku noqdaan in uu tagsi saaro. Laakiin yartii weli waa ay ooyaysaa, taasina dadkii meesha ku soo ururay ayay kaga xanaajisay, gaar ahaan markii la ogaaday gabdhuhu in ay sakhraansan yihiin isla markaasna imtixaan iyo dugsi u barooranayaan.“Waa kuwaas kuwa dalka qarribay dadkana fasahaadiyay. Bal inta ay laala’eg yihiin iyo waxa ay carruurta ku dullaynayaan eega! Dulli Alle idin bad!” waxaa ku haaraamay oday codkiisa xabeebtii hurdada uu ka soo kacay laga garanayo oo go hullaaban.Intii aanay Negeeye iyo Diiriye hadalka odayga ka jawaabin ayay cay iyo canaan kale sida hogosha ugu hooreen.Dadka Filla Adduun ku tunta iyo deriska aqooni ka ma dhexayso, ismana dhex galaan, xataa isma salaamaan. Laakiin intooda waxay u furan tahay ogi nacayb badan ayay u qabaan.Dhawr eray oo canaan ah markii la isweydaarsaday ayay xiisaddu cirka isku sii shareertay, Negeeye iyo Diiriye ayaa sida Buurta Carrafa dhagax la huwiyay. Iyaga oo nabarro qaba markii ay gudaha u yaaceen filladii oo dhan ayaa isu dayaantay. Quraaradihii daqaadaha oo dhulka u daadanaya ayaa la maqlay, ganjeeladii ayaa la gilgilay kooxdii gudaha ku jirtayna kabash kabashtii ayaa ka dhammaatay oo marba qol ayay isu dabo yaaceen. Dadka meesha ku jira waxaa ka mid ah Negeeye iyo sarkaal kale oo bastoolado ku hubaysan.“Iska fadhiya, iska fadhiya idinku, bani aadan kibiray aniga ayaa shaqadooda aqaane”, ayuu Negeeye martidii u sheegay, nabar dhafoorka kaga dhacay inta uu dhiig ka masaxay ayuu bastooladdii la soo baxay oo cabbaystay.Inta uu mar kale ganjeeladii furay ayuu dadkii oo dhagax la soo tuban laba xabbadood cagaha u geliyay. Kabtaydii meeday ayaa ka dhacday, iyaga oo orodkii isa sii dul fuulaya ayuuna sii daawaday. Labadii gabdhood ee muranku ka bilawdayna dadkii yaacay ayaa hore u sii jiitay.Habeenkaas ayaa dadkaa masaakiinta ah ugu dambaysay in ay filladaa barakaysan ku soo xad gudbaan.Raxmo waxay ugu dambaysay gabdho badan oo adeegto ka soo noqday Filla Adduun, kuwaas oo ay mid waliba maalmo yar gudahood shaqada ka carartay. Dhammaan waxay ka argaggaxeen xayodarrada meesha ka socota, iyo isla markaas ragga aan xishoodka aqoon ee Negeeye ugu horreeyo, kuwaas oo inta ay kijada ugu galaan kor iyo hoos meesha ay gacantoodu gaadhi kartaba gaadhsiiya, wax aanay u soo shaqo teginna ka qalqaashada. La ma tirin karo inta gabdhood ee sababtaas shaqada kaga tagtay. Laakiin Raxmo waa ay ugu miskiinsanayd ama ugu dulqaad badnayd.Da’deedu waxay ahayd toddoba iyo toban jir, laakiin ka ma ay dheerayn mitir iyo afartan, culayskeeduna afartan wuu ka hooseeyay. Waxay ku dhalatay Afgooye, iyada oo sagaal jir ah markii ay hooyadeed dhimatay ayuu aabbaheed Xamar ku guursaday naag kale oo Raxmo aad ugu darrayd. Nolol silic leh oo guriga aabbaheed ee aan laga jeclayn iyo ka habaryarteed ee faqiirka ah u dhaxaysa ayay ku soo kortay. Weligeed dugsi ma ay dhigan, iyada oo kow iyo toban jir ah ayayna markii ugu horreysay adeegto noqotay taas oo ay habaryarteed u soo heshay. Markaa ka dib dad ka la duwan ayayxirfaddaa ugu soo adeegtay, kuwaas oo ay qaarkood ka soo martay waayo’aragnimo xun.Qurux lagu ammaano ma leh, laakiin dadkeeda waa ay iskaga dhex jirtaa. Gaabnaanta iyo lafo yaraanta dartood jeer wejigeeda la arko waxay u eg tahay ilmo yar. Waxay nolosha kaga riyootaa oo keliya nin jeclaada oo guursada kana saara adeegtonimada. Laakiin nin gol qabateeya mooyee mid guur ka la hadla waxaa ka jiray oday lixdan jir ah, kaas oo ay qoyskiisa beri adeegto u ahayd. Isagana shaqadiiba waa ay uga carartay iyada oo leh: “Duqaan quxuubka ah fiiri! Aniga qof oo isnacday maas ii malaynaa?”Guriga Negeeye waxa ka dhaca iyo dadka isku roorsada iyadu ma jecla laakiin dan ka ma gasho. Iyada oo heeso hindi ah iyo kuwo banaadiri ah marba mid qaadaysa ayay shaqadeeda si daacad ah u gudataa, taas oo ka kooban cunto kariska, nadaafadda iyo u adeegga dadka halkaa ku laacdama. Habeenka ay shaqada ku daahdo ama aad u daallan tahay waxay isaga hoyataa qolkaa kijada ku xiga oo ay kuwii iyada ka horreeyayna seexan jireen. Hawsha gurigu ha iska dhib badnaato, jawigana ha ku diiqadooto, laakiin dhaqaale ahaan raalli ayay ka tahay oo mushaharkeedu adeegto ku ma xuma, dadka guriga ku tuntana dhacdhac ayay ka heshaa. Iyaguna Raxmo-Yarey ayay u la baxeen oo waxay ku jecel yihiin daacadnimada iyo dhego nugaylka.Maanta martidu waa ay badnayd, hawshuna waa ay cuslayd. Saqdhexe ayay Raxmo iyada oo aan daal isqaadi karin furaashkii qolkeeda dhulka yaallay isku tuurtay. Iyada oo aan dhinaceedu gogosha gaadhin ayay gama’day. Laakiin dadkii iyagu weli waa ay bulaamayaan oo cawayskooda fari ka ma qodna. Goor dambe iyada oo hurdo mayd uga dhow, ilayskuna u dansan yahay, ayay ku toostay gacmo waaweyn oo jidhkeedii yaraa dhan walba u xulaya, timo qodxo la moodo oo dhabanka ka mudmudaya iyo neef ay sigaar iyo khamri ka buuxaan.“Yaa waaye?… Yaa waaye?…” ayay ku qaylisay iyada oo argaggaxsan.“Usuus! Raxmo, waa Negeeye ee aamus!”“Adiga ma waalatay, Negeeye? I dhaaf, i dhaaf, iga kac aniga gurigaaga haddaan kaaga baxaaye...”“Ramxo, miskiinnimada iska daa, kaniba waa gurigaagii ee xaggee baad ka aadaysaa”, ayuu ku yidhi, isaga oo isla markaa yartii sidii libaax sagaaro qabtay laabta gashaday dharkii yaraana midba dhan uga tuuray.“I dhaaf aniga, i sii daa aan ku dhahay. Iga kac! Waa i xoogee miyaa? Alla aaboow!...”Iyada oo sidaas u cataabaysa ayuu ka dan dhammaystay. Kuwii kale markaas waa ay wada hurdeen, haddii se ay qaylada iyo baroorta Raxmo ku toosi lahaayeen sakhrad iyo qaaddiro ayay la daateen oo dadka xabaalaha ku jira ka ma duwana.Markaa ka dib wuxuu bilaabay in uu maslaxo oo ku yidhaahdo:“Raxmo, maxaad la ooyaysaa,"},{"question":"යුරෝපයේ විශාලතම ආර්ථිකයට හිමිකම් කියන රට කුමක් ද?","answer":"යුරෝපයේ විශාලතම ආර්ථිකයට හිමිකම් කියන රට ජර්මනිය යි."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Apa yang boleh dipecahkan tanpa disentuh dan dilihat?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah janji"},{"question":"எளிய மக்களின் வலிகளை நாட்டுப்புற இலக்கிய வடிவங்களே முழுமையாகப் பிரதிபலிக்கின்றன – நிறுவுக.","answer":"மனிதன் என்று தோன்றினானோ மொழி என்று பிறந்ததோ அன்றே நாட்டுப்புறப் பாடல்கள் தோன்றிவிட்டன எனலாம். நாட்டுப்புறப் பாடல்கள் பெரும்பாலும் பாமரமக்கள் பாடியவையாகவே உள்ளன. எளிய மக்கள் பாடல்கள் என்பதால் அதில் வறுமை, சோகம் என வலிகளைப் பிரதிபலிப்பதாய் காணப்படுகின்றாள். வறுமையில் வாழும் ஒருவன் மனிதர்களைப் பற்றிய பாடல் ஒன்றை எழுதுகிறாள்.வாழும் நேரத்தில் வருகின்றாள்வறுமை வந்தால் பிரிகுறாபேய் போல பணத்த காக்குறாபெரியவர் தம்மை பழிக்குறாமனிதன் பணம் வரும் போது மாறிவிடுகிறான் என்பதை வெளிப்படுத்துகிறது. வறுமையினால் வேலைப்பார்க்கும் பெண்களைப் பற்றிய பாடலில்,வேகாத வெயிலுக்குள்ளேவிறகொடிக்கப் போறபெண்ணேகாலுனக்குப் பொசுக்கலையோகற்றாழைமுள்ளுக் குத்தலையோகாலக் கொடுமையாலேகஷ்டப்பட காலமாச்சுஎன பெண் வெயிலிலும், காலணி இன்றி வேலைப்பார்த்து, தன் குடும்பத்தைக் காப்பாற்றுவதாக கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.காட்டுக்குள்ளே விறகொடித்துசாமி வீட்டுகதைச் சுமந்துவந்துகால் ரூபாய்க்கு விறகுவிற்றுகஞ்சி கண்டு குடிக்கணும்ஒரு வேலை உணவிற்காக நாள் முழுக்க வேலைப்பார்க்கும் பெண்ணின் வலியை வெளிப்படுத்தும் விதமாக அமைந்துள்ளது.வெள்ளாம நமக்கு வேணாம்வெவசாயம் ஒண்ணு வேணாம்வௌச்சலும் ஒன்றுமில்லவிட்டுப்புட்டு போயிடலாம்வேற வேல பாத்துக்கலாம்வெளிநாடுபோயி அங்க வேலகீலபாப்போம்வெள்ளக் காரங்க போல நாமவசதியாக இருப்போம்விவசாயம் பொய்த்து போய் வெளிநாட்டிற்குச் சென்று கூலி வேலை பார்த்துப் பிழைத்துக் கொள்ளும் பாமர மக்களின் வலியை வெளிப்படுமாறு இப்பாடல் அமைந்துள்ளது. நாட்டுப்புற இலக்கியங்களைப் பாமர இலக்கியம் எனலாம். பாமர மக்களின் வலியைப் பிரதிபலிப்பதால் அவ்வாறு அழைக்கப்படும்."},{"question":"Hoàn thành đoạn văn sau: Vào năm 1964, Uỷ ban Trung ương Đảng Khoái đã buộc tội Khrushchev với nhiều hành vi sai trái, trong đó có việc gây ra thất bại cho Liên Xô như trong cuộc ","answer":"khủng hoảng Tên lửa Cuba. Sau một thời gian ngắn dưới sự lãnh đạo tập thể, một quan chức có kinh nghiệm, là Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev, đã lên thay thế Khrushchev. Brezhnev tiếp tục duy trì chính sách tập trung vào công nghiệp nặng, tương tự chính sách của Stalin, và cố gắng giảm căng thẳng trong mối quan hệ với Hoa Kỳ. Trong thập kỷ 1960, Liên bang Xô viết đã trở thành một người sản xuất và xuất khẩu dầu mỏ và khí tự nhiên quan trọng."},{"question":"Mikä on rotavirus?","answer":"Rotavirukset ovat yleisimpiä ripuli-oksennustaudin aiheuttajia. Rotaviruksia on useita eri serotyyppejä, joista G1P8-tyypin virus on teollisuusmaissa tavallisin. Elektronimikroskooppikuvassa rotavirus muistuttaa pyörää (latinaksi rota = pyörä)"},{"question":"Kişinin kendisi olmadan e-Devlet şifresi alınır mı?","answer":"Vekilin kimliğini ibraz etmesi, .e-Devlet Kapısı taahhütnamesinin vekil tarafından vekaleten imzalandığının şerh düşülerek imzalanması durumunda e-devlet şifresi vekil olarak alınabilmektedir."},{"question":"Fehezanteny 1: Mpampiasa vola tao amin'ny Las Vegas Club, ny Thunderbird Hotel ary ny Sahara Hotel i Scherer. Fehezanteny 2: Mpampiasa vola tao amin'ny Hotely Thunderbird, ny Las Vegas Club ary ny Hotely Sahara i Scherer. Fanontaniana: Mitovy ve ny dikan'ny fehezanteny 1 sy ny fehezanteny 2? Eny sa Tsia?","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny dikan'ny fehezanteny 1 sy ny fehezanteny 2."},{"question":"महाराष्ट्रातील कापसासाठी प्रसिद्ध बाजारपेठ कुठे आहे?","answer":"अमरावती"},{"question":"Wanne kayan Aikin ne na Su?","answer":"Muhimman kayan aikin su, sun haɗa da:ƘugiyaMaliKalliBirgiFatsaDallaKomaGoraKwale-kwale"},{"question":"ගුද පවිත්‍රීකරණය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ගුද පවිත්‍රීකරණය යනු මල පහකිරීමෙන් පසුව ගුදය පවිත්‍රකිරීමේ ස්වස්ථතාත්මක පරිචයයි. ගුදය සහ සට්ටම් (තට්ටම්) පවිත්‍රීකරණය සඳහා වැසිකිලි කඩදාසි හෝ ඒ හා සමාන වෙනත් කඩදාසිමය නිෂ්පාදිත හෝ භාවිතා කිරීම විශේෂයෙන්ම බොහෝ බටහිර රටවල දක්නට ලැබේ. අනෙක්තන්හී, ජලය භාවිතා කිරීම සිදුවිය හැක ( මිටි වැසිකිළි පෝච්චියකදී මෙන් දිය පිහිරක් භාවිතය හෝ, වගුරුවා අතින් සේදීම). අනෙකුත් සංස්කෘතීන්හිදී හා සන්දර්භයන්හිදී, පහන්කඩ (පාන්කඩ), ශාක පත්‍ර ( මුහුදු පැලෑටි ඇතුළුව), ඉරිඟු කරල් බඩ, මුහුදුහතු හෝ කෝටු වැනි දෑ භාවිතා කෙරෙයි."},{"question":"#පොල්මක්කාර වදන නිර්මාණය වන හැටි පහදන්න?","answer":"මේ වචනය භාවිතයේ ඇත්තේ පොල්මඃකාර ලෙසයි. (මක් නෙවෙයි මඃ)මෙය ලන්දේසි මෙන්ම ජර්මන් වචනයක්. එය Voll Macht යන _පූර්ණ බලය _යන තේරුම දෙන වචනයෙන් බිදී ආ එකක්."},{"question":" Waxaad sheegtaa  magaca al imaam al shaafici ?","answer":" jawab.waa  abuu cabdallaah maxamed ibnu idiris (alshaafici)."},{"question":"Inona no fomba fanaon'ny Malagasy taloha mba hampilamina ny fiarahamonina?","answer":"Mba hampilamina ny fiarahamonina dia nitandro sy nanaja ireo fady misy ny Malagasy taloha."},{"question":"Escribe el evento más importante del texto : La política de progresiva conquista de Etiopía se concretó con la Primera Guerra Ítalo-Etíope y terminó en los hechos con la derrota de Adua el primero de marzo de 1896. Una de las peticiones italianas durante la redacción del Tratado de Versalles después de la Primera Guerra Mundial fue la de recibir la Somalia Francesa y el Somalilandia en cambio de la renuncia a la participación en la repartición de las colonias alemanas. Fue el último intento por parte del estado liberal de perseguir la política de penetración al Cuerno de África.","answer":"La derrota de Adua. "},{"question":"ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਦਿ ਡਰਟੀ ਪਿਕਚਰ’ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਹਰ ਪਾਸੇ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਵਿਦਿਆ ਬਾਲਨ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਚਰਚਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਵੀ ਸੁਣਨ ’ਚ ਆ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਵਿਦਿਆ ਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਉਣ ਲਈ 7 ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਮੰਗਣੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਹਨ। ਵਿਦਿਆ ਬਾਲਨ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ’ ਕਾਰਨ ਵੀ ਅੱਜ ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਚਰਚਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੈ। ਜ਼ਿਕਰਯੋਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਨੇ 6 ਮਹੀਨੇ ਦੀ ਗਰਭਵਤੀ ਔਰਤ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਇਆ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ 9 ਮਾਰਚ ਨੂੰ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ। ਇਸ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਵਿਦਿਆ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਏ ਸਵਾਲ-ਜਵਾਬ ਪਾਠਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਦਿਲਚਸਪੀ ਲਈ ਪੇਸ਼ ਹਨ:ਸਵਾਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ-ਏ ਮਦਰ ਆਫ਼ ਏ ਸਟੋਰੀ’ ਟੈਗ ਲਾਈਨ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਮਤਲਬ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਅਸਲ ’ਚ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਕਈ ਰਹੱਸ ਹਨ। ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਆਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਰਹੱਸਮਈ ਮੋੜਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਕਲਪਨਾ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ। ਜਦੋਂ ਸੁਜਾਏ ਘੋਸ਼ ਨੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸੁਣਾਈ ਤਾਂ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਉਂਦੇ ਰਹੱਸ ਉਲਝਣ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਸੁਜਾਏ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਤਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ 2-3 ਵਾਰੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਨ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ, ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਦੁਬਾਰਾ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਪੜ੍ਹੀ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਰੌਚਿਕ ਲੱਗੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ’ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਈਨ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਸੀ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਵੇਖੋ, ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਰਹੱਸਮਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ’ਚ ਲੰਮੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣੀ, ਇਸ ਲਈ ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਬਣਾਇਆ। ਦੂਜੀ ਗੱਲ ਇੱਕ ਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਹ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਵਧੀਆ ਲੱਗੀ। ਤੀਜੀ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਡਰਾਉਣੀ ਸੋਚ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੁਹਾਡਾ ਕੋਈ ਨਜ਼ਦੀਕੀ ਗਾਇਬ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਕਿੱਥੇ? ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗ ਰਿਹਾ। ਸਾਰੇ ਲੋਕ ਕਹਿ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਅਰਨਵ ਬਾਗਚੀ ਜਿਹਾ ਕੋਈ ਆਦਮੀ ਹੈ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਬੱਚੇ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਬਣਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਹੋ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਨਾ ਵੱਡੀ ਚੁਣੌਤੀ ਸੀ। ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਵੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਉਤਸੁਕਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਣਗੇ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਤੁਹਾਡਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਬਾਗਚੀ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਇਆ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਇੱਕ ਆਮ ਔਰਤ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਛੇ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਦੀ ਗਰਭਵਤੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਲੰਦਨ ਤੋਂ ਕੋਲਕਾਤਾ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਤੀ ਦੀ ਤਲਾਸ਼ ’ਚ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਲਈ ਕੋਲਕਾਤਾ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਲੋਕ ਅਜਨਬੀ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਵਿਚਾਰੀ ਜਾਂ ਦੁਖਿਆਰੀ ਔਰਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ’ ਦੇ ਹੀ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ਵਾਲੀ ਇੱਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਮੈਰਿਡ ਟੂ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ’ ਵੀ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਪਤਨੀ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਹਾਰ ਦੇ ਦਰਭੰਗਾ ’ਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਤੀ ਦੀ ਤਲਾਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇਖੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਇਕੱਠੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਭ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟਾਚਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ’ ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਭਾਵਨਾਵਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਆਧਾਰਤ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਹ ਵੀ ਸੁਣਨ ’ਚ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਲ ਨਾਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਹਾਮੀ ਭਰੀ, ਕਿਉਂ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਅਸਲ ’ਚ ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਰਹੱਸਮਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੜ੍ਹੀ ਸੀ। ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਸਕਰਿਪਟ ਪੜ੍ਹੀ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਸਭ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਾਂਗੀ ਪਰ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਸੁਜਾਏ ਘੋਸ਼ ਨੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਭਾ ’ਤੇ ਯਕੀਨ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਹਾਮੀ ਭਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਹ ਵੀ ਸੁਣਨ ’ਚ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਸਕਰਿਪਟ ’ਚ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਬਦਲਾਅ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਗ਼ਲਤ, ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਗੱਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਅਕਸਰ ਸੁਜਾਏ ਘੋਸ਼ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ ਲਿਖਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਫੋਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸੁਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਸਨ। ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਰਾਇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਸੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿਚਲੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਿੰਨੀ ਕੁ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਕਰਨੀ ਪਈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਦੂਜੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ  ਲਗਾਤਾਰ 64 ਦਿਨ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਕਰਨੀ ਪਈ ਸੀ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਾ ਬਜਟ ਘੱਟ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਘਾਟ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ ਅਸੀਂ ਇੱਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਸਹਿਯੋਗ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਸੁਜਾਏ ਘੋਸ਼ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਚੌਥਾ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਫੇਅਰ ਐਵਾਰਡ ਦਿਵਾਏਗੀ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਸੰਦ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਅਹਿਮੀਅਤ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹੈ। ਐਵਾਰਡ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਨੂੰ 40 ਸਾਲ ਬਾਅਦ ਇਹ ਯਾਦ ਕਰਵਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਦੇ ਚੰਗਾ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਲਈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਐਵਾਰਡ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਸੀ। ਮੈਂ ਐਵਾਰਡ ਬਾਰੇ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੋਚਦੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਲਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਵਪਾਰਕ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਕਿਸ ਹੱਦ ਤਕ ਮਾਅਨੇ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ। ਮੈਂ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਮੇਰੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਦੇਖਣ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ’ਚ ਆਏ ਬਦਲਾਓ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੀ ਕਹੋਗੇ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਬਦਲ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਬਦਲਾਓ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਉੱਤੇ ਵੀ ਪੈ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਸਮਾਜ ’ਚ ਵਾਪਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਓਹੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ’ਚ ਦਿਖਾਈ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਦੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਪੱਖ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹੋ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਜੀ ਨਹੀਂ। ਮੈਂ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਦੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਕਾਰਜ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ। ਨਾ ਹੀ ਮੈਂ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਬਣ ਸਕਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਨਾ ਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਬਜ਼ ਦੀ ਪਛਾਣ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਮੈਂ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ। ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਬਜ਼ ਤੇਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਬਦਲਦੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਹੁਣ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਚੱਲ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਵਿਸ਼ਿਆਂ ’ਤੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਬਣ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਵੀ ਹਰ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ-ਏ ਮਦਰ ਆਫ਼ ਏ ਸਟੋਰੀ’ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਕੌਣ  ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ  ਵਿਦਿਆ ਬਾਲਨ।"},{"question":"ప్రపంచీకరణను నిర్వచించండి.","answer":"ఒక దేశ ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థ కార్యకలాపాల పరిధిని విదేశాలకు విస్తరింపజేయడమే ప్రపంచీకరణ. అభివృద్ధి చెందిన దేశాల ఆర్థిక శాస్త్రవేత్తలు ప్రపంచీకరణను ఈ విధముగా నిర్వచించినారు “స్వేచ్ఛా వాణిజ్య విధానము, పెట్టుబడి, సాంకేతిక పరిజ్ఞానము, శ్రామికుల గమనశీలత. ఈ నిర్వచనము ప్రకారము ప్రపంచీకరణలో నాలుగు లక్షణాలు ఉన్నవి. 1) ఆటంకాలు లేని వర్తక ప్రవాహము, 2) మూలధన ప్రవాహాలు, 3) సాంకేతిక విజ్ఞానాల ప్రవాహము, 4) ఆటంకములేని శ్రామికుల గమనశీలత."},{"question":"Could you explain the historical and cultural significance of the traditional dance forms in Sri Lanka?","answer":"Sri Lanka boasts a rich tradition of dance, including Kandyan and low-country dances. These forms are deeply rooted in religious rituals, storytelling, and social celebrations. Costumes, intricate footwork, and symbolic gestures characterize these dances, preserving cultural heritage and attracting both locals and tourists."},{"question":"Yaushe ne gwamnatin US ta ayyana cewa kungiyar haqqani, kungiyar ta'addanci ce?","answer":"a shekara 2012"},{"question":"Qual é a Capital do Estado do Maranhão, no Brazil?","answer":"A cidade de São Luís."},{"question":"Antara berikut, bahan radioaktif manakah digunakan untuk menentukan usia bahan arkeologi?A. Iodin-131B. Kobalt-60C. Karbon-14D. Natrium-24","answer":"Jawapannya ialah C. Karbon-14. Karbon-14, 14C, atau radiokarbon, adalah isotop radioaktif dari karbon dengan nukleus atom yang mengandungi 6 proton dan 8 neutron. Kewujudannya dalam bahan-bahan organik merupakan asas kepada kaedah pentarikhan radiokarbon yang dipelopori oleh Willard Libby dan rakan-rakannya pada tahun 1949 untuk tujuan pentarikhan sampel arkeologi, geologi dan hidrogeologi"},{"question":"Kahve falında 2 tane kalp görmek ne anlama gelir?","answer":"Falda Birden Fazla Kalp Görmenin AnlamıEğer kişi zaten sevilen bir insansa, arkadaş çevresinin genişleyeceği ve hayatına yeni insanların gireceği şeklinde yorumlanabilir. Kişinin bekar olduğu durumlarda, kahve falında kalp görmek kişiye ilgili olan birden fazla kişinin olduğu anlamına da gelmektedir."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: കേരളത്തിൽ നെൽകൃഷിക്ക് ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന പരമ്പരാഗത രീതികൾ ഏതൊക്കെയാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: കേരളത്തിലെ പരമ്പരാഗത നെൽകൃഷി രീതികളിൽ ജൈവ വളങ്ങൾ, കൈവേല, \\"പൊക്കാളി\\" സമ്പ്രദായം പോലുള്ള പരമ്പരാഗത ജലസേചന വിദ്യകൾ എന്നിവ ഉൾപ്പെടുന്നു."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca Naadigii uu u ciyaari jiray Ciyaaryahan Muriidi Abati iyo lambarkii          uu xiran jiray","answer":" Waxa uu u ciyaari jiray Naadigii Madbacadda (MBC) waxa uuna qaadan jiray          lambarka 10aad"},{"question":"Miten hiv tarttuu?","answer":"Hiv tarttuu: suojaamattomassa seksikontaktissa: emätin- ja anaaliyhdynnässä sekä suuseksissäveren välityksellä, esimerkiksi pistovälineiden yhteiskäytössä äidiltä lapselle. Lapsi voi saada tartunnan hiv-positiiviselta äidiltään raskauden, synnytyksen tai imetyksen aikana. Myös oireeton hiv-infektio tarttuu.Hiv ei tartu arkipäivän kontakteissa. Tartuntaa ei voi saada kosketuksesta, halaamisesta, suutelusta, kättelystä tai astioiden, ruuan tai juoman välityksellä. Hiv ei myöskään tartu hyönteisen piston kautta."},{"question":"ኤርፓድስ የተባለ ገመድ አልባ ድምፅ ማዳመጫ መጀመሪያ ያቀረበው ማነው?","answer":"አፕል ኩባንያ"},{"question":"السؤال: فسر مصطلح أيديولوجيا؟","answer":"الإجابة: هي ناتج عملية تكوين نسق فكري عام يفسر الطبيعة والمجتمع والفرد، ويحدد موقف فكري معين يربط الأفكار في مختلف الميادين الفكرية والسياسية والأخلاقية والفلسفية."},{"question":"¿Qué beneficios tiene el yoga?","answer":"El yoga es mucho más que una rutina de ejercicios para ponernos en forma, porque además de tonificar el cuerpo reconecta la mente; es una disciplina dos por uno que consigue renovarnos por fuera y resetearnos por dentro sin que apenas nos cueste. Porque el yoga es ese deporte tranquilo y sosegado donde los músculos trabajan y se tonifican -y mucho- casi sin que te cueste. \\"Tiene el poder de conectar cuerpo, mente y respiración, ayuda a trabajar las articulaciones y la fascia muscular, a ganar más flexibilidad y a relajar el cuerpo para tener un sueño más reparador y poder descansar mejor"},{"question":"थेरपी/उपचार सुरू केल्यानंतर कर्करोगाच्या रुग्णांना किती दिवसांत परिणाम दिसतात ?","answer":"औषधे सुरू केल्यानंतर काही दिवसांतच कर्करोगाची सर्व लक्षणे कमी होतात. उदाहरणार्थ, यकृताच्या कर्करोगाच्या रुग्णांमध्ये आढळणारी लक्षणे, जसे की भूक न लागणे, उलट्या होणे ही सर्व लक्षणे दुसऱ्या दिवसापासून दुसऱ्या आठवड्यात कमी होऊ लागतात. जलोदरातील (पोटात पाणी होणे) हा बदल दोन आठवड्यांत दिसू लागतो.आपण असे म्हणू शकतो की, होणारे परिणाम कर्करोगाच्या प्रकारावर आणि रुग्णाच्या विद्यमान शारीरिक स्थितीवर पूर्णपणे अवलंबून असतात.आयुर्वेदात दीर्घकाळानंतर परिणाम दिसून येतो असे म्हणणे पूर्णपणे चुकीचे आहे. हा एक असा आजार आहे ज्यामध्ये रुग्णाला आपला जीव गमवावा लागण्याचे प्रमाण अधिक असते. या आजारात कुणीही जास्त काळ जगू शकत नाही. पण आपल्या केमोथेरपीचे वैशिष्टय आहे की, वैद्यकीय उपचार पद्धती सुरू केल्यानंतर लगेचच त्याचे परिणाम दिसून येतात. अन्ननलिकेच्या कर्करोगात, जेव्हा रुग्ण पाण्याचा थेंबही पिऊ शकत नाही तेव्हा आम्ही अशी औषधे देतो, जी तिथूनच काम करण्यास सुरवात करतात.हळूहळू, रुग्ण पाणी किंवा चहा, कॉफी पिण्यास सुरुवात करतो.अगदी भातही खाऊ शकतो. काही दिवसांनंतर, अन्न देखील  खाण्यास सुरवात करतो. त्याचा कालावधी 3 ते 4 महिने असू शकतो."},{"question":"السؤال: إلى أين عرج الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"الإجابة: إلى السماوات العلى، عند سدرة المنتهي ؛ الحد الذي انقطعت عنده علوم الخلائق من إنس وجن."},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-cache","answer":"தேக்கம்"},{"question":"تحتوي اللحوم علي العديد من البروتينات فما هو مصدرها؟","answer":"الأحماض الأمينية."},{"question":"\\"Кудай безер\\" деген сыпатты кандай адамга айтсак болот?","answer":"\\"Кудай безер\\" деген сыпатты  - өтө шум, ашкан митаам адамга айтсак болот. Мисалы: Кудай безер паччагар, Түбүң залим турбайбы, Советтин соту менмин деп, Пара жеп сотту булгайбы! (Бейшеналиев)"},{"question":"chimanga cho otcha","answer":"Chimanga cho otcha chipezeka chimadyedwa kwambiri nthawi yoti chimanga changosala pang'ono kukwima."},{"question":"Mitkä ovat Clostridioides difficile -infektion oireet?","answer":"C. difficilen aiheuttaman paksusuolentulehduksen eli infektion oireita ovat:vesiripulipahoinvointivatsakipuruokahaluttomuuskuume. Oireet alkavat mikrobilääkehoidon aikana tai joskus vasta sen loputtua. Vakavin taudin muoto on pseudomembranoottinen enterokoliitti, jossa suolen tähystyksessä nähdään suolen seinämässä katteisia, tulehtuneita alueita. Vakava taudinmuoto voi olla henkeä uhkaava. Paksusuoli voidaan joutua poistamaan leikkauksella."},{"question":"අස්වැන්න ලබාගැනීමෙන් පසුව, කුඹුරු හිමියා වෙත “දැකුම්” ගෙනයාමේ ක්‍රමය කුමක්ද?","answer":"අස්වැන්න ලබාගැනීමෙන් පසුව, කුඹුරු හිමියා වෙත “දැකුම්” ගෙනයාමේ ක්‍රමයක් ද පැවතිණි. දැකුම් ගෙනයාම යනු කැවුම්, කිරිබත්, හෝ වෑංජන සහිත බත් පෙට්ටියක් කැවිලි වර්ග, බුලත්, පුවක්, දුම් කොළ, කෙහෙල් කැනක් ආදිය සමග කුඹුරු හිමියා බැහැ දැකීමට යාමයි."},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity: \\"Nandalo ramaka ka ..........\\"","answer":"Ilay ohabolana dia :\\"Nandalo ramaka ka may ny tanàna!\\"."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Hiện CLB Hà Nội dẫn đầu bảng xếp hạng với 17 điểm, SLNA xếp thứ 2 với 16 điểm. Vì vậy, trận Hà Nội - SLNA được xem là cuộc \\"đại chiến\\" và đội nào giành chiến thắng sẽ nắm giữ vị trí dẫn đầu trên bảng xếp hạng V-League . Hà Nội đang có những cầu thủ có phong độ ấn tượng là Văn Quyết, Siladi, Tuấn Hải... Nhưng đáng chú ý là sự trở lại của Đoàn Văn Hậu sau khi bình phục chấn thương. Dù vậy, chủ nhà Hà Nội sẽ không có sự chỉ đạo của HLV trưởng Chun Jae Ho do ông bị nhiễm COVID-19. ","answer":"\\"Trực tuyến CLB Hà Nội - SLNA (hiệp 2) 2-1: Thành Chung ghi bàn nâng tỉ số.\\""},{"question":"Lẹyin ọdun mẹta lọgba ẹwọn, Ṣeun Ẹgbẹgbẹ tun n bọ nile-ẹjọ o","answer":"Iroyin kan ti wa nita bayii nipa Ṣeun Kareem, ẹni tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Ẹgbẹgbẹ, wọn lo ṣee ṣe ki igbẹjọ lori ọrọ ẹ tun waye lọjọ kẹfa oṣu kẹwaa ọdun yii, lẹyin to ti lo ọdun mẹta gbako lọgba ẹwọn nibi ti wọn gbagbe ẹ si.Gbajumọ nla ni ọdọmọkunrin yii, lara ohun tawọn eeyan mọ ọn si daadaa ki wahala ẹsun idigunjale ti wọn fi kan an yii too ṣẹlẹ ni ṣiṣe igbelarugẹ fawọn olorin, to si tun maa n gbe sinima Yoruba jade. Oun paapaa ti sọ ọ ri wi pe, oun lawọn mọto akero to maa n pawo wale foun daadaa, bẹẹ loun tun ni ile itura tawọn eeyan ti maa n gbafẹ.Ohun tawọn eeyan mọ mọ Ṣeun Egbẹgbẹ ree o, ki ariwo too gbalu wi pe, ọkunrin naa ni awọn ohun mi-in to n ṣe daadaa ni ikọkọ.Ile-ẹjọ giga (Federal High Court) l’Ekoo lọkunrin yii ti kọkọ foju han niwaju Adajọ Olurẹmi Oguntoyinbo ninu oṣu keji ọdun 2017. Latigba naa lo ti wa lọgba ẹwọn.Ṣeun Ẹgbẹgbẹ atawọn eeyan wọnyi, Oyekan Ayọmide, Lawal Kareem, Ọlalekan Yusuf ati Muyideen Shoyọmbo ni wọn jọ fi ẹsun jibiti ati idigunjale kan. Ẹsun bii ogoji ni wọn si ka si wọn lẹsẹ.Lara ẹsun ti wọn fi kan Ẹgbẹgbẹ atawọn oluku ẹ ni pe wọn lu awọn Hausa ti wọn maa n ṣẹ owo dọla ni jibiti owo to fẹẹ to ogoji miliọnu naira (N39, 098,100), ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọrun owo dọla (90,000) ati owo to fẹẹ to ẹgbẹrun mẹtala owo Euro (£12,550)Wọn ni bo ṣe gba owo yii kaakiri lọwọ awọn Hausa to n ṣẹ owo ilẹ okeere si owo ilẹ wa niyẹn o, ati pe aẁọn Mọla onidọla ọhun to fara gba a, wọn a fẹẹ to bii ọgbọn kaakiri ipinlẹ Eko laarin ọdun 2015 si 2017.Ohun ti a n gbọ bayii ni pe o ṣee ṣe ki igbẹjọ waye lori ẹsun ti wọn fi kan ọkunrin yii lẹyin ọdun mẹta o le to ti wa lọgba ẹwọn. Ọjọ kẹfa oṣu kẹwaa ọdun yii ni wọn sọ pe Ẹgbẹgbẹ yoo tun wa si kootu lẹẹkan si i, lẹyin ọpọlọpọ oṣu to ti wa ni ahamọ ijọba.Ṣe ni nnkan bi ọdun mẹta sẹyin ni wahala ọhun bẹrẹ wẹrẹ ladugbo kan n’Ikeja l’Ekoo nibi ti wọn ti n ta ọpọlọpọ foonu alagbeeka, kọmputa atawọn ẹrọ igbalode mi-in tawọn eeyan n lo. Awọn ọmọ Ibo lo fẹẹ pọju nibi ti a n sọ yii, nibẹ gan-an ni wọn sọ pe Ṣeun Ẹgbẹgbẹ lọ, ko si ohun meji to lọ ṣe nibẹ, wọn ni foonu Iphone olowo nla nla ni ọkunrin yii lọ ji gbe pẹlu awọn eeyan kan ti wọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ ibi.Nibẹ gan an lọwọ ti tẹ ẹ, Iphone mẹwaa ni wọn ba lọwọ ẹ pẹlu, tọrọ ọhun si di ti ọlọpaa. Alaye ti Ṣeun Ẹgbẹgbẹ ṣe ni kete to bọ lọwọ awọn ọlọpaa ni pe, oun ko jale o, wọn kan fẹẹ fi iṣẹlẹ ọhun ba oun lorukọ jẹ ni.Ọrọ ọhun fẹẹ ma ti i lọ silẹ, ṣadeede lariwo tun gba ilu laarin ọsẹ meloo kan sira wọn wi pe wọn tun ti mu Ṣeun lagbegbe kan l’Ekoo, ati pe owo dọla ati Euro to fẹẹ ji gbe lọwọ awọn Hausa ti wọn maa n ṣe pasipaarọ owo lo koba a.Nibẹ yẹn gan-an ni wahala buruku ti de ba oun atawọn ẹmẹwaa, n lọrọ ọhun ba dele-ẹjọ ti igbẹjọ si bẹrẹ lojuẹsẹ.Gbogbo akitiyan agbẹjọro ẹ lati wa beeli fun ọkunrin yii lo jasi pabo o, nitori niṣe ni adajọ ni ko lọ wa owo iduro miliọnu marun-un naira wa, bẹẹ lo tun gbọdọ ni oniduro meji ti wọn yoo je ọga patapata lẹnu iṣẹ ijọba. Nibẹ yẹn gan-an ni idaamu buruku yii ti de ba Ṣeun Kareem.Wọn lohun to ṣẹlẹ ni pe, ọkunrin naa ko ri eeyan kan bayii duro fun un nitori ko sẹni to fẹẹ fi iṣẹ ẹ tabi orukọ rere ẹ ṣere. Bi ko ṣe ri oniduro ati owo miliọnu marun-un naira ti won sọ niyen, ti ọrọ ẹ si dabi ẹni ti wọn sọ pe yoo pẹ lẹwọn ju ọbọ lọ.Ni kete ti wahala ọhun ṣẹlẹ, pupọ ninu awọn eeyan ẹ lo sa fun un, koda lagbo awọn oṣere to ti lẹnu daadaa, yẹyẹ ni wọn n fi ọrọ ẹ ṣe, ti ko si si onifuji kan bayii, to tun kọrin ki i mọ.Ọkunrin olorin hip-hop kan tiẹ gbe orin kan jade to pe ni Jẹ ki n fun wọn l’Ẹgbẹgbẹ, eyi to fi ṣalaye bi gbogbo ọrọ ọhun ṣe jẹ pata.Ni bayii, adura tawọn eeyan ẹ n gba bayii ni pe ki Ọlọrun ṣiju aanu wo o, ki ọrọ ẹ yanju lọjọ kẹfa oṣu kẹwaa to n bọ yii nigba ti igbẹjọ yoo tun waye ni kootu."},{"question":"\\"स्मृतिले जीवनलाई रंगिन बनाउँछ।\\"जीवन एक अद्वितीय यात्रा हो, जुन महान परिवर्तनहरू, मानवताका भावनाहरू, र सम्पूर्णता विश्वका साथै साथै आफ्नो चुनौतिहरू ल्याएको छ। हामीले अनेक पटक आफ्नो यात्रामा परिवर्तनमा सामाजिक, आर्थिक, र साहित्यिक रूपमा प्रभावित भएका छौं। जीवन आफ्नो छलफलहरूले भरिएको छ, जसमा हामीले धेरै बाटोहरू पार गरेर एक नयाँ पर्याप्तिमा पुगेर नयाँ संभावनाहरूमा सामर्थ्य प्रदर्शन गर्न सकेका छौं।आजकल, बस्ने खानेपिने घर छोड्ने समयमा, तपाईंले यात्रा गर्नुपर्छ, नयाँ भाषाहरू सिक्नुपर्छ, अन्य संस्कृतिहरूमा पारिवारिक तथा सामाजिक घटनाहरूमा सक्रिय भाग लिनुपर्छ। यो सबै हामीलाई आत्मविश्वास दिन्छ र हाम्रो सृजनात्मक अभिवृद्धि गर्ने सामर्थ्य प्रदान गर्दछ। यही क्रमले हाम्रा सपनाहरूलाई साकार गर्दछ र हाम्रा प्राथमिकताहरूलाई प्राथमिकता दिन्छ।हामीले एक जीवन बिताउँछौं, जसमा अवसरहरू, चुनौतिहरू, र कठिनाइहरू पर्दछन्। यस यात्रामा हामी धैर्य, परिश्रम, विद्या, र संगठनशीलता जस्ता गुणहरू विकसित गर्नुपर्छ। सफल हुनको लागि, हामीले आफ्नो लक्ष्यहरू सम्पन्न गर्नुपर्छ, आत्मविश्वास रख्नुपर्छ, र साथै सधैं कठिनाइहरूसँग मुकाबला गर्नुपर्छ।निम्नलिखित पाठको आधारमा निम्नलिखित प्रश्नको उत्तर दिनुहोस्:स्मृतिहरूले जीवनलाई कसरी रंगिन बनाउँछन्? ","answer":"स्मृतिहरूले जीवनलाई अनुभवहरूले भरिएको रंगिन बनाउँछन्।"},{"question":"ਇਮੇਜਨ ਚੈਨਲ ਨੇ ‘ਜਮੁਨਾ ਪਾਰ’ ਨਾਮੀ ਇੱਕ ਨਵਾਂ ਲੜੀਵਾਰ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਵਿਧੀ ਤੇ ਬਿਜੂ ਦੇ ਇਰਦ-ਗਿਰਦ ਘੁੰਮਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਪਾਸੇ ਵਿਧੀ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਦੀ ਖਾਤਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਬਦਲ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਬਿਜੂ ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੀ ਬਦਲ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਖ਼ੂਬਸੂਰਤ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਨੂੰ ਬਿਆਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਇਹ ਲੜੀਵਾਰ। ਜਮੁਨਾ ਪਾਰ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਚਲਿਤ ਦੋ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਫ਼ਰਕ ਦਰਸਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਵਿਧੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਸ਼ਾਲੀ, ਸ਼ਰਮੀਲੀ, ਪਰਦੇ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਫੈਸ਼ਨ ਡਿਜ਼ਾਈਨਰ ਹੈ, ਉੱਥੇ ਬਿਜੂ ਲਾਪਰਵਾਹ ਪਰ ਬੇਹੱਦ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਭਾਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਮੁੰਡਾ ਹੈ,ਜੋ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰਕ ਕਾਰੋਬਾਰ ’ਚ ਹੱਥ ਵਟਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਵਿਧੀ ਤੇ ਬਿਜੂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਉਲਟ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਤਵ, ਜੀਵਨ ਸ਼ੈਲੀ ਅਤੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਕਾਇਦੇ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਨਾਲ ਚਲਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਚੁਣੌਤੀਆਂ ’ਚੋਂ ਲੰਘਣਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਟੀਮ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਭਰਪੂਰ ਲੜੀਵਾਰ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਆਮ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਸੰਦ ਆਵੇਗਾ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਲੜੀਵਾਰ ‘ਜਮੁਨਾ ਪਾਰ’ ਕਿਸ ਚੈਨਲ ਨੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃਲੜੀਵਾਰ ‘ਜਮੁਨਾ ਪਾਰ’ ਇਮੇਜਨ  ਚੈਨਲ ਨੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"கேள்வி: மனித உடலில் மிகப்பெரிய எலும்பு எது?","answer":"பதில் : மனித உடலில் மிகப்பெரிய எலும்பு தொடை எலும்பு. நடு உடலுடன், இடுப்பெலும்புடன், தொட்டுக்கொண்டிருப்பதால் மேற்கால் பகுதிக்குத் தொடை என்று பெயர். தொடையெலும்பு மனித உடம்பில் வலிமையானதும் நீளமானதுமான எலும்பு ஆகும். சராசரி மனிதனின் தொடையெலும்பு 48 சென்டிமீட்டர் நீளம் கொண்டது. இதன் குறுக்கு வெட்டு விட்டம் சராசரியாக 2.34 செமீ (0.92 in) இருக்கும்."},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"કાનજી તારી મા કહેશે પણ અમે\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"કાનજી તારી મા કહેશે પણ અમે કાનુડો કહેશું રે...એટલું કહેતા નહી માને તો ગોકુળ મેલી દેશું રે... કાનજી તારી મા....\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"કાનજી તારી મા કહેશે પણ અમે કાનુડો કહેશું રે...એટલું કહેતા નહી માને તો ગોકુળ મેલી દેશું રે... કાનજી તારી મા....માખણ ખાતાં નહોતું આવડતું મુખ હતું તારૂં એંઠુ રે...ગોપીઓએ તારું ઘર કેરાણુ જઈ ખુણામાં પેઠું રે... કાનજી તારી મા....ઝુલણી પહેરતાં નહોતું આવડતું અમે તે દી' પહેરાવતાં રે...ભરવાડોની ગાળ્યું ખાતો અમે તે દિ' છોડાવતાં રે... કાનજી તારી મા....કાલો ઘેલો તારા માત-પિતાનો અમને શેના કોડ રે...કરમ સંજોગે આવી ભરાણા આંગણાં જોડાજોડ રે... કાનજી તારી મા....ઘૂટણીયા ભેર હાલતો ચાલતો બોલતો કાલું ઘેલું રે...ભલે મળ્યા મહેતા નરસિંહના સ્વામી પ્રેમ ભક્તિમાં રેલું રે...કાનજી તારી મા કહેશે પણ અમે કાનુડો કહેશું રે..."},{"question":"නැකැත් නොමැති කාලය  යන්නට තනි වචනයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"නොනගතය "},{"question":"வினா:பைலட் ஆன முதல் இந்திய பெண் யார்?","answer":"விடை: கேப்டன் பிரேம் மாத்தூர்"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Khó như... thoái vốn","answer":"Đây không còn là \\"mục tiêu phấn đấu\\", bởi Quyết định 22/2021/QĐ-TTg của Thủ tướng Chính phủ về tiêu chí phân loại doanh nghiệp nhà nước, doanh nghiệp có vốn nhà nước thực hiện chuyển đổi sở hữu, sắp xếp lại, thoái vốn giai đoạn 2021-2025 ban hành cách đây 1 năm đã ấn định rõ thời điểm phải hoàn thành nhiệm vụ nêu trên. Như vậy, nhiệm vụ đặt ra trong hơn 3 năm tới phải \\"thanh lý\\" toàn bộ số doanh nghiệp dưới 50% vốn nhà nước là rất nặng nề. Nhiệm vụ càng trở nên nặng nề hơn khi đã qua hơn 1 năm kể từ khi Thủ tướng ban hành Quyết định 22/2021/QĐ-TTg ấn định việc \\"khai tử\\" loại hình doanh nghiệp nói trên, nhưng đến nay, tình hình hầu như không chuyển biến. Dù có đưa ra những lý do khách quan để \\"đổ thừa\\", nhưng không thể không thừa nhận một thực tế là, trong giai đoạn 2016-2020, các bộ, ngành, địa phương đã thất bại trong việc thoái vốn nhà nước trong bối cảnh Thủ tướng Chính phủ ban hành tới 4 quyết định về vấn đề này. Cụ thể, trong cả giai đoạn trên chỉ thoái được 6.493 tỷ đồng tại 106 doanh nghiệp, tức chỉ đạt 30% về số lượng doanh nghiệp và 11% số vốn cần phải thoái theo kế hoạch. Tới nay, số doanh nghiệp dưới 50% vốn nhà nước còn tồn tại là 161 đơn vị (gồm 3 tổng công ty cổ phần, 1 công ty mẹ con và 157 công ty độc lập). Nhưng việc \\"thanh lý\\" 161 đơn vị là không hề đơn giản, vì vẫn còn tới 8.407 tỷ đồng vốn nhà nước tại những doanh nghiệp này, tức trị giá vốn phải thoái còn lớn hơn tổng số vốn nhà nước đã thoái tại tất cả doanh nghiệp (bao gồm số doanh nghiệp mà Nhà nước chiếm từ 50% đến 65% và từ 65% đến dưới 100%) giai đoạn 5 năm trước. Ở góc nhìn khác, vốn cũng là một loại hàng hóa, vì hiểu một cách thông thường, vốn là toàn bộ giá trị vật chất được doanh nghiệp đầu tư để tiến hành hoạt động sản xuất, kinh doanh. Theo đó, chỉ hàng hóa có chất lượng mới thu hút được khách hàng, trong khi chất lượng của phần lớn vốn nhà nước tại doanh nghiệp mà Nhà nước là cổ đông thiểu số lại không cao. Nhìn chung, bức tranh tổng thể về tình hình tài chính và hoạt động của doanh nghiệp mà tại đó, đại diện vốn nhà nước không có tiếng nói quyết định là khá ảm đạm. Báo cáo của Bộ Tài chính vào cuối năm 2021 về hoạt động của doanh nghiệp có vốn nhà nước dưới 50% cho thấy, doanh thu của khối doanh nghiệp này trong năm 2020 giảm 3% so với năm 2019; lãi trước thuế chỉ tăng 1% - thấp hơn cả tốc độ lạm phát (3,23%). Có 39/161 đơn vị bị lỗ trong năm 2020 với lỗ 322 tỷ đồng. Đến đầu năm 2021, có tổng cộng 44 doanh nghiệp (chiếm hơn 27% số doanh nghiệp) vẫn còn lỗ lũy kế, với tổng số tiền lên đến 2.809 tỷ đồng, tức là chiếm hơn 1/3 vốn nhà nước tại doanh nghiệp. Trong giai đoạn 2021-2025, ngoài số doanh nghiệp dưới 50% vốn nhà nước phải thoái toàn bộ, hiện còn một lượng lớn doanh nghiệp mà Nhà nước nắm giữ trên 50% vốn điều lệ cũng buộc phải thoái vốn. Quyết định 22/2021/QĐ-TTg cũng quy định 14 nhóm lĩnh vực nhà nước sở hữu từ 50% đến dưới 65% và từ 65% đến dưới 100%, đồng thời buộc phải thoái vốn nhà nước tại tất cả doanh nghiệp hoạt động ngoài 14 lĩnh vực này. Đây là bài toán rất khó vì nhiều doanh nghiệp thuộc nhóm này có tình hình tài chính không mấy sáng sủa, hoạt động sản xuất, kinh doanh không mấy hấp dẫn nhà đầu tư. Làm thế nào để thoái vốn theo mục tiêu đề ra là câu hỏi khiến các cơ quan quản lý nhà nước, cơ quan đại diện chủ sở hữu vốn nhà nước đau đầu. Việc thực hiện nhiệm vụ tại Quyết định 22/2021/QĐ-TTg lại càng khó khăn hơn trước thực tế là ngay cả doanh nghiệp làm ăn hiệu quả, tài chính lành mạnh đã đem bán vốn nhiều lần, song đành \\"mang đến lại mang về\\" hoặc bán được quá ít so với trị giá chào bán. Thoái vốn nhà nước tại doanh nghiệp trong giai đoạn 2021-2025 không chỉ là nhiệm vụ, mà đã trở thành mệnh lệnh đối với các bộ, ngành, địa phương. Ngoài Quyết định 22/2021/QĐ-TTg của Chính phủ, Nghị quyết 23/2021/QH15 ngày 28/7/2021 của Quốc hội về kế hoạch tài chính quốc gia và vay, trả nợ công 5 năm giai đoạn 2021-2025 đã giao nhiệm vụ, trong giai đoạn này phải thu bằng được ít nhất 248.000 tỷ đồng, nếu không sẽ khó thu xếp vốn để đầu tư phát triển hạ tầng kinh tế, xã hội. Thực tế trên đòi hỏi các cơ quan quản lý nhà nước phải sớm có kế hoạch, sớm có phương án, sớm có giải pháp hữu hiệu để thực thi mệnh lệnh này."},{"question":"নিচের প্রসঙ্গ দিয়ে শুরু করে একটি অনুচ্ছেদ লিখুন : এই মাসের প্রথম দিনে, ভালেনসিয়ার বিরুদ্ধে একটি আত্মঘাতী গোল এবং বাজকেজের গোলের মাধ্যমে ২–০ গোলে জয়লাভ করে ৩ পয়েন্ট অর্জন করে। ২০১৮ সালের ৬ই ডিসেম্বর তারিখে, কোপা দেল রে'র ৩২ দলের পর্বের ফিরতি লেগে মেলিয়ার বিরুদ্ধে আসেন্সিও ও ইস্কোর জোড়া গোল এবং ভিনিসিউস ও হাভি সানচেজের একটি গোলের মাধ্যমে ৬–১ গোলে জয়লাভ করে; এর ফলে রিয়াল মাদ্রিদ সামগ্রিকভাবে ১০–১ গোলে জয়লাভ করে ১৬ দলের পর্বে অগ্রসর হয়। তিন দিন পর, বেলের করা একমাত্র গোলের মাধ্যমে এসডি উয়েস্কার বিরুদ্ধে অ্যাওয়ে ম্যাচে ১–০ গোলে জয়লাভ করে। চ্যাম্পিয়নস লিগের গ্রুপ পর্বের শেষ ম্যাচে মাদ্রিদ রুশ ক্লাব সিএসকেএ মস্কোর বিরুদ্ধে ০–৩ ব্যবধানে পরাজিত হয়েছিল। ২০১৮ সালের ১৫ই ডিসেম্বর তারিখে, বেনজেমার করা একমাত্র গোলের বিনিময়ে মাদ্রিদ রায়ো ভায়েকানোর বিরুদ্ধে ১–০ গোলে জয়লাভ করেছিল। ২০১৮ সালের ১৯শে ডিসেম্বর তারিখে, ২০১৮ ফিফা ক্লাব বিশ্বকাপের","answer":"সেমি-ফাইনালে জাপানের ক্লাব কাশিমা অ্যান্টলার্সকে ৩–১ গোলে হারিয়ে দেয়; উক্ত ম্যাচে বেল এই মৌসুমে প্রথমবারের মতো হ্যাট্রিক করেন। ৩ দিন পর, ফাইনালে সংযুক্ত আরব আমিরাতের ক্লাব আল-আইনকে ৪–১ গোলে হারিয়ে টানা তৃতীয় বার এবং রেকর্ড পরিমাণ ৪ বার ফিফা ক্লাব বিশ্বকাপের শিরোপা জয়লাভ করে; এই ম্যাচে লুকা মদরিচ, মার্কোজ ইয়োরেন্তে, রামোস একটি করে গোল করেছিল।"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Ny _ dia namana hatrany fa ny lainga avoakany no hialao lavitra\\"","answer":"Ny mpandainga dia namana hatrany fa ny lainga avoakany no hialao lavitra"},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"અખિલ બ્રહ્માંડમાં એક તું શ્રી હરિ\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"અખિલ બ્રહ્માંડમાં એક તું શ્રીહરિ, જૂજવે રૂપે અનંત ભાસે;દેહમાં દેવ તું, તેજમાં તત્વ તું, શૂન્યમાં શબ્દ થઈ વેદ વાસે. ટેક.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"પવન તું, પાણી તું, ભૂમિ તું ભૂધરા,વૃક્ષ થઈ ફૂલી રહ્યો આકાશે;વિવિધ રચના કરી અનેક રસ ચાખવા,શિવ થકી જીવ થયો એ જ આશે.અખિલ બ્રહ્માંડમાં એક તું શ્રીહરિવેદ તો એમ વદે શ્રુતિ-સ્મૃતિ શાખ દે,કનક કુંડલ વિષે ભેદ ન હોયે;ઘાટ ઘડિયા પછી નામરૂપ જૂજવાં,અંતે તો હેમનું હેમ હોયે.અખિલ બ્રહ્માંડમાં એક તું શ્રીહરિગ્રંન્થે ગડબડ કરી, વાત ન ખરી કહીજેહને જે ગમે તેને તે પૂજેમન-વચન-કર્મથી આપ માની લહેસત્ય છે એ જ મન એમ સૂઝેઅખિલ બ્રહ્માંડમાં એક તું શ્રીહરિવૃક્ષમાં બીજ તું, બીજમાં વૃક્ષ તું,જોઉં પટંતરો એ જ પાસે;ભણે નરસૈંયો એ મન તણી શોધના,પ્રીત કરું પ્રેમથી પ્રગટ થાશે. અખિલ બ્રહ્માંડમાં એક તું શ્રીહરિ"},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 元気に生活するために、厚生労働省は食事や生活の習慣について、約10年に1回目標を作っています。2024年度からの新しい目標が決まりました。野菜や果物を食べる量は、脳や心臓の病気で亡くなる割合を低くすることに関係があります。このため、1日に食べる野菜を今より70gぐらい多い350gにしました。果物は、2倍以上の200gにしました。バランスがいい食事を1日2回以上、ほとんど毎日とる人の割合を50％にしたいと考えています。今、1日に食べている塩の量は10.1gですが、血圧が高くならないように、7gより少なくしたいと考えています。寝る時間が足りないと、亡くなる割合が高くなることがわかってきました。このため、20歳から59歳の人は6時間から9時間、60歳以上の人は6時間から8時間寝たほうがいいと言っています。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- 厚生労働省: 1）国民の健康や生活を守る仕事や、労働者が仕事を見つけるのを助けたり、労働者を保護したりする国の役所。厚労省。- 約: 1）ちかう。取り決める。2）縮める。省く。簡単にする。3）おおよそ。ほぼ。だいたい。- 目標: 1）ものごとをなしとげるための目当て。2）行きつくための目じるし。- 年度: 1）仕事の都合で決めた一年の期間。ふつう四月一日に始まり、翌年の三月三十一日に終わる。- 量: 1）かさ。ますめ。2）物をはかる。3）心や能力の大きさ。- 脳: 1）頭の中にあって、考えたり体を動かしたりするはたらきを受け持つところ。- 心臓: 1）胸の左側にあって、血液を体じゅうに送り出すポンプの役目をする器官。こぶしぐらいの大きさで、左右の心房と左右の心室の四つの部分からできている。2）ものごとの大切な部分。3）度胸がよくて、物おじしないこと。- 割合: 1）物と物との関係を、数で表したもの。割。率。歩合。2）思いのほか。比較的。- バランス: 1）つり合い。平均。- 血圧: 1）心臓から送り出された血が、血管を内側からおす力。"},{"question":"No português do Brasil, a palavra \\"coração\\" tem quantas sílabas?","answer":"A palavra \\"coração\\" tem 3 sílabas: co-ra-ção."},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: Katar, 2022 FIFA Dünya Kupası ev sahipliğini kazanmasının ardından FIFA Başkanı Joseph Blatter, ev sahibi ülkeye saygı gösterilsin diye eşcinsel hayranların orada iken","answer":" cinsel ilişkiye girmemesini dilemişti. Bu açıklamadan dolayı çok sert eleştirilere tabi olduktan sonra Blatter, bu açıklama için özür diledi."},{"question":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் பண்பாடு மற்றும் கலாச்சாரத்தில் பன்முகத்தன்மை காணப்படுகிறது என்பதற்கு சில எடுத்துக்காட்டுகள் யாவை?","answer":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் பண்பாடு மற்றும் கலாச்சாரத்தில் பல்வேறு சமூகங்கள் மற்றும் மதங்கள் ஒன்றிணைந்திருப்பதை காணலாம். தமிழ்நாட்டில் ஆதியில் வாழ்ந்த பல சமூகங்களின் பண்பாட்டு கூறுகள் இன்றுவரை பாதுகாக்கப்பட்டு வருகின்றன. தமிழ்நாட்டில் கிறிஸ்துவம், இஸ்லாம், பௌத்தம் போன்ற பிற மதங்களும் பரவலாக பின்பற்றப்படுகின்றன."},{"question":"የአዲስ አበባ ዩኒቨርሲቲ መገኛ ከተማ ማናት?","answer":"አዲስ አበባ"},{"question":"Dime palabras del Español que provengan del árabe.","answer":"Algunas palabras del español que tienen influencia del árabe son: aceite, azúcar, algodón, almohada, café, albahaca, azafrán, guitarra o  limón."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的戰略兵書是哪一部？","answer":"答案：《孫子兵法》"},{"question":"චීනය විසින් ඉදිකරන අභ්‍යවකාශ නැවැතුම්පොළ වන්නේ කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ටියැංගොන් අභ්‍යවකාශ නැවැතුම්පොළ"},{"question":"Apakah kebaikan sengkuang?","answer":"Sengkuang membantu pencernaan kerana mempunyai kandungan serat yang tinggi yang boleh membantu mengatasi sembelit dan menyokong kesihatan usus. Kandungan vitamin C yang tinggi juga melindungi kulit dan membantu pembentukan kolagen, serta merangsang kulit cerah dan lembap untuk menjamin kesihatan kulit. Sengkuang membantu mengawal berat badan kerana kangungan kalori yang rendah dan kandungan seratnya yang tinggi, Kalium dalam sengkuang juga dapat mengekang tekanan darah dan serat dapat mengurangkan kolesterol."},{"question":"અહીં ગંગાસતી રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"ચક્ષુ બદલાણી ને\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"ચક્ષુ બદલાણી ને સુવાંત વરસી,ને ફળી ગઈ પૂરવની પ્રીત રે.ટળી ગઈ અંતરની આપદા,ને પાળી સાંગોપાંગ રૂડી રીત રે ... ચક્ષુ.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"ચક્ષુ બદલાણી ને સુવાંત વરસી,ને ફળી ગઈ પૂરવની પ્રીત રે.ટળી ગઈ અંતરની આપદા,ને પાળી સાંગોપાંગ રૂડી રીત રે ... ચક્ષુ.નાભિકમળમાંથી પવન ઉલટાવ્યો,ને ગયો પશ્ચિમ દિશામાંહ્ય રે,સુસ્તી ચડી ગઈ સૂનમાં,ને ચિત્ત માંહી પુરૂષ ભાળ્યા ત્યાંય રે ... ચક્ષુ. અવિગત અલખ અખંડ અવિનાશી રેઅવ્યકતા પુરૂષ અવિનાશી રે,બાળીને સુરતા એમાં લય થઈ ગઈ,હવે મટી ગયો જન્મનો ભાસ રે ... ચક્ષુ. ઉપદેશ મળી ગયોને કરાવ્યો પરિપૂરણ અભ્યાસ રે,ગંગા રે સતી એમ બોલિયાંને આવ્યો પરિપૂરણ વિશ્વાસ રે ... ચક્ષુ."},{"question":"మీర్ మహబూబ్ అలీ కాలంలో విద్యాభివృద్ధి గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"ఇతడు వైద్యాలయములు, విద్యాలయములు స్థాపించెను. సిటీ కళాశాల ఉస్మానియా వైద్యాలయము, యునాని వైద్యాలయములు స్థాపించెను. మ్యూజియము, జూబ్లీహాలు నిర్మింపబడెను. విద్యావ్యాప్తికి ఇతడు అనేక ప్రాంతాలలో పాఠశాలలు నిర్మించెను."},{"question":"ලොව වැඩිම චිත්‍රපට ගණනක් නිෂ්පාදනය කරන රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඉන්දියාව"},{"question":"உங்கள் பள்ளியில் நடைபெற்ற பாட்டுப்போட்டி நிகழ்வுகள் குறித்துப் பேசுக.","answer":"வணக்கம்!எங்கள் பள்ளியில் நவம்பர் பதினான்கு அன்று குழந்தைகள் தினம் கொண்டாடப்பட்டது.அன்று பல போட்டிகள் நடைபெற்றது. நான் பாட்டுப் போட்டியில் கலந்து கொண்டேன். ஒவ்வொருவரும் ஒவ்வொரு பாடலைப் பாடினர். ஒரு சிலர் நடனமாடியும் பாடல் பாடியும் மகிழ்ந்தனர். ஒரு சிலர் இசைக்கருவிகளை இசைத்தனர். என்னுடைய தோழி குறையொன்றுமில்லை ‘ என்ற எம். எஸ். சுப்புலட்சுமியின் பாடலைப் பாடினாள். அனைவரும் அப்பாடலை மெய்மறந்து கேட்டனர். ‘பாடலுக்கு அழகு கேட்டார் நன்று எனக் கூறல்’ என்ற சிறுபஞ்சமூலம் கூற்றின்படி அவளுடைய பாடலை அனைவரும் ரசித்தனர். இறுதியில் பரிசு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது. என் தோழிக்குப் பரிசு கிடைத்தது. நான் மிகவும் மகிழ்ந்தேன்."},{"question":"السؤال: إلى أين عرج الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"الإجابة: إلى السماوات العلى، عند سدرة المنتهي ؛ الحد الذي انقطعت عنده علوم الخلائق من إنس وجن."},{"question":"Văn bản này nói về sự kiện quan trọng nào? - Vòng chung kết do Việt Nam làm chủ nhà từ 14 tới 25 tháng 5 năm 2014, gồm tám đội, bốn trong số đó – Úc, Trung Quốc, Nhật Bản và Hàn Quốc – không phải đá vòng loại nhờ thứ hạng của họ tại Cúp bóng đá nữ châu Á 2010, trong khi bốn đội còn lại được xác định thông qua vòng loại. bị cấm thi đấu do các trường hợp dính doping tại Giải bóng đá nữ vô địch thế giới 2011.","answer":"Văn bản này nói về sự kiện \\"Vòng chung kết Cúp bóng đá nữ châu Á\\" diễn ra từ 14 tới 25 tháng 5 năm 2014 tại Việt Nam. Trong sự kiện này:- Việt Nam là nước chủ nhà tổ chức.- Có tám đội tham dự.- Bốn đội: Úc, Trung Quốc, Nhật Bản và Hàn Quốc không phải tham gia vòng loại do họ có thứ hạng cao tại Cúp bóng đá nữ châu Á 2010.- Bốn đội còn lại được chọn thông qua vòng loại.- Có thông tin về việc một số đội bị cấm thi đấu do dính líu tới vụ doping tại Giải bóng đá nữ vô địch thế giới năm 2011."},{"question":"(ekhomba uMaShezi) We MaShezi! Musa ukudlala ngoMbadlwa.Angangena kanjani esikoleni eselugodo oludala kangaka? (ahleke)Udlala ngami ngempela uMaShezi.(ehleka) Hhayi-bo! Nami ngiyazincokolela nje. Angihambe ngiyobonaizimbiza zami. (asukume aphume)Mbandlwa mfowethu, emhlanganweni ngizokwethula uhlelolokudonsa amanzi ngamapayipi umuzi nomuzi. Engethemba ukuthilokho kuyisidingo esibaluleke kakhulu esizweni.Kuyosiza nokuthi nalaba bantu abathi uzenza inkosi babone ukuthiubalulekile kubo. Futhi ngiyakutshela bayophenduka balifelengamathe elenkosi izwi.Mina angifuni balifele ngamathe elenkosi kodwa yiyo inkosieyokwenza ukuthi abantu balifele ngamathe elayo izwi. Kodwa umakusekhona abantu abanjengoDlamini, sengathi akukezulungangempela.(achithe izandla) Hhayi, khohlwa yilowo. Naye uzoyibona intuthukomaqede abone ngokunye. Okwakobani ukukha amanzi empompiningezansana kwendlu?Wowu! Umuntu ongukhandaqinile akakuboni ubuhle obenziwangumuntu amzondayo. Phela uyangizonda uDlamini. AsimyekeuDlamini okwamanje. Indlela obeka ngayo inginika ithemba.Mbandlwa, ngicela usho uma ngabe unenkinga nge-air time futhiungajwayeli ukuwuvala umakhalekhukhwini wakho.Cha, okwamanje ngisenayo. Phela kuseyiyo lena owanginika yona.Uzame-ke ukucupha isisoka enkulumweni yakho ngosukulomhlangano. Angifuni ukubona umholi wami ebhibhidla phambikwabantu1. Tomula ibinzana lamagama esiqeshini afakazela ukuthi uMbandlwa ubonasengathi uDlamini uzoguqula umqondo wakhe uma eseyibona intuthuko.","answer":"'Hhayi khohlwa yilowo. Naye uzoyibona intuthuko maqede abone ngokunye' "},{"question":"لدينا الجملتان 'متعة للكبار والاطفال .' و 'متعة للاطفال فقط .'. هل تدل الجملتان على نفس المعنى؟","answer":"لا الجملتان متناقضتان."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：波斯帝國的統治者如何對待宗教？","answer":"答案：波斯帝國的統治者對待宗教持寬容態度。他們尊重各種宗教信仰，並允許被征服的民族自由實踐自己的宗教。波斯帝國的宗教寬容政策使得各種宗教在帝國內得到發展和傳播，並促進了不同文化和宗教間的交流和融合。"},{"question":"ఈ క్రింది వాటిని అస్ఫాటికాలు, స్పటికాలుగా వర్గీకరించండి.పాలియురిథేన్, నాఫ్తలీన్, బెంజోయిక్ ఆమ్లం, టెఫ్లాన్, పొటాషియం నైట్రేట్, సెల్లోఫేన్, పాలివినైల్ క్లోరైడ్, ఫైబర్గాజు, రాగి.","answer":"→ అస్ఫాటికాలు – పాలియురిథేన్, నాఫ్తలీన్, టెఫ్లాన్, సెల్లోఫేన్, పాలివినైల్ క్లోరైడ్, ఫైబర్ గాజు.→ స్ఫటికాలు – బెంజోయిక్ ఆమ్లం, పొటాషియం నైట్రేట్, కాపర్"},{"question":"Mene ne tambaya ga: \\"An tashi Royal Standard na Ƙasar Ingila lokacin da Sarauniya ke zaune a ɗaya daga cikin gidajen sarauta\\".? ","answer":"\\"Yaushe ne tutar sarauta ke tashi??\\""},{"question":"Кудайга колу жеткендей дегенди кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":" Менменсинүү, кекирейүү, өзүн жогору саноо, текеберчилик кылуу. Кудайга колу жеткенсип, жаман-жакшыны көзүнө илбей калды («Чалкан»)"},{"question":"\\"ഇന്ത്യയിലെ കേരളത്തിലെ മലബാർ തീരത്തോട് ചേർന്നുള്ള ഒരു നഗരമാണ് കോഴിക്കോട് . കാലിക്കറ്റ്‌ എന്ന പേരിലും അറിയപ്പെടുന്നു. കേരളത്തിലെ മൂന്നാമത്തെ വലിയ നഗരവും കോഴിക്കോട് ജില്ലയുടെ ആസ്ഥാനവുമാണ്. ബ്രിട്ടീഷ്‌ ഭരണ കാലത്ത്‌ മദ്രാസ് സംസ്ഥാനത്തിന്റെ ഭാഗമായിരുന്ന മലബാർ ജില്ലയുടെ തലസ്ഥാനമായിരുന്നു. കേരളത്തിലെയും ഇന്ത്യയിലെ തന്നെയും പുരാതന തുറമുഖ നഗരമാണ്. \\"മുൻ ഖണ്ഡികയിലെ വിഷയം എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഖണ്ഡിക കോഴിക്കോട് എന്ന സ്ഥലത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് പറയുന്നത്"},{"question":"Maxay kala yihiin shuruudaha \\"LaaIlaaha illa Laahu\\" ee toddobada ahi?","answer":"Waxay kala yihiin shuruudaha \\"LaaIlaaha illa Laahu\\" sida tan:1. Garasho oo ah in aqoon loo yeeshomacnaha iyo ujeedada \\"Laa Ilaaha illa Laahu\\".2. Yaqiinsasho aan shaki lahayn oo ah sihubaal ah oo loo aamino saxsanaanta LaaIlaaha illa Laahu.3. Aqbalaad aan diidmo lahayn oo ah in laaqbalo Laa Ilaaha illa Laahu.4. Hogaansamid aan ka tegid lahayn oo ah inlagu dhaqmo Laa Ilaaha illa Laah.145. Ka runsheegid oo ah in ay is waafaqaanhadalkiisa iyo uurkiisu.6. Saafi yeelid aan shirki lahayn, oo ah in aancid kale la caabudin.7. Jacayl aan necayb lahayn, oo ah haddii waxkale ka hor yimaado in aad waxa kale katagto."},{"question":"Eric Armstrongek ekoiztu zuen, Jacquie Barnbrookek idatzi zuen eta Jeff Wolvertonek idatzi zuen. Eric Armstrongek zuzendua, Jacquie Barnbrook ekoizlea eta Jeff Wolverton gidoilaria. Lehenengo esaldia eta bigarren esaldia zentzu berean daude? Bai edo ez?","answer":"Ez"},{"question":"Dekri abitan Espay yo?","answer":"Moun Espay yo se moun ki amikal e ki renmen pale ak moun. Pifò nan yo di yo fè pati Legliz katolik women, men pami moun ki di sa yo pa gen anpil ki al lamès vre. Nan ane ki sot pase yo, gen moun ki sot ann Afrik, ann Azi ak nan peyi Amerik latin pou y al viv ann Espay. Anpil nan yo renmen pale sou kwayans yo e yo renmen pale sou koutim yo gen nan peyi yo."},{"question":"木管楽器のサキソフォンに名を残すアドルフ・サックスはどこの国の人でしょう？","answer":"ベルギー"},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Мындай дастанчы Сакеңден (Саякбайдан) кийин дүйнөгө келбейт,-  деп ким айткан?а) Т. Сыдыкбеков б) В. Жирмунскийв) Ч. Айтматов г) М. Ауэзов","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚в) Ч.Айтматов"},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Podczas bitwy o Bendery w czasie wojny o Naddniestrze","answer":"18–21 czerwca 1992 sobór został uszkodzony. W końcu dekady podczas źle przeprowadzonej restauracji zniszczono ocalałe freski Plămădeali."},{"question":"Yaushe aka fara yakin basasar Libya?","answer":"A ranar 15 February 2011."},{"question":"Muna 1666 Jesuit Bark akashandiswa sedziviriro pachii?","answer":"Muna 1666, Jesuit Bark, anozivikanwawo seCinchona bark, akashandiswa sekudzivirira pamarariya. Jesuit Bark ane quinine, komboni ine antimalarial properties. Yaishandiswa zvakafara kurapa nekudzivirira marariya, hosha inotapukira inotakurwa neumhutu iyo yakanga iri itiro hanya huru youtano mumativi akawanda enyika. Kushandiswa kwequinine kubva kuJesuit Bark kwakabatsira zvikuru mukurwisa marariya kutozosvikira mishonga inorwisa marariya yagadzirwa."},{"question":"トランプゲームの７ならべ。最初に出せる数字は何と何？","answer":"６と８です。"},{"question":"ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕ ਸਮਾਂ ਮਾਪਣ ਲਈ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਉਪਕਰਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ ?","answer":"ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਘਟਨਾਵਾਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸਮੇਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਪ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ । ਸਮਾਂ ਬੀਤਣ ਨਾਲ ਸਮਾਂ ਮਾਪਣ ਲਈ ਕੁੱਝ ਉਪਕਰਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਖੋਜ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਕੁੱਝ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ-    - ਸੂਰਜੀ ਘੜੀ-ਸੂਰਜ ਦੀ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਕਾਰਨ ਪਰਛਾਵੇਂ ਦੀ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਨੂੰ ਸੂਰਜੀ ਘੜੀ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਮਾਪਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।    - ਰੇਤ ਘੜੀ-ਇਸ ਘੜੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੇਤ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਬਲਬ ਤੋਂ ਦੂਜੇ ਬਲਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਘੰਟੇ ਵੱਗਣੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਂ ਮਾਪਣ ਲਈ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।    - ਪਾਣੀ ਘੜੀ-ਇੱਕ ਬਰਤਨ ਤੋਂ ਦੂਜੇ ਬਰਤਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਵੱਗਣ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਂ ਮਾਪਣ ਲਈ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।    - ਪੈਂਡੂਲਮ-ਸਧਾਰਨ ਪੈਂਡੂਲਮ ਹਰੇਕ ਡੋਲਨ ਲਈ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਸਮਾਂ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਕਾਲ ਸਮੇਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਵਰਤ ਕਾਲ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਪੈਂਡੂਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਂ ਮਾਪਣ ਲਈ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Napisz kontynuację tego paragrafu - Od 11:30 rano 26 sierpnia (1530 UTC), centrum huraganu Katrina znajdowała się nad Zatoką Meksykańską, około 70 kilometrów na północny zachód od Key West i 120 kilometrów na południowy zachód od Neapolu na Florydzie. Zgłoszono, że burza","answer":" porusza się na południowy zachód blisko 7 mph (11 km / h) z maksymalnymi utrzymującymi się wiatrami o prędkości około 100 mph (160 km / h) z wyższymi podmuchami."},{"question":"O que significa 'Redistribuído por #{tipo_de_distribuicao_redistribuicao} em razão de #{motivo_da_redistribuicao}'?","answer":"'Redistribuído por #{tipo_de_distribuicao_redistribuicao} em razão de #{motivo_da_redistribuicao}' indica que um processo foi redistribuído para outro juízo devido a um motivo específico, como impedimento do juiz anterior ou prevenção de outra vara."},{"question":"Hãy chọn câu trả lời đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Trong các số: 333; 354; 360; 2 457; 1 617; 152, số nào chia hết cho 9?A. 333     B. 360     C. 2457     D. Cả A, B, C đúng","answer":"Lời giảiTa có:   + Số 333 có tổng các chữ số là 3 + 3 + 3 = 9 ⁝ 9 nên 333 chia hết cho 9.+ Số 360 có tổng các chữ số là 3 + 6 + 0 = 9 ⁝ 9 nên 360 chia hết cho 9.   + Số 2 475 có tổng các chữ số là 2 + 4 + 7 + 5 = 18 ⁝ 9 nên 2 475 chia hết cho 9.Chọn đáp án D."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa islaamka iyo abla ableynta nolosha iyo noolaha ?","answer":"ISLAAMKA IYO ABLA ABLEYNTA NOLOSHA IYO NOOLAHA. Inta badan Diinta Islaamku waxyaabaha ay ka hadasho waxaa ugu badan Duruus la xariirta Iimaanka iyo Rumeynta Rabbi,iyo cadaynta inuu jiro Milkiile kaligiis ka arimiya Koonka oo isagana sameystay. Sidaa darteed Diinta Islaamka inta badan kama hadasho waxyaabo ka baxsan hadyigii ay u timid ee ahaa ku hanuuninta Bani Aadamka dariiqa Alle oo ay dhacaysay in ay marar badan dadku ka weecdaan. Iyadoo ay taasi jirto ayuusan Islaamku misana marna ka ilduufin ka hadalka waxyaabaha Nolosha laxariira,sida Abuurka Koonka iyo inta dulsaaran iyo cadaynta danta uu Eebe ka lahaa Abuurka Dunida. Ilaahay waxa uu inoo sheegay inuusan cayaar cayaar u abuurin Dunidan ee sababta uu u abuuray ay tahay dan weyn oo Xaq ah oo mudan in Rabigii ku deeqay loogu xamdi naqo kaligiisna lagu caabudo oo lagu weyneeyo. وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا لَاعِبِينَ (38) مَا خَلَقْنَاهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَلَٰكِنَّ أَكْثَرَهُمْ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ (39)\\"Ma aanan abuurin Samaawaadka iyo Arlada iyo inta u dhaxaysa anaga oo iska cayaarayna,waxaan u abuurnay si dhab iyo ula kac ah oo Xaq ah laakiin dadka badankooda taas ma oga\\"Wuxuu kale oo Rabbi mar kale yiri:-\\"وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاءَ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا لَاعِبِينَ (16) لَوْ أَرَدْنَا أَن نَّتَّخِذَ لَهْوًا لَّاتَّخَذْنَاهُ مِن لَّدُنَّا إِن كُنَّا فَاعِلِينَ (17) \\"\\"Ma aanan abuurin Samaawaadka iyo Arlada iyo inta u dhaxeysa inagoo iska cayaarayna,oo hadaan doono inaan lahwi iska sameysano agtanada ayaan ka samaysan lahayn hadaanba nahay kuwo sidaa yeelaya\\".Ilaahay sareeye ee wuxuu u abuuray Dunida waa Xaq waana sidaa uu noo sheegay,oo kolkuu Dunida abuuray wuxuu ku abuuray noocyo kala duwan oo Abuur ah sida Insi iyo Jini iyo Xayawaano iyo Jamaadaad iyo waxyaabo kale oo Bad iyo Berriba laga heli karo. Ilaahay waxa uu inoo sheegay in ay Cirka iyo Dhulkaba markii hore ahaayeen kuwo isku dhagan oo uu kala qaaday oo kala qarxiyay ka dibna uu Uunka oo dhan Biyo ka abuuray oo isla Biyahana Nolol oga dhigay. أَوَلَمْ يَرَ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا أَنَّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ كَانَتَا رَتْقًا فَفَتَقْنَاهُمَا ۖ وَجَعَلْنَا مِنَ الْمَاءِ كُلَّ شَيْءٍ حَيٍّ ۖ أَفَلَا يُؤْمِنُونَ (30\\"Miyeysan arkaynin kuwa Xaqa diidan in ay Samaawaadka iyo Dhulka ahaayeen kuwo isku dhegan oo aan kala furfurnay oon kala qaad qaadnay ka dibna aan Biyihii ka ahaysiinay Nolosha wax kasta ee miyaysan rumeynaynin\\".Rabi ka dib kolkii uu Koonka abuuray ee uu ku dul abuuray khalqiyada kala gadisan wuxuu mid kasta u yeelay abuurkiisa khaaska ah iyo qaab nololeed u gaar ah oo uu ula falgalo Dunidan la keenay. Oo Alle mar uu arintaa tilmaamayay waxa uu yiri:-قَالَ رَبُّنَا الَّذِي أَعْطَىٰ كُلَّ شَيْءٍ خَلْقَهُ ثُمَّ هَدَىٰ (50)\\"Wuxuu yiri-Nabi Muuse-Rabigayo waa midka wax kasta sii yay abuurkiisa misana ku hagay sidii uu u noolaan lahaa\\".Abuurka aan la koobi karin ee uu Alle Arlada ku abuuray waxa uu si gaar ah oga xushay Insaanka oo uu ka dhigay Masuul uu u igmaday maamulida arimaha Koonka oo uu ku aaminay imtixaana oga dhigay masuuliyada inta Dunida saaran oo idil. وَإِذْ قَالَ رَبُّكَ لِلْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنِّي جَاعِلٌ فِي الْأَرْضِ خَلِيفَةً ۖ قَالُوا أَتَجْعَلُ فِيهَا مَن يُفْسِدُ فِيهَا وَيَسْفِكُ الدِّمَاءَ وَنَحْنُ نُسَبِّحُ بِحَمْدِكَ وَنُقَدِّسُ لَكَ ۖ قَالَ إِنِّي أَعْلَمُ مَا لَا تَعْلَمُونَ (30) \\"Bal xus waqti Alle ku yiri Malaa’igta Aniga Dhulka waxaan u samaynayaa mid Khaliif ka noqda oo maamula,sey Malaa’igtii tiri ma waxaad dhulka maamule oga dhigaysaa mid fasaadinaya oo dhiigga ku daadinaya iyada oo aan anaga ku nasahayno adiga oo aan nuqsaan oo dhan kaa dahirayno,dabeeto wuxuu Alle yiri waxaan ogahay wax aydaan idinka mMalaa'igta ah ogayn\\"۞ وَلَقَدْ كَرَّمْنَا بَنِي آدَمَ وَحَمَلْنَاهُمْ فِي الْبَرِّ وَالْبَحْرِ وَرَزَقْنَاهُم مِّنَ الطَّيِّبَاتِ وَفَضَّلْنَاهُمْ عَلَىٰ كَثِيرٍ مِّمَّنْ خَلَقْنَا تَفْضِيلًا (70)\\"Bani Aadamka waan karaameynay waxaanan u xilsaarnay oon ku qaadnay Berri iyo Badba waxaanan ku irsaaqnay waxyaabaha wanwanaagsan,oo waxaan ka fadilnay in badan oo Khalqiga ah si waliba doorasho dhamaystiran ah\\".Cidda Aadanaha ku soo xigta ee iyadana Masuuliyada culus wax laga saaray waa duulalka inaga qarsoon mid ka mid ah ee Jiniga loo yaqaan in kasta oo uusan Jinigu u xilsaarneyn xaga Khaliifnimada Koonka. وَمَا خَلَقْتُ الْجِنَّ وَالْإِنسَ إِلَّا لِيَعْبُدُونِ (56)\\"Jini iyo Insiba waxaan u Abuurnay inay aniga i caabudaan\\"Yacni ay Aniga i weyneeyaan oo ay kaligay talada iyo amarka Cadaaladda iyo wanaaga ku saabsan iga qaataan oo ay Dulmiga ka dheeraadaan Dunidan aan dul keenayna aysan fasahaadin\\"Wuxuu kale oo Alle ugu goodiyay labadan Makhluuq ee sida gaarka loo xushay ee Masuuliyadda lagu cusleeyay inuu la xisaabtami doono Qiyaamaha oo uu ka jaazin doono Samaan iyo Xumaan sidii ay Dunida ugu dhaqmeen. Oo wuxuu yiri Alle:-سَنَفْرُغُ لَكُمْ أَيُّهَا الثَّقَلانِ (31) \\"La xisaabtankiinu waan u firaaqoobi doonnaa labadan Masuuliyadda lagu cusleeyayoow\\". Runtii waa Nimco weyn in Rabi inaga doortay Khalqiga intaas la eg ee isugu jira kuwo inaga waaweyn kuwo inaga yaryar kuwo aan arki karno kuwo aan arki karin,kuwo inoo eg balse aan Caqli inagu gaarin iyo kuwo inaga duwan intaba. Sidoo kalana waa Masuuliyad weyn oo laynagu aaminay sida aan ula falgalayno oon ula dhaqmayno Khalqiga kala duwan ee intaas la eg ee la soo dul dhoobay Duni maamulkeedii laynoo igmaday. Dhab ahaantii waa Ummado laynagu imtixaanayo Noolahaas kala duwan ee Bad iyo Bariba ku nool ee isagu jira kuwo adimo ku socda iyo kuwo beerka ku siqaba. وَمَا مِن دَآبَّةٍ فِي الأَرْضِ وَلاَ طَائِرٍ يَطِيرُ بِجَنَاحَيْهِ إِلاَّ أُمَمٌ أَمْثَالُكُم مَّا فَرَّطْنَا فِي الكِتَابِ مِن شَيْءٍ ثُمَّ إِلَى رَبِّهِمْ يُحْشَرُون) [الأنعام: 38]. \\"Waxa noole Dunida jooga ee isugu jira kuwo dDhulka ku dul socda iyo Shimbiro garbahooda ku duula waa uun Ummado idinkoo kale ah,kitaabkaa waxba kagama aanan tagin intaa dabadeed xaga Rabigiin uun baa laydinku kulmin doonaa\\".Bal eeg inta Xayawaan ee Dunida dulsaaran,bal eeg sida ay qaarkood isugu eg yihiin ee dhoobadooda meel looga wada qaaday iyada uu misana mid kasta kan kale si uun uu uga duwan yahay. \\"وَاللَّهُ خَلَقَ كُلَّ دَابَّةٍ مِّن مَّاءٍ ۖ فَمِنْهُم مَّن يَمْشِي عَلَىٰ بَطْنِهِ وَمِنْهُم مَّن يَمْشِي عَلَىٰ رِجْلَيْنِ وَمِنْهُم مَّن يَمْشِي عَلَىٰ أَرْبَعٍ ۚ يَخْلُقُ اللَّهُ مَا يَشَاءُ ۚ إِنَّ اللَّهَ عَلَىٰ كُلِّ شَيْءٍ قَدِيرٌ \\"\\"Ilaahay waa midka ka abuuray wax kasta oo Dhulka dul jooga biyo waxaana ka mid ah mid Caloosha ku socda oo xamaarta,oo waxaa ka mid ah mid laba lugood ku socda sidoo kale waxaa ka mid ah mid afar adin ku socda,ilaahay wuxuu doono ayuu abuuraa waana mid wax kasta kara\\".أَوَلَمْ يَنْظُرُوا فِي مَلَكُوتِ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالأَرْضِ وَمَا خَلَقَ اللَّهُ مِنْ شَيْءٍ وَأَنْ عَسَى أَنْ يَكُونَ قَدِ اقْتَرَبَ أَجَلُهُمْ فَبِأَيِّ حَدِيثٍ بَعْدَهُ يُؤْمِنُونَ (185) “Oo miyeyan arag milkiyadda Samaawaadka iyo Arlada iyo waxa uu Eebe abuuray,waxaa dhici karta in ay mudada Noloshooda dhow dahay,Ee sheeko tee ah ayay Xaqa dabadii rumaynayaan”.Bani Aadamka Laftiisa ayuu Eebe ku sheegay in uu Abuurkiisa heerar kala duwan soo maray. “وَقَدْ خَلَقَكُمْ أَطْوَارًا (14)“Eebe waa midka idin abuuray ee Abuurkiina soo mariyay Dowrar kala duwan."},{"question":"Fintino ity lahatsoratra ity: Niverina tsikelikely  amin’ny laoniny ny fiainan’ny mponina ao amin’ny tananan’i Manambotra – any amin’ny faritra atsimo atsinanan’i Madagasikara, herintaona  taorian’ny fandalovan’ny rivodoza Batsirai sy Emnati tamin’ny volana febroary 2022. Nosembanin-drahona ny lanitra raha iny niomana namonjy ny fivoriam-behivavy eo an-tanàna iny i Herisoa Albertine satria araka ny re dia misy hetsika karakarain’izy ireo. Nanorina tranoheva vita amin’ny hazo kelikely teo anivon’ny trano maromaro vita amin’ny hazo izy mba handraisana ny olona nasaina. Mpiasan’ny fahasalamana eo anivon’ny fiarahamonina misy azy i Albertine. Tonga niara-nivory teo ireo zaza amam-behivavy  zato mahery.","answer":"Ny lahatsoratra dia mitantara ny fiverenana tsikelikely ny fiainana andavanandro any amin’ny faritr’i Manambotra, any atsimo atsinanan’i Madagasikara, herintaona taorian’ny fandalovan’ny rivodoza Batsirai sy Emnati nandravarava tamin’ny Febroary 2022. Herisoa Albertine, mpiasan’ny fahasalamana any an-toerana, dia saika hivoaka. manatrika fivorian'ny vehivavy ao an-tanàna, izay mikarakara fihetsiketsehana. Nanao tranoheva hazo kely izy mba handraisana ireo vahiny. Ankizy sy vehivavy maherin’ny zato no tonga nanatrika ity fivoriana ity. Ny lahatsoratra dia manasongadina ny faharetan'ny fiaraha-monina sy ny dingana fanarenana taorian'ny loza voajanahary."},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ 福井県大野市にある自然保護センターでは、毎年冬の今ごろ、建物の外に「野鳥レストラン」という名前の鳥の餌の台を置いています。来た人は建物の中から窓の外の鳥をよく見ることができます。センターの周りは90cmぐらい雪が積もっています。餌を探すのが難しくなるため、「野鳥レストラン」にはたくさんの野鳥が来ます。ヤマガラやシジュウカラ、コガラが来て餌のヒマワリの種を食べていました。森の中ではほかの鳥やリスも見ることができて、遊びに来た家族などが写真を撮っていました。石川県から来た男性は「初めて来ましたが、鳥を近くで撮ることができたり、リスも見ることができたりして楽しかったです」と話していました。この「野鳥レストラン」は2月28日まで開いています。","answer":"「野鳥レストラン」窓から野鳥を近くで見る"},{"question":"ndicela undicacisele esi sivakalisi ngesiXhosa. Isivakalisi: \\"iqaqa aliziva kunuka\\".","answer":"Nantsi intsingiselo yeqhalo \\"iqaqa aliziva kunuka\\". Umntu akaziboni apho aphazame khona, Umntu akaziboni iziphene zakhe."},{"question":"After reading the following text snippet from Wikipedia, please answer the question: Did Charlemagne's son found France? Carolingian dynastyPippinidsPippin the Elder (c. 580–640)Grimoald (616–656)Childebert the Adopted (d. 662)ArnulfingsArnulf of Metz (582–640)Ansegisel (d. 662 or 679)Chlodulf of Metz (d. 696 or 697)Pepin of Herstal (635-714)Grimoald II (d. 714)Drogo of Champagne (670–708)Theudoald (d. 741)CarolingiansCharles Martel (686–741)Carloman (d. 754)Pepin the Short (714–768)Carloman I (751–771)Charlemagne (742–814)Pepin the Hunchback (768–811)Charles the Younger (772–811)Pepin of Italy (773–810)Louis the Pious (778–840)Pepin I of Aquitaine (797–838)After the Treaty of Verdun (843)Lothair I, Holy Roman Emperor(795–855; Middle Francia)Charles the Bald (823–877)(West Francia)Louis the German (804–876)(East Francia)vtCharlemagne (/ˈʃɑːrləmeɪn/) or Charles the Great[lower-alpha 1] (German: Karl der Große, Italian: Carlo Magno/Carlomagno; 2 April 742[1][lower-alpha 2] – 28 January 814), numbered Charles I, was King of the Franks from 768, King of the Lombards from 774, and Holy Roman Emperor from 800. He united much of western and central Europe during the Early Middle Ages. He was the first recognised emperor to rule from western Europe since the fall of the Western Roman Empire three centuries earlier.[3] The expanded Frankish state that Charlemagne founded is called the Carolingian Empire. He was later canonized by Antipope Paschal III.Charlemagne was the eldest son of Pepin the Short and Bertrada of Laon, born before their canonical marriage.[4] He became king in 768 following his father's death, initially as co-ruler with his brother Carloman I. Carloman's sudden death in December 771 under unexplained circumstances left Charlemagne as the sole ruler of the Frankish Kingdom.[5] He continued his father's policy towards the papacy and became its protector, removing the Lombards from power in northern Italy and leading an incursion into Muslim Spain. He campaigned against the Saxons to his east, Christianizing them upon penalty of death and leading to events such as the Massacre of...","answer":"No, Charlemagne's son did not found France. "},{"question":"Ngano kinahanglan nga naay lisensiya sa pusil ang sibilyan bag-o kini makagamit o maka angkon og pusil?","answer":"Ang pusil kay delikado, labi kung anaan kini sa maling kamot. Busa naay mga balaod gibutang aron maprotektahan ang matag-usa, sama sa paghatag ug lisensiya sa pusil."},{"question":"マンガ「ドラえもん」でドラえもんの妹ドラミちゃんはドラえもんより何歳年下でしょう？","answer":"２歳です。"},{"question":"a) Thực hiện các phép tính: 50 : 5; 65 : 5.b) Nêu quan hệ chia hết của các số 50; 65 với số 5.c) Nêu chữ số tận cùng của các số: 50; 65.","answer":"Lời giải:a) Ta có: 50 : 5 = 10; 65 : 5 = 13.b) Theo câu a, ta thấy các số 50; 65 đều chia hết cho 5.c) Các chữ số tận cùng của các số 50; 65 lần lượt là 0; 5. "},{"question":"Escribe la continuación de este texto : Tropas belgas participaron de las operaciones militares en la antigua Yugoslavia, así como en Libia... ","answer":"Y  en Afganistán."},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 大阪　珍しいミニカバの赤ちゃん","answer":"大阪府吹田市にある「ニフレル」という動物の施設で、8月17日にミニカバの赤ちゃんが生まれました。ミニカバは西アフリカの一部の場所で生活していて、世界からいなくなる心配がある動物です。日本の施設などにいるのは、この赤ちゃんを入れて13頭だけです。今月から、部屋の小さな窓から赤ちゃんを見ることができるようになりました。見に来た人は、赤ちゃんがお母さんのミニカバのあとを歩いたり、プールの水に顔を入れたりするのを写真に撮っていました。4歳の男の子は「お母さんのおなかの下にいる赤ちゃんを見ることができてよかったです」と話しました。ミニカバの世話をしている人は「歩き方も丸い体もかわいい赤ちゃんを見てほしいです」と話しました。"},{"question":"語源は「のみが飛び跳ねる」、高木ブーの特技でもあるハワイアン音楽に用いられる小型の弦楽器を何という？","answer":"ウクレレです。"},{"question":"යාන් ඔය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"යාන් ඔය, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පස්වෙනියට (5) දිගම ගංගාව (ඔය) වේ. දිග ආසන්න වශයෙන් 142 km (88 mi) වේ."},{"question":"'Hhayi, hlala nje ngizovula nansi iwadilobhu ngicashe kuyo.' Nempela wasithelauTholakele. Wazibhekisa phansi uBheki. Amehlo ayelokhu entshontsha laphokusithele khona uTholi. Washeshe waqeda ukugqoka uTholi. Waphuma esegqokeingutshana elulwelwesi elula, eyayikuveza konke eyekugqoke ngaphansi. Amabelewayengasawabophile. 'Unazo izingane?''Cha, ngangingakamtholi umntwana. Ubuziswa yini?''Ngibona amabele akho emi sengathi awetshitshi.''Uyazi ukuthi kuthiwa uma iso likuhlupha likhiphe?''Awami ngeke ngiwakhiphe, angibonisa izinto ezinhle zodwa.'Kuthe uma esebeke amabhodwe eziko uTholi, waletha isiphuzo kuBhekani.'Wenzani, uzongichithisa?' Kubuza uTholi ngenkathi ebeka isiphuzo embhedeniphambi kukaBheki. UBheki wayesuke wagaxa isandla phakathi kwamabelekaTholakele.'Ngiyaxolisa. Ngeke ngisakuthinta ngaphandle kwemvume.' Babehleli phansi futhibebhekene uTholi noBheki.'Manje ucabange kanjani ntokazi?''Kukuwe mngani wami. Uma ubona ukuthi awuzukuzifaka enkingeni ngokusondelananami, mina ngikhululekile. Uma sekufika uBhatomu uyomisa kanjani?''Phela ngizimisele ukukufela manje. Angizimisele ukuvinjwa abantuabanjengoBhatomu endleleni yami.'Ngale nkathi uTholi wayesusa izitsha zokuphuza ezibeka etafuleni, uBhekani elokhuembuka ehla enyuka. Le ngubo ekhanyayo yayisuke imgulise uBhekani. IsimosikaTholakele yayisibeka obala.1. Ngokwalesi siqeshana osifundile yini eyayenziwa nguTholakele ngesikhathiecashe ngesicabha sewadilobhu?","answer":"Wayeshintsha izingubo zokugqoka."},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند:  در شرایطی که در بازی فینال، با تیم اتحاد جماهیر شوروی کارشان ۱_۱ دنبال می‌شد، در دقیقهٔ ۸۴ توپ را به گل تبدیل کرد تا اسپانیا برای اولین بار در تاریخ فاتح اروپا بشود.","answer":"فینال یورو ۱۹۶۴ و قهرمانی اسپانیا در آن."},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianaoreryiOmeo ary teny marina :","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"irery\\""},{"question":"मराठ्यांच्या स्वातंत्र्य युध्दाचे नेतृत्व कोणी केले ?","answer":"मराठ्यांच्या स्वातंत्र्य युध्दाचे नेतृत्व महाराणी ताराबाईने केले."},{"question":"🎶 Эл сүйгөн обондордон Элмирбек Иманалиев ырдаган \\"Коштошуу вальсы\\"-ырынын сөзү кайсы?🎧","answer":"Сөзү : Кыялбек УрманбетовдукуОбону : Х. АзиреткуловдукуКөңүлүм байланабы?Көзгө жаш айланабы?Колуңду коё бербей,Кош дедим кайра дагы…Толгонуп шашылбадым,Токто деп чакырбадың.Топ таштай чачылганмын,Сен мени жоготтуңбу?Толгонуп шашылбадым,Токто деп чакырбадың.Топчудай чачылганмын,Сен мени жоготтуңбу?Айтпадым намыс барын,Акырын алыстадым.Капарга алганың жок,Кабыргам кайышканын.Кайгырып шашылбадым,Кайтчы деп чакырбадың.Мончоктой чачылганмын,Сен мени жоготтуңбу?Кайгырып шашылбадым,Кайткын деп чакырбадың.Шурудай чачылганмын,Сен мени жоготтуңбу?Күймөлүп басып араң,Күн менен батып барам.Күн чыгат кайра-кайра,Мен чыкпайм, жашып барам.Күймөлүп шашылбадым,Күтчү деп чакырбадың.Мончоктой чачылганмын,Сен мени жоготтуңбу?Толгонуп шашылбадым,Токто деп чакырбадың.Топчудай чачылганмын,Сен мени жоготтуңбу?"},{"question":"புதிர்:  உடல் சிவப்பு வாய் அகலம் உணவு காகிதம் நான் யார்?","answer":"விடை: அஞ்சல் பெட்டி"},{"question":"Trump ti kede ara ẹ l’Amẹrika, o ni oun loun jawe olubori","answer":"Aarẹ orilẹ-ede Amẹrika, Donald Trump, ti kede pe oun loun wọle ninu idibo aarẹ to waye lọjọ kẹta, oṣu kọkanla, ọdun yii.Lori ikanni abẹyẹfo ẹ lo ti sọ pe awọn ti wọn n pariwo kiri pe Joe Biden lo wọle, iroyin ayederu ni wọn n gbe ka. Aarẹ yii fi kun un pe, “Ki lo mu awọn oniroyin ayederu yii maa ro pe Joe Biden lo maa di aarẹ, ti wọn ko si fẹẹ kọbi ara si esi ibo tiwa rara. Awa naa n mura de wọn daadaa, bẹẹ lo baayan ninu jẹ, ohun ti wọn sọ ofin orile-ede Amẹrika da bayii nitori ibo 2020.“Pupọ ninu awọn to jẹ olubẹwo nibi ti wọn ti n ka esi ibo ni wọn ko fun laaye rara, ti awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu ‘The Democrats’ fi raaye tọwọ bọ esi ibo aimọye miliọnu lati fi ṣatilẹyin fun oludije wọn.”Aarẹ Amẹrika yii ni ohun ti oun mọ daju ni pe awọn eeyan gidi nilẹ Amẹrika ko ni i maa woran ki ibo ti wọn lawọn kan fi ṣeru lati gbe Biden wọle dohun itẹwọgba rara, nitori pe gbogbo aye pata lo n wo ibi ti ọrọ ọhun yoo ja si."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Pierwszy raz na arenie międzynarodowej Giennadij Matwijenko pojawił się 17 listopada 2007 roku podczas zawodów FIS Race w Muonio, gdzie zajął 75. miejsce w biegu na 15 km techniką klasyczną. W 2008 roku wystartował na mistrzostwach świata juniorów w Malles Venosta, gdzie zdobył brązowy medal w sztafecie, a indywidualnie jego najlepszym wynikiem było trzynaste miejsce w biegu łączonym na 20 km. Na rozgrywanych dwa lata później","answer":"mistrzostwach świata młodzieżowców w Hinterzarten zdobył brązowy medal na dystansie 15 km klasykiem."},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.කඩෙන් ගත්තොත් භාණ්ඩයක්  දියෙන් ගත්තොත් මාංශයක්     ","answer":"තේරවිල්ලට විසඳුම  ඉබ්බා  වේ."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Rafotsibe leon-tsokina ka .............................  \\"","answer":"\\" Rafotsibe leon-tsokina ka tsy te hahita vodi-kifafa \\""},{"question":"ක්‍රියා පදයක් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ක්‍රියා පදයක් යනු ක්‍රියාකාරකම විස්තර කරන ක්‍රියා පදයකි. ක්‍රියා පද සඳහා උදාහරණ පහත දැක්වේ: පිහිනීම, කඳු නැගීම, බයිසිකල් පැදීම, රෝලර් ස්කේටිං හෝ ස්කයිඩයිවිං. මෙම තනි සහ සංයුක්ත වචන උදාහරණ සියල්ලම ඕනෑම ජීවියෙකුට කළ හැකි ක්‍රියාකාරකමකට බැඳී ඇත. නිදසුනක් වශයෙන්, මිනිසා බයිසිකලය පදවන විට බල්ලෙකුට මිනිසෙකු සමඟ බයිසිකල් පැදිය හැකිය. ක්‍රියා පද භාවිතය මිනිසුන්ට හෝ මිනිසුන්ට පමණක් සීමා වූවක් නොව සියලුම ජීවීන්ට අදාළ වේ."},{"question":"લજામણી ના છોડ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"લજામણી  એ એક શરમાળ છોડ છે, આ છોડને અડકવાથી તેના પાન કરમાઇ જાય છે. એટલે આ છોડ રીસામણી તરીકે પણ ઓળખાય છે. આ છોડ ભાગ્યે જ ક્યાંક જોવા મળે છે.લજામણી દ્વિદરી વર્ગમાં આવેલા ફેબીસી કુળના માઈમોઝોઈડી ઉપકુળની એક વનસ્પતિ છે.  આ છોડ 50 સેમી થી 90 સેમી ઊંચી થાય છે. તે ઉષ્ણકટિબંધીય અમેરિકાની મુલનિવાસી વનસ્પતિ છે અને ભારતના ઉષ્ણ અને ઉપોષ્ણ પ્રદેશમાં લગભગ બધે જ તેનું પ્રાકૃતિકરણ છે. તેનાં પાંદડા ગુલાબી રંગના, ગોળાકાર કક્ષિય મુંડક સ્વરૂપે ગોઠવાયેલા હોય છે. આબોહવા હૂંફાળી અને ભેજયુક્ત હોય તેવી પડતર જમીનમાં તે પુષ્કળ પ્રમાણમાં ઉગે છે."},{"question":"الضغط الجوي","answer":"يُعرف الضغط الجوي بأنه وزن عامود الهواء الذي يمتد من سطح الأرض وينتهي في آخر طبقات الغلاف الجوي والذي يؤثر في وحدات المساحة. إن للضغط الجوي أهميةٌ كبيرةٌ في تحديد حالات الطقس، وهو يُعتبر من أهم العناصر المؤثرة في حالات الطقس، مع أن الضغط الجوي غير ملموس أو مرئي. ولقد أولى الإنسان اهتماماً كبيراً بالضغط الجوي منذ القِدم، ويزداد هذا الاهتمام مع مرور الزمن، حيث تتم دراسة الضغط الجوي ومحاولة معرفة أسراره باستمرار، كما قام الإنسان باختراع أدوات مُخصّصةٍ لقياس الضغط الجوي. ولقد زادت أهمية الضغط الجوي بشكل كبير مع زيادة فهمنا له؛ حيث يُستفاد منه أيضاً في الملاحة البحرية، والجوية، والميادين الطبية. عادةً ما يتم اعتبار الضغط الجوي عند سطح البحر على أنه معيار للتعبير عن ارتفاع الضغط الجوي أو انخفاضه، ويكون ارتفاع الزئبق عند مستوى سطح البحر عند استخدام الباروميتر الزئبقي 76سم، أي 1,013.25 ميليبار، وهذا الرقم هو ما يعرف بالضغط الجوي القياسي. بناءً على هذا فإن وحدة قياس الضغط الجوي المعروفة بوحدة الضغط الجوي، ووحدة الضغط الجوي الواحدة تساوي 1,013.25 ميلليبار أو 101.325 كيلوباسكال."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.සමනළයා මල හා ළමයා සේබාල ළමා වයසේපෙර තිදෙනා සිටියේ එක යායේ","answer":"සමනළයා මල හා ළමයා සේබාල ළමා වයසේපෙර තිදෙනා සිටියේ එක යායේජීවිතයේ අරුමේමලට වසා පැණි බී රිසි සේමාසමනළයා පියැඹූ දවසේඒ මල ගාවා ඒ පොඩි ළමයාදෑස වසා සිටියාමලට නොවේ දැණුනේ දුක කාගේපොඩි ළමයෝ මොටදෝ හැඬුවේඒ මල නොදනී ඒ මල පරවීසමනළයා කොතැනේ"},{"question":"Zer da irudi ikusmena?","answer":"Irudi ikusmena gure cerebroak irudiak interpretatzen dituen gaitasuna da. Hau da, gure begiek jaso duten argi informazioa prozesatu eta ulertzea."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Манас кытайдын Кочку баштаган жети жүз колу менен беттешкенде минген тулпар?а) Аккула б) Тайторув) Торучаар г) Тайбуурул","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚в)  Торучаар"},{"question":"Tôi bị cận 9 diop có nên mổ không? Hiện tôi đang là sinh viên năm 3, 23 tuổi vậy mổ là sớm hay muộn ạ? Mổ laze có an toàn và cận thị có khả năng tái phát không? ","answer":"Viêc mổ cận thị là một điều trị theo nhu cầu chứ không phải là một chỉ định bắt buộc. Với độ cận 9 đi – ốp vẫn có thể mổ được bằng các phương pháp như Smile mà vẫn an toàn, giúp cho bạn thoải mái trong sinh hoạt. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bawa mulut\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud suka menceritakan keburukan orang lain. Haris sering bawa mulut tentang kelakuan bekas kekasihnya."},{"question":"වැඩිම ෆෝමියුලා වන් ජයග්‍රහණවලට හිමිකම් කියන්නේ කුමන ධාවකයාද?","answer":"බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ජාතික ලුවිස් හැමිල්ටන්. 2007 සිට මේවන තෙක් තරඟ 103ක් ජයග්‍රහණය කර ඇත."},{"question":"400 को 25% को नतिजा पत्ता लगाउनुहोस्।","answer":"400 को 25% 100 बराबर छ।"},{"question":"வினா:ஐரோப்பாவின் விளையாட்டு  மைதானம் - ","answer":"விடை: சுவிஸ்சிலாந்து."},{"question":"Viết bài báo có tiêu đề sau: Lần đầu tiên chiến đấu cơ tàng hình F-35A cất cánh từ đường cao tốc","answer":"Theo trang The Drive, quân đội Na Uy đã cho máy bay chiến đấu tàng hình F-35A cất và hạ cánh trên đường cao tốc trong cuộc tập trận thường niên Baana tại Phần Lan trong tuần này. Tướng Rold Folland, Tham mưu trưởng Không quân Hoàng gia Na Uy gọi đây là một cột mốc không chỉ đối với không quân Na Uy mà còn đối với các nước Bắc Âu và NATO. \\"Điều này chứng minh năng lực của chúng ta trong việc thực hiện khái niệm phân tán. Các chiến đấu cơ dễ bị tổn thương khi ở trên mặt đất nên việc có thể sử dụng các đường băng nhỏ, và giờ là đường cho xe hơi, chúng ta có thể gia tăng khả năng sống sót trong chiến tranh\\", vị tướng 2 sao nói trong một thông cáo báo chí ngày 21.9.Như vậy, Na Uy đã trở thành nước đầu tiên thực hiện được kỹ thuật cất và hạ cánh máy bay F-35A trên đường cao tốc. Trước đó, Thủy quân lục chiến Mỹ đã biểu diễn kỹ thuật này bằng máy bay F-35B, phiên bản có thể cất cánh trên đường băng ngắn và hạ cánh thẳng đứng.F-35 là chiến đấu cơ thế hệ thứ 5 do Mỹ sản xuất và được nhiều nước đồng minh sử dụng. Máy bay này có 3 phiên bản, trong đó F-35A là mẫu cơ bản dành cho không quân, F-35B dành cho thủy quân lục chiến và F-35C dành cho hải quân, chuyên hoạt động trên tàu sân bay."},{"question":"Аналдык орган деген эмне?","answer":"Аналдык орган (анат.) — арткы жылчык; аденофорей жандыктарынын арткы тешиги. "},{"question":"\\"1000000\\"  อ่านว่าอะไร","answer":"\\"1000000\\"  อ่านว่า \\"หนึ่งล้าน\\""},{"question":"செயற்கைக்கோள்களின் வகைகளை அறிந்து கொண்டு வந்து பேசுக.","answer":"அவையோர்க்கு வணக்கம் !மனிதனின் முயற்சியால் விண்வெளியின் கோளப்பாதையில் இயங்கும் ஒரு பொருளாகச் செயற்கைக்கோள் இருக்கிறது.செயற்கைக்கோள்கள் பல்வேறு துறைகளின் செயல்பாடுகளுக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன. இராணுவக் கண்காணிப்பு, உளவு வேலைகள், பூமியைக் கண்காணிக்கும் வேலைகள், வானியல் பற்றிய பல்வேறுபட்ட ஆராய்ச்சிகள், தகவல் பரிமாற்றம் ஆகிய எல்லாவற்றிற்கும் செயற்கைக்கோள் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன.இதன் வகைகள் :• தகவல் தொடர்பு செயற்கைக்கோள்கள்• புவி கண்காணிப்பு செயற்கைக்கோள்கள்• வானிலை செயற்கைக்கோள்கள்• பயோ செயற்கைக்கோள்கள்• சோதனை செயற்கைக்கோள்கள்• இடங்காட்டி செயற்கைக்கோள்கள்• அறிவியல் மற்றும் கண்டுபிடிப்பு செயற்கைக்கோள்கள்"},{"question":"Jox ma been waxi wolof ?","answer":"Sàcc ndënd yombu na waaye foo koy tëge moo jafe."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত অনুচ্ছেদ সংক্ষিপ্ত করুন :তৃতীয়বারের চেষ্টায় সফল হয়েছেন জো বাইডেন।যাতে এমনই একজন জো বাইডেনের প্রতিপক্ষ ছিলেন যিনি মার্কিন রাজনীতির প্রথাগত রীতির অনুসারী নন। জো বাইডেন প্রায় ৫০ বছর ধরে নির্বাচিত জনপ্রতিনিধি হিসেবে কাজ করেছেন। প্রেসিডেন্ট হওয়ার উচ্চাকাঙ্ক্ষা তার দীর্ঘদিনের। অবশেষে তৃতীয়বারের চেষ্টায় সফল হলেন তিনি। পাঁচটি কারণ জয়ে সাহায্য করেছে।  ১. কোভিড, কোভিড, কোভিডজো বাইডেনের জয়ের পেছনে সম্ভবত সবচেয়ে বড় কারণ যা সবকিছুর নিয়ন্ত্রণের বাইরে। করোনাভাইরাস যুক্তরাষ্ট্রে দুই লাখ তিরিশ হাজার মানুষের প্রাণ কেড়ে নিয়েছে। একইসাথে বদলে দিয়েছে মার্কিন মানুষের জীবন ও রাজনীতি। উইসকনসিনে নির্বাচনী র‍্যালিতে কোভিড-১৯ সম্পর্কে ডোনাল্ড ট্রাম্প বলেছিলেন, \\"ফেক নিউজে সবকিছুই কোভিড, কোভিড, কোভিড, কোভিড\\"। মহামারি সম্পর্কে তার যে অবস্থান, যেভাবে তিনি বিষয়টি সামলেছেন সেটি শেষপর্যন্ত তার বিপক্ষেই গেছে। অপরদিকে জো বাইডেন ক্যাম্প কোভিড ইস্যুতে যে অবস্থান নিয়েছিলেন সেটি তাকে এগিয়ে দিচ্ছে এমনটাই দেখা গিয়েছিল গত মাসে করা এক জনমত জরিপে। করোনাভাইরাস যুক্তরাষ্ট্রে দুই লাখ তিরিশ হাজার মানুষের প্রাণ কেড়ে নিয়েছে।যাতে জো বাইডেন ১৭ পয়েন্ট এগিয়ে ছিলেন। অর্থনৈতিক প্রবৃদ্ধি ও সমৃদ্ধি ছিল ডোনাল্ড ট্রাম্পের সবচেয়ে বড় প্রতিশ্রুতি। কিন্তু বৈশ্বিক মহামারিতে যে ধরনের অর্থনৈতিক ক্ষতি হয়েছে তা ডোনাল্ড ট্রাম্পের প্রচারণা কৌশলকে বাধাগ্রস্ত করেছে। মহামারি ও এর ফলে সৃষ্ট অর্থনৈতিক সংকট মোকাবেলায় প্রেসিডেন্ট হিসেবে ডোনাল্ড ট্রাম্প প্রায়শই যেভাবে লক্ষ্যচ্যুত হয়েছেন, বিজ্ঞানকে প্রশ্ন করেছেন, একদম হুট করে এলোমেলোভাবে গুরুত্বপূর্ণ সিদ্ধান্ত নিয়েছেন, পক্ষপাতমূলক আচরণ এই বিষয়গুলো জো বাইডেন ক্যাম্প সফলভাবে ডোনাল্ড ট্রাম্পের বিপক্ষে কাজে লাগিয়েছে। আরো পড়ুন:বিজয় ভাষণে দেশকে 'একতাবদ্ধ' করার প্রতিশ্রুতি দিলেন জো বাইডেনজো বাইডেন জয়ী, কিন্তু এখন কী হবে? জো বাইডেন: আমেরিকার নব নির্বাচিত প্রেসিডেন্টের রাজনৈতিক জীবনগ্রীষ্মকালে করা আর এক জরিপে দেখা গিয়েছিল, ডোনাল্ড ট্রাম্পের রেটিং ৩৮ শতাংশ কমে গিয়েছিল। ২. হিসেব কষে ধীরগতির প্রচারণাজো বাইডেন তার দীর্ঘদিনের রাজনীতিতে ভুল বক্তব্য ও অসমীচীন কাজের জন্য বিশেষ পরিচিতি পেয়েছিলেন। যেসব ভুল তাকে প্রায়শই বিপদগ্রস্ত করেছে। ১৯৮৭ সালের নির্বাচনে এমন ভুল তার হারের কারণ ছিল। ","answer":"যে ধরনের প্রচারণা ও নির্বাচন এবার যুক্তরাষ্ট্রে হয়ে গেল সেটি ছিল নজিরবিহীন। কয়েক শতাব্দীর মধ্যে সবচেয়ে ভয়াবহ বৈশ্বিক মহামারি আর দেশজুড়ে দীর্ঘ সামাজিক সহিংসতার মতো অভূতপূর্ব পরিস্থিতিতে অনুষ্ঠিত হয়েছে এই নির্বাচন।"},{"question":"De que categoria é esta pergunta: Em que país a capital da Civilização Inca se estabeleceu?.","answer":"A categoria desta pergunta é história."},{"question":"ماهي طريقة عمل اللقيمات السعودية؟","answer":"المقادير1 كوب دقيق1 ملعقة كبيرة سكر1 ملعقة صغيرة خميرة1 ملعقة كبيرة نشاء ذرة1 و ½ ملعقة كبيرة حليب بودرة¾ كوب ماءزيت نباتي للقلي1 كوب قطر (شيرة)رشة ملحطريقة التحضير•    ذوبي الخميرة مع السكر في ربع كوب من الماء•    اخلطي الدقيق مع نشاء الذرة والحليب والملح في وعاء كبير•    احدثي فجوة في وسط الخليط ثم أضيفي فيها مزيج الخميرة•    اعجني المكونات بيديك، أضيفي ما تبقى من الماء تدريجياً ثم اعجني من جديد حتى تتشكل لديك عجينة لينة•    ضعي العجينة في وعاء، غطيها واتركيها جانبا لساعتين من الوقت حتى يتضاعف حجمها•    سخني الزيت في قدر على النار•    خذي كمية من العجين براحة يدك، اعصري العجينة واستخرجي بواسطة ملعقة صغيرة مبلولة بالزيت الفائض على شكل كرة بين الابهام والسبابة•    ضعي الكرة في الزيت الحامي بحذر واقليها حتى تصبح مقرمشة•    كرري العملية حتى انتهاء كمية العجين واقلي اللقيمات المقرمشة•    ضعي اللقيمات في القطر حتى تتشربه ثم قدميها"},{"question":"لایحه څه ته وایې؟","answer":"ځواب: د قانون، مقرراتو، طرزالعملونو او یا تعلیمات نامو توضیح کول د څو مثالونو سره او یا نور تشریح کولو چې قابل ادراک ويلایحه وایې."},{"question":"කෝමාරිකා ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න ","answer":"පොදු නාමය : කෝමාරිකාකූලය : ලිලියේසියේ(Liliaceae)උද්භිද විද්‍යාත්මක : ඇලොවේරාඉන්ඩිකා (Aloevera indica)ඖෂධයක් මෙන්ම ආහාරයක් වශයෙන්ද භාවිතා කළ හැක. ඝන පත්‍ර මසින් පිරී ඇත. එහි කෙළවර උල් සහිතය. පත්‍රයේ තැන තැන සුදු පැහැ ලප ඇත. ශාක ප්‍රචාරණය මොරෙයියන් මගින් සිදු කරයි. ඕනෑම දේශගුණික තත්ත්වයක්‌ යටතේ වගා කළ හැක. ශ්‍රිලංකාවේ තෙත් හා වියළි කලාප වල හොඳින් වැවේ. යාපනය හා මන්නාරම පෙදෙස් වල බහුලව ඇත.ඖෂධීය වටිනාකම:ආයුර්වේදයේ දී සාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රතිකර්ම මෙන්ම මාරාන්තික රෝග සඳහා වන ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා ද කෝමාරිකා භාවිතා කරයි. ආහාර ජීර්ණ ක්‍රියාවලිය පහසුවෙන් සිදුකරමින් මලබද්ධය සුව කරයි. අක්මාවේ ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය වැඩිකර අක්මාව ආරක්ෂා කරයි. ඇස් දැවිල්ල, කබ ගැලීම ආදී ඇස් රෝග, වා පිත් සෙම් රෝග ආදියට කදිම ඔසුවකි. මුත්‍රා දැවිල්ල පාලනය කරයි. පෙනහළු ආශ්‍රිත රෝග සුවකරයි. ගර්භාෂගත උෂ්ණත්වය පාලනය කර දරුපල ඇතිකිරීමේ හැකියාවද මේ අපූරු ඖෂධය සතුය. ලියුකේමියා හා ආතරයිටිස් රෝගීන්ට කෝමාරිකා ගුණදායකය. කෝමාරිකා වල පිළිකා නාශක ගුණ ඇති බව මෑතක දී සිදුකළ විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ මගින් අනාවරණය වී ඇත.නිර්මාංශ අයට වඩාත් ගුණදායක ආහාරයකි කෝමාරිකා. ආහාරයක් ලෙස කෝමාරිකා භාවිතා කිරීමෙන් රුධිරයේ ඔක්සිජන් ප්‍රමාණය වැඩිකර ශරීරයේ සෛල ශක්තිමත් කිරීමද සිදුකරයි. රුපලාවන්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ කෝමාරිකා වලට විශාල වටිනාකමක් ලැබෙයි. ඊට හේතු බොහෝය. ප්‍රතිඔක්සිකාරක ගුණයෙන් යුක්ත කෝමාරිකා තරුණ බව ආරක්ෂා කරයි. වයසට යාම නිසා සමේ ඇතිවන එල්ලා වැටීම් වළක්වයි. සමේ තෙතමනය ආරක්ෂා කරයි. හිස්හොරි වලින් හිසකෙස් ආරක්ෂා කරයි. හිසකේ වඩවයි. හිරු කිරණ නිසා සමට වන බලපෑම දුරලයි."},{"question":"Quem é o do signo de Escorpião?","answer":"Quem nasceu de 23 de outubro a 21 de novembro. Portanto, alguém que nasceu dentro desse período é considerado do signo de Escorpião."},{"question":"2000-കളിൽ ആദ്യ സീസൺ ഉണ്ടായ രസകരമായ അമേരിക്കൻ സിറ്റ്‌കോമുകളുടെ ഒരു ലിസ്റ്റ് ഉണ്ടാക്കുക. ","answer":"2000-കളിലെ ചില രസകരമായ അമേരിക്കൻ സിറ്റ്‌കോമുകൾ ദി ഓഫീസ്, പാർക്ക്‌സ് ആൻഡ് റെക്, കമ്മ്യൂണിറ്റി, അറെസ്റ്റഡ് ഡെവലപ്‌മെന്റ് എന്നിവയാണ്. "},{"question":"கேள்வி :  நீல நிறத்தைக் காணக்கூடிய ஒரே பறவை எது?","answer":"பதில்:   நீல நிறத்தைக் காணக்கூடிய ஒரே பறவை \\"ஆந்தை\\"   ஆந்தை, ஸ்ட்றைஜிபோர்மெஸ் வரிசையைச் சேர்ந்த, தனித்த, இரவில் திரியும் 200 வகைப் பறவைகளில் ஒன்றைக் குறிக்கும். ஆந்தைகள் பெரும்பாலும் சிறிய பாலூட்டிகள், பூச்சிகள், மற்றும் ஏனைய பறவைகளை வேட்டையாடும். ஆந்தைகளின் வலுவான நகங்களும், கூரிய சொண்டும், உண்பதற்குமுன் அவற்றின் இரைகளைத் துண்டுதுண்டாகக் கிழிப்பதற்கு உதவுகின்றன.    இந்தியாவில் பழமையான பஞ்சதந்திரக் கதைகளில் சித்தரிக்கப்பட்ட பல விலங்குக் கதாபாத்திரங்களில் ஆந்தையும் முக்கியமான ஒன்று. எனினும் இந்தியப் பண்பாட்டில் ஆந்தையின் அலறல், பயத்துக்குரியதாகவும், கெட்ட சகுனமாகவுமே கருதப்பட்டது."},{"question":"السؤال: كم يبلغ وزن الإنسان على ظهر كوكب المشتري؟","answer":"الجواب: يبلغ أكثر من وزنه على الأرض بمرتين ونصف."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Fiaria-karena misandraaka aminizao totolo izao indridra fa eo amin’ny lafiny varotra ny atao hoe: fanatontoloana.\\"","answer":"Ity ny fanambarana miaraka amin'ireo hadisoana voahitsy:\\"Fiharian-karena misandrahaka amin’izao tontolo izao indrindra fa eo amin’ny lafiny varotra ny atao hoe: fanatontoloana.\\""},{"question":"દુનિયાનું સૌથી પ્રદૂષિત શહેર કયું છે ? ","answer":"લાહોર, પાકિસ્તાન: આઈક્યૂ એરના 2023 વર્લ્ડ એર ક્વાલિટી રિપોર્ટ અનુસાર, લાહોર હાલમાં વિશ્વનું સૌથી પ્રદૂષિત શહેર છે. શહેરમાં PM2.5નું સ્તર ખૂબ જ વધારે છે, જે ફેફસાની સમસ્યાઓનું કારણ બની શકે છેદિલ્હી, ભારત: દિલ્હી લાંબા સમયથી વિશ્વના સૌથી પ્રદૂષિત શહેરોમાંનું એક છે. વાહનો, ઉદ્યોગો અને ખેતરોમાંથી નીકળતા ધુમાડાને કારણે શહેરમાં હવાની ગુણવત્તા ખૂબ જ ખરાબ છે.બીજિંગ, ચીન: ચીનના ઘણા શહેરોમાં પ્રદૂષણની સમસ્યા છે, જેમાં બીજિંગ પણ સામેલ છે. શહેરમાં PM2.5નું સ્તર ખૂબ જ વધારે છે, જે ફેફસાની સમસ્યાઓનું કારણ બની શકે છે.ગુરુગ્રામ, ભારત: દિલ્હીની બાજુમાં આવેલું ગુરુગ્રામ શહેર પણ ખૂબ જ પ્રદૂષિત છે. શહેરમાં વાહનો અને ઉદ્યોગોને કારણે હવાની ગુણવत्ता ખરાબ છે.ગાઝિયાબાદ, ભારત: ગાઝિયાબાદ પણ ભારતનું એક ખૂબ જ પ્રદૂષિત શહેર છે. શહેરમાં વાહનો અને ઉદ્યોગોને કારણે હવાની ગુણવત્તા ખરાબ છે.આ યાદી દર વર્ષે બદલાય છે, અને ઘણા શહેરો પ્રદૂષણને ઘટાડવા માટે પગલાં લઈ રહ્યા છે. જો કે, પ્રદૂષણ હજી પણ વિશ્વના ઘણા શહેરોમાં ગંભીર સમસ્યા છે, અને તેની આરોગ્ય અને પર્યાવરણ પર નકારાત્મક અસર પડે છે.તમારે ધ્યાનમાં રાખવું જોઈએ કે આ યાદી માત્ર એક અંદાજ છે અને વિવિધ સ્રોતોના આંકડાઓના આધારે બનાવવામાં આવી છે. ચોક્કસ પ્રદૂષણ સ્તર વિવિધ પરિબળોના આધારે બદલાઈ શકે છે, જેમ કે હવામાન, સમય અને માપન પદ્ધતિઓ.આશા છે કે આ માહિતી ઉપયોગી છે."},{"question":"*كم ضلعا لشبه المنحرف ؟","answer":"4 أضلاع"},{"question":"چگونه می توانم زهکشی خاک گیاهم را بهبود بخشم؟","answer":"زهکشی مناسب برای جلوگیری از پوسیدگی ریشه ضروری است. اگر خاک رس یا فشرده دارید که به خوبی زهکشی نمی کند، برای بهبود ساختار و زهکشی آن، مواد آلی مانند کمپوست را اضافه کنید. همچنین بسترهای مرتفع می توانند به ایجاد شرایط زهکشی بهتر برای گیاهانی که به رطوبت بیش از حد حساس هستند کمک کند.برای بهبود زهکشی خاک گیاهان، می‌توانید اقدامات زیر را انجام دهید:افزودن مواد آلی: افزودن مواد آلی به خاک، مانند کود ارگانیک یا کمپوست، به بهبود ساختار خاک و افزایش نفوذپذیری آن کمک می‌کند.استفاده از پوشش گیاهی: گیاهانی که خود را در خاک پخش کرده و پوشش گیاهی ایجاد کنند، به عنوان یک لایه محافظ بر روی خاک عمل می‌کنند و از فرسایش و زهکشی ناپایدار جلوگیری می‌کنند.استفاده از خاک‌های سبک: خاک‌های سبکتری مانند خاک شنی یا آهکی، زهکشی بهتری دارند. اگر خاک شما خیلی سنگین است، ممکن است با افزودن شن و ماسه، زهکشی آن را بهبود بخشید.استفاده از شیار: ایجاد شیارها در نواحی شیب‌دار می‌تواند از فرسایش خاک جلوگیری کرده و زهکشی را بهبود بخشد.استفاده از لوله‌های زهکشی: در برخی موارد، نصب لوله‌های زهکشی می‌تواند به تخلیه زهاب زیرزمینی و بهبود زهکشی خاک کمک کند.استفاده از کودهای آلی: کودهای آلی مانند کمپوست یا کود حیوانی می‌توانند به ساختار خاک کمک کرده و زهکشی را بهبود بخشند.گیاه‌پوشانی: گیاهانی با ریشه‌های قوی و چگال می‌توانند به بهبود زهکشی خاک کمک کنند. گیاهانی مانند گندم، شبدر، یا گیاهان کاوری می‌توانند به ثبات خاک کمک کنند.هرچند که این اقدامات می‌توانند بهبود زهکشی خاک را فراهم کنند، اما توجه به نوع خاک و شرایط زمینی مهم است. در صورتی که مشکلات زهکشی خاک بیشتر باشند، مشاوره با یک متخصص خاک مفید خواهد بود. "},{"question":"Manomeza famintinana ho an’ity lahatsoratra manaraka ity :\\tEfa ho roa volana izao, migaingaina tsy misy toy izany ny hafanana, mamaky loha sola hoy ny fitenenana. Tsy nisy na ranon’orana indray mitete aza; “nankaiza ilay mampisara-taona?”, hoy ny fanontaniana heno etsy sy eroa. Mipoitra avokoa ny karazan’aretin-dratsy mpahazo ny kilonga, ary na ny olon-dehibe aza maro no ampahorian’ny tsy fahasalamana.\\tNy tapatapaky ny volana Desambra vao nirotsaka ny orana, kanjo avy hatrany dia oram-batravatra tsy misy ohatra izany. Ny ketsa sy izay tanimboly noheverina mba hahazo aina, potiky ny havandra sy ny ranon’orana. Nanjary korontana ambany, korontany ambony ny fiainam-bahoaka na an-tanàn-dehibe na any ambanivohitra.\\tNitondra fanazavana momba izao zava-mitranga izao tamin’ny fahitalavitra sy ny radio ry zareo manam-pahaizana momba ny toetrandro. Ny vahoaka rehetra koa dia niaiky fa zava-doza no aterak’ity fiovaovan’ny toetrandro ity. Noho izany, tsy maintsy hampitomboina ny ezaka amin’ny fiarovana ny tontolo iainana. Fa ny hetahetan’ny maro kosa, manomboka amin’ity taona ity dia ny hanatanterahana hetsika goavana manerana ny firenena amin’ny fambolen-kazo. Heverina fa isan’ny asa fanavotam-pirenena tokoa izany satria ny fampitomboana ny ala no hahafahana miady amin’ny fiovan’ny toetrandro.","answer":"Ity ny famintinana ny lahatsoratra:Vokatry ny fiovaovan’ny toetrandro, migaingaina tsy misy toy izany ny hafanana. Mipoitra avokoa ireo karazan’aretina mandritra io vanim-potoana io. Any amin’ny tapatapaky ny volana Desambra vao mirotsaka ny oram-baratra mivatravatra ka manimba zavatra maro. Tsy maintsy mifanolo-tanana ny rehetra amin’ny fiarovana ny tontolo iainana sy ny fambolen-kazo mba hiadiana amin’ity fiovaovan’ny toetrandro ity."},{"question":"خلاصه مقاله رو بگو:  (CNN) قتل فرخنده ۲۷ ساله در اوایل این ماه در دست توده ای که او را تا حد مرگ کتک زدند، جسدش را سوزاندند و به رودخانه انداختند، افغانستان را شوکه کرد، کشوری که در آن اتفاقات غیرقابل توصیف اغلب در عناوین اخبار قرار می گیرد. این زن جوان از کابل به دروغ به سوزاندن صفحات قرآن مقدس متهم شد. آنچه که بعد از آن اتفاق افتاد وحشت حاکمیت توده ای بود، همه چیز در ویدیو ضبط شد در حالی که تماشاگران تماشا می کردند. به گزارش خبرگزاری تولو نیوز افغانستان، بلافاصله پس از این حادثه، تصاویر کشتار وحشیانه او در شبکه های اجتماعی به صورت ویروسی پخش شد. و این بار، خشم افغان ها را به خیابان ها کشاند، با کمک فیس بوک و سایر رسانه های اجتماعی. این پلتفرم ها هم برای انتشار تصاویر ضرب و شتم وحشیانه و قتل او و هم به عنوان وسیله ای برای گردآوری کسانی که برای اعتراض به قتل او بسیج و سازماندهی می کنند، خدمت کرده اند. هفته گذشته، جمعیت برای چند روز شعار دادند، خواستار عدالت برای فرخنده و \\"مرگ برای قاتلانش\\". و به گزارش تولو نیوز، تظاهرات در بخش های مختلف کشور برگزار شد و خواستار \\"عقوبت نهایی برای مرتکبان\\" شدند. در واقع، تکنولوژی و ارتباط نقش مهمی در تغییر روایت های قدیمی در افغانستان ایفا کرده است، همان طور که قتل فرخوندا نشان می دهد. نه تنها قتل او ضبط شد و به صورت آنلاین به اشتراک گذاشته شد، بلکه مشخص شد که برخی از مردانی که به قتل او دستگیر شدند، از طریق پست های رسانه های اجتماعی اعتراف کرده اند. و حالا اندوه یک کشور در همان محله های آنلاین و مجازی به اشتراک گذاشته شده است. برخی از رهبران جامعه مدنی افغانستان این اعتراضات را نشانه ای دیگر از تحول افغانستان می دانند؛ کشوری که رهبران تازه انتخاب شده اش، که اکنون در یک دولت وحدت مشترک هستند، در تلاش برای برگشتن از گذشته، به واشنگتن سفر کردند. \\"وقتی ما در مورد این پرونده صحبت می کنیم، چه چیزی را به ما نشان می دهد؟ اول از همه، وقتی ما در مورد حقوق زنان صحبت می کنیم، می بینیم که موفق شده ایم؛ مردم آنچه را که یک دهه پیش تحمل کردند تحمل نخواهند کرد، \\"نرگس نهان، بنیانگذار و مدیر اجرایی برابری برای صلح و دموکراسی، یک سازمان غیر دولتی که برای ترویج \\"یک...","answer":"قتل يک زن 27 ساله توده اي در افغانستان، رسانه هاي اجتماعي را با درخواست عدالت به آتش کشید. عصبانیت مردم و تلاش آنها برای بررسی این پرونده که مربوط به یک زن است نشان می دهد که این کشور در مورد حقوق زنان در حال تغییر است."},{"question":"විදුලිබිල වැඩිවීම දැනුනේ කොහොමද?","answer":"ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ක්ෂණිකව වේගවත් වුණු පසුගිය වසර(2022) ආරම්භයේ සිට මේ දක්වා කාලය තුළ දී ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට වැඩියෙන්ම අසන්නට ලැබුණු වචනයක් වන්නේ 'උද්ධමනය', නැත්තම් 'මිල ඉහළ යෑම'යි.ඉන්ධන මිළ, ගෑස් මිළ, අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආහාර මිල සහ බැංකු ණය පොළිය ආදී වශයෙන් සියලු අවශ්‍යතා වෙනුවෙන් ගෙවිය යුතු මිල විදුලි වේගයෙන් ඉහළගොස් තිබේ.එලෙස ජනතාව ආර්ථික පීඩනයෙන් මිරිකී සිටින මොහොතක මාස කිහිපයක් ඇතුළත දෙවතාවක්ම විදුලි බිල ද ඉහළ ගියේය. විදුලිය ගාස්තු වැඩිවූයේද සුළු ප්‍රතිශතයකින් නොවේ.පළමුව විදුලිබිල වැඩි වූයේ ඉකුත් වසරේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු 10 වැනිදාය. එම වැඩිවීම සියයට 75ක් විය. අනතුරුව දෙවැනි වරට විදුලි බිල වැඩි වූ බව ප්‍රකාශ කෙරුණේ සියයට 66ක ප්‍රතිශතයකිනි.එහෙත් එම ප්‍රතිශතය 'මධ්‍යයන අගයක්' පමණක් වූ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බහුතරයක් අඩු ආදායම්ලාභීන් අයත්වන ඒකක 0 සිට ඒකක 30 දක්වා වූ කාණ්ඩයට විදුලිය ගාස්තුව වැඩිවූ ප්‍රතිශතය සියයට 225ක් තරම් විශාල අගයකින් යුක්ත විය. එහිදී එක් ඒකකයක් සඳහා අය කරන රුපියල් අටක ගාස්තුව රුපියල් 30 දක්වා වැඩි කෙරිණි. ඊට අමතරව ඒකක 31 සිට 60 දක්වා පැවති ඒකකයකට අය කරන රුපියල් 10ක ගාස්තුව රුපියල් 37 දක්වා වැඩි කිරීමටත්, ඒකක 61 සිට 90 දක්වා කාණ්ඩය යටතේ අයකෙරුණු රුපියල් 16ක ගාස්තුව රුපියල් 42 දක්වාත් වැඩි කිරීමටත් අනුමැතිය හිමිවිය.ජනතාව පන්දම් රැගෙන මහමඟට පැමිණ දිනපතා රාත්‍රියේ විරෝධතා පවත්වන්නේ මෙම අධික විදුලිය බිල සහ ඒ මත ඉහළ ගිය අනෙකුත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ සහ සේවාවන් තමන්ට අත්පත් කරගත හැකි මානයෙන් ඔබ්බටගොස් ඇති බැවිනි."},{"question":"கேள்வி: ஒளிவிலகலின்  மூன்று விதிகள்  பற்றி விளக்குக ?","answer":"விடை: ஒளிவிலகல் என்பது ஒளியின் வளைவு மற்றும் இது ஒரு வெளிப்படையான ஊடகத்திலிருந்து மற்றொரு வெளிப்படையான ஊடகத்திற்கு செல்லும் போது காட்சிப்படுத்தப்படலாம். எந்த ஒரு ஊடகத்தின் பேண்டிங் திறன் ஒளிவிலகல் குறியீடு என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது .ஒளிவிலகல் விதிகள்ஒளியின் ஒளிவிலகல் மூன்று விதிகளால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது.முதல் விதி: ஒளிவிலகல் முதல் விதி, நிகழ்வு கதிர், ஒளிவிலகல் கதிர் மற்றும் நிகழ்வின் புள்ளியில் இரண்டு வெளிப்படையான ஊடகங்களின் இடைமுகத்திற்கு இயல்பானது, அனைத்தும் ஒரே விமானத்தில் உள்ளன.இரண்டாவது விதி: ஒளியின் கதிர் ஒரு அரிய ஊடகத்தின் வழியாக அடர்த்தியான ஊடகத்திற்குச் செல்லும்போது, ​​ஒளிவிலகல் கதிர் இயல்பை நெருங்குகிறது, அதே நேரத்தில் ஒளியின் கதிர் அடர்த்தியான ஊடகத்தின் வழியாக அரிதான ஊடகத்திற்குச் செல்லும் போது, ​​ஒளிவிலகல் கதிர் நகர்கிறது. இயல்பிலிருந்து விலகி. இந்த ஒளிவிலகல் விதி ஸ்னெல் விதி என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. ஸ்னெல் விதியின்படி, ஒளிவிலகல் கோணத்தின் சைனின் நிகழ்வுகளின் கோணத்தின் விகிதம் ஒரு நிலையானது. இந்த மாறிலி ஒளிவிலகல் குறியீடாகும். மூன்றாவது விதி: மூன்றாவது விதியின்படி, சாதாரண வழியாக செல்லும் சம்பவக் கதிர் எப்போதும் ஒளிவிலகலுக்குப் பிறகு நேரடியாக ஊடகத்தில் செல்கிறது.    படுகதிர், செங்குத்துக்கோடு, விலகுகதிர் ஆகியவை ஒரே சமதளத்தில் இருக்கும். செங்குத்துக் கோட்டுக்கு எதிர்ப்புறத்தில் படுகதிரும் விலகுகதிரும் இருக்கும். படுகோணத்தின் சைனும் விலகுகோணத்தின் சைனும் எப்பொழுதும் மாறா வீதத்தில் இருக்கும். வீதம் ஒளியின் நிறத்தையும் ஊடகங்களையும் பொறுத்தது."},{"question":"ලොව ප්‍රථම වරට ක්ලෝනීකරණය කළ සත්වයා  කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"සාර්ථකව ක්ලෝනීකරණය කළ පළමු සත්වයා  ඩොලි බැටළුවා  ය. 1996 දී ස්කොට්ලන්තයේ රොස්ලින් ආයතනයේ විද්‍යාඥයන් විසින් ඩොලිව ක්ලෝනීකරණය කරන ලදී. මෙය  ජාන ඉංජිනේරු ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ වැදගත් සන්ධිස්ථානයක් සටහන්  කළේය."},{"question":"Ounjẹ ọdun ni wọn ni ki Bimpe lọọ gbe fun Waheed, lo ba fipa ba a lo pọ n’Ibadan","answer":"Lalẹ ọjọ ọdun Ileya to kọja, nigba ti gbogbo Musulumi ti n dupẹ pe Ọlọrun jẹ ki ọdun ọdun yii ṣoju ẹmi awọn, ẹkun lọmọdebinrin kan, Adebimpe, sun sùn mọju ọjọ keji. Ki i ṣe pe ẹnikan na an tabi febi pa a, bọọda kan laduugbo wọn, Waheed Ògúndélé,  lo fipa ba a laṣepọ.Ounjẹ ọdun ni wọn ni ki Bimpe, ẹni ta a fi ojulowo orukọ ẹ bo laṣiiri lọọ gbe fun ọkunrin naa, Waheed Ogundele to jẹ alabaagbe wọn laduugbo Ologunẹru, n’Ibadan, lalẹ ọjọ naa (ọjọ Jimọ to kọja), n ni jagunlabi ba gba ounjẹ silẹ, lo ba fipa ba ọmọọlọmọ laṣepọ.Lẹyin tọkunrin yii ti sa lọ mọ awọn ẹbi ọmọ naa nibi ti wọn ti n gbiyanju lati fa a le awọn agbofinro lọwọ, ọwọ awọn ọlọpaa pada tẹ ẹ, o si ti wa ninu ahamọ wọn bayii fun iwadii.Mọlẹbi ọmọdebinrin naa to n jẹ Mahmud ṣalaye pe oun niya wọn sọ pe ko lọọ wo aunti ẹ wa nigba ti wọn ko tete ri i (Bimpe) ko de lati ibi ti wọn ran an, n loun ba pade ọmọbinrin naa to n sunkun bọ latinu ile Waheed. Njẹ ki lo ṣẹlẹ, o ni bọọda Waheed fipa ba oun laṣepọ.Mahmud ṣalaye pe “Nigba ta a fẹẹ maa lọọ kirun  ni mọṣlalaṣi ni mo gbọ ti iya ẹ (Iya Bimpe) sọ pe ko lọọ gbe ounjẹ fun ẹnikan (Waheed). Wọn waa ni ki n lọọ wo o wa nigba ti ko tete pada de.“Mo pade ẹ to n sunkun bọ, bẹẹ lẹjẹ n ṣan jade lati oju ara ẹ. Mo ni ki lo ṣe e, o ni Bọda Waheed lo fipa ba oun laṣepọ. Ṣugbọn awọn ọrẹ Waheed ko jẹ ka ri i mu, niṣe ni wọn fẹyin pọ ọn titi to fi sa lọ mọ wa lọwọ.”Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ fakọroyin wa, Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ ọyọ, SP Olugbenga Fadeyi, sọ pe ‘ọwọ wa (awọn ọlọpaa) ti tẹ afurasi ọdaran naa, o si ti wa ni CID (ẹka ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to n ṣewadii iṣẹlẹ ọdaran) ni Iyaganku, n’Ibadan bayii.”"},{"question":"エドワード三世によって制定された、足につけることで有名なイギリス最高の勲章といえば何でしょう？","answer":"ガーター勲章"},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Công ty Nhiệt điện Duyên Hải là đơn vị trực thuộc Tổng công ty Phát điện 1 (EVNGENCO1) được giao nhiệm vụ quản lý vận hành Nhà máy nhiệt điện Duyên Hải 1, Nhà máy nhiệt điện Duyên Hải 3 và Nhà máy nhiệt điện Duyên Hải 3 mở rộng với tổng công suất 3.178 MW và Cảng biển Trung tâm Điện lực Duyên Hải. Sản lượng điện sản xuất hàng năm của công ty lên tới khoảng 20 tỉ Kwh. Hiện tại, các nhà máy của công ty sử dụng công nghệ ngưng hơi truyền thống, nhiên liệu than, công nghệ đốt hiện đại, đảm bảo các chỉ tiêu kinh tế, kỹ thuật và hệ số sẵn sàng cao, hiệu suất, ổn định, an toàn và đảm bảo các yêu cầu về bảo vệ môi trường nhờ các hệ thống lọc bụi, khử NOx, SOx và các thiết bị tiên tiến nhất hiện nay. Công ty Nhiệt điện Duyên Hải xác định việc nâng cao năng lực quản trị doanh nghiệp cũng chính là nâng cao hiệu quả sản xuất kinh doanh. ","answer":"Công Ty Nhiệt Điện Duyên Hải: Tiên Phong Trong Sản Xuất Điện Sạch và Bảo Vệ Môi Trường"},{"question":"வினா :கடவுள் வாழ்த்தில் உள்ள திருக்குறளும்   அதன் பொருளையும் விளக்கவும்","answer":" விடை:இம் மூன்று சொற்களும் (கடவுள்,இறைவன்,தெய்வம்) திருக்குறள் எழுதப்பட்ட காலத்திலேயே உண்டு. இறைவன், தெய்வம் என்பன திருக்குறளிலேயே உண்டு. \`கடவுள்\` என்ற சொல் பதினெண்கீழ் கணக்கு நூலான திருக்குறளிற்கு முற்பட்ட பதினெண் மேற்கணக்கு நூலான புறநானூற்றிலேயே உண்டு.“கல்லே பரவின் அல்லது,நெல்உகுத்துப் பரவும் கடவுளும் இலவே” - (புறம் 335){நடுகல்லாயினவரின் நடு கல்லைத் தொழுவதன்றி, நெல்லும் பூவும் சொரிந்து வழிபட க் கடவுளும் வேறு கிடையாது}எனவே வள்ளுவர் இம் மூன்று சொற்களையும் அறிந்த பின்பே, கடவுள் என்ற சொல்லைத் தவிர்த்து இறைவன், தெய்வம் என்ற சொற்களை மட்டும் பயன்படுத்துகின்றார். {திருக்குறளில் வரும் கடவுள் வாழ்த்து அதிகாரத்தினை நினைத்துக் குழம்ப வேண்டாம். அதிகாரங்கள் பிற்காலத்தில் உருவாக்கப்பட்டவையே}. பழந் தமிழர்களிடையே இயற்கையுடன் இணைந்த இறைவன், தெய்வம் போன்ற வழிபாடுகள் காணப்பட்டனவேயன்றி, இன்றைய மதங்கள் குறிப்பிடும் \`எல்லாம் வல்ல கடவுள்\` நம்பிக்கையோ அல்லது மதங்களோ இருந்திருக்கவில்லை. இதனையே கீழடி அகழ்வாய்வும், மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட சங்ககாலப் பாடலும் (புறம் 335) காட்டுகின்றன.வள்ளுவன் குறிப்பிடும் \`இறைவன்\` என்ற சொல்லினைப் பார்ப்போம். இறைவன்\` என்ற சொல் \`இறை \` என்ற வேர்ச்சொல்லினை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டது. மக்களை இறுக்குவதால் இறை.இறை(Tax) விதிப்பவன் இறைவன். எனவே தொடக்ககாலத்தில் இறைவன் என்பது அரசனையே/ தலைவனையே குறிக்கும். குறள் 1157 இல் வரும் (\`இறை இறவா நின்ற வளை\`) இறைவன் என்பது தலைவியினைப் பிரிந்த தலைவனையும் ; அதே போன்று குறள் 5 இல் (\`இருள்சேர் இருவினையும் சேரா இறைவன்\`) இறைவன் என்பது தலைவனையும் { தலைவன் என்பதற்குரிய பொருளைப் புரிந்து கொண்டு புகழ் பெற விரும்புகிறவர்கள், நன்மை தீமைகளை ஒரே அளவில் எதிர் கொள்வார்கள்}; குறள் 10 இலும் (இறைவன் அடிசேரா தார்) இறைவன் என்பது தலைவனையும் {தலைவனைப் பின்பற்றாதோர்}; குறள் 547 இல் இறைவன் என்பது (இறைகாக்கும் வையகம்) அரசனையும் ; குறள் 388 இல் இறைவன் (முறைசெய்து காப்பாற்றும் மன்னவன்) என்பது அரசனையும்; குறள் 541 இல் இறைவன் (ஓர்ந்துகண் ணோடாது இறைபுரிந்து) என்பது அரசனையும் குறிக்கின்றது.தெய்வம் என்ற சொல்லானது பின்வரும் பொருள்களில் குறள்களில் இடம்பெறுகின்றது.\`தெய்வத்தான் ஆகாது எனினும் முயற்சி தன்மெய்வருத்தக் கூலி தரும்\` - 619இங்கு தெய்வத்தினை விட முயற்சியே உயர்ந்ததாகக் காட்டப்படுகின்றது.வையத்தில் வாழ்வாங்கு வாழ்பவன் வானுறையும்தெய்வத்துள் வைக்கப்படும்\` - 50இங்கு, தெய்வம் = வாழ்வாங்கு வாழ்ந்து மறைந்தவர்கள்.\`ஐயப்படாது அகத்தது உணர்வானைத்தெய்வத்தோடு ஒப்பக் கொளல்\` - 702இங்கு, தெய்வம் = குறிப்பறிந்து நடந்துகொள்பவன்.\`தென்புலத்தார் தெய்வம் விருந்து ஒக்கல் தான் என்று ஆங்குஐம்புலத்து ஆறு ஓம்பல் தலை\`- 43இங்கு, தென் புலத்தார் தெய்வம் = மரித்தோர்.\`குடிசெய்வல் என்னும் ஒருவற்குத் தெய்வம்மடிதற்றுத் தான்முந் துறும் \` - 1023இங்கு, தெய்வம் = ஊழ்.\`தெய்வம் தொழாஅள் கொழுநற் தொழுது எழுவாள்பெய் எனப் பெய்யும் மழை\`. – 55.இங்கு தெய்வம் என்பது சற்றுச் சிக்கலானது. அதனை விளக்கினால் பதில் நீளும். \`தெய்வத்தினையே தொழ வேண்டாம்\` என்ற பொருள் வருவதால் , இங்கு தெய்வம் சிறப்புப் பெறவில்லை என்பதே முதன்மையானது. {விளக்கம் தேவையாயின் யாராவது கேட்டால், கருத்தில் பின்னர் இணைப்புத் தருகின்றேன்}.முடிவாக, வள்ளுவன் வலியுறுத்துவது இயற்கையோடு இணைந்த இறைவன்,தெய்வம் போன்றவற்றையே; மாறாக கடவுள் என்பதல்ல."},{"question":"Discuss the significance of the Turing test in artificial intelligence and its limitations.","answer":"Alan Turing developed the Turing test in 1950 to gauge a machine's capacity for intelligent conduct that can be mistaken for human-like behavior. It served as a baseline for machine intelligence and was a fundamental idea in artificial intelligence (AI). The Turing test is not without restrictions, though. It disregards consciousness or underlying mechanisms in favor of concentrating on outward conduct. If a machine mimics human responses, even without true comprehension or reasoning, it could pass the test. Furthermore, since intelligence is not just focused on verbal skills, it is a complex concept that is not fully captured by the exam. Although the Turing test has historical value, more complex and comprehensive measurements of intelligence are now taken into consideration in the field of artificial intelligence."},{"question":"Ukhrul es también un punto turístico del estado de Manipur. Sentencia 2: Ukhrul es también un punto turístico en el estado de Manipur. Pregunta: ¿Expresan la frase 1 y la frase 2 el mismo significado? - ¿Sí o No? - No lo sé.","answer":"Si, son idénticas "},{"question":"No contexto do futebol brasileiro, complete a frase: Pelé é amplamente reconhecido como...","answer":"Pelé é amplamente reconhecido como o maior jogador de todos os tempos."},{"question":"Фашисттер мешке күйгүзүп жиберишкен улуу педагог:а)Янош Корчакб)Адольф Дистервергв)И.Карбышев","answer":" Тураа жообу:а)Янош Корчак"},{"question":"සය විස යන්නෙන් කුමන ඉලක්කමක් හැදින්වේද?","answer":" සය විස = 26"},{"question":"Суунун атасы ким?","answer":"Суунун атасы- булак."},{"question":"明け方の空にかかる虹は、東西南北どちらの方角にかかるでしょう？","answer":"西"},{"question":"ගෝලීය උණුසුමට මිනිසා විසින් ඇති කරන ලද හේතු මොනවද?","answer":"වන විනාශයශාක යනු ඔක්සිජන් වල ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රභවයයි. ඔවුන් කාබන් ඩයොක්සයිඩ් අවශෝෂණය කර ඔක්සිජන් මුදා හැරීමෙන් පාරිසරික සමතුලිතතාවය පවත්වා ගනී. බොහෝ ගෘහාශ්‍රිත හා වාණිජ අරමුණු සඳහා වනාන්තර විනාශ වෙමින් පවතන අතර . මෙය පාරිසරික අසමතුලිතතාවයට හේතු වී ඇති අතර එමඟින් ගෝලීය උණුසුමද ඉහළ යයි. යාන වාහන භාවිතයඉතා කෙටි දුරක් සඳහා වුවද වාහන භාවිතා කිරීමෙන් විවිධ වායු විමෝචන ඇතිවේ. වාහන වායුගෝලයට කාබන්ඩයොක්සයිඩ් සහ අනෙකුත් විෂ ද්‍රව්‍ය විශාල ප්‍රමාණයක් විමෝචනය කරන පොසිල ඉන්ධන දහනය කිරීමෙන් උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යයි.ක්ලෝරෝෆ්ලෝරෝ කාබන් (CFC)වායු සමීකරණ සහ ශීතකරණ අධික ලෙස භාවිතා කිරීමත් සමඟ මිනිසුන් වායුගෝලීය ඕසෝන් ස්ථරයට බලපාන CFC පරිසරයට මුදා හරිමින්  ඇත. සූර්යයාගෙන් නිකුත් වන අහිතකර පාරජම්බුල කිරණවලින් පෘථිවි පෘෂ්ඨය ආරක්ෂා කරනු ලබන්නේ ඕසෝන් ස්ථරයි. මෙම CFC මගින් ඕසෝන් ස්ථරය ක්ෂය වීම මෙන්ම පාරජම්බුල කිරණ සඳහාද මග පාදමින් පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ නංවා ඇත.කාර්මික සංවර්ධනයකාර්මීකරණය පැමිණීමත් සමඟ පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් ඉහළ යමින් පවතී. කර්මාන්තශාලා වලින් පිටවන අහිතකර වායුන් විමෝචනය වීම පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමට හේතුවක් වේ.2013 දී දේශගුණික විපර්යාස සඳහා වූ අන්තර් රාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලය වාර්තා කළේ 1880 සහ 2012 අතර ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වයේ වැඩිවීම සෙල්සියස් අංශක 0.9 ක් වූ බවයි. පූර්ව කාර්මික මධ්‍යන්‍ය උෂ්ණත්වය හා සසඳන විට වැඩිවීම සෙල්සියස් අංශක 1.1 කි.කෘෂිකර්මයවිවිධ ගොවිතැන් කටයුතු මගින් කාබන්ඩයොක්සයිඩ් සහ මීතේන් වායුව නිපදවේ. මේවා වායුගෝලයේ ඇති හරිතාගාර වායුවලට එකතු වීමෙන් පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩි කරයි.අධික ජනගහනයජනගහනය වැඩි වීමම  මිනිස්සු හුස්ම ගන්නවා යන්නයි. මෙයද වායුගෝලයේ ගෝලීය උණුසුම ඇති කරන ප්‍රාථමික වායුව වන කාබන්ඩයොක්සයිඩ් මට්ටම ඉහළ යාමට හේතුවක් වේ.ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමේ ස්වභාවික හේතුගිනි කඳුගිනිකඳු යනු ගෝලීය උණුසුම ඉහළ යාමට විශාලතම ස්වභාවික දායකත්වය සපයන හේතුවකි. ගිනිකඳු පිපිරීම්වලදී පිටවන අළු සහ දුමාරය වායුගෝලයට යාම දේශගුණය වෙනස් වීමට බලපායි.ජල වාෂ්පජල වාෂ්ප යනු හරිතාගාර වායු වර්ගයකි. පෘථිවි උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙන් ජල මාර්ග වලින් වැඩි ජලය වාෂ්ප ප්‍රමාණයක් පිට වී වායුගෝලයේ රැඳී සිටීම මගින් ගෝලීය උණුසුම වැඩි කරයි.පර්මාෆ්‍රොස්ට් දියවීමපර්මාෆ්‍රොස්ට් යනු ශීත කළ පසක් වන අතර එය වසර ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ පාරිසරික වායූන් එහි සිරවී ඇති අතර , එය පෘථිවි පෘෂ්ඨයට පහළින් පවතී. එය ග්ලැසියරවල රැදී පවතී. මෙම ග්ලැසියර් දියවන විට එය නැවත වායුගෝලයට මුදා හරින අතර එමගින් පෘථිවි උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩි කරයි.ලැව් ගිනිලැව් ගිනි නිසා කාබන් අඩංගු දුමාර විශාල ප්‍රමාණයක් පිටවේ. මෙම වායූන්ද  වායුගෝලයට මුදා හරින අතර පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ගෝලීය උණුසුමද ඉහළ යයි.ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමේ බලපෑම්උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම පෘථිවි උෂ්ණත්වයේ ඇදහිය නොහැකි තරම් ඉහළ යාමට හේතු වී තිබේ. මේ හේතුවෙන් ග්ලැසියර දියවීම ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති අතර එය මුහුදු මට්ටම ඉහළ යාමට හේතු වී තිබේ. මෙය වෙරළබඩ කලාපවලට අහිතකර බලපෑම් ඇති කළ හැකිය.පරිසර පද්ධතියට තර්ජනගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම කොරල්පර වලටද බලපා ඇති අතර එමඟින් කොරල් පර හා මුහුදු සත්ව ජීවිත අහිමි වීමට හේතු විය හැකිය. ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩිවීම නිසා කොරල්පරවල අස්ථාවරත්වය තවත් නරක අතට හැරී ඇත.දේශගුණික විපර්යාසගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම දේශගුණික තත්ත්වයන් වෙනස් වීමට හේතු වී තිබේ. සමහර ප්‍රදේශයන් වල  නියඟත් සමහර ප්‍රදේශයන්ට ගංවතුරද පරස්පර ලෙසින් බල පවත්වයි . මෙම දේශගුණික අසමතුලිතතාවය ගෝලීය උණුසුම ඉහළ යාමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයකි.රෝග පැතිරීමගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම තාපය හා ආර්ද්‍රතාවයේ රටා වෙනස් වීමට හේතු වේ. මෙමගින් රෝග වාහකයන් වන මදුරුවන් හා කෘමීන මගින්  නොයෙක් රෝග පැතිරවීම සිදු විය හැක. ඉහළ මරණ අනුපාතගංවතුර, සුනාමි සහ වෙනත් ස්වාභාවික විපත් වැඩි වීම මගින්  මරණ සංඛ්‍යාවන් වැඩි විය හැක. එසේම, එවැනි සිදුවීම්ද  මිනිස් ජීවිතයට බාධා කළ හැකි රෝග පැතිරීමට හේතු විය හැක.ස්වභාවික වාසස්ථාන අහිමි වීමදේශගුණයේ ගෝලීය වෙනස් කම් නිසා ශාක හා සතුන්ට ව්‍යාප්තිය හා  වාසස්ථාන අහිමි වීමට හේතු වේ. මෙම අවස්ථාවේ දී, සතුන් ඔවුන්ගේ ස්වභාවික වාසස්ථාන වලින් සංක්‍රමණය  වීම සිදු වීමද , ඔවුන්ගෙන් බොහෝ දෙනෙක් වඳ වීමද සිදු විය හැක. මෙය ජෛව විවිධත්වයට ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම නිසාවෙන් සිදු වන තවත් ප්‍රධාන බලපෑමකි."},{"question":" What Is Statistical Learning?","answer":"Statistical learning is a subfield of machine learning that involves using statistical methods to develop models that can learn from data and make predictions or decisions. It is a powerful tool for making predictions and identifying relationships between variables. It is used in many fields,  including finance, healthcare, and social sciences. The algorithms used in statistical learning are based on statistics and probability theory and can typically be evaluated using statistical methods. Some examples of statistical learning include:1. Linear regression: A statistical learning technique used to model the relationship between a dependent variable and one or more independent variables.2. Logistic regression: A statistical learning technique used to model the probability of a binary outcome based on one or more predictor variables.3. Decision trees: A statistical learning technique used to model decisions and their possible consequences in a tree-like structure.4. Random forests: A statistical learning technique that combines multiple decision trees to improve the accuracy of predictions.5. Support vector machines (SVM): A statistical learning technique used to classify data into two or more categories based on a set of features.6. Clustering: A statistical learning technique used to group similar objects together based on their characteristics."},{"question":"మీకు నచ్చిన ఒక సందర్భాన్ని వివరించండి.","answer":"నేను, నా మిత్రులతో కలిసి విహారయాత్రకై మహానంది బయలుదేరాను. ఈ యాత్ర నాకు మధురానుభూతిని మిగిల్చింది. ముఖ్యంగా ఈ క్షేత్రం నల్లమల అడువుల్లో ఉంటుంది. గిద్దలూరు దగ్గరి నుండి నంద్యాల వరకు రైలు ప్రయాణం అరణ్యం గుండా జరిగింది. వంపుసొంపుల మార్గాలు, ఇరువైపులా ఆకాశాన్ని తాకుతున్న పర్వత శిఖరాలు, వాటిపై పొడవైన చెట్లు, ఆ చెట్టుకున్న ‘పూలు చూడముచ్చటగా ఉన్నాయి. మధ్యలో పొడవైన రెండు పెద్ద గుహలు. ఆ గుహల్లోకి రైలు వెళ్ళగానే అంతా దట్టమైన చీకటి. ఏమీ కనిపించదు. ఇది చూచి అనుభవించి తీరవలసిందే. ఎతైన కొండల నుండి కిందికి జాలువారే సెలయేళ్ళు, అక్కడక్కడా గిరిజనుల నివాసాలు సుమనోహరంగా ఉన్నాయి. ప్రకృతి అందాలకు నల్లమల పుట్టినిల్లు. భూదేవికి పచ్చని చీర కట్టినట్లుగా ఉంటుంది. పక్షుల కిలకిలారావాలు, కోయల విన్యాసాలు చూడముచ్చటగా ఉంటాయి."},{"question":"ચોરસ એટલે શુ ?","answer":"ચોરસ એ ચાર સરખી બાજુઓ ધરાવતો આકાર છે અને તેના ચાર ખૂણાઓ કાટખૂણા (૯૦ અંશ) હોય છે. ચોરસનાં ચાર વિકર્ણો પણ કાટખૂણે છેદે છે. કોઇ પણ વિકર્ણ અને ચોરસની બાજુ ૪૫ અંશના ખૂણે હોય છે. ચોરસને ચારની ભ્રમણ સમાનતા હોય છે.ચોરસ એ ચાર સરખી બાજુઓ ધરાવતો ચતુષ્કોણ છે. તેમ છતાં, દરેક ચોરસ એ ચતુષ્કોણ છે તેમ બધાં ચતુષ્કોણ ચોરસ હોતા નથી. ચોરસ એ ઘનનો બે-પરિમાણી ભાગ છે."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Tempat ini memberi makanan, minimum dan tempat tidur secara percuma, tetapi tiada sesiapa pun yang nak tinggal di sini. Apakah tempat ini?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah penjara. Makanan dan minuman dibekalkan dalam penjara tetapi penjara ialah tempat kurungan yang merupakan satu bentuk hukuman dalam sistem kehakiman dan pengadilan jenayah. Banduan yang ditahan tidak mempunyai kebebasan. "},{"question":"Алчы-таасынан жаңылбаган же алчы-таасын жеген ","answer":"1. Өтө эле машыккан, иштин, же айланын бардык ыкмасын билген адам; 2. Өтө куу, эч адамга алдатпаган, эң бир шуртулдаган адам. Бул накыл кептин төркүнү балдардын чүкө оюнуна барып такалат. Илгертеден бери кыргыз эли койдун чүкөсүнөн көп оюндар чыгарышкан. Чүкөнүн төрт жагына тең ат койгон. Кобулдуу жагы – «алчы», тайпак жылмараак жагы – «таа», томпок жагы «бөгө», чуңкур жагы «чиге». Чүкөнүн ичиндеги чоңураак, чымыр, сындуулары – «сака» деп аталган. «Саканын» чуңкур жагын көзөп, ичине «кыт» (коргошун) куйган. Андай сака дайыма «алчы же таа» түшкөн. Сака алчы же таа түшсө утуп алган же дагы атууга укук алган. Мына ошентип, сака алчы же таа түшө берсе, оюн утуштуу болгон. Ошентип, чүкөгө байланыштуу «алчы-таасын жеген же алчы-таасынан жаңылбаган» деген накыл кеп пайда болгон."},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ 東京都は「首都直下地震」という大きな地震が起こった場合、450万人が家に帰ることができない可能性があると考えています。このため、たくさんの人が避難できる場所が必要です。警視庁と東京都にある信用金庫の団体は2日、地震などの災害のときに協力することを約束しました。都にある信用金庫の全部の店を、家に帰ることができなくなった人が避難する場所に使います。店は750あって、学校などの避難所の準備ができるまでの間、避難できるようにします。避難所に行く手伝いもします。信用金庫は、まちの小さな会社などがお金を借りたり預けたりする所です。警視庁は「信用金庫はたくさんの人が利用しているので、災害のときとても役に立ちます」と話しています。","answer":"東京都　地震などのとき信用金庫の店に避難できる"},{"question":"cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Cuántas películas de El padrino hay?","answer":"El tema principal de esa categoría es de películas "},{"question":"\\"අතික්‍රමණය\\"\\"අභිබවායෑම\\"මේ වචනවල අර්ථය සමානද?නැතිනම් අර්ථ පැහැදිලිකර දෙන්න .","answer":"සමාන වචන පිළිබඳ ජී.බී. සේනානායකයන් සටහනක් ලියා තිබේ . විනිව්දිමි අඳුර සාහිත්‍ය සේසත් හෝ එවැනි විචාර ග්‍රන්ථයක . සමාන වවන දෙකහිස ඔලුවවාක්‍යයකිරුළ රජුගේ හිස මත තබන ලද්දේය.කිරුළ රජුගේ ඔලුව උඩ තබන ලද්දේ ය .වචන සමාන වන්නේ හුදෙකලාව ය.අභිබවා යාමට වඩා අතිකමණය බලවත් ය.."},{"question":"在加拿大，当单行道上左转，车辆应行驶在哪条车道？","answer":"在加拿大，当单行道向左转弯时，如果需要左转，应发出左转信号，并确保路道安全后再变换车道； 否则驾驶员应保持车速继续在原车道上行驶。"},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу бир фактыны айтып берчи?","answer":"Албетте, мына сизге кызыктуу факты:Дүйнөдөгү эң ылдам полиция унаасы кайда экенин билесиңби?  Бул Италиядан келген Lamborghini Gallardo.  Анын ылдамдыгы 309 км/саат"},{"question":"ሩት 12 ጌጦች አሉአት፡፡ 5ቱን ለርብቃ ሰጠች፡፡ ሩት ስንት ጌጦች ይቀሩአታል?","answer":"ሩት ክ12 ጌጦች 5ቱን ለርብቃ ስትሰጥ 12-5=7 ጌጦች ይቀሩአታል።"},{"question":"நாடகக்கலையைப் பற்றியும் ,காட்சித்திரைகளைப் பற்றியும் , நாடக அரங்கின் அமைப்புப் பற்றியும் விரிவாக கூறும் நூல் ?","answer":"விடை - சிலப்பதிகாரம்"},{"question":"اولین حمله مغول ها به ایران در چه دورانی بود؟","answer":"خوارزمشاهیان"},{"question":"भारतातील स्वच्छ जलचर माशाचे सर्वाधिक उत्पादन करणारे राज्य कोणते आहे?(A) हिमाचल प्रदेश(B) बिहार(C) पश्चिम बंगाल(D) यापैकी काहीही नाही=> ","answer":"(C) पश्चिम बंगाल"},{"question":"Inona no volana aorinan'ny Oktobra","answer":"Novambra no volana aorinan'ny Oktobra"},{"question":"句子1: 2014年以后, 更多来自乌克兰东部的乌克兰人, 更多的男性和更多的年轻乌克兰人在波兰工作. 句子2: 2014年以后, 更多来自乌克兰东部的乌克兰人, 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"ටෙස්ලා ඔහුගේ ශාරීරික සෞඛ්‍යය ගැන සැලකිලිමත් වූ බව පෙන්නුම් කළ අවස්ථාවක් වන්නේ? පෙර ප්‍රශ්නයට පිළිතුර ඡේදයකින් දෙන්න. මේ සඳහා ඔබට වාක්‍ය 1 - 20ක් අතර භාවිතා කළ හැක. පසුබිම:","answer":"ව්‍යායාම සඳහා ටෙස්ලා දිනකට සැතපුම් 8 සිට 10 දක්වා ප්‍රමාණයක් ඇවිද ගිය බව පැවසෙයි. සෑම රාත්‍රියක ම ඔහු සිය පාදයේ ඇඟිලි සිය වාරයක් තදින් පිරිමැදි බව‌‌ට සඳහන් වීම ද ඔහු ශාරීරික සෞඛ්‍යය ගැන ඉතා ම සැලකිලිමත් වූ බව පෙන්නුම් කරයි."},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-component","answer":"உறுப்புக்கூறு"},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase:  A disputa da categoria Florete Individual Masculino foi um evento do","answer":"Campeonato Mundial de Esgrima de 2014 e foi decidida no dia 19 de julho."},{"question":"Qual é o nome do macaco de estimação de Ross em Friends?","answer":"Marcel"},{"question":"Sau nawa ana yin ku a Nigeria?","answer":"Tun bayan da Najeriya ta samu ‘yancin kai a shekarar 1960, an yi juyin mulkin soja guda biyar a Najeriya. Tsakanin 1966 zuwa 1999, gwamnatin mulkin soja ta yi mulkin Najeriya ba tare da tsangwama ba, baya ga komawar dimokuradiyya na dan kankanin lokaci a karkashin Jamhuriyyar Najeriya ta Biyu ta 1979 zuwa 1983."},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity.Fanambarana: \\"Very tany anaty fiara fitaterana ny findaiko\\"","answer":"Ny fanambarana teo aloha dia manondro alahelo. Malahelo ianao fa very ny findainao."},{"question":"Apakah soalan untuk: \\"\\"Stand by Me\\" adalah lagu yang asalnya dari Ben E. King dan ditulis oleh King, Jerry Leiber, dan Mike Stoller, yang diilhamkan oleh rohani \\"Lord Stand by Me\\", ditambah dua baris yang berakar pada Mazmur 46:2<unk>3\\"? Topiknya ialah Stand by Me (lagu).","answer":"Lagu \\"Stand by Me?\\""},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de uma pergunta trivia da categoria: livros","answer":"Qual livro da série 'Crepúsculo' foi lançado em 2007? Eclipse"},{"question":"Maak een artikel met de volgende kop: Stikstofnormen worden strenger, natuur is er slechter aan toe dan gedacht ","answer":"Nederland krijgt de komende tien jaar te maken met strengere stikstofeisen dan de normen die nu gelden. Beschermde natuurgebieden hebben meer last van stikstof dan gedacht, blijkt uit onderzoek van de Wageningen Universiteit in opdracht van het ministerie van Landbouw, Natuur en Voedselkwaliteit (LNV). Aan de hand van dat onderzoek worden iedere tien jaar stikstofnormen vastgesteld.Het gaat om de zogenoemde KDW, de Kritische Depositiewaarde. Dat is de maximale hoeveelheid stikstof die een natuurgebied aan kan zonder dat de natuur er verslechtert.De NOS berichtte vorig jaar al over een uitgebreid internationaal onderzoek waaruit bleek dat de bestaande stikstofnormen niet streng genoeg zijn. Nederlandse wetenschappers hebben nu onderzocht wat de uitkomsten van dat internationale onderzoek betekenen voor de Nederlandse stikstofnormen.Gemiddeld mag in natuurgebieden de komende jaren zo'n 7 procent minder stikstof neerkomen dan tot nu toe, met uitschieters tot 36 procent.De NOS legde de nieuwe normen op de kaart van de stikstofgevoelige natuurgebieden in Nederland. Daaruit blijkt dat in bijna 47 procent van de gebieden de normen strenger worden. Een kleine 3 procent krijgt juist minder strenge normen. Voor de rest verandert niets."},{"question":"క్రింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండి: ప్రపంచ చిత్తడి నేల దినం గా దేన్ని పాటిస్తారు? ","answer":"ప్రపంచ చిత్తడి నేల దినం గా ఫిబ్రవరి 2 న పాటిస్తారు."},{"question":"வயிற்றில் பல் இருக்கும் உயிரினம் எது? ","answer":"விடை: நண்டு"},{"question":"Analisando as alternativas abaixo, escolha aquela em que é indicado o local onde acontece o processo de glicólise.a) na mitocôndria.b) no cloroplasto.c) no ribossomo.d) no retículo endoplasmático.e) no citosol.","answer":"A alternativa e) está correta. A glicólise acontece no citosol."},{"question":"በ 1825 በሃንስ ክርስቲያን ኦሬስትድ የተገኘው የትኛው ብረት ነው?","answer":"አሉሚኒየም"},{"question":"Pag hatag ug bulleted list sa mga butang na kailangan huna-hunaon kung mag palit ug balay.","answer":"Niay mga butang na kailangan huna-hunaon kung mag palit ug balay:1. Lokasyon2. Purchase price and mortgage rates3. Floor Plan / Layout4. Design / Finishings5. Garage space6. Storage space7. Unsa ka kadugoy mu puyo anang lugara8. Property taxes9. Insurance rates10. Maintenance costs\\""},{"question":"Ahoana no iatrehanao ny tsy fitovian-kevitra amin'ny mpiray tampo amin'ny fanapahan-kevitra momba ny fikarakarana ny raibe sy renibenao?","answer":"Alefaso amim-pahatoniana sy amim-panajana ny tsy fitovian-kevitra, mitadiava marimaritra iraisana, ary asio mpanelanelana raha ilaina. Ataovy laharam-pahamehana hatrany ny tombontsoan’ny raibe sy renibenao."},{"question":"कृपया रिक्त स्थानों को पूरा करें: \\"__________ के साथ-साथ __________ भी होना आवश्यक है, क्योंकि __________ को सही मार्ग पर दिशा में देखने में मदद करते हैं.\\"","answer":"संघर्ष के साथ-साथ संतुष्टि भी होना आवश्यक है, क्योंकि संतुष्टि को सही मार्ग पर दिशा में देखने में मदद करती है."},{"question":"\\"Ny Great Barrier Reef no rafitra haran-dranomasina lehibe indrindra eran-tany, hita ao amin'ny Ranomasina Coral eo amoron'ny morontsirak'i Queensland, Aostralia.\\"Fanontaniana: Aiza no misy ny Great Barrier Reef?1. Ranomasina Mediterane2. Ranomasimbe Pasifika3. Ranomasina Coral any amin'ny morontsirak'i Queensland, Aostralia","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia ny 3. Ranomasina Coral any amoron-tsirak'i Queensland, Aostralia."},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: Grup üyeleri 2001 yılında","answer":"Eurovision Şarkı Yarışması'na \\"Listen To Your Heartbeat\\" adlı şarkıyla katılmış, yarışmada beşinci olmuştur."},{"question":"Question: Which compound has the weakest bond?a. Diamondb. Neon (solid)c. KCld. Water (ice)Answer:","answer":"Answer: (b) Neon (solid)Diamond contains strong covalent bonds. In potassium chloride (KCl), an ionic bond is present whereas in ice molecules, a hydrogen bond is present. Neon solids are usually held together by Van Der Waals forces.Decreasing order of strength of bond is as follows:-Ionic > Covalent > Hydrogen > Dipole−Dipole > Van der Waals"},{"question":"Maxaad kula talin laheyd qofka doonaya in uu guuleysto ?","answer":"Maxaad kula talin laheyd qofka doonaya in uu guuleysto?Dantaada raaco!Waayo? Maxaa yeeley, guushu waxa ay u baahan tahay isxakamayn, shaqo joogto ah, diirad saarid, aqoon ama xirfad, maanfurnaan; intaas oo dhammina waxa ay u baahan yihiin ammin(time)Ammintu waa shayga ugu qaalisan ee ilaha ay ka soo burqadaan, waxa aad baadigoobeyso.Waxa aad moodaa in si joogto ah innooga dayacmayo waqtigu, maxa yeeley:-Waxa aynu akhrinaa ama dawaanaa wararka maalintii oo dhan.Eegista xad-ka-baxa ah ee mareegta bulshada. Ka daawashada aflaanta muuqbaahiyaha iyo youtub-ka.Ku mashquuulida nolosha dadka kale.Ku mashquulka adeegsiga moobeylka, adiga oo kolba qof u sheekeynaya; kolba inta aad ka baxdo haddana ku soo noqonaya!Intaas sare aynu ku soo xusney iyo in kale oo la mid ah, waxa ay lumiyaan waqtigeenna. Maalmuhu waxa ay innagu dhaafaan sibiq.Haddaba, si aynnu u noqonno kuwo guuleysta waa in aynu yeelanaa qorshe. Xeellado aynu ku guuleysan karno waa inaynu yegleelnaa. Hadalku wuu innala fogaadey oo wuu innala foof tagee, halka aynu u soconayba ilaawee; hadalkeenii ugu horreeyay ee aynu ku bilownay muxuu ahaa? Aan kuu sheegee, waxa uu ahaa dantaada raaco.Maxay macnaheedu tahay dantaada raaco?Dantaada raaco, waxa ay u eegtahay sidan:1. Halka aynu subixii marka ay kacno bilaabeyno akhriska wararka, waa in aynu hore u kacnaa oo salaadda tukanaa. Waa in aynu socod yar samaynaa, jimicsanaa ama koob shaaha/kaafee ah ku dhufanaa, sidaas ayay maalintaadu ku noqonaysaa mid degan.2. Inta aad dhex mushaaxeyso TikTok, Instagram, waa inaad iska fogeysaa moobeylka oo aad diiradda saartaa hawsha ugu adag, subaxa horeba.."},{"question":"Apa yang berlaku apabila Beneden Merwede bercabang? Berdasarkan soalan sebelumnya, tulis konteks yang mengandungi jawapannya. Konteks boleh mengandungi 1 - 20 ayat. Konteks:","answer":"Dari sini, keadaan menjadi lebih rumit, kerana nama Belanda Rijn tidak lagi bertepatan dengan saluran air utama. Dua pertiga daripada jumlah aliran air Rhine mengalir ke barat, melalui Waal dan kemudian, melalui Merwede dan Nieuwe Merwede (De Biesbosch), bergabung dengan Meuse, melalui muara Hollands Diep dan Haringvliet, ke Laut Utara. Beneden Merwede bercabang, berhampiran Hardinxveld-Giessendam dan terus sebagai Noord, untuk menyertai Lek, berhampiran kampung Kinderdijk, untuk membentuk Nieuwe Maas; kemudian mengalir melepasi Rotterdam dan meneruskan melalui Het Scheur dan Nieuwe Waterweg, ke Laut Utara. Percabangan Oude Maas, berhampiran Dordrecht, lebih jauh ke bawahnya bergabung dengan Nieuwe Maas untuk membentuk Het Scheur."}]`),I={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:T},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:S,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},C={class:"search-container"},B={class:"card-container"},O=["disabled"],D={key:0},P={key:1};function L(e,a,s,k,t,r){const m=y("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",C,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),b(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=u=>t.searchQuery=u),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",B,[(i(!0),o(c,null,p(r.filteredPoems,(u,g)=>(i(),f(m,{key:g,poem:u},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),r.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...u)=>r.loadMore&&r.loadMore(...u))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",P,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",D,"See more"))],8,O)):j("",!0)])}const _=h(I,[["render",L],["__scopeId","data-v-b94b3cf8"]]),F=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/5.md","filePath":"chatai/5.md"}'),K={name:"chatai/5.md"},H=Object.assign(K,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[q(_)]))}});export{F as __pageData,H as default};
